- [Narrator] Switzerland,
a country internationally
famous for its fine watches,
its great skiing, and
its luxurious resorts,
but Switzerland's biggest
industry is banking.
Because Swiss banks are
unique in all the world.
They have secret numbered accounts
and the owner's name is always
held in strictest confidence.
This secrecy is protected
by the Swiss government.
No individual, no corporation,
not even the power of a
government can discover the name
of a depositor.
For this reason,
anyone with a great deal
of money to hide knows
that Switzerland is the safest sanctuary.
Criminals, tax evaders,
and political agents all find
Swiss banks the perfect place
to conceal their dirty money
and their dirty secrets.
The system is considered
foolproof, or at least it was.
(guests chatter)
(plates clink)
(gun clicks)
(gun fires)
(glass shatters)
(guests scream)
(upbeat music)
(upbeat music continues)
(employee speaking in foreign language)
(client speaking in foreign language)
(employee knocks)
(employee speaking in foreign language)
(letter opener clinks)
(secretary knocks)
(luggage thumps)
(announcer speaking in foreign language)
- Your passport, please.
Thank you.
Mr. Hayes?
- Yeah?
- The purpose of your visit?
- Business.
- Do you have anything to declare?
- No, nothing.
- Have a nice trip, Mr. Hayes.
- Thank you very much.
(suspenseful music)
(trunk thumps)
(engine rumbles)
(Franz knocks)
- Herr Hurtil.
(paper rustles)
- The writing is the same.
"If you want your clients'
secret bank accounts
to remain secret, you'll
pay us 10 million francs.
Wait for instructions."
- I don't understand.
Why should we pay 1 0 million francs
to these people, whoever they are?
What are we to do?
Go to the police?
- Never!
(phone buzzes)
Yes?
- Mr. Dwight McGowan
from America just phoned.
He insisted on coming
to see you immediately.
- Very well.
When he gets here, I'll see him.
- Another one?
- An American McGowan.
Earlier I got a call from
Herr Kosta from Amsterdam.
He said it was a matter
of extreme urgency.
I think I need a drink.
What about you?
- [Franz] Definitely.
- You hear the name David Christopher?
- [Franz] You mean that
American in Geneva?
- An American used to be
with the United States
Department of Justice.
He knows a great many names
and can pull a great many strings,
as we well know, both of us.
(upbeat music)
(bell clangs)
(engine rumbles)
(tires squeal)
- Lady.
Lady!
What in the hell are you doing?
- You were planning to park in my spot?
I'm so sorry, shall I move?
- Forget it.
- Oh, look, he's moving out.
I will hold the place for
you, but this time be quick.
Oh, no, I'm sorry.
It's for this gentleman over here.
Hurry.
You must hurry, you see?
You forgive me?
- I forgive you.
- Good.
We Ferrari owners must stick together.
Auf wiedersehen.
(car honks)
- Oh, not again.
- Looks like it.
(crowd chatters)
- Now, lady, we gotta
stop meeting like this.
- Yes, people will talk.
I have an appointment.
- I have an appointment.
- (laughs) You too.
- Tell you what we'll
do, we’ll toss a coin.
I think I've got a two headed one here.
I'm gonna toss it to see who goes first.
- Very well, I call heads.
(upbeat music)
- Ah, Ms. Abbott.
Mr. Christopher, it's
awfully generous of you
to interrupt your vacation
at such short notice.
However, I completely forgot
that Ms. Abbott is always on
time for her appointments.
- (laughs) Thanks, sir.
- Won't you come in, please, both of you?
(phone buzzes)
- [Speaker] Mr. Hayes from Chicago is here
to see Mr. Benninger.
- Very well, Burnham, send him in.
Herr Benninger and Mr. Robert
Hayes of Chicago to see you.
- Much as I'd like to take advantage
of your very delightful company,
I think it best if we get to
the point of this meeting.
- Of course.
- Now, Ms. Abbott, the bank
has retained Mr. Christopher
in this special emergency
to protect the interest of its clients
and I wanted him to meet you.
- Why does Ms. Abbott need protection?
- I asked the bank for a statement.
This is it.
- A routine statement
identified by a number only.
- Compare the two, and you will know
why I had trouble sleeping
the last two nights.
- "Mademoiselle Denise Abbott,
unless you pay us 1 million
Swiss francs to be silent,
why you have a numbered account
will be revealed in London."
- 1 million francs.
Isn't that stupid?
Where am I going to get a million francs?
And they can see what I've
got, 200,000 or something.
Less now.
- Ms. Abbott, the first steps
have already been taken.
I'm sure Mr. Christopher
will have some questions
to ask you.
And I propose that you make
yourself available to him later.
- Of course.
Mr. Christopher.
- If you need any help,
don't hesitate to call us at the bank
or Mr. Christopher's at
the Roundhouse Daughter.
- I'm at the Bellevue.
Auf wiedersehen.
- Auf wiedersehen.
- Delighted to have you
with us again, Mr. Hayes.
Did you have a good trip?
- Cut the crap, Benninger.
You got some explaining to do.
There's a million there
for account number 763421 .
This, this is what I got
to show from my account.
I trusted you and your damn bank.
Now somebody squealed my
goddamn number to somebody
and I'm dead unless I come
up with a million francs
like today.
- "Robert Hayes, unless you
pay us 1 million Swiss francs
to be silent, your secret bank
statement will be revealed
to your business associates."
- Yeah.
- I'm terribly sorry.
- Sorry, bullshit.
I want to know what
you're gonna do about it.
- So Denise Abbott is the fourth victim
in the last 24 hours,
the others being Andre
Kosta from Amsterdam,
Dwight McGowan from Los Angeles,
and Agaorg Rasha from Vienna.
- That's right.
- Agaorg Rasha.
Didn't I read about him in the newspaper?
Wasn't he killed in a
restaurant last night?
- Yes, I'm afraid so.
Now, what's more, this came this morning.
- "If you want your clients'
secret bank accounts
to remain secret, you will
pay us 10 million francs.
Wait for instructions."
- I can't impress the point
too strongly, Mr. Christopher,
that there must be no publicity.
We cannot afford a scandal.
(Franz knocks)
Yes.
- Sorry, Herr Hurtil,
but Mr. Hayes is another of the victims.
- Hello, Bobby.
- What's he doing here?
- Do you know each other?
- Yeah, well, not socially.
- Answer me.
- The bank has retained Mr. Christopher
to protect its clients, Mr. Hayes.
- Protect us?
What are you, crazy?
He's US Justice Department.
- Not anymore, Bobby, not
for a couple of years.
- Get him outta here.
You hear me?
Swiss banks don't give up
their clients' numbers.
Not for nobody.
You got some friends back
home been looking for you.
You know that, don't you?
They'd like to pay you back
for all you've done for 'em.
They got a long memory.
All right, I'm leaving this bank right now
and I'm making a long distance
phone call, person to person.
My guess is if you are
not out of this town
by this time tomorrow,
they're gonna find you
in the nearest meat house
along with the other dead pigs.
Justice.
That's all I need.
- I must apologize for our
client, Mr. Christopher.
Won't you sit down?
This is my vice president, Mr. Benninger.
- Hello, Mr. Benninger.
- Hello.
- Do you know this man Hayes?
- Yes, I know him, he's a crook.
His partner is worse.
- That threat, you think he was serious?
- Yes, he was serious.
Oh, what are Mr. Hayes's problems
besides the obvious ones?
- Here.
- So Mr. Hayes is victim number five?
- Yes.
- This his own numbered account?
- That is correct.
- What does this represent?
- Give your attention to the deposits
and withdrawals on both accounts.
- It looks like he's taking
money from this account
and putting it in this account.
- Again, correct.
I found out about this just very recently.
He invests the funds that he borrowed
and keeps the profits for himself.
Unfortunately, at present,
he's heavily in debt
to account number 763421 , as you can see.
- Bad investments.
- I'm afraid that we don't
have that information.
- I see, well, if account 761 3421 belongs
to who I think it belongs to,
Bobby Hayes is ridiculous.
He's not a beginner.
He knows what his
associates will do to him
if they find out about it.
That's his problem.
This one's ours, isn't it?
Blackmailers want 10
million francs from the bank
and 1 million francs
from each of the victims,
five so far.
1 5 million francs, right?
- If we exclude the unfortunate Rasha.
- No, the price will stay the
same, that was only a warning.
So 1 5 million francs, that's what?
Approximately 6 million American dollars?
They must think you'll all pay, why?
Because you can't go to the police,
the scandal would be public in 24 hours.
Not very good advertising
for a proper Swiss bank.
And because the
blackmailers have five names
that go with five numbered accounts
and information about those accounts
that the five don't want exposed.
Who could have put the
names and numbers together?
- Well, that's quite obvious, isn't it?
- Is it?
- Well, of course.
These five people must have
been incredibly careless.
- Nobody's careless with
a secret numbered account.
Especially in the case of Bobby Hayes.
And gentlemen,
if I wanted to put the
names and numbers together,
I'd come to Zurich right
here to Hurtil Bank.
I'd find somebody in your organization
who had access to the
names and the numbers.
Now, who do you suppose
that somebody could be?
- Well, I suppose I could put the names
and numbers together.
- You're suspect number one.
- The second and most
likely suspect would be me.
Our master list is kept in
our vault, a special safe.
Only I have the combination.
- You're suspect number two.
That it?
- We Swiss are a cautious people.
- Obviously not cautious enough.
Hurtil, have your
secretary make appointments
with Mr. Kosta and Mr. McGowan.
So Denise Abbott's expecting my call
and Bobby Hayes doesn't want to talk to me
and Mr. Rasha is dead.
I guess that's it.
I'll send you a letter stating
the terms of my employment.
If you agree, I'll be
working for Hurtil Bank.
- Very kind of you to come.
I know we're in trouble,
but I'm confident that you can help us.
- [David] I'm doing my best.
- [Franz] I hope his best is good enough.
- Car for Korsak.
- When was the booking made?
- Today.
Yesterday.
What the hell, it was
last night Chicago time.
- Oh, yes, I have it.
A package was left here for you.
- I'll take that.
- Alright, Mr. Korsak,
would you please sign at the bottom, sir?
I already have your other details.
How long do you need the car?
- Not long.
- And here are the keys
for the silver gray BMW
and you’ll find it at the end of the hall,
through the door in our parking lot.
- Thank you, honey.
- [Cashier] Goodbye.
(engine rumbles)
(phone buzzes)
- David Christopher and associates,
consultant on international affairs.
May I help you?
- When in the hell did
I acquire associates?
- I'm just practicing, darling,
for when you make me your partner.
Besides, it sounds more legitimate.
- The only thing illegitimate
in that office is you, Corinne.
Hey, grab a pencil, will you?
- You are so old fashioned, David.
It's the electronic age now, you know.
- Yeah, all right, turn
on the damn machine.
- It's on, sir.
- Get ahold of Jack Foley
at the Justice Department
in Washington DC.
Tell him I want some
information on a Dwight McGowan.
He's a Texan, but he runs
his business out of LA.
And ask him if Luigi Vasili has got
any of his people coming
in and outta Zurich,
and if so, why?
Next, get ahold of Freddy
Cohen in Paris, honey.
If you can't remember
the number, look it up.
I want some information on the following.
- It is bad news, isn't it?
- No, not necessarily so.
It's just unexpected
complication, that's all.
- Then you mean all of our
planning's just out the window.
- Please relax, Rita.
You make me very nervous.
Come on, sit down, have
a drink, and listen.
- Yes, sit down, have a drink, and listen.
And relax.
Franz, everything depended on today.
We have very little time,
Franz, don't you see?
I know what it is.
The bank doesn't want to pay.
That's it, isn't it?
We won't get the money.
- Now, Rita, for God's sake,
this is getting ridiculous.
Please, try to control yourself.
- I'm sorry.
- I love you, remember?
- I love you too.
But I have this terrible feeling.
What was it, Franz?
- What was what?
- The unexpected complication.
- A consultant called David
Christopher has been hired
by the bank.
He's a very clever man.
We must find a way to deal with him.
(car honks)
(phone rings)
- Hello?
- [Denise] Mr. Christopher?
- [David] Yeah, who's this?
- Denise Abbott.
I'm sorry to disturb you,
but something rather urgent has come up.
- [David] What happened?
- I'll tell you when you get here.
- Alright, I'll be at the
Bellevue in about 20 minutes.
Is that all right?
- Yes, that will be okay.
There is plenty of parking.
(engine rumbles)
(suspenseful music)
(gun fires)
(water splashes)
(steam hisses)
(fists smack)
(groans)
(head thumps)
(police speaking in foreign language)
(people shout)
- Hotel St. Gallen.
(police speaking in foreign language)
- Captain Hans Frey with federal police.
What's going on here?
- Some guy took a shot
at me, ran out that door.
- What's your name, please?
- Oh, I'm Christopher.
- Do you have a passport or something?
- Yeah.
- Please.
Thank you.
- He's about medium height.
He had on a blue raincoat and a dark hat.
- American, huh?
Swiss resident.
Businessman.
What is your business, Mr. Christopher?
- I'm a consultant.
They took a shot at me down there,
we had a fight, and he lost
his gun somewhere over there.
- Schwand?
- Yeah.
- Come over here.
See if you can find a gun.
- [Schwand] Okay.
- Look, Captain, I had an appointment
about a half an hour ago with
a client at the Bellevue.
- Who in Zurich is consulting you?
- Hurtil Bank.
- On what?
- Business.
- Business?
Are you registered at the hotel?
- 709.
- Who was he?
- The man with the...
- Yeah, the man.
- I don't know, I didn't
get that good a look at him.
I was pretty busy.
- Mm.
You've just given me a
fairly detailed description,
Mr. Christopher, so you weren't that busy.
- Captain, there is no gun, but the hat.
- So?
- Well, he did take a shot at me.
Now, they must have heard the shot.
Look, I don't have a gun.
- For the moment, Mr.
Christopher, you may go,
but I think we shall meet again.
I'm in charge of the
federal bank detail, Zurich.
(engines rumble)
(door thumps)
(suspenseful music)
(tires squeal)
(car crashes)
- Head him off!
(tires squeal)
(gun fires)
(car crashes)
(suspenseful music)
(crowd shouts)
(tires squeal)
(gun fires)
(car crashes)
(water splashes)
(gun fires)
(dumpster rattles)
(dumpster crashes)
(gun fires)
(Robert gasps)
(attacker screams)
(shovel clangs)
(gun fires)
(Robert gasps)
(foot smacks)
(Robert groans)
(Robert gasps)
(calm music)
(guests chatter)
(water splashes)
(doorbell rings)
(David knocks)
- [Denise] Who is it?
- Denise Abbott?
- [Denise] Who are you?
- David Christopher, you phoned me.
- You're late.
I didn't think you were coming.
I was taking a bath.
Come in, please.
Please, sit down.
I'll change into something
less comfortable.
Make yourself a drink.
I'll drink what you drink.
(singing in foreign language)
Do you speak German?
- No.
- It doesn't matter.
Personally, I never listen to the words.
What are we drinking?
- Scotch okay?
- Scotch is fine.
Do you?
- Do I what?
- Listen to the words?
- No, no.
- I suppose it's too gauche or something
to admit that in these days
of the philosopher minstrel
telling us all about life,
but frankly I don't give a damn.
Here's to your quest.
- Here's to it.
You said it was urgent.
- You said 20 minutes.
- Yeah, want to apologize about that.
I ran into a curious policeman.
- [Denise] I must admit, I'm curious too.
- About what?
- Mr. Hurtil called to assure
me that this very clever man,
Mr. Christopher, was now
handling my situation.
- Yeah, Hurtil's been a banker too long.
He uses words like situation
when he means blackmail.
- Are you very clever, Mr. Christopher?
- Well, that depends on who you talk to.
- I was also told I...
I'm not the only one
involved in this situation.
- No, there are others.
- And you will investigate them all,
look in their closets and find skeletons?
- Well, show me a closet.
- Why would Mr. Hurtil
hire you to protect me?
- Why not?
- Well, for one thing to say,
you've been with United
States Justice Department?
Then left rather abruptly,
if that's the word,
to make a home in Switzerland.
- [David] So?
- So one wonders what you've got to hide.
- I thought we were going
to talk about your problem.
You have something you want
to ask me or talk to me about,
you just go right ahead.
- Sorry.
Just testing.
Yeah, there is something
that's really bothering me.
Something I want to talk to you about.
How many accounts, secret that is,
would there be at Hurtil Bank?
- I don't know, a thousand, I guess.
- That's it, that's just it.
If there are, why would
you pick the ones like me?
Only someone inside the bank-
- Ones like you?
- The ones with skeletons.
- And skeleton have a name?
- James Ashwood.
Lord James Ashwood.
- And Lord James doesn't want
his name in the paper, huh?
- Wouldn’t be helpful to his career
or agreeable to his wife.
- You and Lord James would-
- No, it's been over now for some time.
- But the blackmailer is thinking
it'd still make good reading.
- I suppose so.
(phone rings)
There.
Excuse me.
Yeah, what is it?
Oh, Mr. Christopher.
Yes, it's for you.
A certain Captain Frey, I think he said.
- Hello, how'd you find me?
Yes, I know the Swiss
police are very efficient.
What do you want?
The hell would I want with a rented car?
(engine rumbles)
Now what in the hell is
all this about a Hertz car?
I don't need a Hertz car.
I got a car, you see it?
- The man wore a Hertz uniform.
He stated the car was ordered by you.
He mentioned your room number.
- The package, Captain.
- And he said that the package
you wanted delivered is
in the trunk.
Shall we examine this package?
- I suppose if I said I
didn't want to, you'd insist.
- Yes, I insist.
Shall we go?
All right.
Here, please.
(dramatic music)
(machine whirs)
(paper tears)
(phone rings)
- Hello.
- It's 11 o'clock, you've overslept.
- I was up half the night
with the Zurich police
who insist I'm responsible
for a Bobby Hayes
that was stuffed into a
trunk of a rented car,
which they say I rented,
which I didn't rent,
now don't further complicate my life.
What is it?
- Did you escape?
- No, no.
I didn't sign for the car.
They let me go.
- I don't understand.
- Never mind, get to the point.
- Jack Foley said there was trouble.
- What kind of trouble?
- [Corinne] Two men, a Korsak and Sando,
employees of Luigi Vasili,
left Chicago in a hurry night before last,
destination Zurich.
- Well, they did their thing.
They're probably halfway home by now.
Unless they stay on.
- Unless what?
- Oh, nothing, never mind.
Go on.
- Well, let's start with Rasha.
Now Freddy says he's a Czech or Bulgarian.
One of those.
An arms dealer specialized
in selling old weapons
to new countries and
really ripping them off.
And they swore to get him.
Freddy says it's only a matter of time.
- Yeah, well, Freddy's right,
only his time ran out yesterday.
What else you got?
- [Corinne] Well, so far
Hurtil and Benninger have
a clean bill of health.
Jack Foley said he's
mailing you a file on Hayes.
I've sent a messenger with
a dossier on Denise Abbott
to your hotel.
Let's see.
That just leaves Mr. Texas.
(guests chatter)
- Dwight McGowan?
- David Christopher?
- That's right.
- How about sharing some of
this back home whiskey with me?
- Beer is fine.
- Waiter, waiter.
Bring my friend here a nice cold beer.
Well, Davey, I've been wondering
when you're going to
get around old Dwight.
Herr Hurtil tells me
you're gonna be my knight
in shining armor and keep
those bastards off my back.
- Same message to the
Internal Revenue Service?
- You've been talking to
someone about me, boy?
- They volunteered the information.
- You sure are a quiet one, David boy.
But now don't you worry.
I got me a deal simmering back
in LA that'll set me flying.
Those tax claims, peanuts.
Old Dwight and his Uncle Sammy just has
a little disagreement
over some back taxes.
Nothing serious.
- Well, old Dwight,
I'd be a liar if I said
they weren't concerned.
- My old daddy used to say,
"Son, don't you lose your head
because your ass is sure to follow."
- You wanna translate that for me?
- Well, let me say it this way.
You take care of this blackmail bullshit
and I'll take care of my
Uncle Sammy, you hear?
- How well did you know Hayes and Rasha?
How about Kosta, Denise Abbott?
- Oh, I didn't know 'em.
Herr Hurtil mentioned 'em to
me, but I never knew 'em, boy.
- Who handled your account?
- [Dwight] Me.
- How about your wife, she know about it?
- Oh, little lady and I have
been divorced for nine years.
- Secretary, business manager?
- Nobody.
I guard those papers with my life, boy.
See, I'm scared, Davey.
I don't have much more time.
I'm getting on and I can't
afford any big setbacks.
- Well, Mac, money ain't everything.
- You trying to tell me something, Davey?
- Yeah, five little secret
accounts came to Zurich.
Hayes was killed and then there were four.
Rasha was killed and
then there were three.
You show up and your daddy
might turn out to be right.
- Hello, Rita Jensen.
- Rita, it's Franz.
- Everything all right?
- So far so good.
I've set it up.
Just a matter of following through.
- What's the plan?
- Just as we discussed.
Now you know what to do.
Meet me tomorrow morning just before noon
at the entrance of the park.
All right?
Auf wiedersehen.
- [Rita] Auf wiedersehen.
- Good morning.
Good morning.
(door thumps)
(paper rustles)
- Herr Kosta, this is Mr. Christopher.
As I told you on the telephone,
we've retained him to protect us and you.
These seem to be the final instructions.
"The day after tomorrow,
your Mr. Christopher."
They know you.
"With 1 5 million francs in uncut diamonds
accompanied by the account
holders will proceed
to Wilderswil to the first
intersection past Interlaken.
There, you will find a car
parked next to a wooden barn
with further instructions.
No surveillance or all lives are forfeit."
- It's gonna be a hell of a crowd.
Can you get the diamonds?
- We have a supply in the vault.
- How about you, Mr. Kosta?
Are you gonna come up with the money?
- Why should I pay a million franks?
I did not break security, the bank did.
- You have evidence?
- Evidence?
- Evidence, facts, proof.
- How else could it have happened?
- No evidence.
- Actually, Mr. Christopher,
Herr Benninger and I have
discussed this matter
and we reached the
conclusion that the bank,
without admitting any
irresponsibility, will pay the ransom
in order to save the lives of our clients.
Especially after the dreadful
death of Mr. Hayes last night,
I can't risk another life.
- That's very noble of you, Herr Hurtil.
- We realize this is a temporary solution,
that the reputation of
the bank is worth more
than 1 5 million francs.
- And the bank will make up its losses
with additional charges to its customers.
- The percentage of loss
will have very little effect
in the charges of the customers.
- No wonder they thought you might pay.
- We'll pay, just this once.
That's why we hired you.
We do not like the possibility
of further loss along these lines.
- I see.
Mr. Kosta, I'd like to talk to you.
- What are you after?
- The bank has hired me
to protect its clients from blackmail.
I just wanna know why
you're being blackmailed.
- Isn't that academic now?
The Hurtil Bank has agreed
to follow the blackmailer’s
final instructions
and pay their demands.
Your job now, it seems to me,
is to see that these
instructions are carried out.
I must go now.
Herr Hurtil, may I thank you
for your gracious handling
of a most difficult situation.
Auf wiedersehen.
- Auf wiedersehen.
Well, as you pointed
out, we have no evidence.
And at this moment, I have no choice.
(engine rumbles)
- I spoke to Mr. Hurtil.
He says there's a ransom to pay.
- Yeah, that's what I
want to talk to you about.
- Good.
Follow me.
(engine rumbles)
(upbeat music)
(upbeat music continues)
(tires squeal)
(upbeat music)
(engines rumble)
(tires squeal)
(engine rumbles)
I'm so sorry.
- It's all this stupid job.
(Denise sighs)
What?
- I must tell you something.
- You're married and
have 1 0 children, right?
- (laughs) No.
I'm serious.
- I'm not.
- No, please.
I want to make a confession.
- Do I look like a priest?
- Look like the man I just made love to.
- Good, now that you confess-
- No, no, please.
- Okay, confess, confess.
- My father...
My father-
- Your father was a drunk.
So was mine, so what?
- You know about that?
- Yeah, I know about it.
- You know the rest?
- Most of it.
Your mother ran away
when your father died.
You were brought up in a convent.
You ran away from the
convent when you were 17.
You worked as a model, a waitress-
- Mistress.
- And my information
is that it wasn't work.
You were in love.
- Mm.
I told you about Jamie.
- Don't tell about Jamie.
- I told you it was over.
- Told me it was over.
- You don't care?
- You said it was over.
- Yeah, it is.
He went back to his wife,
his children, and his career.
(kisses) End of the confession.
- Now it's my turn.
- Do you want to confess?
- Yeah.
I would like
a cup of coffee.
(Denise laughs)
- Alright.
- Later.
(car honks)
(tires squeal)
- Get on that boat.
(Rita speaking in foreign language)
(engine rumbles)
(upbeat music)
(upbeat music continues)
(water splashes)
- Yeah, I'm sorry I'm late.
I got held up in traffic.
- I'm afraid you made a mistake.
- It's no mistake, my
name is David Christopher.
- I don't know any David
Christopher, I'm sorry.
- I'm very big on secrets.
Any friend of Franz Benninger
is a friend of mine.
- And what big secret do you
know about me, Mr. Christopher?
- Well, call me David.
I'll call you, what'll I call you?
- For somebody that big on secrets,
I'm surprised you don't know.
(waiter speaking in foreign language)
(David speaking in foreign language)
- Nothing, thank you.
- Oh, nothing.
Now, Miss, Miss what?
- Jensen.
My name is Rita Jensen.
- Rita Jensen.
- And it's not a very big secret.
And if you would excuse me, please.
- [Franz] What will you have?
- Oh, I don't care.
Campari soda, anything.
- Campari soda from
madam and vodka for me,
ice twist of lemon.
- We're in trouble, Franz.
- In what trouble?
- That man, David
Christopher, saw us together.
- When?
- In front of the bank, I suppose.
He followed me.
- What?
- [Waiter] Would you
like to order now, sir?
- No thank you.
Later, thanks.
What did you tell him?
- Nothing.
- What did he say?
- He said, "Any friend
of Franz Benninger is
a friend of mine."
- Franz Benninger, my own vice president?
It can't be.
I simply cannot believe it.
- That's my information.
(phone buzzes)
- Yes?
- [Secretary] Mr. Christopher, please.
- For you.
- Hello.
I’ll wait.
- [Franz] Franz Benninger,
I would very much like to meet you.
- Yes, when?
- [Franz] At the (indistinct).
- When?
- [Franz] At (indistinct).
- I'll be there.
Franz Benninger.
He wants to meet me.
- He's coming outta the bank.
(suspenseful music)
(engine rumbles)
(bell clangs)
(car honks)
(announcer speaking in foreign language)
(crowd chatters)
(suspenseful music)
(announcer speaking in foreign language)
- Hey, come on.
(suspenseful music)
(gun fires)
(Rita gasps)
(dramatic music)
(officers speaking in foreign language)
(gun fires)
(dramatic music)
- Stop.
Stop, stop or I fire!
(gun fires)
(train rattles)
(brake squeals)
- You deny that you and Benninger
had no part of blackmail?
- Blackmail?
That's ridiculous.
You are talking about blackmail?
You have known Franz for over 30 years.
You think he would stoop to blackmail?
- The two of you have
been up to something.
What is it?
- It was my fault, everything.
My father died two months ago.
He had, I would say, a very good business.
But lately he had trouble,
financial trouble.
- But what has all this got
to do with Herr Benninger?
- Well, my father had his
numbered account in your bank,
so I made an appointment
with Mr. Benninger
and he said without the proper papers,
he could not hand over the account to me.
- That's correct.
- Well, then I saw Mr.
Benninger quite a lot of times
and we fell in love
and he decided to turn over
the numbered account to me.
And then with all these
murders happening, I mean,
we were afraid that if the
case would not get solved
and if David Christopher
could not solve it,
everything would be
lost, so we had to hurry.
And he turned over the account to me
and I in turn paid off the
loan and the debt of my father.
- And he did this without consulting me?
- Yes, Mr. Hurtil, without consulting you.
You see, Franz didn't think
he was doing anything wrong.
The money was legally mine.
I'm the only heir.
And believe me, Mr. Hurtil,
it did pain him to go behind your back.
It really did.
But you see, he loved me
and he wanted to help me.
And I loved him.
- Excuse me.
But I thought you would like to know
that Herr Benninger's condition is good.
He was very lucky.
- Thank you.
- Solves your problem, Herr Hurtil.
Tomorrow morning, give
your driver the diamonds.
Have him pick up McGowan and Kosta
and meet me at my hotel at eight o'clock.
I've got a plane to catch.
- But where are you going?
What about tomorrow morning?
- [David] I'll be back!
(plane rumbles)
(upbeat music)
- I just had a meeting
with David Christopher
at the airport.
- At the airport?
- Yes, at the airport.
We have a problem, Sergeant.
- We do?
- If we find that one of our
banks is being blackmailed
and a number of its clients are involved
with disclosures of their
secret numbered accounts,
complicated by the fact that
two of these clients have been,
shall we say, been terminated violently,
major crimes have been committed.
Murder and blackmail.
So what should we do?
- Captain, we must go to the
commissioner immediately.
- Wrong, not immediately, but very soon.
- I don't understand.
- If we present an unfinished
equation to the commissioner,
a problem without a solution,
we have a scandal of major proportions.
And that is one thing our
country does not need now.
A major banking scandal.
David Christopher is a very clever man.
He told me a very interesting story.
Fascinating.
I've given him 24 hours.
Come, Sergeant, we have work to do.
- Where was he going?
- [Frey] Who?
- Christopher.
- He didn't say.
- [Schwand] But you know.
- Yes, I know.
Uncut diamonds.
Yes, very clever.
- Uncut diamonds?
- High value in a small package.
Easy to conceal, easy to market.
Virtually untraceable.
Yes, very smart, our Mr. Blackmailer.
(upbeat music)
- I just wanted to remind you, Captain,
I'm gonna do this my way.
- You do it your way, I'll do it my way.
(Frey speaking in foreign language)
- Good morning, sir.
Cross is my name.
Here are the diamonds.
- We’ll pick up Ms.
Abbott at the Bellevue.
- Yes, sir.
(suspenseful music)
(suspenseful music continues)
- The autobahn, I'll
tell you when to get off.
- [Driver] Very well, sir.
- What's that?
- Uncut diamonds.
That's what they want,
the bank says that's what they’ll get.
- [Denise] They don't look very pretty.
(suspenseful music)
(suspenseful music continues)
(cow moos)
(paper rustles)
- "Go to Brienz,
where the road to Caral
crosses the railroad tracks.
A steam engine waits for you.
Further instructions by the engineer."
Let me check the car.
Alright, McGowan, let's go.
- I'm sorry, Davey boy,
this is as far as I go.
I can't make it.
- But the instruction says-
- Yes, I know, they said all of us.
- I'm sorry, Davey, I want no part of it.
I'm a sick man.
I've gone as far as I'm going.
- Cross, you take Mr.
McGowan back to his hotel.
He's not feeling well.
- Very well, sir.
- What happened?
- He said he's sick.
He's going back to the hotel.
How is it?
- One of the cylinders is
bad, points need adjustment,
carburetor is dirty.
Besides, she's stolen.
No registration papers,
no insurance, nothing.
(door thumps)
(engine rumbles)
(Frey speaking in foreign language)
(officer speaking in foreign language)
- This is Captain Frey.
We are in Brienz approaching Interlaken
and have just passed
the black Mercedes 600,
going now toward Zurich.
License number ZH5001 .
Pick up and follow, but
do not interfere or stop.
We'll contact later. Danke.
- I think I recognized Herr
McGowan in the backseat.
- Yes.
So did I.
(engine rumbles)
- Oh, here is good.
Yeah, here.
Go right up to the front.
This way.
(train whistle blows)
(train chugs)
Go over to the ski lift platform.
(officer speaking in foreign language)
- [Officer] Aerial
surveillance has observed
suspects boarding Interlaken's gateway.
Will continue surveillance
until further notice, ended.
(suspenseful music)
(phone rings)
- Hello?
- Start the ski tow.
Bring the diamonds up to
the top of the ski lift.
The rest stay in plain sight.
There is a rifle on each one of you.
- What did he say?
- Said I'm to bring the
diamonds to the top of the lift.
You two are supposed
to stay in plain sight.
- May I make a suggestion?
- Go ahead.
- You have no value to these people.
They'll kill you without compunction.
- But you think they won't kill you?
- I have a value.
I may be a future object of blackmail.
And if they were foolish enough to try,
I'm a fairly good shot myself.
Allow me, Mr. Christopher.
- Go ahead.
(helicopter whirs)
- Look.
- Let's go for a ride.
- What are you doing?
You're a bloody fool!
(train chugs)
- I am Captain Frey, police.
Have you seen two men and a
woman, one man an American?
- Yes, I just took them
up to the ski lift.
I was given some money yesterday
and told to expect them.
It was a joke he wanted to play
on his American tourist friend.
It was very funny.
- A joke, huh?
Can you show me exactly
what you did, please?
- Yeah, I called him from the cab.
Start the ski tow.
Bring the diamonds up here.
The rest stay in plain sight.
There is a rifle on each of you.
- He said there was a rifle on each of us.
- You know what he said?
He talked to me on the phone.
- Why are you doing this?
- I flew to London last night.
I had a little talk with Lord James.
- Why did you do that?
- Maybe I was jealous.
- He denied I was his mistress?
- No, he didn't deny it.
But you left out the good part.
Ever since he said goodbye,
you've been blackmailing him.
He's tired of it.
He told his wife, he told his children,
he's gonna take his chances
with the newspapers.
- What does that have to do with this?
- Well, once a blackmailer,
always a blackmailer.
We tried to figure out
what could put four unlikely
characters like McGowan, Kosta,
Rasha, and Hayes together,
and I came up with you, honey.
Beautiful woman alone in Zurich
will do anything for money.
- Even if it were true,
what does it prove?
- Well, it proves that
nobody broke bank security.
Nobody gave away any secret numbers.
There are no mysterious blackmailers
blackmailing all of you.
You pooled your statements
and blackmailed each other.
That's what it proves.
- You have a lovely imagination, David.
- You tell me where I went wrong then.
- If nobody takes the diamonds,
then there is no crime.
Not one you can prove.
- You count two murders,
an attempt on my life
as a misdemeanor?
- Mr. Hayes was killed by
a gangster from Chicago.
That's what I read in the newspaper.
And poor Mr. Rasha was murdered
by his business associate
whom he was cheating.
- I suppose you didn't
try to kill me in the car.
You didn't encourage Bobby Hayes
to try to kill me in the garage.
- I'm not responsible for Bobby Hayes
and I'm not responsible for Mr. Kosta
or for the very charming Mr. McGowan.
(suspenseful music)
(gun fires)
(dramatic music)
(Denise gasps)
(gun fires)
(helicopter whirs)
(screams)
(suspenseful music)
They can be ours.
Yours and mine.
If you want them.
The blackmailer got them.
He killed MacGowan and Kosta.
He got away.
Don't you see?
Who loses, David?
The bank?
Doesn't think of it.
The bank has no morals.
- Yeah, neither do you, lady.
- I will have those, please.
(footsteps pound)
- Get the helicopter.
- Yes sir.
- You have an affinity for
dead bodies, Mr. Christopher.
- Yeah, that's true, Captain,
but this time I've got an explanation.
It's a little complicated,
but you're gonna love it.
- Thank God you came in time, Inspector.
This horrible man is
responsible for all this.
He killed two men and he
was trying to kill me too.
- You are safe now, Ms. Abbott.
These are serious
charges, Mr. Christopher.
You will return to Zurich
in the custody of Sergeant Schwand
while I escort Ms. Abbott.
- Oh, that was the most,
the most terrible experience in my life.
- Yes, yes, it must have
been very difficult for you.
You won't forget to bring the diamonds,
will you, Mr. Christopher?
Now, Ms. Abbott, you'll
tell me the entire story.
(solemn music)
(solemn music continues)
(upbeat music)
(dramatic music)
(dramatic music continues)