- [Dan] Welcome to the Blu-Ray commentary
for "The Swiss Conspiracy".
I'm Daniel R Budnick, please call me Dan,
podcaster, author, bon vivant.
And I'm here with the great Mr. Rob Kelly.
Rob, how are you?
- [Rob] Hi, Dan, I'm really
happy to be here with you.
I am a writer and podcaster as well.
I write a column about movies
called "Real Retro Cinema"
at thirteenthdimension.com.
And I host a podcast called "Fade Out",
which examines the Hollywood
careers of actors, directors,
and producers and others
through the prism of their final film.
(movie chatters)
- [Dan] So we start off
here with some great text
and a guy reading the text,
in case we are having problems reading it.
I love the text because, one, it, it, it,
I, I don't know if this was
originally on the movie.
It feels like something
they may have added in,
'cause maybe preview audiences said,
"Now what's a Swiss bank account?"
'Cause not everyone has, I don't have one,
my mother doesn't have one.
And, and I feel like it's almost-
- [Rob] That you know about (laughs).
- [Dan] Yes, well, that's my mom, right?
So, so, but, there's
something about the ellipsis
at the end of the first paragraph
and the small "B" at
the start of the second,
that makes me think,
did the German side of
the production do that?
But so we get a narrator,
he tells us about Swiss bank accounts,
and now we go into a completely
different sort of scene
in a classy restaurant,
and watch out for the guy with
the black pepper in the mob.
Black pepper means that's,
keep away from that one.
'Cause that guy might have a gun.
So, so, what, what do
you think of this, Rob?
Sort of like this, this
opening, this great sort of,
he's got a rifle in his pocket.
- [Rob] Oh, why don't movies
open like this anymore?
- [Dan] They should-
- [Rob] You know, they just
this kind of big Rivera,
crazy scene and we're gonna
explain later what it means,
but just a real grabber right at the top.
- [Dan] Yes, like-
- [Rob] Just bang, there it is.
- [Dan] And you watch
it, and if you like food,
the guy is serving up like
veal or something like that,
whatever that meat, that meat is.
And now we go, I love it
because we go from the narration
to the shoot, this random
shooting, to the postcards,
and there's a train pushing a thing
up a hill just like we'll
see later in the movie.
I don't think I noticed that before,
but we get this, I love this
because we get this great,
"Hey, it's Switzerland
and we have this wonderful,"
this is, this is what Switzerland is like
to the average person, right?
It's, it's, it's-
- [Rob] Scenic, right, yeah, yep.
- [Dan] Bratwurst and
beer and scenic and Alps
and buildings that look like this
and this 'Oom-Pah-Pah" music,
which frankly drives me up the wall.
- [Rob] (chuckles) By the way,
I love "The Swiss
Conspiracy" getting bigger
and bigger and bigger.
I just love, it's like
very "Goodfellas" credits.
- [Dan] Yes, yes!
- [Rob] You know, when they
zoom in and stuff, it's great.
- [Dan] They're ready to go.
Yeah, and, and the film will
do an interesting thing here
because twice within the
movie, we start in the center
of Zurich and like one
time, like in a parking lot,
both times in parking lots actually.
But then that journey ends
in the gorgeous mountains.
In the opening credits we do the opposite.
We start off in the mountains
and we go into the heart of
Zurich, to the Hurtil Bank.
So, but before we do anything else,
I just wanna say that this,
this podcast, this podcast,
this, this commentary,
what we're gonna do is we're
going to, we're going to just,
we're gonna cover the movie
as you see it before you,
but we're also gonna
talk about the directors,
some of the actors, we're
gonna give some reviews.
There's a wonderful novelization
and I've got a gentleman here who might
be doing some dramatic
readings from that later on.
- [Rob] (laughs) It's,
it's a hell of a read.
I'll, I'll say, you've read it too.
- [Dan] Yes, I have, I
just finished it yesterday.
- [Rob] It's, it's, it's really something.
- [Dan] Yeah, Dixie
Sensburg is my favorite name
for a German or Swiss person I have.
(Rob chuckles)
[Dan] But yeah, it's, it's a,
we’ll talk more about the
novelization, which is written
by Michael Stanley, one of the four
or five writers on the movie.
But what, we will talk about
the great Jack Arnold shortly.
- [Rob] Yeah.
- [Dan] Who at this point was
kind of going out of movies
and doing lots and lots of TV,
although he'd done lots of
TV through the past decade,
but this is his last theatrical.
But we will talk about that.
I'm not counting "The
Wackiest Wagon in the West",
but, so now we are going into Hurtil Bank
and the movie is beginning.
(funky synthesizer music)
- [Rob] There you go, now this is, okay,
now we're gonna find,
it's a very curious way
of delivering a message
here in this movie.
There it is, right there!
- [Dan] Yes, there, there it is!
And, and the funny thing is, you'll see,
I don't know if you see it in this shot
or the next one, there's
an interesting moment
where you’ll actually see if, if he looks
up from where he's standing,
there are two guys sitting
at a desk, like right there.
- [Rob] Yep.
- [Dan] So there are
Literally, yeah, right there
on the left, oh, they're not there now.
But in the next, the
second time it happens,
near about 45 minutes into the movie,
there are literally two
guys sitting right there.
And you think, one, "Who
dropped that envelope there?"
- [Rob] (laughs) Right.
- [Dan] Logically at
this point in the movie,
who dropped that envelope there?
And the second time it happens, you sort
of have someone who could have dropped it,
but wouldn't those two guys
who are like staring right
at that point see it?
I don't, and this is great too,
because you get this
moment where suddenly there
are 40 secretaries in the room.
So I love this, this is,
I don't understand the
way Swiss banks work.
(Rob chuckles)
All I have is the information they gave us
over the, the, the text.
- [Rob] Well, Dan, I mean,
if you did know how Swiss Banks work,
would you admit that, anyway?
- [Dan] But that's true,
I'm not allowed to.
So I, I will say to you, yes, please.
- [Rob] Oh, I just wanna mention here
that having flown a lot
recently, this to me is one
of the more suspenseful scenes
is whether this guy's gonna get his bag.
(Dan laughs)
Because I find checking my bag
and expecting the airport
to deliver it, the airline
to deliver it where it says it's gonna
be to be very stressful.
- [Dan] Hilariously stressful.
- [Rob] So I'm glad
John Saxon gets his bag,
but yeah, I found, my pulse was pound-,
pounding when I was watching.
I was like, "That bag gonna show up?"
- [Dan] Yeah, (laughs) so we are in Zurich
and it is the great John
Saxon playing the character,
Hayes, now, in this movie.
Now, obviously we're gonna
be spoiling everything about this movie,
so if you've seen, you
should've seen this movie.
'cause the movie does have
a twister-ooney of an ending
and a lot of side trips.
But yeah, so he's playing Hayes
and there are, there
are five people blank,
blackmailed in the movie.
One of them was the gentleman
killed in the beginning,
Rasher, this is Hayes.
We're gonna meet Abbott,
who's the lovely young lady.
We're going to meet McGowan,
who's the older John
Ireland-like gentleman.
And then, I suddenly, Kosta,
is that the fifth guy?
- [Rob] I believe, yeah, I think so, yeah.
- [Dan] The really disinterested
guy who's like, "Oh, God,"
who looks like he gets
blackmailed every day, you know?
"Oh, I'm so bored with this."
(Rob chuckles)
So one, one of the things I do love
about the opening of this,
I mean, we have the, the, the text,
we have that shooting
in a random restaurant,
we have the "Oom-Pah-Pah" music,
we have the gorgeous Alps,
we go into a bank,
now we're following John
Saxon out of an airport.
It's just, it's this
whole sort of (grunts)
of, "What is going on?"
And if you're reading the novel,
this is actual, novelization,
this is actually like 40 or 50 pages in
'cause there's a lot of background.
- [Rob] (laughs) Yeah, yeah,
I mean one of the things that,
that of course is truism
of movie novelizations, of,
of, you know, book novelizations
of movies is they have
so much more space to fill.
- [Dan] Yes.
- [Rob] So there's just so much more,
every character gets 20
to 30 pages of backstory.
- [Dan] (laughs) Yeah.
- [Rob] And there are, again, we'll,
we'll talk about it a little
bit later, but there are a lot,
there's lots of stuff in the book that is
so not in this movie.
- [Dan] Yes.
- [Rob] This, this movie's
pretty straightforward,
87 minutes, you know, it's
just bing, bing, bing,
just very direct, it's, it's not a whole,
it's not a really big character piece,
which is not a criticism at it.
It's just, it's, this is the plot,
we're gonna watch these
people go through it.
Ah, Ray Milland, the great Ray Milland!
- [Dan] And Anton
Diffring, two, two greats,
and the great Ray Milland.
I, I'd love to talk about Ray Milland now,
but I think we're gonna
save our actor stuff
for when we've calmed down a bit.
'Cause right now we're kind
of coasting on all the stuff happening.
- [Rob] Setting up all the plot.
- [Dan] Yes, yeah, so, so I, I did,
according to the novelization,
approximately 40%% of the Hurtil
Bank is Swiss bank accounts.
(Rob hums and movie chatters)
And, and so, and one of the things
that makes Swiss bank
accounts so wonderful
for these banks is they are
a lot of criminals, a lot
of dictators, a lot of very
shady people put their money in,
and if they die and no one
knows about the account,
the money goes to the bank.
- [Rob] Good deal.
- [Dan] So, so that's
actually a pretty good deal.
So, so like taking on a
South American dictator
who's got 10 million bucks or something,
you know, you put it in there,
if he dies, no one's
gonna come step forward.
You're not gonna get a bunch
of revolutionaries
coming in the front door.
That guard, that guard actually
wouldn't see them probably
if they came through the front door.
(Rob laughs)
But, but the, but the, you
know, they, the, you know, and,
and that's kind of one
of the reasons why it's
so lucrative for them.
And I guess they're neutral
and they don't care particularly, right?
- [Rob] Yeah, I mean this is their,
their number one concern is the pr-,
I mean, the whole, the
whole hook of this movie is
that they're just gonna get exposed.
- [Dan] Yes!
- [Rob] You know, like that's
it really, it's not even like,
"Oh, we're gonna expose you
and you've also done
some nefarious things."
I mean, although some people have.
- [Dan] Yeah.
- [Rob] But it really is just your name
is gonna get promoted and
we don't even want that,
which is just kind of amazing.
- [Dan] Yeah, you get Hayes,
the John Saxon character,
is the only one who's really cheesed off.
- [Rob] Right (chuckles).
- [Dan] And it's happened,
but, but then the more you sort
of look at what he's doing
and why he's so cheesed off.
And then when he gets mad
at the great, we're about
to see him soon, the
great Mr. David Janssen.
- [Rob] Yeah!
- [Dan] His, his, I'd like
to talk about later when
the assassins are going
after Christopher, I want to
talk about how confused I get
by that plot line.
(Rob laughs)
But right now we're gonna talk about,
now, in today we call this a "meet cute",
that's about to, I think
it's about to happen.
And Hurtil, that's Hurtil Bank.
- [Rob] There he is!
- [Dan] Dennis, Denise, you have
to pronounce it as "turtle".
There he is, and we,
we would call this a "meet cute" today.
I call it a "meet gruff"
because it's David Janssen.
(Rob laughs)
And how old is he right there?
He's like in his late 40s, right?
- [Rob] He is, let's see, he,
he unfortunately passed
away very young at 49.
And this is '76, '75.
- [Dan] Yeah, made in '75.
- [Rob] So he was 44 when he made this.
- [Dan] Oh, my goodness.
- [Rob] I mean, good lord,
I'm older than David Janssen is now.
I don't feel like-
- [Dan] Yes.
- [Rob] (laughs) I think
he looks older than me,
I think, I don't know.
- [Dan] Wow, I, I was, I was
still getting carded at 44.
- [Rob] (laughs) Guys just, people just
looked older back then.
- [Dan] Yes, they did!
- [Rob] They did.
- [Dan] And if, if you see
pictures of him like, now,
I've never seen "Richard
Diamond, Private Detective",
which I feel like I should have seen
because I'm such a fan of David Janssen.
I'm saving it for retirement.
(Rob laughs)
But, but in that, he kind of looks young.
I mean, that's like 1 5
years or so before this.
And he kind of looks young-ish.
Maybe it's 'cause it's black and white.
But yeah, so here he is, our
star, Mr. David Christopher,
I'm just gonna call him
"our David" throughout.
And meeting up with Denise Abbott,
they do this wonderful thing here,
which actually I think I've seen
in a "Mr. Show" sketch like
a couple decades later,
where they just meet awkwardly
and then they realize-
- [Rob] Yeah, they keep going
to the next thing, right,
right, right, yeah.
- [Dan] They're, they're going
to the exact same space and-
- [Rob] Senta Berger,
we should mention here,
he's meeting Senta Berger, yes.
- [Dan] Yes, yes, and we're go,
and it's, it's a, it's, I
will say one tricky thing,
I didn't, I didn't realize
until I read the novelization
and watched this like a
third or fourth time that
for being a movie about
a Swiss bank account
and that being kind of
like a secretive thing
that you think you might wanna sort
of bring the viewer in on,
they don't do that at all.
- [Rob] Nope.
- [Dan] In the movie, which is weird
because like basically
what we're seeing now
of the bank, that opening walkway,
the secretary room, briefly 'Benigen',
who is an Anton Diffring's
office, and then Hurtil's office,
and again, I'm gonna pronounce
it like "turtle", like,
like Denise Abbott does, all,
that's all we see of the bank,
which is a little odd.
And again, I'm gonna mention
that later when I talk
about Mr. Christopher's
investigatory style.
But what is going on here?
Oh, yes, Hayes, Hayes arrived.
- [Rob] Yeah, Hayes is showing up now.
I, did you get the same
read from this movie?
I watched this movie
several times, you know,
to station to this, but
didn't you get the sense
that this feels, and this
is not a knock at all,
but doesn't, it feels
a little bit like this
is the TV movie version.
Oh, this is the movie version
of a TV show starring David Janssen
as David Christopher, right?
- [Dan] Yes, yes!
- [Rob] Because everyone knows him
and he's kind of legendary.
And we're gonna find that
John Saxon's character
already knows him and
they have like a grudge.
You know, he's, "This
guy's justice", you know,
he's already like, and, and everyone's-
- [Dan] "You're gonna be
hanging in the meat house
with the rest of the pigs."
- [Rob] Exactly, everyone talks
about David Christopher like
he's this legendary law man
as if we kind of know
him already and we don't.
So it had the read like,
they finally were like,
"Oh, look, we got the money together
and we finally made a
David Christopher movie,"
after like six seasons (laughs).
- [Dan] Yeah, yeah, like
the show was on the air
for two, three, like, like a strange,
like when they did the
"Strangers with Candy" movie
or the "Trailer Park Boys" movie,
where it's like, it's not,
it's not a continuing thing deep in the,
it's like it went back
to the beginning again.
- [Rob] Or Batman.
- [Dan] But we all pretend like-
- [Rob] You know, the 60s
Batman movie, you know?
- [Dan] Yeah, yeah,
exactly, that's perfect,
perfect example, you have the 60s Batman,
or "A Man Called Flintstones".
- [Rob] (laughs) Wait, yes, or that.
- [Dan] Which would be a spy type thing.
So, which is sort of what this is like.
But, and he's playing,
this is, this is soon
after "Harry O" got
canceled and at the time-
- Right, and he said that he was never
gonna do TV again after that-
- [Dan] Yes.
- [Rob] Because he was so mad
about the show being canceled.
- [Dan] And, and he did,
he did a few TV movies,
he did "Superdome",
and I'm completely
blanking on what else he,
he was in "2 Minute Warning",
but that was a theatrical
around this time.
And, but we'll talk, we’ll talk more
about David Janssen later maybe.
- [Rob] Absolutely.
- [Dan] Maybe when he's flirting
with Ms. Abbott later
on and they're listening
to "Sloop John B." in German,
which we can talk about.
- [Rob] Oh, that is a, that's a moment.
- [Dan] It's fantastic,
so, so what we've got here,
yeah, is the, so what, what we get here,
and it's, it's kind of interesting
'cause if you read the novelization,
the novelization takes everything
that's happening in like
the first 20, 25 minutes
of this movie, which
is a lot of characters,
a lot of names, and it slows it down.
- [Rob] Yep.
- [Dan] So if you, if you
read the novel, if you were
to read the novelization first,
I think you would go into the movie
and you'd know the characters
so well that you wouldn't have
to piece things together.
But there is, it, it does a
thing which movies did back
in the 70s, which,
but back in the 60s too, which is like,
today, if a movie is making
a point about something
and it's not misdirection of some sort,
it lets you know what the point is.
You know, if someone is someone's mother,
they will let you know,
maybe the movie will stop
and some light music will play,
"That's his mother," (mimics light music),
something like that, but in
this one if it's his mother,
it'll be like, you know,
Mr. Christopher, our David,
will like, call his secretary and be like,
"I want you to check on
this and check on this
and check on this, check on his mother,
check on this, check out this, check out,
and that's all we’ll get, so like-
- [Rob] (laughs) They assumed audiences
were relatively intelligent back then
and you could piece things together.
- [Dan] Were, were
really paying attention.
Yeah, exactly.
- [Rob] Yeah!
- [Dan] With the, with a
great example being that,
that John Saxon's character, Hayes, works
for a big Chicago mob boss,
whose name is mentioned at least twice,
but both of the times it's
mentioned on phone calls.
And one of the times you
can't quite hear the name
because David Janssen is moving around.
And the second time it's just said
in with a mix of other names.
- [Rob] (chuckles) Right.
- [Dan] So that's, that's
kind of an important name,
but it's almost thrown away.
But it's not because you
should be paying attention.
I don't mean to be rude, anyone,
everyone just turned off the commentaries.
(Rob laughs)
"I don't want this jerk
telling me what to do,"
but it's David Janssen and Ray Milland,
everyone, don't you wanna
know what's going on?
They're drinking so much!
- [Rob] (laughs) And they also
assume you're gonna read all
that text in the beginning,
which they would never do now.
- [Dan] True.
- [Rob] You know what I mean?
- [Rob] They're just not
gonna bother that, so.
- [Dan] Yeah.
- [Rob] I can't, I can't profess
to be an expert on David Janssen,
but I would, I get a read from him
in every movie I've ever seen him in,
is that he's one of those
guys who was great at acting
but also felt very conflicted
that he was doing this at all.
You know, like the George C. Scott,
George C. Scott was like, "Is
this really the job of a man?"
You know, that kind of, but you know,
and yet he was so great at,
'cause he just feels in every movie,
like he's just kinda like, "Ugh."
- [Dan] Yeah, exactly.
Like there are moments I love
the "Changeling" so much.
But then there are moments
that, where he's like,
"What do you want from me?"
(Rob laughs)
Where, you know, you're sort of thinking,
he's kind of thinking like,
"Am I really doing this?"
- [Rob] Exactly, exactly.
- [Dan] Like, "Is this?"
Yeah, but I, I sort of, I got that read
with David Janssen too, like he was-
- [Dan] Warren Oates was
another guy like that.
I, you know, there's a, I, I don't mean
to get too far off this,
but I remember there was a
great story I heard from,
from Wayne Rogers who was,
did a western with Warren Oats
and they were hiding behind something,
waiting for their cue,
and Warren Oats just said,
"Do you feel a little silly
about being grown men playing cowboy?"
Like (laughs) that's, I get that read
from David Janssen where he's just like,
"Look, I'll do this, but I just,
I just feel like maybe this
whole thing is, I, I could,
maybe I should be boxing
or something more manly
than what I'm doing."
- [Dan] Yeah, yeah, yeah,
this is a beauty of a scene
because you get John
Saxon, who as far as I,
who was acting for ages.
- [Rob] Oh, he's-
- [Dan] When he, when he
started off, they tried
to make him sort of a teen idol
and he's just kind of, he's
just, he's in everything.
He's in so much stuff
alongside David Janssen,
alongside the great Ray Milland,
who's has been in everything.
- [Rob] Yep.
- [Rob] And it's just,
and Anton Differing too.
I mean it's just this,
this great group of guys
and yeah, as you said, John Saxon, Hayes,
there is really swinging for the wall.
"Department of Justice, you're going,"
I already said the meat, meat house thing.
Oh, darn it, I should
have yelled that now.
- [Rob] I found a, I found a, a,
a great newspaper article in
the promotion of this film,
which is just about John Saxon
and the, the, the title
was "Success Suits Him",
which is like, well, yeah, all of us.
And he has this great quote where he said,
"Janssen and I had a lot of bull sessions
on 'The Swiss Conspiracy'
about the old days when we
were wondering if we'd get
the breaks that were beginning
to fall for Eastwood and Hudson."
- [Dan] Oh!
- [Rob] So (laughs) I love the idea
of these two guys sitting,
making this movie,
kind of bitching and moaning
about (laughs) the other actors
in this universal stable
that got the, yeah.
- [Dan] Eastwood and Hudson,
too, that's engaging (laughs).
(Rob laughs and grunts)
- [Rob] Yeah.
- [Dan] That's, yeah, 'cause
like I said, like, like I said,
Janssen was right off of
"Harry O" right here, which ran
for two seasons, two
TV movies, two seasons.
It's a really great show.
It's one of those shows that kind
of vanished sort of for decades.
- [Rob] Mmhmm.
- [Dan] But now if you
go on like your sort
of nostalgia stations, if they
have like a mystery block,
"Harry O" always seems to be on there now,
which is kind of weird
'cause it's alongside shows
like "Cannon", which ran
for five years, or "Barnaby
Jones", which ran for 80 years,
how long did "Barnaby Jones"
run... however long it ran for.
(Rob laughs)
But "Harry O" was only like two seasons
and it was like 40, 42 episodes.
So it's like they cycle
through them pretty quickly.
- [Rob] Yeah.
- [Dan] And, but he's great in that.
It's a great show.
And he's kind of playing a
"Harry O" variation here,
Harry, but, but with Harry you get,
Harry, in the first half of the series,
lived on a, a lovely beach house
and he's just on the beach building a boat
and people keep giving
him detective stuff to do.
And then the second half of the series,
he lives in a lovely apartment
in LA next door to Farrah Fawcett.
- [Rob] Eh, okay, I don't know,
beach house or Farrah
Fawcett, I don't know.
Hmm, would I make that
trade, I don't know.
- [Dan] So, and, and, and
now he's just this, this-
- [Rob] Drinking, a lot of drinking.
- [Dan] A lot of drink, I, I love that,
and it's, it's, it's funny, I,
what, the moment Anton Differing comes in
and gives Hurtil the, the, the, the letter
and they're comparing
the red sharpie on it.
And he, and the,
what's the first thing
Hurtil does when he sets
down his piece of paper?
(movie chatters)
Goes to get a drink.
Do you want a drink, of course!
And they, they all have drinks
and it's, it's a, it's a lovely
time here with the offices.
So, so yeah, we're just, we're, we're,
we're deep in the discussions.
We, we, we know the names
of the people now and we've obviously met,
we know that, I think we know that Rasher,
one of them, is dead.
He was the guy who got
shot through the window.
And we've met Denise Abbott
and we've met Hayes who is really pissed
off that our David's involved.
And McGowan, who's the older
Texas gentleman is flying in
and Kosta is-
- [Rob] Now we're meeting Charlie, yeah.
- [Dan] Yes, and Kosta's
coming in from Amsterdam
and yeah, yeah, at this point we're just,
he, he's, he's kind of,
we're, we're kind of just
doing a slight recap,
which this movie will do
again in about 40 minutes,
a slight recap of what's
happened and we're setting it up,
but we get the, we get
the great moment where,
where Anton Differing somewhere
in here says something like,
"We've got five very careless people."
And, and our David just gives 'em a look.
Like, "Not with these sort of accounts,
you don't get careless, come on."
And which is, which is a, which is, I like
because it's a slightly
suspicious thing to say, right?
- [Rob] Mmhmm.
- [Dan] Like if you're
second in command of the bank
and one of the things you do is
you have secret bank
accounts to just kind of say,
"Oh, yeah, it's nothing to do with us,
just five people being careless," eh.
- [Rob] (laughs) That's
got everything to do
with you guys, what are you talking about?
- [Dan] Yes, (laughs) yeah,
so, so what are we doing now?
Oh, yes, so we are, we are, oh,
we, actually, we are, this is cool
'cause we are about to meet two gentlemen.
There's, here, and here's,
here's sort of, I, I'm not, I'm,
I'm gonna go into this a little more
when we get Elke Sommer showing up first,
but the movie has a lot
of side journeys it takes.
- [Rob] Mmhmm.
- [Dan] And the novel,
novelization even more so.
So it is kind of one of those movies,
it's almost like an Agatha Christie kind
of thing where you have to
clear away a lot of like brush
in order to get to where you
need to be kind of thing.
- [Rob] Oh, here are, here are
our two henchmen, here are.
- [Dan] Here we go.
- [Rob] Jules and Vincent
of "The Swiss Conspiracy".
- [Dan] Yes, exactly, so, so there's,
and they're not, yeah,
they're not suspicious at all.
I mean, David Janssen,
I think at this moment,
he'd realty only been in
"Last House on the Left".
And I don't know that if
there was a huge crossover
between "Swiss Conspiracy
and "Last House on the Left".
There might have been, but I'm sure a lot
of people were like, "Oh, God,
good, the calvary is here.
We're, we're saved now."
(Rob laughs)
Or if they said, "Oh, everybody's dead."
- [Rob] By the way, I just wanna,
I just wanna mention this
actress 'cause she's,
this is it, this is her one scene.
Christiane Rücker, she's
the car rental clerk.
She was in movies like
"Frankenstein's Castle of Freaks"
and "The Torture Chamber of Dr. Sadism".
- [Dan] Sadism, aw.
- [Rob] Which is, I think
that's where I recognized her.
When I saw her I'm
like, "I know that face.
Where have I seen that face?"
I think that's what I saw her from.
- [Dan] Yeah, I know "Torture
Chamber" is, that's one
of Christopher Lee's, right?
I believe that's a Christopher Lee mo-,
and that's a German one I believe,
I think, I think that's a German film.
And "Frankenstein's Castle of Freaks",
of course everyone loves that.
I think there's a caveman
in that named Ook,
if I remember correctly,
I'm, I might be thinking
of a different "Frankenstein's
Castle of Freaks".
Oh, and now we are with, I
think her name is Corinne.
- [Rob] Yep.
- [Dan] He calls her Connie at one point.
This is Sheila Ruskin, who is-
- [Rob] She's, she's, she's,
she's answering a phone
on a "Star Wars" electronic
battle command game,
which is very confusing.
- [Dan] I was gonna say,
or she just got like a subscription
of "Sports Illustrated".
(Rob laughs)
They went, "Ooh, free fall?"
- [Rob] Good forearm strength
to lift that thing up.
- [Dan] (laughs) We'll, we'll take it.
So, so here we get, and,
and here's, here's kind of
with her, scenes with her,
yeah, she's a, she's a British actress.
She was in a lot of stuff in the 70s, 80s,
I actually know her best
for playing a character named
Cassie in a "Dr Who" serial,
"The Keeper of Traken" from 1981 ,
where she wore a huge red wig,
which is why it took me ages
to recognize her when I was watching this.
I sat there going, "I know her."
And then when I saw the name,
I was like, "Oh, finally."
But yeah, she's the secretary
and she's the high tech secretary.
- [Rob] Yeah, I need to
mention my favorite credit
from hers, just 'cause I'm
a nerd about this stuff.
She was in "I, Claudius".
- [Dan] Oh, yes!
- [Rob] Which is one of my
favorite things of all time.
She plays Vipsania in that.
And so I, every time that
anybody is in "I, Claudius",
I'm like, "Oh, okay, Elke
Sommer, here we go, Elke Sommer!"
- [Dan] So, so, so the
thing I love about this,
and I try, I was trying
to come up with a name
for what they're doing in this scene.
All I could think of was it's, they're,
they're engaged in specific vagueness.
(Rob laughs)
Because everything they say
in this implies that...
it's 'Bennigen', right?
That's not a restaurant,
that is, is that his name?
- [Rob] Benninger.
- [Dan] Anton Differing, Benninger!
I, 'Benigen', what an idiot.
So it's, I might just
call him Anton Differing.
I'm sorry, don't do that
again, so, but there's-
- [Rob] He's got a crocodile
on the wall wearing sunglasses, you know.
- [Dan] Yes, exactly, and there is Ms.,
Ms. Jensen, or Janssen, Jensen?
Elke Sommer, and they're two
German actors by the way.
And speaking very good English.
And the great thing about
this scene, like I said,
it's specific vagueness,
everything they're saying you could apply
to the blackmail scheme,
but you could also
apply to something else.
- [Rob] Right.
- [Dan] And at the very end,
because he's being vague
and then she says,
"What's this terrible
thing that's happening?"
And he says, "Dennis Christopher,
he's been put on the case."
- [Rob] See, the name again!
They say the name like it's
(mimics dramatic music),
Dennis Christopher, ooh, boy!
- [Dan] "We'll put him on the case!"
And, and, and they're like,
it ends with a closeup
and like, "We're gonna have to
find a way to deal with him."
And it's like, and, and
your thought is, "Well,
we're only 24 minutes into the movie.
If this is a mystery at all,
these can't be the bad guys, right?"
- [Rob] Right, yeah, exactly, right.
- [Dan] I mean 'cause then it's,
now it's like "Colombo" or something.
We know that it's, it's, you know,
and you expect at the end of
that scene, you expect one
of them to say something
along the lines of like,
"What are we having for dinner?
I was thinking of fish."
"Great, I'll go buy some red herring."
(Rob laughs)
And, and because that's,
that's, sorry, this,
again, spoiler, that's exactly
what they are in there.
What they're, what they're
doing is so completely different
from what we're actually
doing in the movie that it's,
it's, you almost expect them
to be the people who
are doing it at the end
because it's so obviously not them.
- [Rob] That scene, I mean,
we'll find out exactly what,
what they're talking about
and why that's a double blind.
But it, it, it makes me think about, like,
I think you've seen, Steven
Soderbergh said recently
that cell phones have
ruined current thrillers
'cause everybody can just call everybody.
And it's like that, this
plot twist that comes
up is that they're, you know,
they're having an affair
and that's the big secret,
that wouldn't work as
a plot twist nowadays
'cause no one would care, you know?
- [Dan] Yeah, exactly.
- [Rob] Like, "The bank
manager's having an affair."
"So, like, what does that
have to do with my money?"
Like, you know (laughs)?
- [Dan] Exactly, and, and the big,
the big issue they're having,
and this is a bit of a spoiler,
but we're about to have
a fun fight scene here,
so I thought I'd just spoil
one of the, the big thing
with the Elke Sommers
character, Ms. Jensen,
there is that she doesn't
have the proper paperwork
to access a bank account.
And could you imagine if
there had been a big scene
where she like went in with
like a birth certificate
and it was a lot of shot cuts between,
"Here's my birth certificate,"
closeup of the teller's eyes,
closeup of the birth
certificate, dun, dun, dun, dun!
Closeup of her sweating, closeup
of Anton Differing looking
at her from a distance,
and then the person going,
"Everything's in order,"
stamp, stamp, dun, dun!
(Rob laughs)
That's why they didn't
follow that plot line,
is what I'm saying, because right here,
Hayes is, he's not,
he's not effing around.
- [Rob] No, he's just
firing wildly (laughs),
just trying in attempt to
kill Dennis Christopher, yeah.
- [Dan] He is, and I do, I do, one
of the things I applaud about
the movie is that, like,
it's a US, German
co-production shot in Zurich
and they have this big action
scene in a parking garage
that looked like it could
have been shot in Burbank.
(Rob laughs)
And it's a fun, it's a fun scene though.
I mean, it's lots of windows exploding,
and, and, and the fire extinguisher can.
- [Rob] It's a good, with
the fire extinguisher,
good gag, I like that, that's good.
- [Dan] And they really go for it here,
the two of them, they, oh (laughs).
- [Rob] This is a great fight, you know?
- [Dan] It is, it is a really good fight.
- [Rob] Looks real, wildly
punching each other.
Yeah, look at that.
Oh, elbow to the face!
- [Dan] It's nice, it's not like,
it's not a super dynamic fight,
although that was a nice little
tracking shot by the car.
It's not like a super
dynamic fight with a lot
of cuts and things like that.
It's just like two actors
and then occasionally two stunt men just
whomping the hell out of each other.
- [Rob] They're banging,
banging into each other.
- [Dan] Yeah, which is a
great way to, they're just,
it's just very visceral.
It's, it's a great fight.
And the whole time you're thinking,
"Mr. Hayes, if you wanted
to keep your blackmailing thing a secret,
this might be a mistake."
- [Rob] Yeah, I know, yeah,
see, he's laying it out
on the line here, oh,
now that the cops are gonna get involved.
- [Dan] Yeah, so these-
- [Rob] You flatfoots (laughs).
- [Dan] These goof, these goofball cops.
And then, and again, I will,
I will mention the
assassins more when they go
after Christopher, but I
do wonder if the assassins
are somewhere in here watching the cops,
watching Christopher, watching Hayes.
Because I, I love this,
two guys who just ran in
off the farm, just like-
- [Rob] (laughs) The guy in the overalls.
- [Dan] Just suddenly grab,
I love that it's a guy, I,
I'd like to think these are
like two guys on like the,
like maybe the Swedish crew
and they're like, "Could we do,"
I'm not gonna denigrate
myself and everyone by trying
to do a Swedish accent,
a Swiss, Swiss accent,
you know, sorry, yeah.
But you know, it's just like two guys
on the crew who are like
maybe the lighting guys.
"Could we run in and grab him?"
"Sure, yeah."
- [Rob] (laughs) He's
the prop guy from the,
the fire extinguisher, he had
to make sure that was working.
- [Dan] Exactly, and he
happened to be there.
And I don't know about the policing
that goes on in this scene
or it's, it's, it's, it's,
it's, it's, it's kind
of interesting because this is, there,
quite a bit of this
movie actually works best
when you watch the movie a second time.
And you know what, and I mean, you know,
this isn't an all time classic,
this isn't, say, "The French Connection",
although the title might try
to convince you otherwise.
- [Rob] (laughs) The titles,
they definitely were trying
to go for something with the, you know,
"French Connection"... "Swiss Conspiracy!"
- [Dan] Swiss Conspiracy, yes.
- [Rob] Yeah, you know about the,
the Spanish Interregnum, I mean (laughs).
- [Dan] Yes, there, there was, I had,
well, I, I had, what was it?
The, the, the Luxembourg Inheritance.
- [Rob] (laughs) Could do a
whole series of these things.
- [Dan] I, I had the Polish
Confusion was my favorite
... was that bad?
'Cause that one isn't set in Poland.
- [Rob] Right (laughs), right.
- [Dan] And, but, but,
but it has, but it has,
and even like we're about
to see in a few minutes,
it even does a French
Connection-y thing where,
with an action scene in
the middle of the movie,
the big action scene is in the middle
of the movie like the "French Connection".
- [Rob] Yep, yep, yep.
- [Dan] We’ll, we'll, we'll
talk about when they get
to that, but it's, it's,
it is one of those movies
that I think watching it
a second time really works
because, first off, like the
guy with the mustache here,
Captain Frey, I'll just call him the cop.
He, I guess he's a good cop, I don't know.
- [Rob] I, do we know
that, I mean, he seems,
he's always like three
steps behind everybody
in this case, you know?
- [Dan] He, he always,
he, yeah, he always shows
up a little late, he, he, you know, like,
we'll see in the final scene,
he shows up literally like
30 seconds from the end.
You know, it's like, "Really, guys?"
I mean, I'm sure like in the
end when he's on the ski lift,
he must see what's going on
and be like pounding the
ski lift going, "Go faster.
Go faster," but, but it's,
yeah, he's an interesting cop
because in about a half an
hour they'll give over like two
or three of the movie, mo-,
minutes of the movie to him,
which I feel is a strange thing.
But we'll talk about
that when we get to that.
So now we're at Hayes, and
Hayes is about to say goodbye.
- [Rob] Yeah.
- [Dan] And now, did
you think when you saw,
'cause Hayes yells out,
"We're gonna put you
in the meat yard," or
whatever we're doing to,
"We're gonna, I'm gonna,
you're gonna be taken care of."
Did you think when
these assassins arrived,
because they don't show in the
package who they're killing,
did you think they were going
after our Da-, our David?
(car screeches)
- [Rob] You know-
- [Dan] What did you always think?
- [Rob] You know, I, no, I think I,
I, at this point I gave
over to, when I watched this
for the first time, I gave
over to just being confused.
And I was like, "Okay, I don't
get why they're doing this.
And that's okay," and I
mentioned, you mentioned earlier
that like the, you know,
we find out just kind
of an offhanded line of
dialogue from David Janssen
that Rasher is the guy who gets killed
in the beginning, I, ashamedly,
I had to watch this movie,
I think three times before I picked
up that line of dialogue.
And I kept saying,
"Wait, who's the guy that
gets shot in the beginning?"
- [Dan] Yes!
- [Rob] And then I think
on the third pass I heard Janssen say,
"Rasher is the one who was killed."
I was like, "Oh, that's Rasher, okay!"
So I, I was okay with my
confusion throughout this movie
because I just let it
kind of wash over me.
I'm like, "Okay, this is a bunch of,
this is a movie about
a bunch of guys in a,
small rooms trying to, you
know, outdo one another
with occasional guest appearances
by Senta Berger and Elke Sommer,
you know what I mean?
- [Dan] (laughs) Exact, exactly.
- [Rob] I love that, I love him
running, John Saxon running.
- [Dan] Yes, yes, it's a great run.
And it's, I think it's, I
think it's an excellent scene.
Again, it's not like, it's
not like, like I said,
the "French Connection" in the middle
of it has the great
elevated train car chase.
- [Rob] I love this, all
these, all these kids.
- [Dan] Yes!
- [Rob] "Get out of my way!"
- [Dan] And that's just like,
that's just what they do
in Switzerland and they're neutral.
They can just hang out in an
alley, no one's gonna stop 'em.
(movie chatters)
- [Rob] "Hey, come on, let's party."
"No, leave me alone, I'm gonna,
chasing John Saxon, please.
There we go, get outta my way."
- [Dan] I feel like if
you watch a lot of sort
of American type films made in countries
that aren't America, you'll
get a lot of scenes like that,
where they think like
in this part of Europe,
people just hang out in like,
outside of bars just making lots of noise.
- [Rob] Yep, yep, yep.
- [Dan] And maybe they do,
maybe they do, I've never been.
- [Rob] Maybe, yeah, I don't know.
Oh, here we go, this is, yes!
(car zooms and wood rattles)
- [Dan] There's some
nice stunting in here.
It's, it's, it's a pretty good,
it's not a dynamic chase scene,
like the "French Connection" scene,
which is just, you know, put the car in
with the stunt driver and
have him do crazy stuff.
And you're like, "Ah, ah," throughout or,
or that beautiful moment
when like the, the,
you see like the elevated
train going at top speed
and then the car's just right
underneath it kind of thing.
- [Rob] Yeah, yeah.
- [Dan] It doesn't, it doesn't
have anything like that.
This is more, this is more the kind
of car chases you saw
on the Italian ripoffs
of like "French Connection"
and "Bullet Serpico"
in the 70s, which I know the name of them,
but I've never said it out loud
and I don't want to embarrass myself.
It's, they're, it's
P-O-L-I-Z-Z-I-O, Polizzio,
and then like T-S-C-H-E-I
or something like that.
"Polizzio Tscheis" or something like that,
films like "Syndicate Sadists"
and "The Violent
Professionals" are like that.
They're just these sort of,
I love this here, with the-
- [Rob] This is a good
stunt here with the boom
and then the, yeah, the
hood comes up on that.
That's a great, you know?
- [Dan] I do, I do, I do love that.
And because, obviously, I,
I doubt that was planned
and it's nice that the
hood went back down.
- [Rob] Mmhmm.
- [Dan] So, so, so it's
kind of, it's kind of cool.
But unfortunately, we're
gonna lose Hayes here.
- [Rob] Oh, man, ooh, right in the hand.
- [Dan] Yeah, now, if you've
been reading the book,
the novelization, we get a lot of,
we get a lot of backstory.
We know exactly what Hayes is up to.
We know why these guys are after him.
In the movie it's a little sketchier.
- [Rob] Yeah.
(wood creaks)
- [Dan] I, I will tell
you, later on when they're
after Christopher, give you,
give you a little sketching in
of what's going on, just
to show my confusion
with this hitman plot line.
I mean, it's fun to watch.
And in the novel when they
kill him, it's unpleasant.
It's very unpleasant to read.
- [Rob] Is this a small
role for David Hess?
I feel like he was bigger
than this at this point.
Like not a big star, but just,
he's kind of an unnamed henchman.
I don't know, this was a little
small for him at this point.
I was almost like, "Oh, wait
a minute, it's David Hess."
You know, like playing.
- [Dan] (grunts) I think like, I,
I think his main thing at this time had
been like sort of "Last
House on the Left", so.
- [Rob] All right, maybe
I'm just thinking of it,
I'm looking at it from the, you know,
50-year-tense kind of thing.
- [Dan] Yeah, 'cause David Hess
started off as a songwriter,
writing songs for Elvis.
And he wrote "I Got Stung"
for Elvis, which was a,
which was a hit, I think, I think, I think
that "I Got Stung" in
history is, is important
because it was like the
last song Elvis recorded
before he went in the Army
at the end of the 50s.
- [Rob] Hmm, okay.
- [Dan] And David Hess
co-wrote it under like,
the name David Hill or you know,
David Bubbles or something.
It was a more fun name than David Hess,
which sounds like a slightly
unpleasant name, you know?
But from what I know,
though, he was a great guy.
I know he's passed, but I'd hate
to have his spirit
suddenly appear behind me
during this commentary,
if I go dead on this-
- [Rob] That would be
kind of cool, actually,
to be honest with you,
that sounds kinda neat.
- [Dan] Yeah, well, that'd
be great, maybe he could,
he could add a little
extra to it (laughs), but,
but yeah, I, I think this
is probably, at this time,
probably okay for him.
- [Rob] Okay.
- [Dan] I, I think, and he's
definitely like, the two
of them are a force to be reckoned with.
- [Rob] Yeah.
- [Dan] In the scenes they're in,
they've got a couple more coming up and,
but then you get a lot of
people in this movie who kind
of show up and they're here
for a bit and they do some things.
It's a str-, I, I feel like
from reading the novelization,
and this may, may be just me,
I feel like the film
was meant to be longer.
(hand taps)
Do you, do you get that feeling or is it?
- [Rob] Well, I mean, yeah.
I mean, they probably, this
movie's a tight 87 minutes
and the book is 300 pages.
- [Dan] Yeah.
- [Rob] But that's always the way, I mean,
like I said, I've,
I have a tough time
with novelizations just
'cause they are so, I feel
like they're so padded.
- [Dan] Yes!
- [Rob] But they sort of have to be.
And, and you know, the, the
author, Michael Stanley,
who you mentioned is credited
on the screenplay here.
You know, he gets to do stuff
that the movie didn't
have the budget to do.
Like there's an extended
sequence inside the vault.
- [Dan] Yes!
- [Rob] Where we see all
of the, the doohickeys
and the this thing comes down.
And then the, the what,
and they didn't, you know,
they weren't gonna spend the money
to build this massive, "Ocean's
Eleven" style bank vault-
- [Dan] Yes.
- [Rob] For this movie,
but in the, in the book,
he can spend a couple of pages
where, you know, Ray Milland
and Janssen are in there
and it's, you know,
(mimics explosion) and
then you turn the wheel.
- [Dan] Yes!
- [Rob] And then this thing
comes down and stuff like that.
Oh, here, we have to mention the-
- [Dan] Yes!
- [Rob] The Beach Boys song.
(Rob and Dan laugh)
- [Dan] So, so this is
"Sloop John B" in German.
- [Rob] In German of, of course.
- [Dan] Playing over here, yes.
Playing because, yeah, Ms.
Abbott will come out in a moment.
Denise Abbott, that's,
is that a German name?
I mean, I was gonna say she doesn't look
like Bud's daughter or anything.
- [Rob] (laughs) You've
not heard the Beach Boys
until you've enjoyed it
in the original German.
- [Dan] She doesn't travel
around with like Betty Costello,
getting into random fighting
monsters or anything like that.
(Rob laughs)
But, but yeah, this, so,
so this is them meeting up
listening to some great music
and she, she, I do like,
I do, I, I kind of,
the thing I like about
Denise Abbott is she,
she has this moment earlier
where she jokes over the phone,
"Oh, there's plenty of parking."
And it kind of falls,
it's kinda like a dud.
But you could see she's like
a really attractive woman who
has a nice sense of humor,
she just may be not too,
she's like, she's like
just standing around.
She's gorgeous, but she wants to be funny.
She wants to do shtick, maybe
it is a Bud Abbott thing.
I don't know, but, but,
but, so like her, "There's
plenty of parking,"
and, "I'll slip into
something less comfortable,"
are, are kind of funny lines, you know,
and it's, it's like there's a feeling
where like if I hadn't been,
in the movie, it's tough to
gauge exactly what she does.
She seems to be a
professional black mailer.
In the novelization, she's a
model, she's a famous model.
- [Rob] Completely plausible.
- [Dan] Yes, yes, and, and so, and, but,
but there's, I get this feeling,
like when you're watching her
and she delivers those lines,
like, she's like, "This,
these looks are a burden,
I wish I, I had a more,
more a "Diller" look to me
so I could do more comedy."
That's the feeling I get
sometimes, but that's just me.
- [Dan] I, well, I find my great looks
to be a hindrance sometimes, Dan.
I admit that and I'm
willing to admit that here.
- [Dan] Exactly, I actually
only have 80 minutes
of Rob's time, so for 10
minutes of this commentary,
I’ll be doing a Rob impersonation.
- [Rob] (laughs) By the way, the knot
on David Christopher's tie
is, is something to behold.
(Rob and Dan laugh)
- [Dan] It is.
- [Rob] Look at that thing.
- [Dan] I feel like his,
I feel like his secretary
normally does his tie tying
for him and the longer
he gets away from home,
either he wears the-
- [Rob] It loosens, yeah.
- [Dan] It loose, (laughs)
now, now I was just going to,
since we got them chatting
really briefly, I was just going
to bring up Mr. Jack Arnold briefly.
- [Rob] Oh, sure, yeah.
- [Dan] I don't, I don't know that,
so Jack Arnold was born
in 1916, died in 1992,
and he was a director extraordinaire.
To me, he's one of the main
names when you are referring
to sort of the 50s' "Keep
Watching the Skies" genre
of American Sci-Fi, because he did,
"It Came from Outer Space",
"Creature from the Black Lagoon",
"Revenge of the Creature", "Tarantula",
"The Incredible Shrinking Man".
That's enough, those are,
those are all, all huge.
He also did "The Space Children"
and "Monster on the Campus",
which maybe aren't as big,
but have their charms.
And he, he did "High School Confidential".
He did "The Mouse That Roared"
over in England with Peter Sellers.
- [Rob] Peter Sellers, sure.
- [Dan] Yes, he did a
whole bunch of film noir.
He did, he did episodes of a show called,
I believe it was called
"Dusty's Trail", which
became a movie called "The
Wackiest Wagon in the West",
which this same year, 1976,
that this movie came out in Europe,
"The Wacky", "Dusty's Trail",
they took four episodes of this sitcom,
which was a Sherwood Schwartz,
basically "Gilligan’s
Island" on a wagon train,
(Rob laughs)
and edited four episodes together,
took out the laugh track, and
released it as a theatrical.
- [Rob] Wow (laughs).
- [Dan] So technically his
last theatricals were this
and a couple episodes of that sitcom,
which ain't the greatest.
- [Rob] Wow, well this,
this was gonna fit perfectly
for my fade out show then,
if this is his final theatrical film.
- [Dan] Oh, yes, yes, exactly.
So, and, and he did lots of TV.
He did tons of TV, he
was doing like a love,
"Love Boat", he did,
he did like 1 5 episodes
of "The Brady Bunch",
which is interesting.
I don't know what episodes he did.
I, I wish I'd love to do maybe
a Jack Arnold marathon over,
over an, an afternoon.
He did lots, he did "McLeod",
"Love, American Style",
the Virginian "Mod Squad",
lots of "Gilligan's Island".
He did "Sheriff Lobo", he did
a couple of "Ellery Queens".
He did a "Buck Rogers
in the 25th Century".
He did a lot of stuff.
He was like, he was, it's, I, I like him
because he's not like a
really dynamic director,
but the camera's always in the right spot.
We always, well, maybe in
this one we don't always know
what's going on, but we
generally always feel like
we're supposed to know what's going on.
That's the thing with
"The Swiss Conspiracy"
is you don't always know what's going on,
but the film carries you along.
Maybe it doesn't matter in the end.
- [Rob] I, I always feel
like if any director
has one really great movie, right,
that's great enough, right?
- [Dan] Yes.
- [Rob] But, but then you think
maybe they got lucky, right?
Maybe they got lucky,
but when they get two,
I'm like, "Then it's
them, then it's them."
And any, any director who can say,
"I have 'Creature of the Black Lagoon'
and 'The Incredible Shrinking Man',
just those two on my res-"
Besides all the ones you
already just mentioned,
that, you're like,
"That's a solid career".
That's an amazingly solid career.
- [Dan] Yes, you, you won.
Yeah, you got it, you got it.
You were doing the right
thing, yeah, exactly.
- [Rob] You did, maybe, right.
Maybe you were a
journeyman, but who cares?
You were, you were the right journeyman
at the right time, you know?
- [Dan] Yes, exactly.
- [Rob] Oh, no.
- [Dan] Oh, dear.
- [Rob] John Saxon, this is, this is,
this is a show wrap for-
- [Dan] Yeah, for Mr., Mr. Saxon there.
And it's, it's, it's, it's interesting,
and, and, and I, I, I’ll, this
will be the last time I refer
to it, but when the, we
do see the assassins going
after our David, I am
going to mention the,
the strangeness of the, the,
the hit men who are supposed
to be sort of undercover,
doing this casually,
killing a guy and then stuffing
him in the fake rented car
of an ex Department of Justice guy
who's investigating blackmail
in one of the biggest Swiss banks.
(phone rings)
Seems a bit of a drawing attention
to yourself kind of thing.
- [Rob] I always wondered if like,
companies want their name associated
with things when it's nefarious stuff.
- [Dan] Oh, yes, yes!
- [Rob] You know, like Hertz Car Rental,
do they want their name in a movie
where it's people getting,
bodies get dumped in trunks?
You know, they don't want that.
- [Dan] May, maybe they had
like a thing where like, if,
if you rent from LAX on
this day, open your trunk,
John Saxon might be inside, and if he is-
- [Rob] That'd be, that
would’ve been amazing.
That would've been a-
- [Dan] You'd win a free autographed copy
of the novelization of
"The Swiss Conspiracy".
- [Rob] (laughs) "Swiss
Conspiracy", would've been great.
- [Dan] That would’ve been fantastic.
So here's the second and
final scene with Corinne,
who seems like he, sh-,
she should be doing more.
This is one of those weird things
that makes me think maybe the
film should have been longer
and maybe they kept it around 90 minutes
because "French Connection"
was around 90 minutes.
And because she feels like she should be
in it more, right?
- [Rob] Because she, she has,
she probably has a much larger role
in the David Christopher
TV series in my head.
- [Dan] Yes, exactly, exactly, and there,
there is, I think it's,
if you, I think it's, if you
watch the previous scene,
I think it's into this scene.
When you see Hayes's body
in the, in the trunk,
the music starts to go
(mimics ominous music)
and then it cuts out when it cuts to her.
Like there's a bad, like
if you listen to it,
it's either this scene
or the previous one.
But I think it's this one.
If you listen to the music
closely, put headphones on
and listen to the, there's
a kind of a bad sound edit
when it cuts to her.
- [Rob] Oh, I didn't
even notice that, okay.
- [Dan] Almost, almost like are they,
did they cut her scene short
or did they, I mean,
did they have a scene where he's in jail?
'Cause he said he spends the night in jail
and they, they dismissed
that Hertz Rent A Car thing
so quickly, I mean, it's gone now.
It's done now, it'll never
be referred to again.
- [Rob] Yep.
- [Dan] So I'm, I'm wondering if
that was a scene maybe
that got cut out, I don't.
- [Rob] Oh, interesting.
- [Dan] I don't know, but we're about
to meet the great John Ireland.
- [Rob] Yeah, we're gonna
meet one of our, yeah,
one of our, one of our
sus-, well, not our sus-,
we will later, learn later he's a suspect,
but right now he's a victim.
But yes, John Ireland,
this is his longest scene.
So let me, let me briefly, we'll just talk
about his credits, he passed away in 1992.
You know, an amazing list of credits,
"All the King's Men",
"Spartacus", "Red River",
"Farewell, My Lovely", "Raw
Deal", "My Darling, Clementine".
- [Dan] Yes.
- [Rob] "Satan's Cheerleaders", which,
when am I gonna get to say
those two movies back to back?
"Gun Slinger", "The Incubus",
I mean, just, you know, and
he's, he's realty great here
as this kind of, first of all,
he's acting like he's 50 years
older than David Christopher,
and he's like 9, you know,
because they're kind
of not that far apart.
But he's a, "My boy."
Like he's definitely, you know, the,
the, the, the Texas oil
man, this kind of thing.
I'm surprised they don't
have him in a 10 gallon hat.
- [Dan] Yeah, with big hat,
like a J. R. Ewing hat, right?
- [Rob] Yeah, exactly,
but again, he's indoors
and he's, he's a gentleman
and you don't wear your hat indoors.
So that's what it, but look at him,
he's drinking the whiskey
straight outta the bottle.
- [Dan] That he brought himself, yeah.
- [Rob] (laughs) That he
brought, brought himself.
You know, this is great, yeah.
- [Dan] That's a, yeah,
that's a big thing,
in the novelization, I think
McGowan and Hayes are like
on the same plane
and McGowan is watching
Hayes at one point.
Which is funny because,
if you think about it,
like McGowan's watching Hayes,
the cop is watching Hayes,
the assassins are watching Hayes.
Everybody's watching Hayes,
but now what do they do?
Hayes is, Hayes is dead,
I mean, they're all, I
guess they're probably all
in this restaurant watching
each other, I would bet.
- [Rob] (laughs) Right, exactly.
Half this restaurant's
lunch rush is spies.
- [Dan] Exact, spies.
(Rob laughs)
- [Rob] And they're, and they're
all ordering the minimum,
you know, because they're
just there to, for appearance.
- [Dan] You can tell, "Did
you bring your own booze?
Okay, put 'em over here."
- [Rob] "I'll just have an appetizer."
I mean, well, that's not.
- [Dan] I'll just, just,
"No, I don't want whiskey,
bring me nachos."
(Rob laughs)
"Light on the jalapenos 'cause ugh."
- [Rob] (laughs) I love
his eyebrows, by the way.
John Ireland's eyebrow are,
are really Donald
Moffitt, Andy Rudy level.
- [Dan] Yes, he's got those,
those wonderful crazy,
those wonderful crazy eyebrows.
And there's, and, and the, the,
the conversation they're
having it, it's one
of those interesting conversations
where it's all very important,
but in between the calling him "boy"
and watching him pour the whiskey
and watching David
Janssen drinking his beer,
you can kind of miss what they're saying,
which is basically that McGowan
is having big tax troubles.
- [Rob] Yep, yep, oh, here
we go, there's Elke Sommer.
- [Dan] And she's back, and we're, again,
we're knee deep in, "Is
everything all set?"
"Yes, everything's all set."
And very shortly we're about
to get the big demand from the,
the, from the blackmailers.
- [Rob] I wanna mention this just
'cause Elke Sommer doesn't
have a lot of scenes
in this movie, she is credited
at the top as guest star.
- [Dan] Yes!
- [Rob] Right, I will die on this hill.
You cannot have a guest star in a movie.
Movies, all movies' cast are one-offs.
- [Dan] Yes, exactly.
- [Rob] Cannot have a guest,
this is not "The Love Boat".
- [Dan] Yes, exactly.
- [Rob] There, Elke Sommer is
a cast member in this movie.
She's not a guest star.
I know that with her agent
and got her special billing.
And I get it, oh, here's another
way of delivering the mail.
But that's every time I see "guest star"
in a movie, like that's not a thing!
- [Dan] That doesn't make, yeah, exactly.
That always confu-, and oh,
and here are those two
guys, you'll see 'em.
- [Rob] They're right there (laughs).
- [Dan] There are two guys
right there, come on, really?
- [Rob] We all know guys like
that in our office, right?
- [Rob] Yeah, you, you realty
didn't see the person walk up
and drop the, drop the thing right there?
- [Rob] Right in the middle of the floor.
Right in the middle of the floor,
not even on a table, you know?
- [Dan] Exactly, I mean,
that guard is very focused
on whatever it is he's looking at.
In, in the novelization he's
thinking about bratwurst.
(Rob laughs)
The, the book actually
opens with two pages
of him talking about how
much he loves 'wurst,
bratwurst and sausages,
and when I say sausage,
I'm not being coy, I'm
talking about actual sausages.
- [Rob] No, literally, yeah, no, there's,
there's a lot of food-
- [Dan] Literally sausages.
- [Rob] A lot of food
porn in the, the novel.
- [Dan] Yes, and a lot of-
- [Rob] Among other porn.
(Rob and Dan laugh)
- [Dan] Now, now this
introduces us to Kosta,
the guy from Amsterdam.
- [Rob] Yes, this is Curt Lowens,
great character director, Curt Lowens.
- [Dan] And it, and it's
interesting here, when you, again,
when you watch this a second time, you,
we are reading the final
demand from the blackmailers,
1 million from each of the five people,
10 million from the bank,
follow these instructions.
So this is the, so af-, from
this point on, we're waiting,
I think it's like two days from
now they're going to do the,
the climax is going to occur.
So we're getting that
information here halfway
into the movie and it's interesting
that the Kosta character,
from what we know about
him later in the movie,
shows up at this point when
it seems to be a lost cause.
- [Rob] Mmhmm.
You know, when it's like,
"Oh, well, Christopher,"
but has Christopher really
done much investigating?
- [Rob] Right!
- [Dan] He talked with a
half drunk John Ireland,
I mean, McGowan for, for like two minutes.
And he flirted with, he
flirted with Denise Abbott.
But has he actually
done any investigating?
- [Rob] Right, and he, I mean
he fought off John Saxon,
but that, that he didn't,
he didn't start that.
He, he got himself out of it.
- [Dan] And that's, I mean,
that's a special brand
of investigation, like automatic getting
in brawls over and over again,
but it, but it's interesting-
- [Rob] You know he's relaxed here
'cause he's got no tie now,
now he's open-shirting it
with the chest hair, very
manly, very, very manly.
- [Dan] And Ko-, and Kosta, I,
I think Kosta dropped the letter.
I think that makes sense.
Who dropped the first letter?
I can't say, because if you think about,
if you think about who
the blackmailers are,
they must have hired someone
to drop the first letter.
Because if you think about
it, Rasher's dead, McGowan
and Hayes are arriving, Kosta,
unless he's actually in town
and lying, isn't there yet.
But he, I wouldn't think
he'd wanna be in town
and get seen accidentally,
because that would be suspicious.
And Denise Abbott isn't there yet.
So who dropped the first letter?
- [Rob] Well, all right, we can, we,
we'll argue about this on
our second commentary track
which you can access on
the special hidden menu.
- [Dan] Yes, exact, exactly.
- [Rob] (laughs) I mean, but
he's like a big roller though.
Wouldn't people notice
him walking into the bank
and leave, dropping a letter on the floor?
- [Dan] Yeah, that's, that's the thing.
Like, maybe he did
something where he said,
he like pointed something.
He said, "Guard, I think
that person's doing something illegal."
- [Rob] "Look over there."
- [Dan] And, you know, he's just,
he's just thinking, "Wurst, wurst,
oh, I'll look over to the left."
Drop, "Sir, we're okay."
And he knows those two guys
at the desk ain't gonna be looking at him.
- [Rob] (laughs) That's
true, those guys, yeah,
those guys are, those are-
- [Dan] So we met Kosta and Kosta's great
because he doesn't do
much and he doesn't care.
And so, and so he, I,
and I don't know whether that
makes him instantly suspicious
that he shows up right at this point,
or just not suspicious at all.
In the end we'll go with the
former, but I can't really,
I couldn't really tell
when it first happened
because he's so dismissive.
"Just pay the money, I don't care.
Why do you care?
Just pay the money,
I'm going, I'm leaving.
Just pay the money," okay, okay.
- [Rob] Oh, now here we go, here we go.
- [Dan] This is interesting, yes.
- [Rob] I love this car chase.
'Cause it's not a chase, it's a,
it's foreplay, you know,
as we'll learn in a minute.
But this is great.
This is, and, I mean,
look how fast he's going.
I mean, I know they're probably
under cranking it a little, but he realty-
- [Dan] It looks pretty
good though, if they are.
- [Rob] It looks pretty good.
Like they're really going fast
and they're going around
these hairpin turns
and they're gonna go
through, there's, look at it,
look, look how happy, look
at that, he's just great.
- [Dan] You don't, you
don't see him smile,
like in "Harry O", you
don't see him smile.
There is, there is a, there's
a Bob Hope special he's in,
which I might mention in a
minute, where he smiles a lot
and it's kind of distracting.
- [Rob] (laughs) It's, "What's wrong?
Why is David Janssen smiling
or something upsetting, this is-"
- [Dan] But like you said, this is, yeah,
this is very much like a foreplay.
And it might end with, you know,
when he goes off the cliff near the end.
I don't know if that's meant
to be something suggestive, I'm not sure.
- [Rob] (laughs) Subtext.
- [Dan] I'm not sure,
that's not my, you know,
but I love the fact that like,
we're now we're in "On Her
Majesty's Secret Service".
What's going on here?
You know, I, like, like it's a mix
of like the chase from
"Goldfinger" when he's in,
in Switzerland and then like going
through like "On Her Majesty's
Secret Service" stuff.
And they got these great tunnels,
look at this, they're great!
- [Rob] Oh, the lights go down, oh,
how cool is that, look at that.
- [Dan] And it's, and the
great thing is this is, like,
like I said at the beginning,
this is the opposite
of the opening credits.
Takes us from the gorgeous
Alps, which are Swiss,
to banks, where they,
which they have everywhere.
And this, this scene starts
in a crappy little parking lot
where you, where you first think,
is one of them going the wrong way?
And now look at how gorgeous it is!
- [Rob] Look at, they're
g-, they're driving the,
the road is wet, look at that.
They're really, these stunt
drivers are doing this, this is-
- [Rob] Are they, and it's pretty funny.
And it's weird because like,
in the same way that the
big action scene earlier
on didn't involve our leading man,
which is slightly strange,
this scene here, which is another
kind of cool action scene,
is really just like you said, foreplay.
- [Rob] Oh, here we go,
oh, this is trouble.
- [Rob] And you do wonder when you get
to the end of the movie,
did she know this was there?
(car screeches)
- [Rob] Yeah, whoa, oh, look
at that, oh, that's great!
- [Dan] Oh no!
- [Rob] look at this, I mean,
I love how relaxed he is too.
Like, his car is teetering off the edge.
And look at him, I mean,
he's just kinda like,
"All right, well this is a problem."
Like, he doesn't even
look like, look at him!
- [Dan] Yes, it's like,
"I don't want to move."
(Rob gasps)
- [Rob] This is, this is-
- [Dan] It's, it's real-,
and the camera panned over
to there, so they got it,
they got it set up nicely.
So it is actually like,
he's actually there.
- [Rob] Look how casually
he gets outta that car!
- [Dan] Yes, and I, I,
I, and I will be honest,
I was actually very glad that
they didn't show his car go
down the hill and explode
and stuff, I was very glad.
- [Rob] No, it's fine, you don't need it.
- [Dan] We’ll see him next up.
- [Rob] And there we are.
- [Dan] And here we go.
Now I, I'm gonna say,
I, I think right here,
maybe we should talk about one
or two of the actors while they're,
to give them their privacy.
But I will say this, this scene
is about three minutes long
and it's just one shot just like this,
which I think is pretty
brave for theatrical
to just let the two actors talk like this.
- [Rob] I agree, now, before I get
to the those credits though,
I do wanna read a passage from the novel.
- [Dan] Yes, please, I'm sitting back,
I'm muting myself, I'm outta here.
- [Rob] This, (laughs) this book
gets very explicit, everybody.
So I'm not gonna read those passages
'cause we want to keep this
commentary safe for work.
But I will, I will read
the part that it sort
of just follows some very
explicit sexual references.
So it's, because it, it
happens right as this scene,
David thought of his car and
the winding hairpin turns
and the surge of power
when he demanded speed
and held himself strong with her writhing,
it turned to a sobbing,
moaning, shuttering effusion
of delight underneath him.
Then without breaking their union,
he lowered himself onto the
bed, lifting up her legs
to follow him until they
were both comfortable.
Gradually he moved, he moved faster
until his own tension increased
to the point of explosion.
And he rolled over on his back
and she was straddling him.
Only then did he give
into the ultimate ecstasy
that left every part of his body,
except his thrusting penis,
locked in a rigidity that was steel-like
and growl his satisfaction
from the depths of his being.
So there you go.
- [Dan] Well, when, when you're
selling the novelizations
on the checkout counters
next to "National Enquirer",
you gotta pull people in.
- [Rob] Woo, Michael Stanley!
- [Dan] Yeah, woo Mike!
Ooh, and that happens a bunch in the book.
- [Rob] Oh, a lot, it happens a lot.
- [Dan] That's not one off.
- [Rob] That was the
most pa-, that was the,
that was the most g-rated one I could find
of the passages, yeah, wow.
- [Dan] Exactly, yeah, it's
a heck of a novelization.
- [Rob] It is.
- [Dan] Everybody, so I just,
I'm just gonna talk about,
we've already kind of
talked about David Janssen.
- [Rob] A little bit.
- [Dan] But he was born in '31 ,
he died in 1980, sadly very young.
His first big thing was "Richard Diamond,
Private Detective", which is based off
of a wonderful radio show
created by Blake Edwards.
I've never seen the TV show,
again, saving it for retirement.
He's probably best known in
pop culture for "The Fugitive",
which ran for four seasons
and was one of the first shows
that had a proper finale.
Nowadays, we get them all the time,
unless streaming services
cancel your shows early
and then leave you hanging for eternity.
But back then you didn't
really get finales
and "The Fugitive" is one of those.
He was also on a show called
"O'Hara, U.S. Treasury".
I've never seen it, I do a
podcast on short lived TV shows,
so I may cover that one
day, if I can find it.
Of course he was in
"Harry O", he was in a lot
of movies, including the great "Dondi".
- [Rob] Oh, boy.
- [Dan] (laughs) Which
is in, which is listed
in the Medved's "Fifty
Worst Films Of All Time".
He's also, he was in "Maroon",
"Two-Minute Warning",
"Covert Action", he was in
"Inchon", which is kind of a-
- [Rob] Final film.
- [Dan] Yes, yes, a notorious
film for being a huge,
huge bomb, I've never
seen it, maybe one day.
- [Dan] Paying the
actors in cash and stuff.
There was a lot of ads, like (laughs).
- [Dan] Yes, yes, he was.
And he was in lots of, he was in a bunch
of TV movies, "Mayday at 40,000 Feet!",
"Stalk the Wild Child", "Fer de Lance",
"Superdome", "Moon of the Wolf",
which he plays a Louisiana sheriff,
I did the co-, co-did the commentary
for the Blu-ray of that,
'cause I love that film
and he's fantastic in it.
But that, yeah, that's
David Janssen and I,
and now we're getting some more.
- [Rob] I do wanna mention one thing
about David Janssen than I read.
- [Dan] Yes!
- [Rob] Which, he passed
away at 49, which is tragic.
I mean, that's incredibly young.
But his pallbearers at
his funeral included
Rod Stewart, Gregory Peck,
Milton Berle, Gene Kelly,
and Richard Harris, I mean,
that is a life well lived
when those are your pallbearers.
- [Dan] You did it, yeah, wow.
That was well done, sir, yeah, they, and-
- [Rob] What do Rod Stewart
and Milton Berle have to talk?
Well, I guess I could figure
out what they had to talk
about, you know, still.
(Dan laughs)
That's amazing, what, what
a group, what a group.
- [Dan] Yeah, that's Michael S-.
Yeah, that's a Michael Stanley book
that never got written, yeah.
(Rob laughs)
The, and, and the one last thing with Da-,
David Janssen is that he's,
he was in a Bob Hope special
around this time, a 90
Minute special called "Joys",
which is a takeoff on "Jaws",
which is a really weird murder mystery.
- [Rob] I've gotta see that.
- [Dan] I think you can,
you can watch it online
if you've never seen it.
Bob Hope, "Joys", it's 1975,
1976, '77, it's really weird.
- [Rob] Yeah, I gotta check that out.
How have I not seen that to this point?
- Yeah, it's really weird.
But, but yeah, so that's that.
So now we're doing,
we're, we're beginning to,
what I call, sort of
close off the red herrings
that happened in the movie.
And I'm gonna talk about Elke
Sommer just real quick here.
Maybe I won't, sit back, everyone,
I'm gonna give you 10
minutes of Elke Sommer.
No, we don't have time.
Elke Sommer was born in 1940.
She is, as far as I know,
she's still alive and,
and fingers crossed, alive
and well, she is German
and her first big role was the wonderful,
bringing up Blake Edwards again,
"Shot in the Dark", which
is a absolutely joy-,
joyous film, the second in
the "Pink Panther" series,
possibly the best, po-, I,
I would say the best made
of the films in the "Pink Panther" series.
She was in the Bob Hope film,
"Boy, Did I Get a Wrong Number!"
Again, also in the "Fifty
Worst Films of All Time" book
by the Medveds, she was
in a "Carry On" film,
which I wrote, I wanna say
it's "Carry On Behind".
But my last word is scribbled here.
So it's "Carry On",
something beginning with B.
She was in a version of
"Then There Were None".
She was in the great film, "The Oscar",
well, I say great film,
you should watch it.
She was in two Mario Bava
films, "Baron Blood",
"Lisa and the Devil", she was
in two fun "James Bond" ripoffs,
"Deadlier Than the Male",
which I believe was a
Bulldog Drummond thing.
And one of Ray Milland's earliest films
was a really fun Bulldog Drummond film.
And she was in "The
Wrecking Crew", which is one
of the Dean Martin, Matt Helm films.
And she was just in a touch, she was also
on "I Miss You, Hugs and Kisses",
which is a "Video Nasties" adjacent film.
And she was in a lot of stuff.
And she's just one of, every
time, she shows up in a lot
of things around this time,
and every time you see her,
she's in, she's in a TV
movie called "Probe",
which is a precursor to
a show called "Search",
which I love, she's great in that.
And that, and "Search"
actually had an episode
that involved a Swiss bank account
and people being blackmailed.
- [Rob] Oh, hey, okay.
- [Dan] That was made about
four years before this.
Instead of David Janssen,
you get Doug McClure, which is awesome.
- [Rob] (laughs) Okay, sure.
- [Dan] And Doug McClure, and,
and in that one they actually
go into the vaults
and into the computers and
such of the Swiss bank to,
and they're those huge 70s,
60s style computers, folks.
And they do go into the
vaults and the banks
and they sort of, they,
they do more intensive research
than Mr. Christopher seems
to do, which is just kind
of talking people and
following people around.
- [Rob] (laughs) And run on highways.
- [Dan] Yes, fantastic, so
I, I feel like I should talk
about, would you mind if I just
mention Anton Differing real quick?
- [Rob] Of course not, yeah, sure.
- [Dan] Again, I keep saying
I don't, why I keep saying,
"Real quick," but he was born in 191 6.
He died in either '88 or '89.
I can't tell what I wrote down here.
It's a nine or an eight,
he died soon after 1988.
And he played, he was German
also, he played lots of Nazis.
He was in "The Man Who Could Cheat Death".
He was in "Fahrenheit
451 ", "Where Eagles Dare",
"The Colditz Story", "I Am a Camera".
He was in the great "Mark of the Devil 2".
He was in a couple of giallos,
"Iguana With a Tongue of Fire",
"Seven Deaths in the Cat's Eye",
He was in a "Nunsploitation" film,
"Love Letters of a Portuguese Nun".
He was in "The Beast of Must
Die", a fun werewolf film.
He was in "Victory", the
Sylvester Stallone, Pelé film.
He was in "The Winds
of War", TV miniseries,
Jess Franco's "Faceless",
and Jerry Lewis' "The
Day the Clown Cried".
- [Rob] Oh, by the way,
I'm sorry to interrupt,
but this, that scene there
with the line down the,
it looked like they were
in two different scenes
that were split together even
though they're not (laughs).
- [Dan] Yes, it did, that
was a little weird, yeah.
- [Rob] (laughs) It's like all
of a sudden there's like a,
why was Brian Bromell brought in
to do a split diopter shock
for this, for this movie?
- [Dan] Yeah, it's exactly,
yeah, that was a little weird.
So right now we're kind of, we're kind
of tearing towards the end
and we're getting, we're, we're
getting, we are getting the,
we're gonna finally resolve
what's going on with Benninger.
And it looks like our
assassins are still there.
And oh, the, by the way,
the final thing Anton Differing did
was a three-part "Dr Who" story in 1988,
the 25th anniversary "Dr
Who" story, "Silver Nemesis",
where he plays a Nazi
and he goes up against some cybermen
in the seventh doctrine, ACE.
He seems like he's not terribly
interested in what's going
on when you watch him in that.
And I, and I've read
that he was just there
so he could listen to
Wimbledon on the radio
because wherever he lived,
he couldn't see Wimbledon.
But he, they said he just,
when he wasn't on the set,
he was in his hotel room
listening to Wimbledon matches.
- [Rob] I love that, I love
that, I love these guys.
It is like Nicholson in
his Laker games, you know,
he's just like, "Look, I
got my priorities here.
We're, we're ready to,
I'll shoot Chinatown,
but I really gotta see
this final free throw."
(Rob laughs)
- [Dan] So, so here, yeah.
So here we're, we're,
we're resolving this big,
we're, a bunch of red
herrings are all resolving
at once here, and we are gonna find out,
yeah, that obviously,
Differing and Sommer,
they're, they have nothing to do
with the blackmail that's going on.
And somehow our assassins are
now after Mr. Christopher,
could you figure out how
exactly that happened?
- [Rob] No, no, I'm still kind of,
(laughs) I was impressed at the, I mean,
I never, I don't know
the budget of this film,
but I assume it was, you
know, fairly substantial
with these, you know, these
are all name actors in it.
And, but this, this whole sequence had
to be pretty expensive to do.
I mean, they're really, they're,
they're blocking off an airport
for at least a little while,
not an airport, it's a train station.
- [Dan] They're in this tr-,
he's not looking at those books!
- [Rob] No, he's (laughs).
- [Dan] I thought it was for a second.
- [Rob] Come on, David Hess,
you're not even faking it, come on.
"I'm not looking, got at least
lover here on the thing."
(Dan laughs)
But look at that, I mean, you know,
they have to block all this out.
This is a, this is a train
station, you know what I mean?
That probably was a pain to have to do.
- [Dan] Yeah, and this is a
really nicely edited scene.
This, the shooting right here,
this is, this is nicely done.
So it's, it's, they had, they
had multiple setups and things
and poor Anton Diff-,
actually, no, he survives.
Spoiler, but yeah,
that's really nicely shot right
there through the suitcase.
- [Rob] No pun intended.
- [Dan] That's, yeah, exactly.
That's a nice little, you know,
almost like you mentioned "De Palma",
that's almost something
like a "De Palma" thing,
like a shooting through some suitcases.
- [Rob] In public too, you
know, like in public, you know?
- [Dan] I do hope they hired extras
because I'd hate to think that David Hess,
because I know he, he would compare,
he apparently could be very
sort of method at times.
I'd hate to think it was
like, "We're gonna knock
over those Swiss citizens," so they-
- [Rob] Oh, there, oh,
there it is, gets up, oh!
- [Dan] Oh, no, and I love, there he go-,
he can run pretty good, I mean,
for some reason I thought
he wouldn't make it.
You know, he's got a bit of a, you know,
"I'm the Swiss Ed Asner,"
or something to him.
I don't know what I'm thinking when I look
at him, but, but he moves.
- [Rob] Yeah, he's finally
doing something here.
- [Dan] And poor, poor David
Janssen, he doesn't, one
of the things with "Harry
O" was that "Harry O",
early on he, he had to
retire from being a cop
because he had a bullet in his back.
So whenever David Janssen
like ran as Harry,
he had a strange limp, kind
of like he does right there.
Maybe, well, I mean,
David Janssen, he, he,
he didn't live easy, he,
he always had a good time,
I think is the way I would say it.
- [Rob] "This is the quiet car.
What are you doing shooting
people in this thing here?"
(Dan laughs)
I should mention here, just as,
as Mr. Benninger is sort of
exiting our film, oh, Sommer,
I do wanna read one
brief paragraph about him
from the novelization where it says,
"'Franz Benninger,' the
cruder Hurtil bank clerks used
to joke over their forth Löwenbräu,
'could only reach climax if he
made love in a morning suit.'
The executive vice president
of Hurtil Bank came from
a family that had been
with Hurtil Bank for a century,
and he wore his position in the bank
as if it were a bishop
presiding over the liturgy
in his home cathedral."
- [Dan] Wow.
- [Rob] So they, (laughs) that's kinda-
- [Dan] That's, that's the
kind of, if, if you, yeah,
if you've never read novelizations,
that's the sort of stuff you get.
- [Rob] Background details you get
on these characters in
the novelization, yeah.
- [Dan] Lot of it, and what
we're getting right here
is, I call this, yeah, closing
the door on the red herrings,
because now the Hayes thing
with the assassins is done.
And just the fact that
when, when Hurtil says
to Ms. Rita Jensen right
there, "Blackmail,"
and she says, "Blackmail,
what are you talking about?"
- [Rob] Mmhmm.
- [Dan] It's like, okay, can
we get back on the blackmail?
I love that we're spending
two minutes describing,
"I didn't have the
papers, you know, I wanted
to get my real ID and I didn't
have the right address on my,
on my, on my bill."
You know, and it's just like, "Oh, man."
And even David Janssen,
even Christopher is like,
"Maybe we should be
working on the blackmail,
rather than hearing this
exposition, is this necessary?"
- [Rob] "I didn't remember
my eight digit pin number
for my bank account," or whatever.
- [Dan] Yes, yes, it was like,
"I brought the birth certificate
and they forgot to notarize it,
they just wouldn't look at it."
- [Rob] (laughs) This is
a lovely home she has,
by the way, I love this garden.
- [Dan] Yeah, yeah, or is, is this,
is this a hospital or where is this?
- [Rob] Is it a hospital, I
don't think, I don't know.
- [Dan] I don't know
because there's a gentleman
who comes out who I like
to think is the producer.
- [Rob] Oh, of course it
is because the doctor just,
yeah, the, yeah, they're, they're
in a hospital, yeah, yeah.
- [Dan] Or again, one of the friends
of those guys who were
in the overalls earlier.
- [Rob] There you go.
- [Dan] Like when he shows
up, he's like Ray Milland,
Elke Sommer, David Janssen,
and this happy guy in
like the Swiss petticoat.
- [Rob] He looks really happy
to be there, this actor.
- [Dan] Yeah, yeah, he's
having a great time.
- [Rob] He's really thrilled
with his one line, yep.
- [Dan] Yeah, and so we're
gonna, now we're moving
towards the climax of the movie, sort of,
actually it's gonna,
it's gonna do something weird in a moment,
but we're getting right here
that he actually does his
main investigating now.
- [Rob] He's finally,
"All right, all right."
- [Dan] But he does it all,
he does it all like now.
He's doing, he's about to start,
the planes taken off,
all the investigation
is gonna happen right here.
And I just, and I just
wanna say one more thing
about the assassins, oh, and that's, I,
I, the thing I like about this scene,
I always think of you when
I watch this scene, Rob,
because I know this is the way you,
you made money throughout college.
- [Rob] (laughs) I did, I
put myself through art school
as a, as a go-go dancer.
- [Dan] Go-go dancer with a great wig.
- [Rob] Yeah, look at that.
- [Dan] And I, I don't think,
I think I've only been in like one,
and this is how, you
know, sheltered, I guess,
I am, I've only been like in,
in one bar or club in my life
where there were go-go dancers
and I think they were in cages.
- [Rob] Oh, really, you're
one up on me then, okay.
- [Dan] Yes, just happened one time.
And I think I was just stopping
by to ask for directions.
- [Rob] (laughs) I stopped by here just
to find a way to get out of here.
- [Dan] Just to find a way to leave here.
And I just, I just wanna say,
I just, I, I, sorry, folks.
I have, I have certain things
when I'm talking quickly
and I'm, I'm slightly anxious.
I have certain things I
say over and over again.
Like, "I'm just gonna say this quickly,"
I, I don't know who hires the
assassins to kill Christopher.
My thought is this, that the
assassins are watching Hayes
when he attacks Christopher.
And then when they kill Hayes,
which was their assignment,
and they are hired-in
assassins, they don't pick
and choose what they do.
They hired, what was in that
package says, "Kill this guy."
They kill him, then they leave.
And presumably, they
kill him in Switzerland
so his body isn't in the US.
So they can do, but what
I think what happens
is they see this guy,
they don't know who Christopher is,
and they think, "Hey, we'll
put his body in a trunk
and pretend it's this guy's car
to incriminate him and then we'll leave."
But as they're leaving, they
say, "Yeah, we killed the guy."
"What'd you do with the body?"
"Oh, we put it in David
Christopher's trunk."
"The guy from the Department of Justice?"
You know, like, you know,
and they say, "Yeah," they say,
"He's been giving us trouble.
"Kill him too."
So I think that's why they,
now I made all that up.
That's not in the movie or the book,
but I think that's why they
suddenly go from killing Hayes
to wanting to kill Christopher.
Because you don't like
put the body in the trunk
to incriminate the guy
and then go after him.
- [Rob] Right, because right then you're,
then you're revealing he's not
the guy that did it, right.
- [Dan] Yes, and just in the same way
that I thought Hayes was
going to call in assassins
to kill Christopher, rather,
'cause my thought was maybe
he tries to kill Christopher,
can't do it, then calls
the assassins and his boss
or whoever says, "Strangely enough,
we have some assassins on the way.
We’ll give them another killing to do."
And so it's like, first kill this guy
and then the guy you just killed
has hired you to kill this guy.
But in the timeline, there's no time,
I mean, unless as they're
killing him, he's yelling out,
"Hey, guys, before you kill me,"
and he pulls out a picture
of David Janssen, "Could
you kill this guy?"
"You got it, Mr. Hayes!"
(Dan mimics gunshot)
So we just got that weird scene.
I think it's a weird
scene with, with the cop.
And it's funny 'cause the
weird scene with the cop
with them leaving cuts to
another scene with the cop.
- [Rob] Another scene with
the cop (laughs) eating.
All of a sudden, yeah,
all of a sudden the cop
is like the main essential character.
- [Dan] The main character
for like three minutes.
The cop becomes the main character.
And that previous scene was a weird one
because it's basically
him recapping everything
that's happened and is about to happen.
- [Rob] If you would
ask actor Inigo Gallo,
who plays the cop, Captain
Frey, what the movie's about,
he would say, "It's about a cop
that investigates a Swiss conspiracy."
- [Dan] Exactly, exactly,
special guest star David Janssen.
- [Rob] Exactly, with, yeah,
with occasional appearances.
Well, guest appear-, there we go.
No, there were no guest appearances, Dan.
I said that earlier.
- [Dan] (laughs) Exactly, yeah, that is,
that is always so confusing.
And maybe that's something from, maybe,
maybe in another universe,
this was, you know,
he had his own TV show,
"Dennis Christopher".
(Rob chatters)
"Department" or "DOJ", or
something, I don't know.
- [Rob] Exactly, exactly.
- [Dan] And, and maybe that
ends with him having to leave.
And this is a follow up to that.
I don't know, but I don't
even know what we're doing.
Oh, yes, so, so the climax has begun,
and again, this is the second sequence
where we're gonna go from,
we basically went from
an ugly parking lot.
We're gonna go up into
the gorgeous Alps, now,
the first time it was for sex,
this time it'll be for violence.
And I don't know if that means anything.
I don't know if that means anything.
And the movie ends leaving
out the opening scene
where it begins on top of the Alps.
So I think there's some sort
of cyclical thing going on,
or I'm just full of bologna.
I'm probably full of
bologna, but I noticed it.
- [Rob] Oh, here, no, you've
got three of our suspects.
And now let me, let,
let me just very quickly
go through the, we didn't talk about the,
the career of Senta Berger.
- [Dan] Oh, yes, please.
- [Rob] Or Curt Lowens,
lemme just go through the,
now that they're together.
- [Dan] Because they're gonna
be driving for a bit, folks.
- [Rob] Yeah, they'll be driving for a bit
- [Dan] So enjoy the Autobahn
and "Uncut Diamonds", yeah.
- [Rob] Yeah, right, there we go.
So Senta Berger was born in 1941 .
As far as I know, she's still with us,
like you said, like Elke Sommer.
I hope she's happy, she was in
movies like "The Ambushers",
"The Quiller Memorandum",
the another movie that's kind
of sounds like this,
"The Quiller Memorandum".
- [Dan] Yeah, like the
"Cassandra Crossing", yeah.
- [Rob] "Cassandra Crossing", "de Sade",
"If It's Tuesday, This Must be Belgium",
which again, I like seeing
those two films back to back.
"When Women Had Tails" and the sequel,
"When Women Lost Their Tails".
I didn't know that that
first film made enough money
that there was a second (laughs).
- [Dan] Hey, if, if, if every,
if anyone's putting that out on Blu,
I think you got two guys here who’ll
do the commentary for both of those.
- [Rob] (laughs) Yeah,
let's, let's call her shot.
- [Dan] Discount, discount
for "Uncut Diamonds".
- [Rob] (laughs) She was
also in "Cross of Iron".
And then Curt Lowens,
he passed away in 2017.
He was in movies like "Angels and Demons",
"The Midnight Clear" and "The Entity".
Great movie, "The Mephisto
Waltz" with Alan Alda.
- [Dan] Oh, with Alan Alda, yeah!
- [Rob] And the reason I mention that is
because I know him from his
guest appearance on one episode
of "MASH" he is in, which of
course also featured Alan Alda.
He plays a, he plays a colonel
from Luxembourg who comes
to retrieve a dead soldier
who we find out is not actually dead.
- [Dan] Oh.
- [Rob] And he's very funny.
So that, that's Curt Lowens, here.
So yeah, those are, those, our two.
I wanna make sure we mention
the credits of the these two.
- [Dan] Yes, yes, yes.
And I'm, I'll just do while,
while we're looking here, and,
and there's an interesting
thing, which I think is,
is, this is less suspicious
in the novelization,
I think, than it is here,
where McGowan suddenly says,
"Sorry, can't do it."
- [Rob] Yeah, he begs out
out, yeah, he just, yeah,
he punks out, yep.
- [Dan] For, for some reason
they, they present him
by giving him more background,
the novelization, you know
that he is a sick man.
- [Rob] He's taking his
heart pills there, right?
- [Dan] Yes, exactly, exactly.
- [Rob] "Sorry, Davey, boy,
that's as far as I go."
- [Dan] And of course when
the movie ends, you know,
this, he's, he's handing
him the bologna right here.
All three of them are handing
David Janssen a big pile
of wurst, and, and,
but, but here, it seems
to me it seems suspicious,
in the novelization it seems more like it
could actually have happened.
But it does seem strange that, you know,
he possibly didn't know
where they were going
or like, I mean, I mean,
obviously he's faking it,
so it doesn't matter in the end.
- [Rob] Right, yeah, right, he's making
up anything that sounds plausible.
- [Dan] And, and I just wanna mention,
John Saxon and David Hess real quick,
and I also always say, I think,
I always think like the limo's
gonna hit the car right there.
It comes so, and there's John Ireland
in the background tearing out
and he's like, "You guys still acting,
'cause I'm, they're
sending me up the hill?
I'm gonna talk to you later, bye-bye."
It's such a, it's a weirdly awkward use
of the frame to have like,
I wonder if it's something
like where Jack Arnold was
behind the camera going, "No,
don't back into the shots.
What are you doing?"
- [Rob] "Just drive out of the frame,
don't worry about it," yeah, yeah.
- [Dan] We, we've got,
our actors are trying
to do something that's so distracting.
Oh, and here's the cop again.
Like, we're pretending the cop is going
to get involved in the ending.
So David Hess was born in
36, died in I believe 2011 .
And like I said, he was a songwriter,
first off, he did the soundtrack
for "Last House on the Left",
which is alternately
goofy and so depressing.
And of course, yeah, his
big thing was "Last House
on the Left" where he played Krug.
I've seen "Last House on
the Left" several times.
It's a good movie, but
not maybe something you
wanna have fun watching on
an after, watch this instead.
- [Rob] No.
- [Dan] And he, he was in "Hitchhike",
Mario Bava's "Hitchhike".
He was in "House on the Edge
of the Park", which is sleazy,
but somehow more fun than
"Last House on the Left".
He was in the fun
mid-eighties Italian slasher,
"Body Count", he was
in, oh, and he directed,
I think he was on an episode of "Manimal".
Don't quote me on that,
but he directed the fun,
very early slasher in 1980,
"To All a Good Night",
a Santa Claus killer,
slasher set in a sorority.
So he was a great guy, very,
from what I know, rather congenial fellow.
Although he looked like
he would, you know,
maybe punch you in the face, you know,
as much, so much as look at you, but,
but I guess he was pretty-
- [Rob] Like David Janssen, I'm guessing.
- [Dan] Yeah, yeah, exactly, exactly.
So, so, and, and then, yeah, John Saxon
and Carmine Orrico was his, his name.
And 1936, say, he was actually
born a month and a half
before David Hess, probably
in the same hospital.
Oh, we got another Saxon through here.
I bet they born with,
Hess was born with a full head of hair.
John Saxon, 1936, died in
2020, and he was in everything.
(train chugs)
I mean, I don't even feel
like I need to go into it.
I mean, he was in "Black Christmas",
he was in "Night Caller from Outer Space".
I'm jumping all over, he
was in "Rock Pretty Baby",
"Enter the Dragon", of course.
He was in three of the
"Nightmare on Elm Street" films.
He was in several of the Gene
Roddenberry failed pilots
of the 70s, "Planet Earth",
"Strange New World".
He was in, he was in "Fast Company",
he was in "The Glove", he was
in "Prisoner of the Lost Universe".
He was in, he was a starring guy
in "The Bold Ones", "The New Doctors".
He was in everything,
he's freaking John Saxon.
I'm gonna stop talking and we’ll go on
to what's happening right here, which is-
- [Rob] They're in a
funicular, which is just a,
a word I love to say, (laughs) funicular.
- [Dan] And, and it's at,
it's at, it's at this point
where you realize that, you know,
maybe they all don't have
much to say to each other,
you know, that it's, the tension is up
and the, the small talk is over.
They don't have much more to say.
They're, they're just
kind of, and I think even
in the novelization, it's mentioned here
that no one really says anything
as this train with this,
again, the guy, the
conductor of the train,
I feel like is part of that family, who,
of the guy who played the doctor
and the two guys who ran
out in the parking garage.
- [Rob] Yeah, the overall guy, yep.
- [Dan] I, I feel like maybe they're,
maybe they're all the same family.
So I love they keep cutting
too, like I don't know
that you need to cross
cut to the cop this often.
(movie chatters)
I, because he arrives late,
he always arrives late.
- [Rob] They are not in
weather gear, by the way.
- [Dan] Yes.
- [Rob] In proper winter
gear here, their dress shirts
and their floor chimes,
walking through the snow here.
- [Dan] That's one of the
big, I mean, like, my thought,
my first thought when they're
right here at the ski lift is
that maybe, maybe that's
the way the Alps works.
Maybe it's a lot warmer than it looks.
- [Rob] I, okay, all
right, Dan, all right.
All right, so we are heading
into the last 10 minutes of this film.
- [Dan] Yes.
- [Rob] Very briefly, very blunt,
I just wanna get to a couple
of contemporary reviews.
- [Dan] Oh, yes, yes.
- [Rob] That I found, which
are absolutely marvelous.
So this, this one was released in Europe
and then a year later in America.
So a lot of the American
reviews, they're kind of,
it's a fait accompli at that point.
The film had sort of come and gone.
Here we go, that guy, the guy
in the, running the train.
But anyway, I found one
from the Chicago Tribune
by Gene Siskel, the Gene Siskel.
- [Dan] Oh, wow, wow.
- [Rob] He rated the film cheesy.
He says, "Ray Milland,
who looks very sad now that he is bald,"
which is incredibly mean-spirited.
And also coming from Siskel is
kind of a curious criticism.
(Dan laughs)
He says, "The script writers
shouldn't want any publicity.
There's not much of a story here.
A thriller without
thrills," which is kind of,
very good, very mean-spirited.
- [Dan] Yeah.
- [Rob] The East Times'
Kent and Male said,
"Senta Berger as one
of the blackmail victims provides sparkle
in a rather mundane plot."
The Daily Mirror, "Lots
of nice alpine scenery,
but no dramatic peaks are scaled."
All right, I gotta give 'em,
that was, yeah, that's okay,
that was clever, I'll give 'em that.
(Dan laughs)
The Richmond Time Dispatch
from Richmond, Virginia,
"Good suspense and a good
look at the closed doors
of the Swiss banking business."
That's a bit positive.
The Observer in London, a,
"As full of holes as a string vest.
It is grotesquely overacted,
Milland, Saxon, Ireland,
though Janssen is pleasantly relaxed
as the pr-," that's the way I'd put it.
"Pleasantly relaxed as the private eye
who ambles through it."
- [Dan] Yeah, that's okay.
- [Rob] The Morning News,
Wilmington, Delaware,
"Elke Sommer got a birthday
cake, which was a wheel
of Swiss cheese dotted with candles
during the making of this film."
(Dan laughs)
And then curiously, I
found a credit, a, a,
a story in Newsday from Nassau,
New York that says, right,
it was a, is an article about Robert Shaw.
And it says, "Right after Jaws, Shaw went
to work on 'The Swiss
Conspiracy', starring John Voight
and directed by Maximilian Shell."
And I'm like, "Wait, what?"
And I thought, "Were they
attached to this film?
And then they got," no,
it turns out that's a movie
called "End of the Game",
which was directed by Maximilian Shell
and has Robert Shaw and John Voight.
And so whoever wrote that
article just simply mistook
that movie for "The Swiss Conspiracy".
And then that, that got run
in like a dozen different articles, so.
- [Dan] Wow, that's, that's interesting.
'Cause we all know at this time,
Maximilian Shell was in that ship
on the edge of the black hole.
- [Rob] (laughs) That's right.
- [Dan] Waiting for Ernest
Borgnine to show up.
- [Rob] And then, (laughs)
and then one other thing I
wanna mention is some of the
double bills this played on,
which I find fascinating.
It mostly, it mostly played with, as a,
as a second feature to "St.
Ives", the Charles Bronson film,
which, it's solid, that makes sense.
- [Dan] Yeah, yeah.
- [Rob] It also played a lot of times
as a second bill to "Trial by Combat",
which is a Donald Pleasants war film.
I've not seen that film.
I found it playing in the
Leicester, England car park.
This is the, these were
the movies you could see
in one night at this theater, right?
"Swiss Conspiracy", "Dog Day
Afternoon", "The Exorcist",
"Jesus Christ, Superstar",
and the X-rated porn
film, "Dance of Ecstasy".
I mean, that was, movies
were just great in the 70s.
- [Dan] Down in Leicester Square,
they're having a good time
watching whatever the hell you want.
- [Rob] Can you imagine
going to the theater
and deciding, "Do I want to
see 'Jesus Christ, Superstar',
'The Exorcist' or 'The Swiss Conspiracy'?"
- [Dan] And I bet you,
I read the novelization
of "The Swiss Conspiracy".
It's pretty spicy, all
right, screw the ecstasy.
We're getting Janssen and Berger.
- [Rob] Want two tickets to
that, please, absolutely.
- [Dan] Let's do it.
And it's funny because the,
the cover of the book and the,
and the poster has a great thing
where it shows like a cutoff dead guy
in a ski lift-car-thing.
But like dollar bills are
flying all over the place.
- [Rob] Oh, it's great.
- [Dan] There's no, it's a,
it's a fantastic, it's a killer.
It's like, like, like
one of those great sort
of like "Eiger Sanction"
kind of super cool.
- [Rob] Yeah, oh, another
one, "Eiger Sanction" is kind
of a, you know, similar
kind of read to it.
- [Dan] Yeah, so, so right
here we are getting that it,
it turns out that Mr. Christopher
has done investigation
and right here he reveals
everything that's going on,
including all the stuff with, what is it?
Lord James Asher Wood, who like,
like I said, in the novelization,
she is, Ms. Abbott is a
model who just happens
to be blackmailing a lord.
In the movie, it seems like she
makes her living blackmailing this lord,
which would seem to be tenuous.
And how do you fill out
the tax forms on that?
Although, does that really
matter in Switzerland?
Blackmailing is probably a
thing you could put, right?
In Switzerland, they're not
gonna come to you and go like,
"Hey," here we go, the big reveal.
McGowan is sick, but
he's not quite as sick.
- [Rob] No, not that sick.
- [Dan] "I'll pop my
heart pills and go," I,
I always wonder why he
didn't take him off the lift.
Because isn't that like,
like wouldn’t that give him more time?
I mean, they're on the lift anyways.
- [Rob] That's true, yeah, you
would think that would not,
you'd want, wanna see that Curt Lowens
had been shot dead there.
- [Dan] Yeah, yeah,
like, like 'cause that,
'cause up until, because,
'cause right now it's gonna happen if,
if Lowens wasn't there, they'd
just be going up there and,
and you know, it's sort of revealed that,
that Christopher knows what's going on
and they're still look, like right,
that shot, they're still
looking back at him.
- [Rob] Yep, yep.
- [Dan] Like the back of his head,
maybe it seemed like the
bullet came out the back,
gross, and, but,
but they would've just seen
maybe like a helicopter taking
off or something like that.
Maybe been confused by this.
But, but they know now that
who's ever in the helicopter is, ah,
and can I just, I, I, I finished
that sentence in the middle
because you know where I was going there,
because I, we're running out of time
and I want to talk about how fragile
helicopters are apart from Blue Thunder.
- [Rob] (laughs) All he
had to do is hit the tail,
hit the rotor once with the bullet
and it just bails outta control.
- [Dan] It's, it's funny,
like I, I live in Los Angeles
and about once every month
or two we'll get, like at
some point during the day,
a bunch of helicopters
will appear above us.
Now, luckily we've never had
fugitives David Janssen running
through our backyard or anything,
but like those helicopters
seem pretty sturdy.
- [Rob] Yep.
- [Dan] And helicopters
in movies, poor guy.
- [Rob] Oh, right at
the edge of a cliff too.
- [Dan] Here he goes, and I
love this shot where he peers
over and it's still falling
- [Rob] Body (laughs).
- [Dan] It's still going, I just, in,
in my mind they do
like, they do like tours
of the Alps, showing off like, you know,
they shot "On Her Majesty's
Secret Service" here.
They shot "Goldfinger" on this road.
And if you look at the base of this cliff,
you'll find a mannequin that
looks like John Ireland.
- [Rob] (laughs) We never
bothered to get it out of the,
out of the ravine.
- [Dan] Yeah, exactly,
"Just leave it there.
Just leave it there," you know.
And there are pictures
like in, like people
from Ohio like holding up the mannequin
and smiling next to it, and so.
(Rob laughs)
But yeah, so, so yeah, it turns out, yeah,
that there was a lot of
misdirection in this movie
and it turns out that he was
actually correct in not going
into the bank because it had
nothing to do with the bank.
It's a very, I, I do like the ending here
because to me it's very,
very sort of Agatha Christie,
you might almost have seen Poirot,
although Poirot would never
have gone up the ski lift.
- [Rob] No.
- [Dan] You might have seen
Poirot with something like this
where all the misdirection
is towards assassins
and the, the vice president and the bank,
but it's actually not, it's the
simplest thing in the world.
Five people who needed money basically
blackmailed each other.
- [Rob] Great, great,
that's a great ending.
It is, I, I almost wish they
had explained it a
little more dramatically.
Like, but it's a great,
it's a great wrap up.
By the way, that gun, let that gun,
what is it gonna have like a pellet in it?
What's she gonna do,
not gonna stop anybody.
- [Dan] Exactly, it's
a lighter, yeah, it's-
- [Rob] I love that simple gag.
Just throw the diamonds at her
and while she catches the
diamonds, grab the gun.
- [Dan] Yeah, because she's not gonna let,
she's not gonna let these
gross uncut diamonds
drop two feet into snow.
(Rob laughs)
I guess, I guess you, I'm,
I'm making fun of that.
But, but I guess at this moment,
I mean this is probably one
of the tense moments of
their, her life, right,
so I would probably drop the gun too.
- [Rob] And now she's gonna sell this
and of course she's a beautiful woman
and he's gonna fall for this, yeah.
- [Dan] And I do love, "Can you explain,"
and then just Mr.
Christopher's response, yeah.
It's basically like,
"yeah, but it's gonna,
it's gonna take a little time."
And I do like, I do like that very much.
'Cause I can't tell right
here from the cop whether
or not like the next six hours is gonna
be Mr. Christopher in a cell.
- [Rob] Right, yeah.
- [Dan] Having to explain what happened
with him believing her.
I'd like to think at this
point he's like, "You know, I,
I kind of believe David Janssen now
and I kind of know that, you know,
he didn't do this,"
kind of thing, you know.
'Cause if you look at
it like now, now four
of the five people are
dead who were blackmailed
and she's the only one left.
- [Rob] So yeah, our, our,
our chopper shot here,
- [Dan] Our beautiful shot here.
- [Rob] God, he's gotta be
cold, he's gotta be freeing!
- [Dan] I, I'd like to
think he had a little flask
in his pocket that he sipped right
before they said action and right after.
- [Rob] I think that was probably true
of any given scene in this movie (laughs).
- [Dan] Possibly, yes, possibly, and-
- [Rob] Look at that snow.
- [Dan] This is so gorgeous.
- [Rob] He had to stand
there for a long time.
- [Dan] He's on this like reaching
and my first thought was, "Oh,
they're using that helicopter," but, no.
- [Rob] But they're right,
they're not, there it is!
It's right there, the second chopper,
Jack Arnold, good for you, man.
- [Dan] One of my, one,
a favorite film of mine,
made around this time, "Blazing
Magnum", which is sort of a,
one of those Politzzo
names that I can't say is,
which is set in Toronto.
There's a scene in that where a guy shoots
down a helicopter, kind
of with more firepower
than David Janssen does.
- [Rob] And there we go.
- [Dan] But he, yeah, so.
(Rob mimics credit music)
- [Dan] And, and, and again, yeah,
we cut to the great "Oom-Pah-Pah" music
and now we're get this great theme.
(funky synthesizer music)
And I love this because this theme plays
throughout the movie and it's
sort of like the, the base
of it is like funky and
there's the clavinet
and then the sort of main theme,
(mimics theme music)
is almost giallo-esque.
(funky synthesizer music)
So it's sort of like you get
very European on top with the,
with the women going, "Da, da,"
and the synth actually going
(mimics synthesizer music),
but underneath you get
(mimics credit music),
so it's like on top he thinks
he's like Ennio Morricone,
but he really feels
like he's Stevie Wonder.
And I kind of like, it's a fun theme.
(funky synthesizer music)
And two, the two movies Jack Arnold made
before this were Blaxploitation films.
So bringing the funk into this theme.
- [Rob] What a career,
what a career, you know?
- [Dan] What a career!
- [Rob] Good for you, yeah.
- [Dan] Yeah, that's, yeah,
that's so, so that is, I,
I don't think I have anything
more to say, I mean, I could-
- [Rob] That's "The Swiss
Conspiracy", everybody,
that's, it's, it was a fun watch.
I was really, realty thrilled
that Film Masters would
ask you and I to do this.
I, I had not seen this film before
and I had so much fun researching it
and watching it multiple times, trying
to figure out the plot and failing
and just being like, "That's
fine, I'm okay with that."
But, man, it was just a blast doing this
with you, Dan, this this was a fun time.
- [Dan] Yeah, it was a great time, Rob,
and I hope y'all enjoyed it
and the movie's ending and go back
and watch it again with all we've said.
Go back and watch it again.
You'll, you'll be glad you did.
Thanks for listening everyone.
- [Rob] Long live physical media.
(funky synthesizer music)