[Waves crashing]
[Mysterious piano music]
But you don't seriously expect me
to lug all these, do you?
What if they want to do
a book signing or something?
Well, they have bookshops in Canada...
And running water and electricity.
It never hurts to do
a little promotion.
I'm going to a university degree ceremony,
not to a book launch.
Well,
thanks for your enthusiasm.
A man of your age
has to look out for himself.
Now, stop that, and don't try
and make me feel guilty.
I’ve asked you to come with me
I don't know how many times...
And nobody packs a case
like good old Alice.
Well...
I'll wait for your call.
[Hums]
- [Door slams]
- Bye, Alice!
[Moody jazz music]
[Airplane engine noise]
[Seagull squeals]
[Footsteps approaching]
You're not wearing the
same shirt two days in a row.
It's a new school, Maria.
I like this shirt.
So did I, yesterday.
Now, go upstairs and change.
ls he coming today?
Go upstairs and change, please.
Now.
- [Moody piano music]
- [Seagulls squealing]
Maria, you're driving me crazy.
Maybe you'd like to help me?
Here. Give me the goddamn ball.
[Door closing]
[Suitcase slams] All right, I’m sorry.
ls that what you want?
I’m sorry we had to move.
I’m sorry about your father.
I'm just sorry about everything.
ls that what you want?
Why don't you be of some help
and just take this up to your room.
It's not my room.
My room had wallpaper.
Right.
[Melancholic piano music]
[Driver] This is the
address you gave me.
I know.
Well, you getting out, or what?
Yes, in a minute.
It's just I’ve traveled
7,000 miles to get here.
You keep the meter running
if you want.
You must be Emile. Hi.
I’m Nadia.
Oh, sorry,
we were expecting you earlier.
Oh, I took the ferry from Vancouver.
I wanted to see the islands.
[Sigh]
I couldn't bear another plane
after nine and a half hours from London.
- Oh, can I help?
- No, no. I have it.
- Come on in.
- Thank you.
This is for you.
Oh, thank you.
I think you might find it of interest,
and this is for the little one.
- [Emile laughs]
- Thank you.
It's such a wonderful crossing
on the ferry.
The air is...
I ought to get away more often.
You should.
London, you know, it's so crowded,
and there's so much traffic.
[Sighs] It's such hard work
to get anywhere.
Well, I am sorry that
I was so late arriving,
and I'm sorry that
you had to wait up.
I--I'm usually up.
And what about the rest?
Are they-- are they sleeping?
Oh, it's just Maria and I.
What about your husband? Uh, j--
- Jacob.
- Jacob, yes.
Uh, we split.
That's-- that's why... I moved.
Oh, I see.
As a matter of fact,
I’ve just moved myself. Yes.
Can be overwhelming, can't it?
It's so hard to know what to do next,
and I can hardly bring myself
to begin to unpack. [Chuckles]
- [Eerie piano music]
- [Wind whooshing]
You look so like your mother...
And...
It's very kind of you to have me to stay,
especially under the circumstances,
and my letter coming
out of the blue like that...
Sure.
And i--I’m sorry that I...
I haven't been more in touch.
I--i wanted to.
Look, [clears throat]
I’ve gotta get up early in the morning,
so I’m gonna head up to bed.
You can just make
yourself feel comfortable,
and I'll see you in the morning.
- [Emile] Well, thank you. Good night.
- Good night.
Oh!
[Sighs]
- [Melancholic piano music]
- [Rain drops spattering]
[Old jazzy music starts playing]
If you wanna be a writer,
you've gotta get started.
This should really be Freddy's.
He's the writer.
Freddy's mechanical.
I need him here with me.
He's the only one
who can fix things...
When he's not lazing around
on his ass.
Why is this place so important?
It's our land.
It's the only thing we've got.
You know, when the old man died, he made me
swear to take care of this place.
I can't do it alone.
But you could just let it go.
I know Freddy wouldn't mind.
Freddy loves this place
as much as I do.
It's wonderful. It really is.
[Mellow piano music starts]
What are you writing?
Will you read it to me?
Stars...
- Hang on a sec. It's not done yet.
- Oh, you. You're always saying that.
- I just wanna hear it.
- Well, I...
I’m not quite sure
how to read this out loud.
Um, uh...
Well, I'm sure nobody else is gonna be
able to read your handwriting. Come on.
Read it.
I’m sure I'll like it.
Just... try not to worry too
much about the form, because--
Freddy, read it.
I can't believe you guys
are still dicking around.
And why is my
truck not finished?
Huh, Freddy?
Stony liquid has infected
your heart, Carl.
Stop with the fucking bullshit,
and get your ass outside.
Coming?
Yeah, I’m just...
[Mellow piano music continues]
- 'Morning.
- Good morning.
How did you sleep?
Well, not too well, my dear,
but I suppose it takes a few
days to adjust, doesn't it?
- Would you like some tea?
- I would adore some tea, yes, thank you.
Yeah, I’m not much of a sleeper either,
with or without jet-lag.
[Emile] Yes, well...
It can be difficult, can't it,
adjusting to a new situation.
I’m certainly finding that,
you know, now that I've retired.
My London flat is disorganized,
and Alice is determined to
sort it out for me, of course.
Is Alice your girlfriend?
Good lord, no. No, no,
she's just my assistant, but...
Has been forever, really.
Oh.
I’m gonna boil myself an egg.
Would you like one?
I would. I'd adore an egg, yes.
Thank you.
Four minutes, would you?
If it's not too much trouble.
No trouble.
So did you find anything
of interest in that box?
Sorry?
My father's box.
I saw the typewriter was out.
Oh, the typewriter, yes. Yes,
I recognized that old thing.
You want it?
I?
The typewriter.
I mean, we have no need for it.
- It's yours if you want it.
- No, you must keep it.
You know, Carl bought it,
you know?
Yes.
Yes, your father bought
that typewriter.
- Uh, what do you need?
- Uh, so-- sorry, milk.
Uh, the top left.
We only have soy.
Ooh, yes.
What's the matter?
You don't have soy milk in england?
No, no, that's not it. No, no,
I'm just curious about the packaging.
Soybeans are amongst the most common
genetically modified species,
and I’m just wondering--
in Canada,
ARE YOU OBLIGED TO PUT SOMETHING
ABOUT GMOs ON THE PACKAGING?
WHAT ARE GMOs?
- Genetically modified organisms.
- Oh, I wouldn't know.
Oh, god. How does this open?
Why don't you just
pretend you're a guest,
sit down,
and I'll wait on you.
- Thank you.
- Here you are.
I’ve got...
Here's today's paper.
Oh, thank you very much indeed.
THE COLONIST. [LAUGHS]
The colonist...
All of this science
and development,
and here we are, still on
the brink of extinction.
Corporate greed and our
desperate desire for more oil,
that'll be our undoing.
It's--we'll kill everyone,
and we'll call it
"the fight for freedom."
So what, you're anti-technology?
No, I'm not anti-technology.
No, I’m more... pro-ecology.
It's all in the book.
Uh, what book?
- The one I gave you.
- [Gasps] Oh, it's your book?
It's not actually a new book.
It's more of a reprinting of something
I came out with some time ago.
It's actually the basis of my...
Master's thesis.
It's about organic farming and a particular
strain of wheat that's been very robust.
Yes. Quite a best-seller in...
Some circles.
- What are you laughing at?
- Nothing.
You should read it.
[Chuckles] Oh yes, yes. Easy to tell
you're a professor, that's all.
Oh.
Oh, was I lecturing you?
Uh, so when is the ceremony?
Uh, Saturday, Saturday evening,
and I hope you might come.
Maybe. I-- I...
I mean, it's a mess.
I don't know if
I wanna leave Maria alone.
Well, no, it's hardly a ceremony
for a babe in arms. [Laughs]
- She's 1 0.
- 1 0?
- I thought she was a baby. I--
- nope.
I brought her
that little fluffy... toy.
[Stutters] It's a good thing...
1 0-year-old girls
like fluffy little toys.
[Keys rattling]
[Bell dings]
- Why are you sitting out here?
- Heh, wonderfully brisk, isn't it?
Yeah, but you'll catch a cold.
It's quite damp. Here.
Thank you.
I... just thought I'd put it
to some use before you threw it out.
[Nadia] Right. You'll...
- You'll probably need this then.
- Thank you.
Anyway, I have to step out
for a couple of hours,
so if you wanna go
for a walk or anything,
there's a spare set of keys on the mantel.
Just lock up behind you.
Maria's got her own set,
so she can let herself in...
- Sure.
- ...And I'll see you later.
Hmm.
[Car door closing]
[Car engine starts]
[Moody jazz music]
[Birds chirping]
[Typewriter keys clicking]
[Melancholic cello music]
[Music fades]
Oh, hello.
Your mother's gone out.
I expect she'll be back soon.
I’m Emile, your great-uncle.
Great-uncle Emile.
Don't suppose you've
seen one of these before?
It's a typewriter.
Found it upstairs.
Your mother wants to throw it out, but...
I’m very fond of the old thing.
There's a lot of history
in a machine like this.
I... um, I'm just staying
for a short while.
I’m going to get a degree,
an honorary degree
at the university.
I'm a scientist.
Do you like science?
No need, really.
Hey.
How's it going?
This is 62 Wellington, yeah?
ls it? Eh, yes, I think it is.
Yeah. I’m just gonna grab some
supplies, dump 'em in the yard,
maybe you could let the lady know
I'll be back in a bit to get started.
Yes, yes, all right.
- Hi. What's all this?
- [Tom] Hey.
It's, uh... painting gear.
For...
Painting your house.
Uh, I’m Tom.
Oh, well, Tom, I didn't hire
a painting company, so...
Oh, well, I’ve got the paperwork
right here.
I'm supposed to get started
right away, supposedly.
According to who?
Um, guy's name...
From Vancouver--
Jacob something. There you go.
Here's the invoice.
Well, I don't want the
fucking house painted.
What about my contract?
I don't know.
Talk to the guy that hired you.
Well, I did talk to him.
He asked me to paint your house.
Well, he's not paying for me.
If you don't mind me saying so,
you know, I’ve taken a good look, and i--
I’m thinking it could use
a little fix-up.
I didn't ask for your opinion,
and I certainly don't need
any favors from anyone,
especially my ex-husband,
thank you very much.
Well, I’ve got an idea.
You could pay for it,
and then no one would be
doing you a favor, would they?
Could you just get your stuff
and get out of here?
Okay, just back up a second.
Seriously, like, I turned down
other work for this job.
Now, you know, give me
a fucking break. Come on.
- I'll do it myself.
- No, no, no, no.
Don't touch my gear.
I just asked you
to get your shit and leave.
Um, perhaps you should leave.
Oh, I can handle this.
Thank you.
You got five minutes to get off
this property, or I’m calling the cops.
Contract's a contract.
I'm keeping the dough.
I'm gonna miss this place.
Well, that's because you got
most of the easy jobs around here.
England...
It's long ways away.
I really don't know
if I deserve it.
I think you have more talent
than you give yourself credit for.
I don't know that that's true.
I don't think this farm
will ever let me go.
You love it here...
Just like Carl.
[Paper ripping]
Don't do that. [Sighs]
Don't ruin it.
You were a beautiful writer.
I remember I couldn't always
decipher everything.
I used to look at your notebooks
while you were sleeping.
You wrote on the
edge of the paper,
you just kept
scribbling everything out...
[Sighs] As if you'd...
Stop breathing if you didn't
get your ideas onto the page.
I never had your gift.
I just never did.
You should have been
the one to leave.
[Paper ripping]
[Melancholic cello music]
[Nadia] We have company.
[Sighs] Mmm, no.
Not for three days. No.
No, of course...
It doesn't need anything.
No! I’m not gonna have
this conversation right now.
Hold on-- Maria, your father
wants to have a word with you.
There's nothing
wrong with this house.
[Maria] Hi.
I left the window open,
for Christ's sake.
She told her father
the roof was leaking.
You can tell him to call back later.
We have company.
No, yeah, I’m fine.
Yeah.
Okay, just hold on a second.
He wants to talk to you.
Excuse me.
No, that's not what she said.
I don't need your help,
I didn't need your help
I didn't ask for it...
Do you like school?
I wasn't much good at school
when I was your age.
Of course, it was different.
Where I grew up...
Not many people around.
Did you know I had to walk six miles
every morning just to get to school?
This was in saskatchewan.
That's where I was born.
Do you know where that is?
Of course, it wasn't that long ago,
but, you know, out there in the winter,
ooh, and the prairies...
Very difficult to get anywhere.
Horses, they were--
it was better to use horses
than go in a car, [laughs]
And then when the drifts
got really high,
then it was impossible to go
to school at all, and we didn't.
Think of that.
I know I don't sound
as if I come from saskatchewan,
or anywhere in Canada
for that matter,
but that's because
I speak the queen's English.
I’m, I’m just as Canadian
as you are,
like queen Elizabeth, queen of england.
Well, she's queen of Canada as well.
You know, she's on the stamp,
and she's on the coins,
and... she's head of state,
after all,
which is why I sound as Canadian
as the queen of england. [Laughs]
Hey. Did you excuse yourself?
- Excuse me.
- Thank you.
[Sighs] Sorry.
- Can I get you anything else?
- What? Oh, no, thanks, no.
- That was delicious.
- Oh... no, it wasn't.
It was terrible. Thank you.
Uh...
[Eerie piano music]
[Carl] Why are you always
writing in that goddamn book?
You know, I’ve gotta see
what is so goddamn important
that it takes up all your time,
so... [book slams shut]
You tell me what you're writing,
I'll give you back your little book.
It's just a letter to Emile.
Yeah.
Yeah, you keep writing him.
How many letters
have you gotten back?
[Carl] Hmm?
Yeah, exactly.
Not one.
So...
Why do you keep
wasting your time?
Why are you so miserable?
What, are you, are you sick?
What?
You hardly even talk anymore!
[Freddy] I miss him.
[Carl] You miss him?
What, you think I don't miss him?
He's my brother, too. You act like
he's your fucking girlfriend!
Just... fucking leave me alone,
please.
Listen how fucking
pathetic you are.
You're fucking disgusting.
You fucking asshole!
[Door slamming]
I meant to write you.
I really did.
I never knew he
treated you like that,
and what could
I have done at the time?
Someone had to stay.
Someone had to take care
of the place.
I never knew.
I’m sorry.
[Dishes clanking]
What can I get you?
Well, I just wondered
if there's anything I could do.
No.
Well, thanks for dinner again.
You're welcome.
Look, I’m sorry if my visit
comes at an awkward time.
I couldn't possibly
have known about Jacob.
No, it's fine.
I can stay in a hotel,
if that would...
Look, you can do what you want.
I’m the one who asked you to come.
If you don't wanna stay here,
that's fine.
[Melancholic piano music]
[Alarm ringing]
- You all right?
- [Emile laughing]
Yes, I'm sorry.
Uh, you're, um...
Welcome to-- to turn
that on if you want.
It gets a bit chilly in here.
I don't think the thermostat's working.
The furnace is pretty old.
Well, you should get it fixed.
Well, I don't know anyone.
We just moved, so...
Well, what about
that painting fellow?
He seems quite handy.
That's true.
I should probably call him anyway.
I was... pretty rude.
Did you know my mother?
Well, uh... not well.
I admired her a great deal.
Your father was a lucky man.
[Melancholic piano music]
I don't know anything
about my family,
just what's in a few boxes.
- It's not much.
- Mm-hmm.
I guess my grandma must have
packed these up after the accident.
There was some newspaper
clippings on the top.
It's what they sent
to the orphanage.
Well, they called it "the home,"
which is kind of funny,
cause it wasn't supposed to be my home.
It was...
I wasn't supposed to be there very long,
just till you came.
I didn't mind it at first.
They were all very nice to me,
very kind.
They told me all about you,
how they tracked you down in england
and contacted you, and...
You were...
Supposed to be there
soon to pick me up,
take me with you.
Sometimes,
if I couldn't sleep at night,
I’d even imagine myself as one of
those kids in those books, you know,
with you in one of those dusty,
old libraries,
and secret passages,
places to hide,
visits to the castles in the summertime,
I don't know...
But you never came.
I’m sorry.
[Nadia] Are you?
Cause I am.
I really am...
Well, you seem like a pretty nice guy,
and I could try and like you, but...
I don't trust people,
and you did that to me.
I mean, I'm sure
you have your reasons, but...
I don't really care to know what they are.
I just wanted you to know that...
There was a little girl
waiting for you
a long time ago...
And you left her waiting...
And she's gone.
[Melancholic cello music]
Did you do that on purpose?
- Sorry, didn't see you.
- What are you doing? You're nuts?
Hey, you've got a pickup,
don't you?
Yeah.
[Sigh] Would you mind running these
down to the dump for me?
- Why? What's wrong with your car?
- I’ve got 1 0 more. They won't fit.
It'll cost you.
Don't push your luck.
I hired you, didn't I?
I don't know why
I hold on to all this shit.
I shouldn't have come.
I’m sorry.
- I thought it would be different.
- How?
- What do you mean?
- How would it be different?
Oh... I don't know.
I just wanted to
meet you and Maria.
Oh. Well, you did.
What do you think?
- I don't know.
- What did you expect?
Well, I’m not sure.
Look, I’m sorry, Nadia.
Sorry for what?
God forbid you'd actually
stick around and get to know us.
- Do you want me to leave?
- Why did you come?
- I came to see you.
- No, you didn't.
You came here for a stupid award.
Maria and I were just an excuse.
That's not true.
[Mellow piano music]
I don't understand what's so
special about this stupid truck.
- What is a fan belt?
- I've come to say goodbye.
You know he makes me replace
something just about every week,
whether he needs it or not,
just to satisfy some
goddamn obsession.
Freddy...
I've come to say goodbye.
Yeah. Hey,
don't get yourself dirty, all right?
I'll be done in a sec.
You can throw your stuff
in the back.
I'll be back.
Yeah.
You know I will.
[Car engine running]
Hey. Need some help?
You know, when I was younger,
I was so good with engines.
On a farm, of course, a farmer's
gotta be able to fix everything.
My brother, my younger brother,
he was the mechanic.
Everything worked on
that farm because of him.
Hmm.
Nothing he couldn't fix.
Taught me everything I know...
Knew. [Chuckles]
- So, can you hear it?
- Yeah.
- It's idling oddly, isn't it?
- Here, let me, yeah?
Oh, please.
[Engine turning over]
Oh.
You've done that before.
Yeah, I’ve been around engines
my whole life.
- Thank you for that.
- No problem.
I should actually
get back to work.
She's not gonna be too happy
with the progress I’ve been making.
- Will you let me help?
- Oh, no, that's okay. I’ve got it.
No, I insist.
I want to do something useful.
Obviously, my mechanical skills
are a bit rusty, so...
- Please, put me to work.
- Yeah, yeah, okay.
Yeah, I could use a little hand.
I was gonna get going
on these posts here...
[Sander swishing]
- There's that one.
- Yes.
You know, we used to have to
paint our house in the prairies,
oh, once a year.
There was very little shelter
from the elements, and so...
The buildings would blister
in the sun in the summer
and peel in the wind and
the snow in the winter.
I have not done
this for a long time.
Aha.
Have you ever done this before?
No.
You want to try? Hmm?
Yeah. You just hold that.
Dip it in the paint,
once or twice.
Now, lift it up,
and don't let it drip.
Lift it up. Good, good,
and then just roll it gently
onto the surface there. Good.
Good!
Well done. [Claps]
Look, I’ve got a helper.
[Laughs]
Very good. Good.
- Oh, no!
- Shit.
- Never mind, never mind.
- It's okay. I'll get it. I'll get it.
Ah, shit.
I’m not paying you
to paint the sidewalk, I hope.
- Sorry about that.
- It's all my fault. No, I, i--
I splattered this paint rather
carelessly on the stairs,
and gallant Tom
came to the rescue.
Well, they didn't have any cold ones,
so I'll put the rest in the fridge.
- Excuse me.
- Thanks.
You guys are painting in the rain.
You're idiots.
It just started raining.
Hey, sweetheart.
- Cheers.
Strange woman.
- Yes.
- Is she your daughter?
Uh, no, no, niece, niece.
She always been like that?
Well, I'm only just
getting to know her myself.
Yeah, you and me both.
It's okay, don't worry about it.
Don't cry over spilled paint.
[Audience laughing on TV]
What are you doing?
I thought you had homework.
I thought maybe we could take
Emile for a drive before dinner.
I’d like you to come.
I don't wanna come.
Well...
You're coming.
I was watching something.
[Doorknob rattling]
[NADIA] MARIA, OPEN UP.
[Knocking]
WHAT'S WRONG WITH
GOING ON A LITTLE DRIVE?
Sweetie?
[Knocking]
- OPEN THE DOOR.
- GO AWAY!
It'd be nice.
It'd be the three of us.
He's your uncle.
He's got nothing to do with me!
- He's your uncle, too.
- I don't care. Go away!
[Hard slams] Open this goddamn door,
or I'll break it down.
- [Slams echoing]
- [Mysterious eerie music]
Are you really my uncle?
I’m your great-uncle.
What's a great-uncle?
Well, he's great, better than
an ordinary uncle. [Laughs]
Very funny.
Well, a great-uncle is
the brother of your grandfather.
- So you're my grandfather's brother?
- Yes, that's right.
What was his name?
Carl.
Did he die or something?
Yes, a long time ago.
Is that why my mom
never talks about him?
Well, yes,
she was very young at the time,
long time ago.
- You're not going to wash your hands?
- Beg your pardon?
Don't you think
you should wash your hands?
Oh. [Laughs]
Yes, I suppose so.
Yes, silly of me.
Thank you.
[Eerie music]
[FREDDY ECHOING] THAT MAY
BE THE LAST BIT OF WORK YOU DO.
Well, writing's
a different sort of work.
Oh, really?
Well, I guess
you would know, hmm?
You're the scholar.
I'm just the common laborer.
That is not what I meant.
No, of course not.
It's simply that at university,
I'll not be doing a lot of manual work.
[Scoffs] You sound
like an old man.
Would you get out of here?
[Maria] Sorry.
No, I'm... no, I'm sorry.
I must have been
talking to myself.
How come you came here?
Well, I came to get an honorary
degree at the university,
but really, I just wanted to
see your mother and to meet you.
But what if we hadn't
moved here from Vancouver?
Oh, well, then I would've...
Stayed in Vancouver
and seen you there.
Vancouver is so cool
compared to this place.
- Oh, it seems very nice here.
- It's boring.
It's the retirement
capital of the world.
[Laughing]
What's so funny?
Some people say that
getting an honorary degree
is like getting
a retirement gift.
- See? What did I tell you?
- Mm-hmm.
You're right, Maria.
So my mom wants
to go for a drive.
Oh, but driving around
can be very dull.
Wasn't any mention made
as far as stopping for
ice cream or beaver tails?
Beaver tails?
Yes, they're those great,
big doughnuts, really,
you know, covered in cinnamon
and lemon juice, sugar.
- Mm, they're awfully good.
- I said I wasn't going.
You don't want to go?
Do you?
Well, I'd go if we could
stop for beaver tails.
- Then I guess I'll go, too.
- Good!
Well, then, I’m gonna get ready,
and I'll see you downstairs.
[Emile] Mm...
- Good?
- [Maria] Mm-hmm.
Shall we sit down here?
You know, when your mother gets back,
we should go and find the beach
where the big ships pass
through the channel.
It's marvelous watching large
ships drifting by on the horizon.
You know, when I was young,
there was a man from Finland
who missed his home so much
that he built a ship...
Right in the middle
of the prairies.
ls that true?
Yes, of course it's true.
A huge wooden sailing vessel,
identical to the ones
that he remembered
from the fishing village
where he came from.
What was he going to do with it?
Well, he dreamt of
using the river system
all the way up to the Great Lakes,
and then...
Through the St. Lawrence
and then across the Atlantic
back to Europe.
Did he ever make the trip?
No, I’m afraid not.
Why not?
He died...
Before the ship was finished.
That's sad.
Yes, it was.
There are a lot of people
who went a bit crazy
out there on the prairies.
It can be pretty lonely.
[Melancholic piano music]
- [Engine running]
- [Breathing heavily]
[Coughing]
Freddy?
[Glass rattling]
[Emile grunting]
[Slamming on glass]
[Cars zooming by]
Should we take Emile
to the park?
I wanna go to the beach.
Why do you suddenly
wanna go to the beach?
Well, perhaps we might see
some ships.
[Mellow piano music]
[Laughing]
- [Waves crashing]
- [Seagulls squawking]
Oh!
- Ow!
- [Maria] Are you all right?
Oh, yes, i-- oh.
I'll just sit here for a moment.
I'll be fine.
- I think we need to get you home.
- No, nonsense, no.
I just tripped, that's all.
I'll be fine.
Are you sure?
Maybe you should rest tonight.
Look, I just tripped.
I'll be perfectly fine in a moment.
A man your age shouldn't be running
around on these rocks anyway.
Oh, would you stop talking about me
as if I belong in some museum?
[Laughs]
- Here--
- I tripped, that's all.
Well, you just sit here. I'm gonna go
get the car. I'll be right back.
ls it hard getting old?
I told you, I'm not old.
You're older than me.
- Well, how old are you?
- 1 0.
And what does it feel like,
being 1 0?
I don't know. Fine, I guess.
Well, now,
I'll tell you a secret.
It isn't how old you are
on the outside that matters.
It's how old you feel
on the inside...
And do you how old
I feel on the inside?
No.
I'm 1 0 years old, just like you.
- Really?
- Yes, really.
But on the outside,
what's the hardest
thing about getting old?
All those things
you haven't managed to do.
[Waves crashing]
[Water running]
[Door opening]
- Hey. What do you need?
- [Tom] Hi.
Nothing. I just came to let you know
I'm packing in for the day.
- Oh. How far did you get?
- Pretty far.
I should be able to finish it up
tomorrow or next day at the latest.
Any luck with the furnace?
Oh, yeah. Put a new filter in there.
It's blowing like a chinook now.
Well, great.
Can I get you a beer?
Yeah.
So how much do I owe you?
Uh, you can pay me when I’m done.
We'll talk about it.
Just so you know,
I'll be counting the hours.
[Chuckles] Of course you will.
- But thanks.
- You're welcome. Thank you.
Let me get that for you.
Cheers.
What brought you here?
You've got family here or what?
- My grandma was born here.
- Hmm.
Smells like grandma's
doing a little cooking.
Hey, you're welcome to join us.
No, no, no, no.
No, I don't wanna impose.
- I didn't mean that.
- No, no, you wouldn't be imposing.
I, uh-- well,
we're having an early dinner.
I wasn't sure what time
you were gonna finish up.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Pasta? Sure.
Okay.
Maybe I'll just fly home and...
- Clean up a bit.
- Okay.
See you in, uh...
I don't know, half an hour?
Yeah, I just live up the road.
We're neighbours.
Oh.
[Door closing]
- [Video game beeping]
- [Emile laughing]
Maria, take that computer inside and
finish your homework upstairs, please.
I don't have any.
I was just showing
uncle Emile how it works.
Well, stop bothering him.
He's got his speech to finish, honey.
She's not a bother.
You can come inside
and help me set the table.
Did you hear me?
When I ask you to do something,
please do it.
I’m sure you don't ignore
your teachers like that.
I’m not asking you twice.
[Door shuts]
Should we do it together?
Here.
Set a fourth place.
Tom's gonna join us for dinner.
You mean Tom the painter?
Yes, Tom the painter.
What for?
Because I invited him.
I’m not sure that
I can stay for supper.
I thought the ceremony
wasn't until 8:00.
Well, that's right,
but you don't think that I would come
half the way across the world
to arrive just 1 5 minutes before.
It's a bit of an ordeal,
you know.
I wouldn't know.
I don't wanna insult
the university people
by arriving late,
and they're sending a car...
Well, maybe I can just
start the meal with you.
[Knocking]
Come in.
Ah.
Now, careful with that.
It's very hot.
Are you excited?
Not really, no.
Why not? You should be.
Hmm? Yes, I suppose you're right.
You don't win awards every day,
you know.
Well, this is a degree,
my dear, not an award.
Well, you don't get degrees
every day either,
and some people
never win anything.
Yes, you're right.
Here, let me help you with that.
There. Much better.
Yes, well, thank you. Yes!
Well, my shirt is very grateful.
My dad can't iron
his shirt either.
Uh-huh.
Do you get to see your dad?
[Sighs] Not so far.
I'm supposed to spend
some weekends over there.
Oh, that'll be nice.
I think my mom hates him.
I don't think I'm ever
getting back there to see him.
Oh, I’m sure you will.
I hate her.
Oh, my dear,
you mustn't say that.
I’m just being honest.
Well, sometimes,
when you're honest, you know,
you can hurt other
people's feelings.
Are you always honest?
- Usually.
- Really?
Well, I might tell a little lie,
to try and get out of something
that I didn't really want to do.
[Melancholic piano music]
So it's okay to
lie once in a while?
I’m not sure I'm the right
person to answer that.
- Have you told a lot of lies?
- Not a lot.
Please, sit down.
Thank you.
Well, it's a bit of a relief
finding you.
I didn't think Nadia had
any relatives living,
and if we had known earlier,
we would have contacted you.
I've been living in england.
Why didn't you contact us?
Well, I had no idea
where she was.
I assumed that she was still
living with her mother's... family.
They took her in, you know,
as a baby, after the accident.
Well, her grandmother has died,
and she's all alone,
except for you.
Sorry to hear that.
Do you have
any children of your own?
No, no.
Do you have any
experience with children?
Well, no, not really.
Why do you ask?
Standard questions.
I feel like I'm
being interrogated
or interviewed. [Laughs]
Well, what makes you think
you can raise her?
Oh... [laughs]
No, I'm here to
rent out my farmland.
I--i just thought it was an
opportunity to look in on her.
[Stutters] I have no intention
of taking her away with me.
Oh.
Single-parent families are
not allowed on our campus.
It's as simple as that.
Well, I’m afraid
I've misunderstood, then.
[Melancholic piano music]
[Whispers echoing]
[NADIA] MARIA?
Come on.
I think it's time for dinner.
Did you hear me?
Yes, I heard you. We're coming!
Well, your car will be here soon.
It's getting late.
[Emile] Yes,
I'll be along in a minute.
What's taking him so long?
ls he all right?
We were talking.
Oh.
Well, you're gonna make him late,
and dinner's ready.
- I wanna go.
- Where?
To the award ceremony.
What do you think?
You've got school tomorrow,
and Tom's here.
You mean Tom, the guy who's
slopping paint all over our house?
That's not very nice.
Why can't we go?
We're not gonna have this
conversation right now.
Now, get downstairs.
[Nadia sighs]
So maybe if Tom's not
busy next weekend,
we can do something
with your room.
Great.
[Doorbell ringing]
Hmm. That will be my taxi.
- I'd better go.
- I’m coming.
Where do you think you're going?
Hey, Maria?
You get back here, young lady.
Maria, perhaps you should
listen to your mother!
I'm going.
I’m going with uncle Emile,
and nobody's gonna stop me.
I'll be with her.
It'll be all right.
Where is it, anyway?
University auditorium--
it's the main hall.
You don't have to worry.
I'm sure it'll be fine.
[Emile] Do up your seatbelt.
[Melancholic piano music]
[Sighs]
Ah, she'll be all right.
How would you know?
Just trying to help.
I don't need your help.
You don't spend a lot of time
with people, do you?
I don't need any advice
about my daughter.
Well, fair enough.
I'm just saying she'll
probably be all right.
You know, I think...
I think the old guy
will look after her.
Well, he's not responsible for her.
I am.
Where are you going?
Oh, I'm gonna go to
the goddamn ceremony.
[Keys jingle]
Hey, listen, you don't have to leave.
I'll be coming right back.
You want me to stick
around and do the dishes?
- Sorry.
- It's all right.
I'll be back tomorrow,
finish up the work for you.
- Thank you.
- Thanks for dinner.
Right.
[Mellow piano music]
[Engine choking]
My car won't start.
- Yeah, I noticed that.
- Why are you smiling?
Well, I just-- I saw your uncle
tweaking it the other day.
Can I have a lift, please?
Mm-hmm.
Thank you.
I’m awfully glad
you're coming to this 'do.
It wouldn't have been
much fun on my own.
Can we go to that place
in saskatchewan sometime?
Oh, maybe your mother
will take you one day.
But I want you to take me.
I have not been for, ooh, years.
- Because you live in england?
- Yes!
- Do you have your own family in england?
- Oh, no.
- Then why do you live there?
- Well, it's my home.
I’ve lived there for 40 years.
[Chuckles]
Well, where's your family?
Well, you're my family...
- You and your mother.
- That's it?
Yes, I'm afraid so.
Then you should come
and live here with us.
[Emile chuckles]
[Melancholic piano music]
[Applause echoing]
- [Brakes squealing]
- [Vehicle crashing]
[Sighs]
[Crowd applauding]
It was always humiliating
being your younger brother.
Half the time, you spoke to me
as if I were your son.
I hated your condescension.
Why didn't you say something?
Why didn't you talk to me?
How was I supposed
to know how you felt?
As if I could say
anything to you.
You were a bastard.
It's so pathetic to stand here
and listen to you
cast around for
someone to blame.
I hate you.
I always hated you.
That's fine.
[Announcer] We'd like to
present you with this degree...
For all your contributions.
[Applause]
Thank you very much. Thank you.
Madam chancellor,
vice-chancellor,
thank you.
I'm just so overwhelmed today.
[Melancholic piano music]
Occasions like this
Mark our lives, all our lives.
WHETHER WE'RE YOUNG PEOPLE...
Receiving a degree for which
we have worked very hard indeed,
or an old man like
myself receiving a degree
for which he didn't
have to do anything...
You never took care of Nadia,
you coward.
We're all reminded of
the events and the people...
Who brought us to this place,
to this moment.
You never had the guts
to see her.
YEAR AFTER YEAR,
SHE LIVED ALONE AND MISERABLE.
Hey, Carl...
Go easy on him.
He's wasted everything.
So often, we waste
an opportunity like this.
We struggle alone
most of the time,
and then we forget to thank
those who helped us,
those who supported us,
those who were there for us,
even when we were
crabby and ungrateful,
or perhaps even when we...
Neglected our responsibilities.
[Melancholic music continues]
You're a coward.
There's nothing
cowardly about loving her.
He doesn't deserve her love.
I deserve a chance, a chance...
To... speak from the heart.
This honorary degree
is a rather belated
acknowledgment
for a thesis I first published,
oh, so many years ago now
that it seems to be from
an entirely separate time...
OF MY LIFE.
I’ve spent now many
years living abroad,
and now,
on this long-delayed return,
I’ve begun to understand
that time and distance...
Cannot ever erase my memories of
nor my need for...
The family that...
I left behind...
And, in a sense, betrayed.
[Baby fussing]
[Music fades]
Madam chancellor,
your generous invitation to this occasion
has restored me to this family.
My niece, Nadia,
and my great-niece, Maria.
I'll never stop thanking Maria
and her mother
and you all.
[Applause]
[Uplifting piano music]
[Nadia] Hey, come here, you.
Congratulations, professor.
Thank you.
[Mellow piano music]
You okay?
You ready?
You're gonna miss your train.
When you leave tomorrow...
You're not coming back, are you?
Can you just promise me
that one day...
You'll come back.
Just promise me.
[EMILE] MY DEAR NADIA,
IT'S NOT MUCH,
BUT IT'S THE LEAST I CAN OFFER.
YOU CAN DO WHATEVER
YOU WANT WITH IT.
I'M CERTAIN THE LAND
IS QUITE VALUABLE NOW,
SO AT THE VERY LEAST,
IT WILL MEAN SOME MONEY
FOR YOU AND MARIA...
OR YOU MAY WANT TO REBUILD THE HOUSE
AS A PLACE YOU CAN GET AWAY TO,
BUT WHATEVER YOU DECIDE,
YOU SHOULD KNOW
THAT YOU WERE BORN
IN THAT PLACE.
IF YOU DECIDE TO KEEP IT,
LET ME KNOW.
I PROMISED MARIA
I'D COME TO VISIT.
ALL THE BEST,
EMILE.
[Melancholic piano music]