[narrator]: Once upon a time,
there was a young man
who lived a very exciting life.
The problem was,
it was all in his head.
[singing religious hymn]
And when he tried
to put words on it,
it always slipped away.
So he began prowling
in the darkness
of other people's lives.
He meant no harm,
but he was very gentle.
And, of course,
he didn't call it prowling.
For him, it was just... knowing.
Then one night,
he heard a sad song.
It was soft, like the breeze
on his hands and his face.
And he saw...
a woman,
walking about a glass house,
singing.
"There's a certain slant
of light winter afternoons"
"that oppresses"
"like the heft
of cathedral tombs."
- She was sort of like a bird.
- She was sort of like, uh...
far away in the sky,
kind of... flying, sort of.
Sort of flying, kind of flying,
sort of flying.
"When it comes
the landscape glistens."
"Shadows hold their breath."
"When it goes
it's like the distance"
"on the look of Death."
"The heavenly hurt it gives us."
"Solitude"
"a whiteness"
"where the meanings are."
"A nearness to tremendousness"
[typewriting]
[narrator]: He tried
not to come back.
Night after night.
After night.
-Ow...
[narrator]: And slowly,
Norman the Gentle
slipped into the darker side
of curiosity.
He was not alone.
[screaming]
- No!
Nooo!
No!
No! Noooo!
-God...
Oh, my God...
[screams echoing]
God. I saw a woman
and she's, uh...
Beaumont Street.
And... I didn't do anything.
I didn't do anything.
Almighty Father,
creator of Heaven and Earth,
I beseech thee.
Please forgive me
for I’ve sinned against you.
-A little something
for your writing, son.
- Oh, thanks, Dad.
- If you need money, just call.
Jobs don't grow on trees,
Sweetie.
- That's okay, Mother.
- I'll take care of myself.
Bye.
[narrator]: He didn't
tell his parents
what had finally pushed him
out of their perfect blue house
and into life.
And he didn't know
where he was going.
He just set out on his journey
towards honour, action
and, of course, he hoped,
love.
- Hey, hey, hey!
- Would you stop that, you dink?!
-Excuse me?
-That's art!
Jesus! You're worse than
the Sanitation Department.
What's happening here,
in fact, is a happening.
Environmental art.
-Of course. I’m so sorry.
-It resonates.
We rape the environment
to make newsprint,
to write stories about
how we rape each other
and how we rape the environment
and now the papers...
God. It resonates.
-It certainly does.
You know where I can buy
a newspaper?
-Which day, today?
Ummm...
I think over here.
Hey, hey listen, you wouldn't
want a job, would you?
Like, I work here for this guy,
but I’m trying to subcontract
the work out.
You see, I’m really quite
a very talented artist.
- Obviously.
- The last guy got knifed.
-No...
-Well, they think
the thief had a knife.
- I’d be interested.
- Good.
- Yeah.
- Yeah, okay.
Sixty percent for me,
forty for you.
You can report for work
tomorrow, okay?
- Sure.
- Great. Let's find the paper.
Nice suit. Here it is. There.
What?
Oh, yeah.
That. What a bummer.
She was a great,
- great singer.
- Oh, dear God.
-"The suspect in custody
has a history of such attacks."
Oooh, she suffered 17 stab
wounds and a broken neck.
Yuck, that's grim.
They don't say where
the stab wounds were.
She was probably dismembered,
you know. They usually are.
Hmm, what a drag.
Hey. Hey, Bud, what's the story
here? You into this job or what?
-Uh, listen, I’ll be back
tomorrow. Now's not a good time.
-What?
[bell tolling]
-She was...
like a horse.
Horse?
-Dearly beloved,
we are gathered here together
to mourn the passing of one of
the most truly gifted among us.
Her untimely death
was the result of a violent,
virulent cancer that is
creeping across the land.
-Did you know her?
-Our only comfort can be the
belief that beauty does not die.
When it is crushed in one,
it is carried forth in another.
Sometimes only
in the gloriousness
of our expression of grief.
But in the case of
the mysterious Madelaine X,
we have the simplicity
and purity of song
to celebrate her beauty.
[honking]
- Hi.
- Well, look who's here!
Mr. Suit. Huh!
- You going to work?
- Yeah, sure.
- All right, all right.
- Let me show you. Let's see...
Magazines, newspapers,
girlie magazines in the back,
theatre stuff here, movies,
candy, chocolate bars...
Hey! You listening to me?
- Yeah, sure.
- Okay. You got a name?
- Norm.
- As in Norman?
- Just Norm.
- Okay. I’m Zelda.
-Great.
- Okay, make yourself at home.
- Thanks.
-Okay.
[screams echoing]
-No-♩-♩! No-♩-♩!
No-♩-♩-♩!
-Almighty-Ray, that's good,
that's good.
-Yeah, I was thinking about
this story about this guy
- who sees a woman attacked.
- Neat.
- By what?
- Some sicko that followed her.
-And?
-And it could be
sort of powerful.
-And he saves her?
-No, he just stands there,
sort of paralyzed.
And he feels horrible about it.
-Nope, won't work.
Turn right here.
You can't have a wimp
in the middle of a story.
Guys won't identify
and girls won't be attracted.
-He's not a wimp. He's just
really affected by things.
- So what's the point?
- Nothing, really.
Just that the world isn't
a very kind place sometimes.
- Riveting.
- Think so?
-Needs a love interest.
Pull over here.
-You live here?
-Yeah. Come on.
- This is safe here, right?
- Yeah. Come on. It's fine.
-Neato!
- I’m sorry about the mess.
- I'm a bit of a slob.
I bought this book once.
It was called
How To Organize Your Life
and Become Wise and Everything
in Three Easy Steps
but I lost it.
Norm... I want you.
-Zelda, I wasn't
thinking of, uh...
-Of what?
-Of sexual intercourse.
-Oh, you're so cute,
I can't stand it.
Okay, no agenda.
I was just, you know,
trying to work out
the sleeping arrangements.
So let's see... Oh, there.
- That's for you, okay?
- Okay.
-So you're a homo, right?
-Umm...
-No, it's okay, I’m cool.
I mean, I figure some people
like vanilla,
- some people like chocolate.
- I’m not a homo, Zelda.
-Oh.
-Sorry.
- Um, Norm?
- Hm-hm?
-So, uh... what's wrong with me?
-There's nothing wrong with you.
You're very...
you know...
-No.
- Alluring.
- Uh-huh.
-I'm sorry, Zelda.
This love stuff
is pretty complicated.
I once had a... liason
with this girl on our street
and it was beautiful
and everything...
But when it was over,
she'd always say something
really dumb, you know? Like...
about her mascara or some...
It was like a tuba coming in
a measure early.
Not that you're like a tuba.
It's just complicated.
-Well, if you want anything
uncomplicated, Norm,
I’m right here.
And I won't be a tuba.
- Okay.
[She imitates a tuba. ]
[laughing]
-A tuba. That's good.
[faint]: No-♩-♩!
-Hey, it's okay.
It's all right.
Sshhh. It's okay.
[foghorn]
- Zelda, can I tell you a secret?
- I'm your gal.
- I saw Madelaine X once.
- So did I.
On Much Music. She was great.
She was wearing this incred...
-No, I mean I saw her
at her home.
-Over for tea, were ya?
-I just got lost in the area...
I saw her.
-Come on.
Someone like that would be more
protected than the queen.
-Yeah, well a guy got into
the queen's bedroom once.
Nobody's safe.
I’m not even sure if it was her.
-But you could tell
from a photograph, right?
- It was dark.
- It was far away and it was...
I just saw her sort of moving.
- Look it, look it.
- Okay, I got this great idea.
Every station in town's gonna be
collecting footage
on her, right?
Well, I have this very,
very close personal friend
at the station.
It's very close-by.
Hey, Jimmy!
I owe you one.
Love you. Mean it.
"The soul selects her own society"
"and then shuts the door."
"for a nobody"
"till nobody... no more."
-That's her.
-No shit?
-Yeah.
"How dreary to be like somebody."
- There's something wrong, though.
- What?
-Well, her lips aren't in sync
with the music sometimes. See?
-Yeah, that's called
singing to playback.
They all do it for videos.
-That's what she was doing
that night that I saw her.
- She was singing to music.
- Like, she was singing
- to recorded music?
- Yeah.
- Her own?
- 50?
- So her voice was different.
- Huh.
"The soul's a lecture
on society for a nobody"
"for a nobody"
"till nobody... no more."
-Can you ever just go
for a walk?
-No, I'm pretty isolated.
-What is that saying?
"If you can't stand the heat,
get out of the kitchen."
-Well, I can't.
The whole world's a kitchen.
I'd have to fake my own death.
- Fake my own death.
- You know what?
That is really possible.
She could've faked
- this whole thing...
- Zelda, I don't think so.
- Forget that all
of those clapping hands
have fingernails on them
and that there's a, umm...
-Bloodthirstiness?
-Well, that's rather
a strong word.
No, no, I think that...
I think that society
has a sense of balance
and that if you respected
one individual for too long
or if you've liked him
for too long
and that balance
gets out of whack
and there is a need
to hate that individual
to a parallel degree.
I mean, alive or dead, we pull
our icons down eventually.
It's a very strange
pattern we have.
-Well, it's a very grim outlook.
Umm, could somebody call
that paranoid?
-No, it's not paranoid,
ifs just realistic.
You know, there is a price.
-She sure does know
how to work the press.
-Why are you doing
this interview,
if you're so ambivalent
about public life?
-It's my job.
I mean, I like it.
I can't say that I don't
like the attention.
Everybody wants
to be understood.
Well, I'm just observing
that the relationship between
the performer and the press
or the performer
and the observer
is like this strange dance
and we're locked
in some kind of embrace.
It's almost a sexual embrace.
And sometimes I love it
and sometimes it absolutely
terrifies me.
[rewinding]
It's almost a sexual embrace.
And sometimes I love it
and sometimes it absolutely
terrifies me.
[man]: Hey, don't push! Hey!
-Thanks.
Oh, Mother...
- Hello, Norman.
- Hello, Mother.
-I was just around the corner
and... here you are.
-Here I am. Thanks.
-I won't stay long.
We were just worried about you.
-Oh, Mum, you don't have
to worry about me.
I told you I can take
care of myself.
-I know that, dear.
So, this must be your new...
ensemble.
-You forgot your handkerchief.
-Thank you.
-Who's that, dear?
-I don't know. Uh, Mum,
I have got a few things
I’ve gotta go do.
Uh, thanks for the cookies.
They look great.
Uh, tell Dad I’ll give
you guys a call
later on in the week, okay?
Zelda, could you take care
of the news stand for me
- for a little while?
- Oh, okay.
[neighing]
-Oh!
-What are you doing here?
You followed me.
-Yes, I did.
-What do you want?
-To know if you need
any gardening work done?
-Do you always follow
people to their homes
to ask them if they need
gardening work?
-Rarely. I’m sorry. I...
I thought that...
I don't know what I thou...
I was afraid
I wouldn't see you again.
-Do you like me?
-Yes. Well, I mean...
It's hard to say.
I don't even know you.
Umm...
but I do think your lawn
could use a trim.
There's always
the Japanese maple.
Which has the attractive bonus
of fall color.
Or there's the... the "podcar".
Uh... "podpus".
"Podpus". Which makes
a lovely, lacy screen
when planted in rows.
-Do you plan to take out trees?
-Oh, I don't think removal
is the answer.
Well, first of all, did you know
that the root system
of most trees has as much volume
as the exterior branch system?
Interesting, eh?
So, consequently,
I think that removal is, uh...
too radical.
- It's all in the shaping.
- In the shaping.
-So what I was thinking was that
I’d just start on it and, uh...
keep on going until
we decide to stop.
And then stop.
Uh, this means, of course,
that I'll have
to consult with you
on a regular basis.
I don't know if you plan
to be around, or...
-Oh. Yes, I'll be around.
-Well, then, there you go.
Uh, my name is Norm.
-Thanks, Norm.
- Hm-mm.
- Hi.
- Huh!!
- Oh, I am sorry. I am so sorry.
-Don't you do that.
-I...
I was just gonna ask you
about the, uh, the back.
-Don't.
-Okay, fine, fine.
-I don't think this gardening
thing is such a good idea.
-Oh, no, I think
you're very mistaken.
I was just about to ask you
about trimming this hedge,
but we could, uh, make it,
uh, undulating, sort of.
-Undulating?
- Yeah, you know, like waves.
- Could be great, couldn't it?
- Can you do me a favour?
- Sure.
-Can you make sure that no one
comes onto this property?
- Okay.
Are you worried about something?
-Yes, this hedge.
How would we make it undulate?
Doesn't sound very practical.
-Beautiful things
aren't practical.
- Ah, Belinda!
- [cowbell]
Hey, Belinda!
-I mean, it just makes
more sense
for me to kind of
camp out there.
Sure you don't mind, eh?
-No, no, that's fine. It's cool.
By the way, how's the
Madelaine X story coming?
I got your number, Buddy.
You're doing the story
and you're freezing me out,
aren't ya?
-You're imagining things.
-What about that woman?
The one who looks like a horse?
How does she tie in?
-You looked at my stuff.
I don't think that's
very respectful, Zelda.
-That's rich. Respectful?
-Look, I’m sorry
about the news stand job.
It's just not my cup of tea.
But I’ll...
you know, I'll visit.
Oh, by the way,
where's my little tape recorder?
- What recorder?
- Zelda!
-Oh, yeah. It's, um...
It's at the news stand.
-I’ll be back for it. Nice try!
Aren't you hot, Ma'am?
-Jane.
[murmuring ]: I can't believe
how long it's been
since I’ve said that.
Yes, it must be at least
30 degrees out here.
-Excuse me for asking,
but why don't you put on
some cooler clothes?
-I don't have any.
-Yeah, well, it's dangerous
to overheat yourself, you know.
You could make some.
-I’m not a big sewer, Norm.
-Well, here, I have an idea.
Come on. It's okay. Come on.
[giggling]
- Hi there!
- [cowbell]
-Uh, excuse me,
what are you doing here?
-Name's John Waters
from down the road here.
This here is Belinda.
She's just finished running away
for the third time this week.
So, on the way back, I just
noticed your lane way here,
and I figured...
well, why not see if they'd like
to try and keep her happy.
She don't want to live
with me no more.
- [mooing]
- Hello there, Madam.
-Hello.
-He says he wants
to sell the cow.
Listen, Sir, I don't think
we need a cow here
and so I think you should just...
-Oh, my goodness, Norman,
no need to be rude.
- I'm not being rude.
- I just think that...
uninvited guests... Remember?
-I don't think he's a threat,
Norm.
So you'd like
to sell us this cow?
- Oh, yes, Ma'am.
- She's a great milker.
Especially when I sing to her.
-You sing to her?
-Oh yeah. She really likes
the cow-cow boogie.
She likes that cow song.
"Bessie moo-moo cow"
[laughing]
She's a good milker.
.Are you getting any?
-No. You?
-No.
He said she likes music.
What do you think?
-Why not?
"There's a certain slant
of light winter afternoons."
"That oppresses like
the heft of cathedral tombs."
"When it comes
the landscape glistens."
"Shadows hold their breath."
"When it goes it's
like the distance"
"on the look of Death."
"The heavenly hurt
it gives us..."
-Norm?
"Solitude a whiteness."
"And an ache where"
"the meanings are."
"A nearness to tremendousness."
-Okay. So I’ll be
leaving now, Jane.
-Oh, okay.
- Bye, Norm.
- Bye.
Excuse me for asking, but, uh...
aren't you ever afraid
of being alone here at night?
-Why?
-It's just that the world isn't
a very kind place sometimes.
-You've noticed that too,
have you?
-Yeah. Well, I had some...
problems with my parents
when I was young.
-Like what?
-Uh...
Well, they beat me.
You know, cigarettes, all that.
-They beat you with cigarettes?
-Never mind. Forget it.
-Your mother didn't
look the son.
-How do you know?
-In the park, remember?
She was checking up on you.
Bearing love and cookies.
- Were you watching me?
- Yes.
And I had to get away
from this place.
I needed some company.
-Yeah, but you must know
other people.
-No, not really.
I’m not good at it.
-Why me?
-I don't know why I'm attracted
to helpless people.
They move me.
Do you have someone
who loves you?
It's okay.
[flipping radio stations]
[announcer]: Madeleine X's
murderer has been arrested
and is awaiting trial.
But this story isn't over yet.
It seems that no one has ever
heard Madelaine sing live.
Not only did she lipsync
all her concerts,
but it now appears she always
brought in the voice tracks
for her albums already recorded.
So somebody out there has
a great voice and isn't telling.
Well, whoever she is,
here she is at number four
on the Hot 1 00.
Hello I’m Nobody.
"Hello I am nobody."
"Who are you."
"Oh I am nobody"
"the two of us..."
[She's humming
Hello I’m Nobody.]
[narrator]:
Norman came to believe
that she was the real singer,
and she had found him
to protect her.
He swore that he would.
-She, she, she...
Argh! God.
[narrator]:
But still no words,
and no one to listen.
Until one day...
-Okay, I'm gonna act on a need.
-You don't care if it's
a mutual need?
-I'm sorry. Of course I do.
-Well it is.
-Shoot!
[sighing]
-Hey, Buck.
What the hell brings you back?!
-Actually, paper.
I finally wrote something.
-What, how to put
zip in your 'zaleas?
-No, actually, it's sort
of like a love story.
- Oh!
- Careful.
-Must be about that horse woman
with the stupid hat, huh?
-Yeah, her.
-Uh, I guess she makes you
"melt inside your skin." Huh.
"Makes your spine turn
to rubber." Oooh, Normie.
- Good, huh?
- Huh.
"Then I thought she was
the real singer."
The voice behind Madelaine X?
Holy shit, Norm!
- No, no, no, no.
- Was that her?
- Forget it. Keep your pants on.
- I was wrong.
She can't sing to save her life.
- How do you know?
- Maybe she was fooling you.
- She wouldn't fool me.
- I can't believe this.
This is great, Norm.
You found her.
- Give it back, Zelda.
- What?
- Give it back.
- No.
-Give it back!
Zelda! Zelda!!
-Ha-ha!
-Zelda!
- Give me... back. Uh.
- Ha-ha-ha!
Norman.
- God. Give it to me.
- Give it back!
-Don't deny how I’ve suffered
because of you.
- I don't believe this.
- Will you give it back?!
So you're a reporter now.
ls that the career of the week?
You make me fucking crazy!!
You're like this grasping
demento running around
with a ladder, planting
it in the ground and...
and climbing up in the ozone
and falling flat on your face!
Where you climbing to, Zelda?
Huh? You don't know.
You just want up, right?
You got any skills, Zelda?
You gonna work to get any, huh?
Oh, no, no, no! Work, no! Blah!
Oh, that's terrible.
You don't work, do ya?
It's all about having the right
connections, isn't it?
It's all about where you plant
your fucking ladder!
[applause]
Oh, great.
- Hey, they liked it, Normie.
- Give 'em some more.
They like that, uh... you know,
that masterful shtick.
- It's you they like, Zelda.
- Go on, do something.
- What?
- Yeah.
-Oh. All right.
Hey! Jerk.
- Jeez, I hope she likes this.
- Of course she's gonna love it.
She's gonna love it.
I wrote it, she’ll love it.
I wrote it, I wrote!
I can't believe I wrote
something. Oh, God.
[knocking]
[mounting footsteps]
-We were all shocked
and devastated
by what happened to Maddie.
It's gonna be difficult,
but we'll have
to make the best of it.
-How do you make
the best of death?
-Well, you know what we mean.
-Who told the press?
-My ex.
-Jane, they'll be
all over us like flies.
We won't be able to breathe.
They're riding everyone
at the record company:
The musicians,
Maddie's cleaning staff.
-Nobody knows anything.
Now listen.
I write a couple more songs.
You try to imitate
Maddie's mixes.
You call it a previously
unreleased album
- and that's it, the story's over.
- No.
But we will protect you.
We'll put in
a surveillance system.
Jane, with one interview,
one live appearance
and a few photos
and then we can do
all of the rest.
Then, we can go on
recording for years.
Come on. The press
loves this stuff.
-Liz...
-I’ve never asked for very much.
-Jane, you can have
as much money as you need.
I mean, we did buy you
this house.
- She bought it.
- It wouldn't have occurred to you.
[laughing]
You know,
we can't be sure that
they won't discover you anyway.
-I wish it'd been me
instead of Maddie.
- Please don't talk like that.
- Please don't talk like that?
-Jane. Jane!
- Jane, Jane, Jane...
- She's playing with us.
-She's getting
all psychotic again.
Jane, relax. Please, Jane.
-Relax, please?
Can't let the golden egg
crack, can we?
- Jane, stop this game.
- She'll be fine.
-She'll be fine. Just give her
a taste of life in limos.
She'll be fine.
She's got no way out.
-Jane, please don't do this.
-Anybody who dares to act
this crazy must be crazy.
-What?
Jane, who the hell is that?
-Excuse me,
but I think that you two
should leave. Because, uh...
Because I think you should.
-Powerful argument.
- Who the hell are you?
- I'm Norm.
And I have been charged
with the duty
of making sure
that unwanted guests
are kept off this property.
So, if you please...
- Okay.
I guess I'll just have
to come back again.
-Mm-hm.
-And I will come back, Jane.
-Please.
-Ha! Ha! Ha!
-You okay? What did they want?
-Money wants me to talk.
I just can't think...
-It's okay, it's all right.
I made something for you.
-You're too nice to me.
- Yeah, well it...
- When I was little,
I went to visit a canary farm,
just to watch them.
Hundreds of canaries
in big cages,
and I could hear
that one of them
had an incredibly clear voice
and so,
for a long time I stood there,
trying to find which one it was
and then finally I saw him.
He was this scraggly, pathetic,
little grey thing
with no feathers,
singing his little heart out.
Later, the owner told me
that the other canaries al...
always peck at the one
with the purest voice.
-Maybe it had the purest voice
because they pecked at it.
-Maybe.
"Have you seen the ghost of Tom."
"Long white bones
with the skin all gone."
"Pooor... Tom."
"Wouldn't it be chilly
with no skin on."
You know, don't you?
-Yeah.
-Hi, kids.
-What are you doing here?
- I, uh...
- Go away.
-I followed you here. I was
curious to see what was so...
alluring.
-How did... Zelda, go away!
She works at the news stand.
Don't worry,
she doesn't know any...
-Huh. So I see this has
become quite an in-depth
little story here, Normie.
-Norm?
-She doesn't know
what she's talking about.
I just found out...
-You do realize that
this young man has written
quite an intensive article
on you? Right?
-It's not an article.
Jane. Jane, listen,
it's not an article.
-Huh. You know,
you have a really...
You have a lovely voice, Jane.
You ought to do something
with that.
- Kill you!
- I promise I'll kill you!
-You know what? I'm a singer
too. I have this...
-Do you realize
what you've done?
-I have an idea, yes.
-Whatever possessed you
to barge in like that?
You don't realize how long it
has taken me to gain her trust.
You've been kicked around so
much, you don't even understand
- how fragile some people can be.
- Oh, fragile-smagile.
Listen, listen, you got a juicy
story and I want in on it.
Just relax. I can help you
with the woman's angle, okay?
Okay, now look it, look it,
I can help you.
Let's just trot right
in there, right this second,
and get the exclusive. Do you
have any idea what that's worth?
-Well.
Well, I don't know.
I don't think she's gonna talk
in front of somebody else.
I really don't.
- Come on.
- The woman has been living alone
for 15 years. She's not about to
start throwing dinner parties.
-Oh. Okay, listen, listen.
I’ll see you back at the stand
in an hour and a half, okay?
But listen, if I don't see you
there, I got this, uh...
this little hit single here
that I’m sure quite a few people
would be interested in.
- Just one?
- One what?
- You've just got one song?
- Yeah.
-Oh, Jesus, Zelda,
where the hell were you?
There was some
great stuff earlier on.
Well, at least
it's sort of clear.
-Huh?
-I better get back to her. She's
nice and exposed right now.
-If you're scamming me,
you just remember
you got an hour and a half to
get back to the stand. Okay?
If you're not there,
this place is gonna be swarming
with fans real fast.
-Don't worry, Zelda.
-By the way, listen, I, umm...
I thought you loved her.
-Her? You gotta be kidding.
All that stuff I was writing,
I wrote that to pry her open
a little bit.
They thrive on compliments.
You know.
-God.
- I underestimated you.
- Yeah.
Go.
Look, Jane,
you don't understand.
-No, I don't. Feels like a
pretty cliché, story to me, Norm.
She thinks it's love,
but it's only ambition.
Oh, it's been done, baby,
it's been done.
- Look at me. Look at me.
- We could run away together.
I’m not a reporter,
I'm not a writer,
I’ve never, ever
written anything.
I only heard all
that stuff today
when those people came here.
I just...
I just love you. I love you
more than I can tell.
That's what I wrote. Listen.
Here. Read it, please. Read it.
That's what I wrote.
Jane, please. Please. Please.
Please.
You don't understand.
"Wouldn't it be chilly
with no skin on."
-No, I don't.
-I just, I just...
Zelda did that. She... she...
- It's my recorder, but...
- Do you wanna know things?
- I left it at her house and...
- ls that what you want?
You wanna know things?
- Come with me.
- She recorded it. I got it ba...
- No, come on with me.
- Jane, I would never hurt you.
-You're gonna like this, Norm.
It'll appeal
to your sense of drama.
- Jane...
- Here we have...
a magic doorway.
Yes, ladies and gentlemen,
this is where
the sadly neurotic singer
created some of her finest work.
And behind this curtain,
we have a lovely array
of...
music-recording equipment.
Of course, the other
instrumentation and final mixing
were done elsewhere by
my best friend, my producer...
my face.
-Jane, if you only read
what I’ve written...
-Over here, we have
a series of songs
that no one has ever heard.
Black screams with happy faces.
- Yes, ladies and gentlemen...
- Jane...
-You're so right.
I think we should start.
-Stan?
-Well.
We can get comfortable first.
You like me?
-Yes. You know I do.
-I love your body.
- I've loved watching you work.
- Jane...
-Come on, Norm.
Every story needs
a tender love scene.
- This isn't a story.
- Yes, it is.
So...
ask me a question.
-Why are you doing this?
-Good question.
I think it has something to do
with the geopolitical
menace of terrorism
and our responsibility
to the third-world nations...
- I love you.
- Shut up!
Ask me how I got started.
Norm, the interview.
Ask.
-How did you get started?
-I just started.
That's a little dull, isn't it?
Okay, let's see...
Uh, Madelaine and I
had been friends
since we were young.
And one day,
we made an arrangement.
She was much more socially sexy
and knew the music biz
and I could sing.
I never dreamt...
Ask me why I'm a recluse.
"Why are you a recluse, Jane?"
Uh, that's an interesting
question.
I guess... I guess
the best way to put it
is that some people are good at
parties and some people aren't.
Oh!
Yes, thank you.
I am very special and talented.
Oh, yes, really, I am.
It comes to me in flashes,
you see.
Anecdotes?
Oh, I have a raft of them.
In fact, my whole life is just
one big media anecdote.
[moaning]
-ls that good?
-Jane, listen to me.
Listen to me, Jane.
I love you.
Don't you realize
how much I love you?
- And then...
- I met a fine young man
at my own funeral.
And he was interested
in gardening
- and I was interested in him.
- It's okay.
It's okay. Listen to me.
I promise I won't hurt you.
-Oh!
Really?
Ask me about one of the most
exciting moments of my life.
- Please don't play this game.
- No! Ask!
-What was one of the most
exciting moments of your life?
-Oh, God.
I'm so glad you asked me
that question.
Now...
Now, one of the most exciting
moments of my life.
I was home alone, a while ago,
just rehearsing one of my songs,
when I received
an unexpected guest.
And he cut my face and my arms.
And he pushed me to the ground.
And he ripped my clothes.
-That wasn't you.
That wasn't your fault.
-And then I heard my own voice
far, far away, screaming
and screaming and screaming...
-"No-♩-♩-♩..."
[crying]
-It's okay, it's okay.
It's your hands, it's your face,
you're here.
It's okay, it's okay.
[car door slamming]
[faraway voices]
[louder voices]
-Hey, Jane! Jane, it's Zelda.
I know that you've
gotta be in there and...
Why don't you just
come on out here?
There's a few people who want
to just ask you a few questions.
It's no big hairy deal.
We just wanna, uh...
sort of like an impromptu
press conference here, okay?
So just come on out. Don't be
worried about anything. Okay?
-We'll meet in 12 hours,
all right?
Jane, are you all right?
It'll work, I promise you.
It's the only way.
Say you understand.
All right?
All right.
-Ladies and gentlemen...
-There she is.
-I will speak to you,
but not here.
Let me bring you
to my recording studio.
And I will answer
all your questions there.
[babble of voices]
- Come on. Hurry up, everyone.
- She's ready to talk. Come on.
Can you do both of us
at the same time, because...
Okay, sshhh, sshhh. Okay.
- What's going on here?
- Oh my God.
-I'm sorry to have deceived you,
but it was the only way
to protect her.
I led you here so that
she could escape.
Please, please, please.
She's a very fragile woman.
And she prays that you'll
let her live quietly.
And she asked me to tell you,
to thank you
for listening to her songs.
And she also asked me
to say goodbye.
[babble of voices]
Thank you.
[Zelda]: She was a personal
friend of mine, so I actually...
-Hey, lady, lady,
is that your kid in there?
- Hey, do you live here?
- Yes, I do.
- Who are you?
- There was a young man...
- How does he know Madelaine X?
- Is he involved in music?
- Is he a musician?
- Uh, one at a time, please.
Yes, Norm is very musical.
-Oh, Mother! No, no,
I'm sorry, not you. No.
Uh, yeah, yeah. So that's
flight 871 , Toronto to Paris,
Air Canada,
this evening, 11 P.M.
All right, thank you.
-Actually, Norm's always been
quite creative.
Very creative
and very sensitive.
That's his father's influence.
Actually, ever since
he was a very small boy,
I’ve always felt Norm
was somehow special.
[narrator]: And finally,
Norman raced back
to rescue his princess.
-Jane!
[narrator]: But her heart
had been broken.
For her fear of the world
was much too great
and her refuge from it
had been destroyed.
So she had taken her own life.
Norman did not know how to live
in a world that had endings
like this.
He had wished for something
so very different.
So he concentrated
all of his powers,
all that he'd learned,
and all that he'd loved,
and turned back time.
And then he wrote himself
a much kinder ending
to the story.