1
00:00:02,250 --> 00:00:05,249
(suspenseful music)

2
00:00:16,417 --> 00:00:19,166
(wind whistling)

3
00:00:47,958 --> 00:00:50,707
(wind whistling)

4
00:00:57,917 --> 00:01:01,499
(mysterious man whistling)

5
00:01:12,542 --> 00:01:14,166
(gun cocking)

6
00:01:14,167 --> 00:01:17,832
(dramatic theatrical music)

7
00:01:29,375 --> 00:01:33,291
(suspenseful theatrical music)

8
00:01:59,042 --> 00:02:02,707
(dramatic orchestral music)

9
00:02:23,750 --> 00:02:26,666
(flames crackling)

10
00:02:28,833 --> 00:02:32,082
(light idyllic music)

11
00:02:35,333 --> 00:02:36,916
- Looks like we have company.

12
00:02:44,125 --> 00:02:45,374
- Hold the column, Jerry.

13
00:02:49,417 --> 00:02:50,749
(birds chirping)

14
00:02:50,750 --> 00:02:52,207
Hoy, Jess!

15
00:02:52,208 --> 00:02:55,791
(light instrumental music)

16
00:03:12,250 --> 00:03:14,207
He runs the hunting
lodge not far from here.

17
00:03:14,208 --> 00:03:15,749
One of the best guides in the country.

18
00:03:15,750 --> 00:03:17,416
- [Jerry] Runs a pretty good rope, too.

19
00:03:17,417 --> 00:03:19,957
- Oh, he's already served
his time in these rocks.

20
00:03:19,958 --> 00:03:22,457
He trained at Carson
with the mountain troops.

21
00:03:22,458 --> 00:03:23,499
(light gentle music)

22
00:03:23,500 --> 00:03:26,332
(water splashing)

23
00:03:34,042 --> 00:03:35,749
- You're three weeks late, Major.

24
00:03:35,750 --> 00:03:37,332
- Well, you sound disappointed.

25
00:03:37,333 --> 00:03:39,249
- Well, it's a big country.

26
00:03:39,250 --> 00:03:41,416
I’d hope you'd take your Army
somewhere else this year.

27
00:03:41,417 --> 00:03:42,249
- Sorry.

28
00:03:42,250 --> 00:03:44,082
This is my new exec Lieutenant Stevenson.

29
00:03:44,083 --> 00:03:45,166
- How do you do?
- Sure could use

30
00:03:45,167 --> 00:03:46,332
you in this outfit.

31
00:03:46,333 --> 00:03:47,624
- Thanks, but you'll have to defend

32
00:03:47,625 --> 00:03:49,457
the Rocky Mountains without me.

33
00:03:49,458 --> 00:03:51,582
- Mr. Hill doesn't love us anymore, Jerry.

34
00:03:52,458 --> 00:03:53,874
- In two days there won't be any game

35
00:03:53,875 --> 00:03:55,124
within 20 miles of here.

36
00:03:56,042 --> 00:03:57,457
What am I supposed to do?

37
00:03:57,500 --> 00:03:58,999
Salute when you go by?

38
00:03:59,000 --> 00:04:00,374
(Major Knowles chuckles)

39
00:04:00,375 --> 00:04:01,499
- We better move along.

40
00:04:02,792 --> 00:04:03,666
- [Jerry] Forward!

41
00:04:04,667 --> 00:04:06,499
- Say, where you taking those pop guns?

42
00:04:06,500 --> 00:04:07,957
I don't want any of my
clients to get clobbered

43
00:04:07,958 --> 00:04:08,916
with a howitzer shell.

44
00:04:08,917 --> 00:04:10,749
- The same danger area as last year.

45
00:04:10,750 --> 00:04:11,582
- Oh.
- Here.

46
00:04:20,958 --> 00:04:23,957
We'll pack into the firing
range here at Pepper Valley.

47
00:04:23,958 --> 00:04:27,957
Should be there in about
five days, night of the 15th.

48
00:04:27,958 --> 00:04:29,624
- What's your firing schedule?

49
00:04:29,625 --> 00:04:32,707
- Daylight shoots starting
at 0700 hours on the 16th.

50
00:04:33,583 --> 00:04:36,666
And in this outfit, that
means 0700 to the second.

51
00:04:36,667 --> 00:04:38,291
You can keep this.

52
00:04:38,292 --> 00:04:40,541
- There's some young sheep up there.

53
00:04:40,542 --> 00:04:41,957
Watch out for them.

54
00:04:41,958 --> 00:04:42,791
- Right.

55
00:04:47,458 --> 00:04:50,041
(gentle music)

56
00:04:53,375 --> 00:04:56,041
(curious music)

57
00:05:00,750 --> 00:05:03,582
(dramatic music)

58
00:05:07,542 --> 00:05:09,124
- You're a dead man.

59
00:05:09,125 --> 00:05:11,416
(gun cocking)

60
00:05:11,417 --> 00:05:14,541
(dramatic music)

61
00:05:14,542 --> 00:05:17,541
You died a thousand years
ago in the foxhole in Anzio,

62
00:05:20,208 --> 00:05:23,541
but, man, you sure look healthy.

63
00:05:29,417 --> 00:05:31,166
- Pete Corder.

64
00:05:31,167 --> 00:05:32,624
- Jesse, you remembered.

65
00:05:32,625 --> 00:05:35,082
- How could I forget a
colorful character like you?

66
00:05:35,083 --> 00:05:36,707
- Colorful, if nothing else.

67
00:05:36,708 --> 00:05:38,124
- How'd you find me up here?

68
00:05:38,125 --> 00:05:40,207
- I ran into one of the Army
boys about three years ago.

69
00:05:40,208 --> 00:05:41,166
He told me you were

70
00:05:41,167 --> 00:05:42,374
transferred to the mountain troops

71
00:05:42,375 --> 00:05:44,832
and stayed here in Colorado after the war.

72
00:05:44,833 --> 00:05:48,041
So, I rented a horse in
Manitou and came calling.

73
00:05:48,042 --> 00:05:50,166
- I thought by now you'd
be selling slot machines

74
00:05:50,167 --> 00:05:51,541
to the Sultan of Siam.

75
00:05:51,542 --> 00:05:52,582
- He had them.
(Jesse chuckles)

76
00:05:52,583 --> 00:05:53,416
Coffee?

77
00:05:57,500 --> 00:06:00,166
- Yeah, thanks a lot.

78
00:06:00,167 --> 00:06:04,249
(Pete sings in foreign language)

79
00:06:08,083 --> 00:06:08,957
- Oh, uh, uh, uh.

80
00:06:10,625 --> 00:06:11,624
Napoleon brandy.

81
00:06:12,958 --> 00:06:14,291
I’ve been saving it for an occasion.

82
00:06:14,292 --> 00:06:15,124
- Oh, yeah?

83
00:06:17,208 --> 00:06:18,582
What is the occasion, Pete?

84
00:06:20,083 --> 00:06:21,207
- [Pete] You really wanna know?

85
00:06:21,208 --> 00:06:22,041
- Fascinated.

86
00:06:23,500 --> 00:06:24,332
- Okay.

87
00:06:25,500 --> 00:06:26,749
Follow the bouncing ball.

88
00:06:27,583 --> 00:06:29,416
I took my discharge in
Europe after the war.

89
00:06:29,417 --> 00:06:30,624
I hooked up with a Frenchman,

90
00:06:30,625 --> 00:06:32,707
who needed help in a
little trucking business.

91
00:06:32,750 --> 00:06:35,749
We operated along the
Spanish border at night.

92
00:06:35,750 --> 00:06:38,624
The hours finally
interfered with his health.

93
00:06:38,625 --> 00:06:41,332
After they buried him, I
headed for the Riviera.

94
00:06:41,333 --> 00:06:43,666
Oh, and that was fine, Jess.

95
00:06:43,667 --> 00:06:45,166
The sun and sand,

96
00:06:45,167 --> 00:06:46,832
a long run of luck at the casino.

97
00:06:47,833 --> 00:06:49,082
I met a Brazilian who owned a yacht,

98
00:06:49,083 --> 00:06:50,166
so I took a trip to Rio.

99
00:06:50,167 --> 00:06:52,249
It turned out the Brazilian
also had a husband,

100
00:06:52,250 --> 00:06:53,291
so I went to Bueno Aires.

101
00:06:53,292 --> 00:06:54,124
(both chuckling)

102
00:06:54,125 --> 00:06:56,416
And after that, it was Cairo,

103
00:06:58,000 --> 00:06:59,666
Madrid,

104
00:06:59,667 --> 00:07:00,499
Berlin,

105
00:07:03,042 --> 00:07:03,874
nothing.

106
00:07:05,375 --> 00:07:06,957
You still fascinated?

107
00:07:06,958 --> 00:07:07,791
- Yeah,

108
00:07:08,917 --> 00:07:10,916
but not surprised.

109
00:07:10,917 --> 00:07:11,916
- Well, I was.

110
00:07:13,125 --> 00:07:14,624
I sold the old homestead,

111
00:07:14,625 --> 00:07:16,874
because of a little trip to Las Vegas.

112
00:07:16,875 --> 00:07:18,999
I had enough left for a
two-week splurge at Sun Valley.

113
00:07:19,000 --> 00:07:20,291
Object: matrimony.

114
00:07:21,750 --> 00:07:23,541
There's a scarcity of
rich widows this season.

115
00:07:23,542 --> 00:07:25,666
(Jesse chuckles)

116
00:07:25,667 --> 00:07:26,957
So the word is flat broke.

117
00:07:30,667 --> 00:07:31,957
(gentle music)

118
00:07:31,958 --> 00:07:34,082
Hey, it's foggy, isn't it?

119
00:07:34,083 --> 00:07:35,166
- [Jesse] ls that all?

120
00:07:36,792 --> 00:07:37,624
- No, no.

121
00:07:39,250 --> 00:07:40,291
No, I remembered you,

122
00:07:41,958 --> 00:07:42,999
and the time I carried you out

123
00:07:43,000 --> 00:07:44,832
of the foxhole to the aid station,

124
00:07:46,708 --> 00:07:48,082
and a lot of laughs we had,

125
00:07:49,542 --> 00:07:50,957
and 40 bucks I owe you.

126
00:07:53,625 --> 00:07:54,624
I thought it might all be good

127
00:07:54,625 --> 00:07:56,582
for a couple of days of chow

128
00:07:56,583 --> 00:07:58,332
and a place to figure it out.

129
00:07:58,333 --> 00:08:00,582
(gentle music)

130
00:08:00,583 --> 00:08:01,457
I’m tired, Jess.

131
00:08:01,458 --> 00:08:02,332
I'm very tired.

132
00:08:04,792 --> 00:08:07,416
When I’m broke, I'm the
poorest man you can imagine.

133
00:08:09,417 --> 00:08:12,416
(gentle music)

134
00:08:12,417 --> 00:08:14,249
- Let's bed down that horse of yours.

135
00:08:20,167 --> 00:08:23,499
(Pete whistling lively)

136
00:08:40,333 --> 00:08:42,707
- What brought you up here?

137
00:08:42,708 --> 00:08:43,624
- I like mountains.

138
00:08:44,917 --> 00:08:47,749
(dramatic music)

139
00:08:56,292 --> 00:08:57,291
- That girl,

140
00:08:59,083 --> 00:09:01,791
the one with a smile, Peggy,

141
00:09:05,583 --> 00:09:07,124
you ever marry her?

142
00:09:07,125 --> 00:09:09,707
(gentle music)

143
00:09:12,583 --> 00:09:13,416
- No.

144
00:09:15,167 --> 00:09:17,416
- Too bad, she was a nice girl.

145
00:09:17,417 --> 00:09:18,999
- Yeah, sure, nice and friendly.

146
00:09:19,958 --> 00:09:20,999
Everybody's friend.

147
00:09:22,500 --> 00:09:23,332
Come on.

148
00:09:24,333 --> 00:09:26,916
(gentle music)

149
00:09:28,250 --> 00:09:31,624
(dramatic music)

150
00:09:31,625 --> 00:09:36,582
(airplane engine humming overhead)

151
00:09:36,583 --> 00:09:38,249
- What's that?

152
00:09:38,250 --> 00:09:41,207
The Blue Chip Express Direct
from Las Vegas to Monte Carlo?

153
00:09:42,542 --> 00:09:43,957
- Could be.

154
00:09:43,958 --> 00:09:45,541
Don't see many around here.

155
00:09:45,542 --> 00:09:47,499
It must be way off his course.

156
00:09:47,500 --> 00:09:49,541
- Flying awful close to your real estate.

157
00:09:50,583 --> 00:09:51,416
- Yeah.

158
00:09:52,625 --> 00:09:54,249
Come on.

159
00:09:54,250 --> 00:09:58,541
(airplane engine humming)

160
00:09:58,542 --> 00:10:00,332
- Just a little rough air, folks.

161
00:10:01,792 --> 00:10:03,541
Nothing to be afraid of.

162
00:10:03,542 --> 00:10:06,332
Things will settle down as soon
as we clear these mountains.

163
00:10:08,375 --> 00:10:10,416
- What are you giving us, Red?

164
00:10:10,417 --> 00:10:12,041
You guys are just bouncing us around,

165
00:10:12,042 --> 00:10:13,624
so you won't have to buy dinner.

166
00:10:15,042 --> 00:10:16,457
- I suppose this weather
means we'll be late

167
00:10:16,458 --> 00:10:17,582
getting into New York.

168
00:10:17,583 --> 00:10:19,124
- We'll make it up.
- Well, I hope so.

169
00:10:19,125 --> 00:10:21,666
I have an important engagement
there in the morning.

170
00:10:22,625 --> 00:10:24,166
- What line are you in?

171
00:10:24,167 --> 00:10:25,041
- What?

172
00:10:25,042 --> 00:10:26,957
Oh, banking and investments.

173
00:10:26,958 --> 00:10:29,499
- Oh, we got a treasury
man sitting up ahead.

174
00:10:29,500 --> 00:10:30,916
- Oh, is that so?

175
00:10:30,917 --> 00:10:33,457
Well, I get down to Washington
myself now and then,

176
00:10:33,458 --> 00:10:35,249
consultant to the secretary.

177
00:10:35,250 --> 00:10:36,791
- Me, I’m done with work.

178
00:10:36,792 --> 00:10:38,624
You're looking at a retired man.

179
00:10:38,625 --> 00:10:41,207
Two-hundred a month steady as she goes.

180
00:10:41,208 --> 00:10:43,749
Guess that doesn't mean
much to a fella like you.

181
00:10:43,750 --> 00:10:46,041
- Well, we all take our share.

182
00:10:46,042 --> 00:10:47,416
My name's Parkinson,

183
00:10:47,417 --> 00:10:48,416
George Parkinson.

184
00:10:50,125 --> 00:10:51,166
- Stan Leppich.

185
00:10:51,167 --> 00:10:52,957
- Oh, how do you do?

186
00:10:52,958 --> 00:10:56,249
(plane engine humming)

187
00:10:58,083 --> 00:10:59,541
- Everything all right, Miss?

188
00:11:03,917 --> 00:11:04,916
- Just ducky.

189
00:11:08,000 --> 00:11:10,957
- Say, haven't I seen you somewheres?

190
00:11:15,500 --> 00:11:18,082
- Now, chief, an old sailor like you,

191
00:11:18,083 --> 00:11:19,291
you ought to be ashamed.

192
00:11:20,708 --> 00:11:22,457
(Stan chuckling)

193
00:11:22,458 --> 00:11:24,791
- Guess my line's kind
of rusty, eh, Parky.

194
00:11:24,792 --> 00:11:26,582
- I wouldn't know about those things.

195
00:11:26,583 --> 00:11:28,416
- Just the same, I'll bet I seen her.

196
00:11:29,458 --> 00:11:32,166
Hey, you think she's a movie star, Red?

197
00:11:32,167 --> 00:11:33,916
- I’ll have to see her smile first.

198
00:11:36,083 --> 00:11:37,624
- [Stan] Like to join our club?

199
00:11:39,542 --> 00:11:41,541
- Well, that depends on the rules.

200
00:11:41,542 --> 00:11:44,249
- Oh, we just sort of make
them up as we go along.

201
00:11:44,250 --> 00:11:46,416
Now Parkinson here, he's
used to handling things,

202
00:11:46,417 --> 00:11:47,957
so he'll be the president.

203
00:11:47,958 --> 00:11:49,874
(George scoffing)

204
00:11:49,875 --> 00:11:51,791
Uh, I didn't get your name.

205
00:11:52,667 --> 00:11:54,666
- Sheryl Gregory.

206
00:11:54,667 --> 00:11:56,082
- Okay, Sherry.

207
00:11:56,083 --> 00:11:58,207
Red, he's the secretary.

208
00:11:58,250 --> 00:12:00,624
Of course, he'll have to have
your phone number. (chuckles)

209
00:12:00,625 --> 00:12:03,707
(engine revving)

210
00:12:03,708 --> 00:12:05,249
- [Red] Just a down draft, folks.

211
00:12:05,250 --> 00:12:06,124
(engine revving)

212
00:12:06,125 --> 00:12:08,124
(metal clanking)
(woman screaming)

213
00:12:08,125 --> 00:12:10,041
(Sheryl screaming)

214
00:12:10,042 --> 00:12:13,957
(crash booming)
(metal clanking)

215
00:12:13,958 --> 00:12:14,791
- The plane?

216
00:12:18,750 --> 00:12:20,874
- It could be a tree crashing in a forest.

217
00:12:21,792 --> 00:12:22,624
- Or the wind?

218
00:12:23,875 --> 00:12:25,416
Just the wind and nothing more.

219
00:12:44,083 --> 00:12:45,957
- Put some more wood
on the fire, will you?

220
00:12:48,500 --> 00:12:49,624
- Was it the plane?

221
00:12:49,625 --> 00:12:50,457
- How would I know?

222
00:12:50,458 --> 00:12:51,957
- Okay, Jess, how's the
weather been around here?

223
00:12:51,958 --> 00:12:53,582
- Lousy, and it's gonna get worse.

224
00:12:53,583 --> 00:12:54,791
- Look, if I'm intruding...

225
00:12:54,792 --> 00:12:56,124
- You're not intruding.

226
00:13:02,833 --> 00:13:04,207
- Where you going?
- Up on the mountain.

227
00:13:04,208 --> 00:13:05,957
- What do you expect
to see in all that fog?

228
00:13:05,958 --> 00:13:07,124
- More fog.

229
00:13:07,125 --> 00:13:08,416
Keep your eye on the fire.

230
00:13:14,292 --> 00:13:17,041
(dramatic music)

231
00:13:33,792 --> 00:13:36,374
(gentle music)

232
00:13:44,958 --> 00:13:47,874
(flames crackling)

233
00:13:54,417 --> 00:13:55,249
- Hold it.

234
00:13:57,500 --> 00:14:00,082
I had the radio on while you were gone.

235
00:14:00,083 --> 00:14:01,416
It was the plane.

236
00:14:01,417 --> 00:14:02,291
- What'd they say?

237
00:14:03,375 --> 00:14:04,999
- Flying out of San Francisco to Chicago.

238
00:14:05,000 --> 00:14:08,416
Last heard from 80 miles west
of the Manitou Mountains.

239
00:14:08,417 --> 00:14:09,416
- Way off course.

240
00:14:11,208 --> 00:14:12,582
- The Army won't be able to send out

241
00:14:12,583 --> 00:14:15,374
any search planes till the weather clears,

242
00:14:15,375 --> 00:14:17,332
and like you said it's gonna get worse.

243
00:14:18,792 --> 00:14:19,832
- Crash in these mountains,

244
00:14:19,833 --> 00:14:21,499
they're probably all dead anyway.

245
00:14:22,583 --> 00:14:24,082
- Don't you want some dinner?

246
00:14:24,083 --> 00:14:25,874
- [Jesse] No thanks, I'm not hungry.

247
00:14:36,042 --> 00:14:37,291
- You're going to bed.

248
00:14:37,292 --> 00:14:39,999
- Staying up all night isn't gonna help.

249
00:14:40,000 --> 00:14:42,207
- Well, you've learned
since the war, haven't you?

250
00:14:42,208 --> 00:14:43,041
- What?

251
00:14:43,042 --> 00:14:44,957
- People aren't worth the trouble.

252
00:14:45,000 --> 00:14:47,457
It's better to bury yourself
in a mountain ditch.

253
00:14:49,542 --> 00:14:51,916
- Are you trying to
make a hermit out of me?

254
00:14:51,917 --> 00:14:53,499
- Me?

255
00:14:53,500 --> 00:14:54,916
I had nothing to do with it.

256
00:14:56,208 --> 00:14:59,957
(Pete whistling lively)

257
00:14:59,958 --> 00:15:01,916
Oh, sweet dreams, Jess.

258
00:15:01,917 --> 00:15:05,249
(Pete whistling lively)

259
00:15:11,708 --> 00:15:13,291
(plane engine humming overhead)

260
00:15:13,292 --> 00:15:14,832
- Whistle this is Whistle One.

261
00:15:14,833 --> 00:15:16,249
Say again. Over.

262
00:15:16,250 --> 00:15:19,416
(plane engine humming overhead)

263
00:15:19,417 --> 00:15:21,666
They're trying to tell us
something about a plane.

264
00:15:23,750 --> 00:15:24,582
Can't get it.

265
00:15:26,917 --> 00:15:28,374
Out of contact, sir.

266
00:15:28,375 --> 00:15:29,832
- Sergeant?

267
00:15:29,833 --> 00:15:30,666
- Yes, sir.

268
00:15:30,667 --> 00:15:32,082
We'll move on.

269
00:15:32,083 --> 00:15:33,332
All right, you mule soldiers.

270
00:15:33,333 --> 00:15:35,499
Let's see some graceful
motion around here.

271
00:15:37,083 --> 00:15:40,332
(plane engine humming)

272
00:15:43,292 --> 00:15:46,541
(light dramatic music)

273
00:16:04,917 --> 00:16:07,999
(light upbeat music)

274
00:16:09,542 --> 00:16:12,374
(chuckles softly)

275
00:16:13,292 --> 00:16:16,374
(light upbeat music)

276
00:16:22,750 --> 00:16:26,082
(light dramatic music)

277
00:16:28,333 --> 00:16:31,707
- In case we get lost we can
put a note in the bottle.

278
00:16:31,708 --> 00:16:33,124
(chuckles softly)

279
00:16:33,125 --> 00:16:34,249
- Okay, partner.

280
00:16:38,875 --> 00:16:40,041
Get one thing straight.

281
00:16:40,958 --> 00:16:42,332
There's no picnic out there.

282
00:16:43,375 --> 00:16:45,332
Some of those mountains go straight up,

283
00:16:46,917 --> 00:16:48,499
and we use this for an elevator.

284
00:16:49,750 --> 00:16:50,582
- Can I learn?

285
00:16:53,500 --> 00:16:54,541
- I can teach.

286
00:16:56,625 --> 00:16:58,082
- Then what are we waiting for?

287
00:17:01,792 --> 00:17:05,124
(Pete whistling lively)

288
00:17:06,583 --> 00:17:07,499
- Save your wind, boy!

289
00:17:07,500 --> 00:17:08,541
You're gonna need it!

290
00:17:12,708 --> 00:17:14,416
(light dramatic music)

291
00:17:14,417 --> 00:17:17,249
(birds chirping)

292
00:17:24,500 --> 00:17:27,332
(coyote howling)

293
00:17:31,542 --> 00:17:34,291
(dramatic music)

294
00:17:50,167 --> 00:17:51,374
- Elevator time, huh?

295
00:17:51,375 --> 00:17:52,207
- Yep.

296
00:17:54,542 --> 00:17:56,457
- Do we carry the horses,

297
00:17:56,458 --> 00:17:58,207
or do they walk up?

298
00:17:58,250 --> 00:18:00,332
- Turn them loose they'll
find their way back.

299
00:18:01,792 --> 00:18:02,749
Climb into this.

300
00:18:03,750 --> 00:18:06,457
- I got to climb a mountain in this?

301
00:18:06,500 --> 00:18:07,791
- You’ll learn to love it.

302
00:18:12,375 --> 00:18:14,541
- There isn't any other
way around, is there?

303
00:18:14,542 --> 00:18:16,541
- Not unless you wanna take
two or three days at it.

304
00:18:16,542 --> 00:18:17,416
Here's your rifle.

305
00:18:19,125 --> 00:18:19,957
- Well,

306
00:18:22,833 --> 00:18:25,082
I hope you remember what
the Army taught you.

307
00:18:27,500 --> 00:18:29,207
- If you remember what I told you.

308
00:18:30,375 --> 00:18:31,624
You climb with your feet.

309
00:18:32,500 --> 00:18:34,041
Use your hands for balance.

310
00:18:34,875 --> 00:18:37,082
And don't get spread eagle on that pitch,

311
00:18:37,083 --> 00:18:39,166
because you'll start to vibrate

312
00:18:39,167 --> 00:18:40,249
and probably fall off.

313
00:18:41,375 --> 00:18:42,249
(Pete laughs)

314
00:18:42,250 --> 00:18:43,416
Come on.

315
00:18:43,417 --> 00:18:46,666
(tense dramatic music)

316
00:18:58,375 --> 00:19:00,957
(wind blowing)

317
00:19:11,583 --> 00:19:14,082
We'll have to belay it from here.

318
00:19:14,083 --> 00:19:15,249
(Pete gasping)
(dramatic music)

319
00:19:15,250 --> 00:19:16,082
Scared?

320
00:19:17,208 --> 00:19:18,749
- How'd you guess?

321
00:19:18,750 --> 00:19:21,499
(dramatic music)

322
00:19:23,458 --> 00:19:26,041
(wind blowing)

323
00:19:29,875 --> 00:19:32,624
(dramatic music)

324
00:20:14,708 --> 00:20:16,707
(chain rattling)

325
00:20:16,708 --> 00:20:19,124
(wind blowing)

326
00:20:19,125 --> 00:20:21,957
(dramatic music)

327
00:20:46,750 --> 00:20:48,207
- On belay.

328
00:20:48,208 --> 00:20:50,624
- "Up belay, on belay, climbing,"

329
00:20:51,542 --> 00:20:53,416
as we mountain climber say.

330
00:20:53,417 --> 00:20:56,166
(dramatic music)

331
00:21:00,917 --> 00:21:05,916
(tense music)
(Pete groaning)

332
00:21:05,958 --> 00:21:06,791
Jesse!

333
00:21:08,625 --> 00:21:10,624
I can't let go!

334
00:21:10,625 --> 00:21:13,124
- Pull your hands together slowly.

335
00:21:14,250 --> 00:21:17,291
(suspenseful music)

336
00:21:17,292 --> 00:21:18,374
Don't look down!

337
00:21:19,250 --> 00:21:22,082
(dramatic music)

338
00:21:24,583 --> 00:21:26,749
- I'm shaking, Jesse.

339
00:21:26,750 --> 00:21:27,832
I'm gonna fall off.

340
00:21:28,667 --> 00:21:29,916
- Listen to me.

341
00:21:29,917 --> 00:21:31,874
You won't fall.

342
00:21:31,875 --> 00:21:34,749
You've got to pull one hand free.

343
00:21:34,750 --> 00:21:37,582
That's the only way you
can stop the vibration.

344
00:21:37,583 --> 00:21:39,332
You've got to turn one hand loose.

345
00:21:41,250 --> 00:21:43,832
(wind howling)

346
00:21:47,167 --> 00:21:47,999
(groans softly)

347
00:21:48,000 --> 00:21:50,332
(gasping deeply)

348
00:21:50,333 --> 00:21:53,166
(dramatic music)

349
00:21:59,125 --> 00:21:59,957
- Climbing.

350
00:22:00,875 --> 00:22:04,124
(dramatic music)

351
00:22:04,125 --> 00:22:06,707
(Pete gasping)

352
00:22:08,125 --> 00:22:10,874
(dramatic music)

353
00:22:22,583 --> 00:22:25,166
(Pete gasping)

354
00:22:33,542 --> 00:22:35,582
When I grow up, I wanna be just like you.

355
00:22:37,542 --> 00:22:39,791
- You're doing all right for a beginner.

356
00:22:39,792 --> 00:22:43,707
(Pete gasping deeply)

357
00:22:43,708 --> 00:22:45,749
Starting to get dark.

358
00:22:45,750 --> 00:22:46,832
We better keep moving.

359
00:23:02,333 --> 00:23:05,666
(plane engine roaring)

360
00:23:11,458 --> 00:23:13,207
- Artillery to aircraft. Roger.

361
00:23:13,250 --> 00:23:15,957
Receiving you loud and clear. Over.

362
00:23:15,958 --> 00:23:16,791
Major?

363
00:23:18,500 --> 00:23:20,666
- There's a commercial
aircraft down somewhere.

364
00:23:20,667 --> 00:23:21,457
(engine humming)

365
00:23:21,500 --> 00:23:23,499
Could be in these mountains.

366
00:23:23,500 --> 00:23:25,582
You guys seen anything? Over.

367
00:23:25,583 --> 00:23:26,624
- Nothing?

368
00:23:26,625 --> 00:23:28,707
Want us to give you a hand? Over.

369
00:23:28,708 --> 00:23:31,582
- Couldn't even tell you
where to start looking.

370
00:23:31,583 --> 00:23:33,791
We'll check you later if we need you.

371
00:23:33,792 --> 00:23:35,916
Oh, better hold your fire practice

372
00:23:35,917 --> 00:23:38,832
till we get a line on survivors. Over.

373
00:23:38,833 --> 00:23:40,582
- Wilco. Anything we can do.

374
00:23:40,583 --> 00:23:42,416
Good luck. Out.

375
00:23:42,417 --> 00:23:45,166
(engine roaring)

376
00:23:53,333 --> 00:23:56,082
(dramatic music)

377
00:24:11,458 --> 00:24:14,707
(tense dramatic music)

378
00:24:22,250 --> 00:24:25,749
(dramatic music)

379
00:24:25,750 --> 00:24:28,499
(coyote howling)

380
00:24:37,708 --> 00:24:40,457
(dramatic music)

381
00:25:26,500 --> 00:25:29,249
(coyote howling)

382
00:25:30,500 --> 00:25:32,124
- That coyote won't be satisfied

383
00:25:32,125 --> 00:25:34,124
till he gets into the wreck.

384
00:25:34,125 --> 00:25:36,457
- That's a pleasant thought.

385
00:25:37,458 --> 00:25:39,249
- All right, Parkinson.

386
00:25:39,250 --> 00:25:40,082
I guess we're all kind of

387
00:25:40,083 --> 00:25:41,957
getting on each other's nerves.

388
00:25:41,958 --> 00:25:43,791
- I'm not interested in the dead.

389
00:25:47,500 --> 00:25:48,916
- Hey, let me see that.

390
00:25:53,292 --> 00:25:54,707
Well, what do you know.

391
00:25:56,000 --> 00:25:57,666
It's Sherry!

392
00:25:57,667 --> 00:26:00,041
I knew I seen her someplace before.

393
00:26:00,042 --> 00:26:02,499
- Yeah, certainly, she's the type.

394
00:26:02,500 --> 00:26:04,999
- What you got something against models?

395
00:26:05,000 --> 00:26:07,166
- Our tastes are different, Mr. Leppich.

396
00:26:07,167 --> 00:26:09,832
(Stan chuckles)

397
00:26:15,000 --> 00:26:16,416
- How's Red doing?

398
00:26:16,417 --> 00:26:17,832
- Well, he's sleeping again,

399
00:26:19,125 --> 00:26:20,374
if you can call it sleep.

400
00:26:21,833 --> 00:26:24,041
- Hey, why didn't you tell us?

401
00:26:24,042 --> 00:26:24,874
- Tell you what.

402
00:26:26,917 --> 00:26:27,999
What about it?

403
00:26:28,000 --> 00:26:29,041
- What about it?

404
00:26:29,042 --> 00:26:30,624
(laughs) You're famous.

405
00:26:31,792 --> 00:26:35,249
You know, you haven't changed a bit.

406
00:26:35,250 --> 00:26:37,041
- That's where you're wrong, sailor.

407
00:26:38,917 --> 00:26:40,457
Wanna do me a favor?

408
00:26:40,458 --> 00:26:41,291
- Well, sure.

409
00:26:42,333 --> 00:26:43,582
- Burn it.

410
00:26:43,583 --> 00:26:45,249
- Why?

411
00:26:45,250 --> 00:26:48,582
- Because a year ago
that picture made me $50.

412
00:26:48,583 --> 00:26:51,957
Sometimes you don't like to
be reminded about last year.

413
00:26:51,958 --> 00:26:54,332
- Oh, I found your bag.

414
00:26:54,333 --> 00:26:55,166
- Oh.

415
00:26:56,250 --> 00:26:57,082
Thanks, chief.

416
00:27:02,000 --> 00:27:03,916
- Let me keep it a little longer, huh?

417
00:27:05,625 --> 00:27:08,332
(Stan chuckling)

418
00:27:08,333 --> 00:27:09,791
It'll help keep the wind out.

419
00:27:11,667 --> 00:27:14,874
- That copilot, what can you do for him?

420
00:27:14,875 --> 00:27:16,791
How can you help a guy hurt like that?

421
00:27:16,792 --> 00:27:18,874
- Maybe if he'd been up in
the cockpit where he belonged,

422
00:27:18,875 --> 00:27:20,416
this might not have happened.

423
00:27:20,417 --> 00:27:21,791
- And you'd be in your counting house

424
00:27:21,792 --> 00:27:22,832
counting out your money.

425
00:27:22,833 --> 00:27:25,457
But you're stuck in this refrigerator.

426
00:27:25,458 --> 00:27:28,082
And the only if is if
somebody's looking for us.

427
00:27:28,083 --> 00:27:29,166
- Of course, they're looking.

428
00:27:29,167 --> 00:27:29,957
- Where?

429
00:27:30,000 --> 00:27:31,582
- What?
- Where they gonna look?

430
00:27:31,583 --> 00:27:33,999
Weather like this we could
sit here for a month.

431
00:27:34,000 --> 00:27:35,249
- Well, that's ridiculous.

432
00:27:35,250 --> 00:27:36,082
- Yeah, ain't it?

433
00:27:38,500 --> 00:27:40,082
- Mr. Leppich,

434
00:27:40,083 --> 00:27:42,832
I'll prepare a schedule of the rations.

435
00:27:42,833 --> 00:27:44,249
Now suppose you go through the wreck,

436
00:27:44,250 --> 00:27:45,457
and see if I’ve overlooked anything.

437
00:27:45,500 --> 00:27:46,707
Ms. Gregory, if you'll...

438
00:27:46,708 --> 00:27:48,707
- Who made you king of the mountain?

439
00:27:48,708 --> 00:27:51,291
- I happen to have had some
experience at organization.

440
00:27:51,292 --> 00:27:53,416
- All right, then you
scrounge through the wreck.

441
00:27:53,417 --> 00:27:54,791
I’m going out and get some wood,

442
00:27:54,792 --> 00:27:57,582
so we don't freeze to
death if this snow hits us.

443
00:27:57,583 --> 00:27:59,707
- Well, see that you
make a good job of it!

444
00:28:02,500 --> 00:28:04,582
- (laughs) What a doll.

445
00:28:04,583 --> 00:28:05,416
- Yeah.

446
00:28:08,625 --> 00:28:09,832
Hey, hey, wait a minute.

447
00:28:14,542 --> 00:28:17,291
(dramatic music)

448
00:28:33,042 --> 00:28:35,791
(Stan chuckling)

449
00:28:37,125 --> 00:28:37,957
I haven't had so much fun

450
00:28:37,958 --> 00:28:39,957
since they kicked me out
of the Campfire Girls.

451
00:28:39,958 --> 00:28:41,207
- They did that to you?

452
00:28:41,208 --> 00:28:43,457
You should have come
over with us Boy Scouts.

453
00:28:43,458 --> 00:28:44,832
- That's why they kicked me out.

454
00:28:44,833 --> 00:28:47,499
(Stan chuckles)

455
00:28:49,125 --> 00:28:50,457
(gentle music)

456
00:28:50,458 --> 00:28:51,499
You know, I keep thinking I could've

457
00:28:51,500 --> 00:28:53,041
been in that part of the plane.

458
00:28:55,667 --> 00:28:57,416
Well, it wouldn't make
a lot difference anyway.

459
00:28:57,417 --> 00:28:59,249
- Come on, what kind of talk is that?

460
00:29:00,375 --> 00:29:02,207
- Always good for a laugh, that's me.

461
00:29:06,458 --> 00:29:08,082
Come on, woodsman, cut that tree.

462
00:29:10,500 --> 00:29:13,249
(dramatic music)

463
00:29:20,167 --> 00:29:23,249
(suspenseful music)

464
00:29:29,333 --> 00:29:31,457
(gunfire blasting)

465
00:29:31,458 --> 00:29:34,332
(suspenseful music)

466
00:29:34,333 --> 00:29:35,624
- Come on, girl!

467
00:29:35,625 --> 00:29:36,749
This is it!

468
00:29:36,750 --> 00:29:39,832
(suspenseful music)

469
00:29:51,333 --> 00:29:52,166
Here we are! Over here!

470
00:29:52,167 --> 00:29:53,624
Don't move another step!

471
00:29:53,625 --> 00:29:55,207
Boy, are you guys welcome!

472
00:29:55,250 --> 00:29:56,124
How'd you ever find us?

473
00:29:56,125 --> 00:29:57,832
What kept you?
- Take it easy.

474
00:29:57,833 --> 00:29:59,291
- Oh, you're wonderful, doll!

475
00:30:00,958 --> 00:30:02,624
- Thanks, but no reward necessary.

476
00:30:02,625 --> 00:30:03,957
- Well, hey, how about me?

477
00:30:06,208 --> 00:30:07,041
Oh.

478
00:30:12,708 --> 00:30:13,582
That was the down payment.

479
00:30:13,583 --> 00:30:16,332
We'll make the installments easy, hmm?

480
00:30:16,333 --> 00:30:18,582
- Uh-huh, paid in full.

481
00:30:18,583 --> 00:30:20,207
- If Ms. Gregory's through entertaining,

482
00:30:20,208 --> 00:30:21,416
my name is Parkinson.

483
00:30:21,417 --> 00:30:22,249
- Jess Hill.

484
00:30:22,250 --> 00:30:23,457
We'll get you out of
here as soon as we can.

485
00:30:23,458 --> 00:30:24,374
- I'm Pete Corder.

486
00:30:24,375 --> 00:30:25,957
Who's the Navy?
- Oh, Stan Leppich.

487
00:30:25,958 --> 00:30:27,249
Stan Leppich.
- How you doing?

488
00:30:27,250 --> 00:30:29,957
- And this is Sheryl Gregory.

489
00:30:30,000 --> 00:30:32,207
- And what about the others?

490
00:30:32,208 --> 00:30:33,416
- There's just a co-pilot.

491
00:30:33,417 --> 00:30:35,207
He's pretty badly hurt.

492
00:30:35,208 --> 00:30:36,124
- Where is he?

493
00:30:36,125 --> 00:30:37,957
- In the tail. I’ll show you.

494
00:30:37,958 --> 00:30:39,041
- We'll set up camp for the night.

495
00:30:39,042 --> 00:30:39,874
- Uh-huh.

496
00:30:45,375 --> 00:30:46,916
- What's the matter with you?

497
00:30:46,917 --> 00:30:48,832
Any objections to getting out of here?

498
00:30:49,708 --> 00:30:51,916
- No, no, I was just making some plans.

499
00:30:58,542 --> 00:31:00,832
- Parkinson here is our number one power.

500
00:31:00,833 --> 00:31:01,832
Real loaded, huh, Parky?

501
00:31:01,833 --> 00:31:03,124
- Oh, I wouldn't say that.

502
00:31:03,125 --> 00:31:04,041
- That's all you've been saying

503
00:31:04,042 --> 00:31:05,791
ever since we left San Francisco,

504
00:31:05,792 --> 00:31:07,874
big stock and bond man from New York.

505
00:31:07,875 --> 00:31:09,416
- Oh, it's a pleasure to meet a big stock

506
00:31:09,417 --> 00:31:10,749
and bond man from New York.

507
00:31:11,958 --> 00:31:13,582
(light dramatic music)

508
00:31:13,583 --> 00:31:15,291
- We came up as quick as we could.

509
00:31:16,250 --> 00:31:17,707
Took us two days to get here.

510
00:31:21,417 --> 00:31:22,541
Oh, in there, huh?

511
00:31:22,542 --> 00:31:23,374
- Mm-hmm.

512
00:31:25,625 --> 00:31:26,916
- Thank you.

513
00:31:26,917 --> 00:31:30,249
(light dramatic music)

514
00:31:44,750 --> 00:31:46,666
How long has he been like this?

515
00:31:46,667 --> 00:31:47,707
- Most of the time.

516
00:31:48,917 --> 00:31:49,999
- Just the head?

517
00:31:50,000 --> 00:31:51,916
- As far as I know. I don't know much.

518
00:31:53,667 --> 00:31:56,082
- Neither do I, but let's
try a real bandage on him.

519
00:31:56,083 --> 00:31:56,916
- All right.

520
00:31:58,833 --> 00:32:00,957
This is where we were when the plane hit.

521
00:32:00,958 --> 00:32:02,749
Somehow the tail ripped free.

522
00:32:03,625 --> 00:32:04,749
It was good luck, wasn't it?

523
00:32:04,750 --> 00:32:05,582
A miracle.

524
00:32:07,042 --> 00:32:09,082
Red here was standing up in the aisle.

525
00:32:10,292 --> 00:32:13,499
No miracle for him or the others.

526
00:32:16,292 --> 00:32:17,541
Why was that, Mr. Hill?

527
00:32:18,542 --> 00:32:20,291
Because we live such good lives,

528
00:32:20,292 --> 00:32:24,457
or maybe because we've got
such great things ahead of us.

529
00:32:24,458 --> 00:32:26,999
(gentle music)

530
00:32:27,000 --> 00:32:27,916
- I wouldn't know.

531
00:32:30,250 --> 00:32:31,666
Looks like a skull fracture.

532
00:32:33,625 --> 00:32:35,249
Here hold this.

533
00:32:35,250 --> 00:32:37,916
(gentle music)

534
00:32:39,625 --> 00:32:42,291
- He was a nice guy, nice smile.

535
00:32:43,125 --> 00:32:44,624
Only a little bit on the make.

536
00:32:46,500 --> 00:32:48,332
- ls that the way you measure people?

537
00:32:49,292 --> 00:32:50,749
- That's how they measure me.

538
00:32:52,208 --> 00:32:53,124
- Well, you can relax.

539
00:32:53,125 --> 00:32:54,082
I won't bother you.

540
00:32:57,125 --> 00:32:58,707
- Look what are you sore about?

541
00:33:00,042 --> 00:33:00,874
- Nothing.

542
00:33:02,875 --> 00:33:05,499
- Look, I'm sorry we're
such a bother to me.

543
00:33:05,500 --> 00:33:06,916
I’m sorry about him.

544
00:33:06,917 --> 00:33:08,624
I’m sorry about the whole thing.

545
00:33:09,958 --> 00:33:11,707
- Here hold this out.

546
00:33:16,958 --> 00:33:20,499
(Pete singing in foreign language)

547
00:33:20,500 --> 00:33:22,416
- Parky's out getting more firewood.

548
00:33:22,417 --> 00:33:23,749
- Good for Parky.

549
00:33:23,750 --> 00:33:27,291
(light upbeat music)

550
00:33:27,292 --> 00:33:28,749
Well, well, well.

551
00:33:28,750 --> 00:33:30,374
(sultry music)

552
00:33:30,375 --> 00:33:31,666
Little Miss Celebrity.

553
00:33:31,667 --> 00:33:34,124
How the working girl wins a mink coat.

554
00:33:34,125 --> 00:33:35,207
- [Stan] She asked me to get rid of that.

555
00:33:35,208 --> 00:33:37,582
- I don't know why that girl
has a lot to be proud of.

556
00:33:37,583 --> 00:33:38,457
- Give that to me.
(suspenseful music)

557
00:33:38,458 --> 00:33:39,874
- What?
- You've got no right!

558
00:33:39,875 --> 00:33:40,791
- What do you mean?
- Give it!

559
00:33:40,792 --> 00:33:42,666
- Tell her, Mister!
(overlapping voices shouting)

560
00:33:42,667 --> 00:33:44,749
- What's your trouble?

561
00:33:44,750 --> 00:33:46,332
- Your friend here.

562
00:33:47,667 --> 00:33:49,207
- My apologies, Madam.

563
00:33:55,542 --> 00:33:56,749
- May I have it, please?

564
00:33:59,958 --> 00:34:01,916
- Seems I’ve been missing something.

565
00:34:01,917 --> 00:34:03,499
- Nothing important.

566
00:34:03,500 --> 00:34:04,416
But this is.

567
00:34:05,375 --> 00:34:07,041
I have a very badly injured man in there,

568
00:34:07,042 --> 00:34:08,416
and he can't be moved.

569
00:34:08,417 --> 00:34:10,207
He probably has a fractured skull,

570
00:34:10,208 --> 00:34:13,124
and there's no sense in
taking any chance with him.

571
00:34:13,125 --> 00:34:14,457
You'll be all right.

572
00:34:14,458 --> 00:34:16,249
We have a tent and we
brought plenty of food,

573
00:34:16,250 --> 00:34:18,707
so it won't hurt you to
camp out for a while.

574
00:34:18,708 --> 00:34:20,291
- [Sheryl] How long is a while?

575
00:34:20,292 --> 00:34:21,832
- [Jesse] Till I can get a doctor up here.

576
00:34:21,833 --> 00:34:23,749
- [George] That may take weeks.

577
00:34:23,750 --> 00:34:25,249
- I'll leave for Manitou tomorrow morning.

578
00:34:25,250 --> 00:34:26,541
With a little good luck
I’ll have you out here

579
00:34:26,542 --> 00:34:27,582
in four or five days.

580
00:34:28,625 --> 00:34:31,374
In the meantime, keep
yourselves warm and dry.

581
00:34:31,375 --> 00:34:33,749
We don't want anymore
sick people on our hands,

582
00:34:34,750 --> 00:34:37,332
and save your arguments till we get out.

583
00:34:37,333 --> 00:34:39,916
This country's tough enough
without complicating it.

584
00:34:45,750 --> 00:34:48,499
(dramatic music)

585
00:35:06,250 --> 00:35:09,082
(dramatic music)

586
00:35:12,792 --> 00:35:13,957
- [Pete] Come and get it.

587
00:35:16,625 --> 00:35:18,041
- Well, there's mud in your eye.

588
00:35:18,042 --> 00:35:20,332
- Uh-uh, uh-uh, ladies first.

589
00:35:20,333 --> 00:35:21,749
With your permission, Madam?

590
00:35:29,833 --> 00:35:32,499
Allow me to compliment
you on your mink coat.

591
00:35:32,500 --> 00:35:34,207
You wear it like a badge of honor.

592
00:35:35,250 --> 00:35:36,499
- Lay off the floor show.

593
00:35:39,125 --> 00:35:41,582
- Well, isn't this cozy?

594
00:35:41,583 --> 00:35:44,457
I bet you all hate to get
back to New York, huh?

595
00:35:44,458 --> 00:35:46,166
- Not me, Mister.

596
00:35:46,167 --> 00:35:48,499
My discharge is burning
a hole in my pocket.

597
00:35:49,917 --> 00:35:51,499
The old lady's been waiting a long time

598
00:35:51,500 --> 00:35:52,582
for the big furlough.

599
00:35:54,500 --> 00:35:57,082
You know, sometimes I wonder
how we ever got three kids.

600
00:35:57,083 --> 00:35:59,707
(Stan chuckles)

601
00:35:59,708 --> 00:36:01,791
Anybody waiting for you, Sherry?

602
00:36:01,792 --> 00:36:02,957
- Hmm?

603
00:36:03,000 --> 00:36:04,207
Oh, oh, yeah.

604
00:36:04,250 --> 00:36:06,916
Yeah, the fellow I’m gonna marry.

605
00:36:06,917 --> 00:36:08,291
He'll be worried sick.

606
00:36:08,292 --> 00:36:09,957
- Well, let me guess.

607
00:36:09,958 --> 00:36:13,457
He's charming, successful,
nice iron gray hair,

608
00:36:13,458 --> 00:36:16,332
a little bit overweight,
and two divorces, right?

609
00:36:16,333 --> 00:36:17,166
- He's young.

610
00:36:17,167 --> 00:36:19,874
He's younger than you
are and better looking.

611
00:36:19,917 --> 00:36:21,916
But you're right about
his being rich though.

612
00:36:22,792 --> 00:36:27,166
Yeah, he's been away on a
business trip to Europe.

613
00:36:29,250 --> 00:36:30,832
He just got back a few days ago,

614
00:36:32,500 --> 00:36:33,457
and he sent for me.

615
00:36:36,500 --> 00:36:38,332
So, you see, how worried he must be.

616
00:36:57,792 --> 00:36:59,541
Nobody's looked at Red for a while.

617
00:37:06,542 --> 00:37:07,624
- [Pete] Let that girl's story

618
00:37:07,625 --> 00:37:09,416
be an inspiration to you, Parkinson.

619
00:37:11,042 --> 00:37:13,457
- I’m not interested in her affairs.

620
00:37:13,458 --> 00:37:14,374
- Just money, huh?

621
00:37:16,375 --> 00:37:17,957
You know what I wanna know
about a good investment,

622
00:37:18,000 --> 00:37:20,957
like if the chief and I
wanted to invest our savings?

623
00:37:20,958 --> 00:37:22,166
- [George] Certainly when we get back,

624
00:37:22,167 --> 00:37:24,499
I'll be happy to discuss it with you.

625
00:37:24,500 --> 00:37:26,249
- Well, suppose you give me a card.

626
00:37:28,833 --> 00:37:31,416
- I seem to have misplaced my wallet.

627
00:37:31,417 --> 00:37:33,666
- Oh, you'll probably
find it in the morning.

628
00:37:36,125 --> 00:37:39,457
(Pete whistling lively)

629
00:37:42,333 --> 00:37:45,916
(Pete continues whistling)

630
00:37:49,250 --> 00:37:51,916
(gentle music)

631
00:37:53,833 --> 00:37:55,791
- Know what's wrong with the world?

632
00:37:57,292 --> 00:37:58,332
- What's your answer?

633
00:37:59,417 --> 00:38:02,374
- You crash on a mountaintop
in the middle of nowhere,

634
00:38:02,375 --> 00:38:04,291
and you still haven't got any privacy.

635
00:38:06,042 --> 00:38:06,874
- Sorry.

636
00:38:08,167 --> 00:38:08,957
- So am I.

637
00:38:11,542 --> 00:38:12,749
Stay if you want to.

638
00:38:16,875 --> 00:38:20,916
- That story you told in
there wasn't true, was it?

639
00:38:23,625 --> 00:38:25,541
- It was true while I was telling it.

640
00:38:25,542 --> 00:38:26,541
Was I very bad?

641
00:38:28,083 --> 00:38:28,916
- Yep.

642
00:38:29,958 --> 00:38:31,832
- You see what a liar I am, Mr. Hill.

643
00:38:33,750 --> 00:38:35,624
Tell me, Mr. Hill, how does
it feel to talk to a girl

644
00:38:35,625 --> 00:38:38,416
like me who poses for pictures like that?

645
00:38:38,417 --> 00:38:39,332
Interesting, huh?

646
00:38:40,250 --> 00:38:42,166
Almost like reading the Kinsey report.

647
00:38:44,083 --> 00:38:46,207
- Now who's got the
chip on their shoulder?

648
00:38:46,250 --> 00:38:47,416
- Oh, don't misunderstand me.

649
00:38:47,417 --> 00:38:48,666
It's me I don't like.

650
00:38:50,292 --> 00:38:51,374
- Any special reason.

651
00:38:53,250 --> 00:38:55,749
- Because I'm going back to New York

652
00:38:55,750 --> 00:38:57,957
and that splendid career of mine.

653
00:38:57,958 --> 00:39:01,457
(coyote howling)

654
00:39:01,458 --> 00:39:03,541
What's that thing hanging around here for?

655
00:39:05,125 --> 00:39:08,374
(coyote howling)

656
00:39:08,375 --> 00:39:09,207
(rock thumping)

657
00:39:09,208 --> 00:39:11,957
(coyote howling)

658
00:39:12,917 --> 00:39:14,832
- Now what about this career of yours?

659
00:39:15,792 --> 00:39:18,041
- Let me tell you about that.

660
00:39:18,042 --> 00:39:20,666
There's a town in
Washington called Hepwith.

661
00:39:20,667 --> 00:39:22,541
They breed cattle, and nice fellas,

662
00:39:22,542 --> 00:39:25,291
and wholesome girls, and me.

663
00:39:26,417 --> 00:39:29,082
I went to New York to make my fortune.

664
00:39:29,083 --> 00:39:31,666
The only trouble was my
fortune was my frame.

665
00:39:32,750 --> 00:39:34,457
People wanted to buy it all right,

666
00:39:34,458 --> 00:39:36,791
to plaster on magazines
like the one you saw,

667
00:39:37,708 --> 00:39:40,249
and occasionally take it to an apartment

668
00:39:40,250 --> 00:39:42,124
while mama was in the mountains.

669
00:39:44,917 --> 00:39:46,832
"But Hepwith girls aren't like that,"

670
00:39:46,833 --> 00:39:48,041
I kept telling myself.

671
00:39:49,917 --> 00:39:51,124
So after a few photos,

672
00:39:51,125 --> 00:39:52,916
I went back home again.

673
00:39:52,917 --> 00:39:55,249
(chuckles) Score one for Sherry.

674
00:39:56,417 --> 00:39:58,207
- Who scored next?

675
00:39:58,208 --> 00:40:00,082
- Oh, Hepwith, a home run.

676
00:40:01,000 --> 00:40:04,082
Seems those nice fellas
read those fancy magazines.

677
00:40:05,167 --> 00:40:06,374
I was a scarlet woman.

678
00:40:08,208 --> 00:40:10,374
So next stop New York again.

679
00:40:12,458 --> 00:40:16,207
Only this time, Mr. Hill,
I'm going to play to win.

680
00:40:16,208 --> 00:40:18,332
(light dramatic music)

681
00:40:18,333 --> 00:40:21,166
- So Hepwith girls really
are like that, huh?

682
00:40:21,167 --> 00:40:22,499
- That's what the boys say.

683
00:40:23,458 --> 00:40:25,416
The boys must be right?

684
00:40:25,417 --> 00:40:28,749
(light dramatic music)

685
00:40:30,917 --> 00:40:32,082
I’m getting cold.

686
00:40:32,083 --> 00:40:32,916
I better go in.

687
00:40:41,375 --> 00:40:42,207
Well?

688
00:40:44,458 --> 00:40:47,457
(soft tender music)

689
00:40:52,542 --> 00:40:54,374
See how easy it is, Mr. Hill?

690
00:40:54,375 --> 00:40:55,832
You're one of the boys,

691
00:40:57,583 --> 00:40:59,374
only not one of the rich ones.

692
00:41:02,125 --> 00:41:04,541
Well, it's too bad, isn't it?

693
00:41:12,667 --> 00:41:15,291
- Well, this is a fine
time to be getting home.

694
00:41:15,292 --> 00:41:16,666
- Look, I'd like to get some sleep

695
00:41:16,667 --> 00:41:19,666
if somebody will tell me
what the arrangements are?

696
00:41:19,667 --> 00:41:22,749
- Well, I'd be glad to have
you in my sleeping bag.

697
00:41:22,750 --> 00:41:24,874
I'll take the blanket and the lead too.

698
00:41:24,875 --> 00:41:27,207
- My wallet, I remember where I left it.

699
00:41:30,625 --> 00:41:33,374
(dramatic music)

700
00:41:52,875 --> 00:41:55,707
(dramatic music)

701
00:42:23,500 --> 00:42:24,916
- Hey, Jess.

702
00:42:24,917 --> 00:42:26,249
When you get into Manitou,

703
00:42:26,250 --> 00:42:27,749
mail this for me, will you?

704
00:42:27,750 --> 00:42:28,582
- Sure.

705
00:42:30,708 --> 00:42:31,541
- Just a minute.

706
00:42:32,750 --> 00:42:34,957
- Hey, will you hold this
for me a second, doll?

707
00:42:38,500 --> 00:42:39,624
- The address is on it.

708
00:42:40,875 --> 00:42:42,499
- Anybody else got any messages?

709
00:42:43,958 --> 00:42:45,707
- My regards to Broadway.

710
00:42:46,875 --> 00:42:48,416
- Man, how that girl can walk.

711
00:42:49,708 --> 00:42:52,457
- Look you, I’ve walked
this way all my life.

712
00:42:53,417 --> 00:42:56,124
Got any complaints take them
up with my family doctor.

713
00:42:57,375 --> 00:42:59,207
- Don't you ever stop asking for trouble?

714
00:42:59,208 --> 00:43:01,041
- What trouble? She's crazy about me.

715
00:43:01,042 --> 00:43:01,874
- Mr. Hill.

716
00:43:03,250 --> 00:43:04,374
I have to speak to you.

717
00:43:04,375 --> 00:43:05,207
- Go ahead.

718
00:43:07,333 --> 00:43:08,166
- It's...

719
00:43:13,208 --> 00:43:16,457
It's very important that
I leave here with you now.

720
00:43:16,458 --> 00:43:17,874
- Everybody wants to
get off this mountain.

721
00:43:17,875 --> 00:43:19,249
Why should it be you?

722
00:43:19,250 --> 00:43:21,374
- My circumstances are most pressing.

723
00:43:21,375 --> 00:43:22,874
If money would help,

724
00:43:22,875 --> 00:43:24,332
I’ll see that you're paid, Mr. Hill.

725
00:43:24,333 --> 00:43:27,874
Well paid, 500, a thousand dollars!

726
00:43:27,875 --> 00:43:29,624
That would make it
worthwhile, wouldn't it?

727
00:43:29,625 --> 00:43:32,041
(Pete chuckling)

728
00:43:32,042 --> 00:43:33,582
I fail to see the joke.

729
00:43:33,583 --> 00:43:35,624
- Well, the joke's on us, Parky.

730
00:43:35,625 --> 00:43:37,916
The big broker here is
a clerk in a bond house.

731
00:43:37,917 --> 00:43:39,041
He hasn't got a dime.

732
00:43:40,250 --> 00:43:41,291
- What are you talking about?

733
00:43:41,292 --> 00:43:42,124
- You ask him.

734
00:43:45,542 --> 00:43:47,707
- I've made you a proposition, Mr. Hill.

735
00:43:52,708 --> 00:43:53,541
Well?

736
00:43:58,750 --> 00:43:59,707
- Put your money away.

737
00:43:59,750 --> 00:44:00,541
- But I’m offering you--

738
00:44:00,583 --> 00:44:01,541
- I'm going alone.

739
00:44:01,542 --> 00:44:02,624
- Very well.

740
00:44:02,625 --> 00:44:04,166
Two-thousand.

741
00:44:04,167 --> 00:44:05,832
- What's the idea, Daddy Warbucks?

742
00:44:05,833 --> 00:44:06,957
What kind of guy are you?

743
00:44:06,958 --> 00:44:07,874
You think 'cause you got all this dough,

744
00:44:07,875 --> 00:44:09,166
it makes you better than us.

745
00:44:09,167 --> 00:44:09,999
Maybe there's a law!

746
00:44:10,000 --> 00:44:11,582
You shouldn't get cold and hungry!

747
00:44:11,583 --> 00:44:14,624
(airplane engine humming overhead)

748
00:44:14,625 --> 00:44:15,791
Hey, it's a plane.

749
00:44:15,792 --> 00:44:17,666
A plane! They're coming to get us!

750
00:44:17,667 --> 00:44:19,999
Sherry, you want a taxi?

751
00:44:20,000 --> 00:44:24,291
(airplane engine humming)

752
00:44:24,292 --> 00:44:27,374
(dramatic music)

753
00:44:27,417 --> 00:44:28,666
No.

754
00:44:28,667 --> 00:44:29,916
No, they're going the wrong way.

755
00:44:29,917 --> 00:44:31,791
Hey, come back, you nut heads!

756
00:44:31,792 --> 00:44:33,082
Back here!

757
00:44:33,083 --> 00:44:34,707
You can't do that!

758
00:44:34,708 --> 00:44:35,541
(airplane engine humming overhead)

759
00:44:35,542 --> 00:44:37,624
- It can't get low enough to spot us.

760
00:44:37,625 --> 00:44:40,457
(dramatic music)

761
00:44:44,208 --> 00:44:45,041
- Empty.

762
00:44:46,458 --> 00:44:47,707
What about it, Parkinson?

763
00:44:51,083 --> 00:44:53,749
- Red said there was a
treasury guy on the plane.

764
00:44:55,583 --> 00:44:56,916
- Where'd you get that money?

765
00:44:56,917 --> 00:44:58,499
- That's no concern of yours.

766
00:45:06,125 --> 00:45:08,916
- A plane load of people get killed,

767
00:45:08,917 --> 00:45:10,416
you grab the brass ring, huh?

768
00:45:11,750 --> 00:45:12,749
Let's have the rest.

769
00:45:18,667 --> 00:45:19,999
- All that money.

770
00:45:22,208 --> 00:45:24,457
I can't even imagine money like that.

771
00:45:26,250 --> 00:45:28,291
- I didn't mean any harm.

772
00:45:28,292 --> 00:45:29,707
It's just that for once in my life,

773
00:45:29,708 --> 00:45:31,541
I wanted to have something.

774
00:45:31,542 --> 00:45:32,874
I’m a poor man.

775
00:45:32,875 --> 00:45:35,416
- Then why the big zillionaire act?

776
00:45:35,417 --> 00:45:37,082
- You people, you're young.

777
00:45:37,083 --> 00:45:38,874
You don't know what it is to dream.

778
00:45:38,875 --> 00:45:42,041
No, you don't know what it
is till you get to be my age,

779
00:45:42,042 --> 00:45:44,999
and you dream of what
your life might have been.

780
00:45:45,000 --> 00:45:49,041
- What would all of you big
successful men know about that?

781
00:45:49,042 --> 00:45:50,416
- Parkinson, you kill me.

782
00:45:51,250 --> 00:45:53,332
All you had to do was keep your
mouth shut, bury the money,

783
00:45:53,333 --> 00:45:55,332
then hire a guide to bring
you back here next spring,

784
00:45:55,333 --> 00:45:57,291
but you had to blab.

785
00:45:57,292 --> 00:45:58,457
- Shut up.

786
00:45:58,458 --> 00:46:00,957
(dramatic music)

787
00:46:00,958 --> 00:46:03,082
- No!
(suspenseful music)

788
00:46:03,083 --> 00:46:04,457
Now, drop it!

789
00:46:04,458 --> 00:46:07,624
(tense dramatic music)

790
00:46:07,625 --> 00:46:09,166
If you think I'm playing...

791
00:46:09,167 --> 00:46:12,249
(suspenseful music)

792
00:46:16,042 --> 00:46:19,207
Now, get back over there, all of you.

793
00:46:19,208 --> 00:46:20,832
- You're making a lot
of trouble for yourself.

794
00:46:20,833 --> 00:46:21,666
- Get back!

795
00:46:22,542 --> 00:46:25,374
(dramatic music)

796
00:46:30,792 --> 00:46:33,249
- Look, Parky, nobody wants to hurt you.

797
00:46:33,250 --> 00:46:36,082
(dramatic music)

798
00:46:39,792 --> 00:46:43,207
- Look, Mr. Hill, you're
gonna guide me out of here.

799
00:46:43,250 --> 00:46:45,082
Let me make this clear.

800
00:46:45,083 --> 00:46:46,666
I detest my life.

801
00:46:48,292 --> 00:46:49,499
This can change it.

802
00:46:50,625 --> 00:46:52,457
If you get in my way, I’ll kill you.

803
00:46:53,375 --> 00:46:55,249
- Parkinson, I got to hand it to you.

804
00:46:55,250 --> 00:46:56,666
You're a big man after all.

805
00:46:58,917 --> 00:47:00,207
- I feel big with a quarter of

806
00:47:00,208 --> 00:47:01,707
a million dollars, Mr. Corder.

807
00:47:05,375 --> 00:47:07,082
Well, do we understand each other?

808
00:47:08,625 --> 00:47:10,457
Your answer, Mr. Hill!

809
00:47:10,458 --> 00:47:13,291
(dramatic music)

810
00:47:16,792 --> 00:47:18,041
- You've got the gun.

811
00:47:18,042 --> 00:47:19,957
- [George] Well, then we
better leave right away.

812
00:47:21,250 --> 00:47:23,916
- [Sheryl] Some dreamer
you turned out to be.

813
00:47:23,917 --> 00:47:26,374
- Uh, get me the other
pack, will you, Pete?

814
00:47:26,375 --> 00:47:29,207
(dramatic music)

815
00:47:37,542 --> 00:47:38,374
- Okay, Pappy?

816
00:47:40,167 --> 00:47:40,999
- Go ahead.

817
00:47:42,292 --> 00:47:45,124
(dramatic music)

818
00:47:49,042 --> 00:47:50,082
- No deal, Parkinson.

819
00:47:51,250 --> 00:47:52,082
Lay it down.

820
00:47:53,333 --> 00:47:54,707
(gun thumping)

821
00:47:54,708 --> 00:47:55,541
That's a big boy.

822
00:47:55,542 --> 00:47:56,416
Don't get excited.

823
00:47:58,958 --> 00:48:02,082
(light dramatic music)

824
00:48:02,083 --> 00:48:04,332
All right, Jesse, you
heard what the man said.

825
00:48:05,417 --> 00:48:06,624
Let's get moving.

826
00:48:06,625 --> 00:48:09,416
(dramatic music)

827
00:48:09,417 --> 00:48:12,249
- Look, Pete, if this is
your idea of a joke...

828
00:48:12,250 --> 00:48:14,916
- Sure, just a barrel of fun.

829
00:48:15,917 --> 00:48:17,332
Look at his face.

830
00:48:18,500 --> 00:48:20,666
- I'm sorry, Jesse, the
stakes got too high.

831
00:48:21,750 --> 00:48:24,374
- No dice, Pete, I’ve seen
you run a bluff before.

832
00:48:24,375 --> 00:48:27,374
(gunfire blasting)

833
00:48:27,375 --> 00:48:29,207
- Don't make me do without you, Jess.

834
00:48:29,208 --> 00:48:31,332
(gun cocking)

835
00:48:31,333 --> 00:48:32,374
Pick up your rifle, Parkinson.

836
00:48:32,375 --> 00:48:34,707
You just bought yourself
some high-priced help.

837
00:48:37,250 --> 00:48:39,249
- I think I've made a wise partnership.

838
00:48:39,250 --> 00:48:40,666
50-50 basis?

839
00:48:40,667 --> 00:48:41,957
- A pleasure.

840
00:48:41,958 --> 00:48:43,999
All right, we're all going camping

841
00:48:44,000 --> 00:48:45,249
before that plane gets back here,

842
00:48:45,250 --> 00:48:48,041
and nobody's gonna get any brave ideas,

843
00:48:48,042 --> 00:48:49,457
because one of us will always be awake

844
00:48:49,458 --> 00:48:50,624
just to watch the store.

845
00:48:52,500 --> 00:48:53,332
Okay, chief?

846
00:48:54,583 --> 00:48:55,416
- Anything you say.

847
00:48:55,417 --> 00:48:57,916
I got the cleanest nose in town.

848
00:48:57,917 --> 00:48:59,249
- Sherry.

849
00:48:59,250 --> 00:49:01,291
- All I want out of this is my mink coat.

850
00:49:02,500 --> 00:49:04,957
- Well, we might be able to
do even better than that.

851
00:49:06,167 --> 00:49:08,957
Look, Jess, half this box buys
my way back to the Riviera.

852
00:49:08,958 --> 00:49:10,666
Fun in the sun.

853
00:49:10,667 --> 00:49:13,666
You wouldn't wanna hate a
guy for that, would you?

854
00:49:13,667 --> 00:49:14,791
- What about the pilot?

855
00:49:15,792 --> 00:49:17,666
- [Pete] He goes with us.

856
00:49:17,667 --> 00:49:19,291
- You'll kill him.

857
00:49:19,292 --> 00:49:20,457
- Sorry, everybody plays.

858
00:49:20,458 --> 00:49:22,166
Everybody wins.

859
00:49:22,167 --> 00:49:25,082
Maybe it's the quickest
way back to a doctor.

860
00:49:25,083 --> 00:49:26,624
- My old buddy,

861
00:49:26,625 --> 00:49:28,582
still figure all you have
to do is set the screws,

862
00:49:28,583 --> 00:49:31,749
and everything comes out
the way you want it, huh?

863
00:49:31,750 --> 00:49:32,832
Well look out there.

864
00:49:33,833 --> 00:49:36,666
There's a blizzard fixing
to cut loose any hour.

865
00:49:36,667 --> 00:49:39,124
Temperatures dropping every minute.

866
00:49:39,125 --> 00:49:42,374
Now if you think you can
climb those hills, go ahead.

867
00:49:42,375 --> 00:49:44,832
But together, we haven't got a prayer.

868
00:49:44,833 --> 00:49:46,166
- I’m not worried, Jess.

869
00:49:47,542 --> 00:49:49,332
You'll get us out of here just fine.

870
00:49:50,833 --> 00:49:51,707
All right, let's break camp.

871
00:49:51,708 --> 00:49:53,374
Chief, you knock down that shack.

872
00:49:53,375 --> 00:49:54,832
- Why?
- 'Cause I’m the admiral.

873
00:49:54,833 --> 00:49:56,957
- Aye, aye, Admiral,

874
00:49:56,958 --> 00:49:57,999
- You better build one of those fancy

875
00:49:58,000 --> 00:49:59,416
mountain stretchers for the pilot.

876
00:49:59,417 --> 00:50:01,124
- Pete, do you know what you're doing?

877
00:50:01,125 --> 00:50:02,707
- Believe me, clear as crystal.

878
00:50:03,833 --> 00:50:06,332
Hey, get your things, bright eyes.

879
00:50:06,333 --> 00:50:07,166
- You bet.

880
00:50:11,208 --> 00:50:13,499
- Oh, Parkinson, I got a tip for you.

881
00:50:13,500 --> 00:50:14,957
- If it's concerning that girl--

882
00:50:15,000 --> 00:50:15,832
- No.

883
00:50:17,250 --> 00:50:18,249
I mean serious.

884
00:50:19,500 --> 00:50:21,916
Nobody knows that I’m in on this.

885
00:50:22,875 --> 00:50:25,207
If they were to find
your wallet in the wreck,

886
00:50:26,500 --> 00:50:29,041
nobody'd ever look for
you either, would they?

887
00:50:29,042 --> 00:50:30,707
- But the others, surely they'll tell.

888
00:50:30,708 --> 00:50:31,541
- No.

889
00:50:33,250 --> 00:50:35,291
No, I don't think they'll
tell anybody anything.

890
00:50:43,958 --> 00:50:46,666
Oh, I’d leave that here if I were you.

891
00:50:54,750 --> 00:50:58,332
(Pete whistling cunningly)

892
00:51:08,167 --> 00:51:10,916
(dramatic music)

893
00:51:28,250 --> 00:51:31,082
(dramatic music)

894
00:51:47,250 --> 00:51:50,457
Oh, you want papa to kiss
it and make it better?

895
00:51:50,458 --> 00:51:52,666
- I want papa to fall down a ravine.

896
00:51:52,667 --> 00:51:54,832
- You know what keeps me warm, Sherry?

897
00:51:54,833 --> 00:51:56,791
The thought of all those balmy breezes.

898
00:51:57,708 --> 00:51:59,957
How'd you like to trade
that coat for a bikini?

899
00:51:59,958 --> 00:52:00,916
- What and give up all this.

900
00:52:00,917 --> 00:52:04,082
- The trouble is you
haven't seen me at my best.

901
00:52:04,083 --> 00:52:05,541
You'd love me on the Riviera.

902
00:52:07,958 --> 00:52:10,791
(dramatic music)

903
00:52:20,125 --> 00:52:21,207
- Mr. Corder!

904
00:52:22,917 --> 00:52:24,041
This is hers.

905
00:52:24,042 --> 00:52:25,499
She's been marking the trail.

906
00:52:26,500 --> 00:52:29,582
(suspenseful music)

907
00:52:30,917 --> 00:52:31,832
- How long?

908
00:52:33,958 --> 00:52:35,957
Honey, you haven't seen
me at my worst either.

909
00:52:35,958 --> 00:52:37,166
- You want me to beat it out of her?

910
00:52:37,167 --> 00:52:38,499
- I don't think he likes
you very much, Sherry.

911
00:52:38,500 --> 00:52:39,457
You better tell us.

912
00:52:41,417 --> 00:52:42,249
All right.

913
00:52:43,500 --> 00:52:46,166
(George groans)

914
00:52:49,792 --> 00:52:52,582
- Touch her again, you can
find your own way out of here.

915
00:52:54,625 --> 00:52:55,832
- He's right, Parkinson.

916
00:52:56,750 --> 00:52:57,624
A deal's a deal.

917
00:53:04,958 --> 00:53:05,874
I’ll double back a ways

918
00:53:05,875 --> 00:53:07,874
and see if she left any other souvenirs.

919
00:53:09,167 --> 00:53:11,916
(Sheryl gasping)

920
00:53:17,083 --> 00:53:19,374
- Mighty brave girls
they raise in Hepwith.

921
00:53:21,125 --> 00:53:23,291
- I finally made the big time.

922
00:53:23,292 --> 00:53:25,666
I got slapped around by a guy with

923
00:53:25,667 --> 00:53:27,749
a quarter of a million bucks.

924
00:53:27,750 --> 00:53:28,957
- Let me see that ankle.

925
00:53:32,333 --> 00:53:34,041
- Nice legs for a mountain goat.

926
00:53:35,083 --> 00:53:36,082
- Did you sprain it?

927
00:53:36,958 --> 00:53:38,874
- No, no, I don't think so.

928
00:53:38,875 --> 00:53:40,707
- You guys make me sick.

929
00:53:40,708 --> 00:53:43,499
Slobbering over her like she
was a queen or something.

930
00:53:43,500 --> 00:53:44,957
- Now look, Buster.

931
00:53:44,958 --> 00:53:47,124
- Maybe you won't pose for
pictures like that anymore.

932
00:53:47,125 --> 00:53:48,207
Not after this trip.

933
00:53:48,208 --> 00:53:49,291
- Why you!
- Uh-uh!

934
00:53:53,042 --> 00:53:54,749
- What's he got against me anyway?

935
00:53:57,208 --> 00:53:58,957
- Did you leave anything
else back there in a trail?

936
00:53:58,958 --> 00:54:01,832
- No, I just got the bright idea.

937
00:54:03,000 --> 00:54:04,291
Hey, maybe if somebody's looking for us--

938
00:54:04,292 --> 00:54:05,624
- I wouldn't count on that.

939
00:54:07,000 --> 00:54:08,666
Might as well face this fact too.

940
00:54:10,167 --> 00:54:11,332
Pete wiped that camp out,

941
00:54:11,333 --> 00:54:13,082
so it would look like no survivors.

942
00:54:14,083 --> 00:54:16,666
As far as anybody knows,
you both died in the crash.

943
00:54:18,792 --> 00:54:21,166
He's only keeping you
along because he needs me.

944
00:54:25,792 --> 00:54:27,124
And when he doesn't...

945
00:54:30,542 --> 00:54:31,707
- You know, it's funny,

946
00:54:32,625 --> 00:54:34,957
before I didn't much care
if I was dead or not.

947
00:54:36,958 --> 00:54:39,416
Now I just don't go for the idea.

948
00:54:39,417 --> 00:54:41,041
(Stan laughs)

949
00:54:41,042 --> 00:54:43,207
- Two wars and not a scratch.

950
00:54:43,208 --> 00:54:44,832
You know what really kills me?

951
00:54:44,833 --> 00:54:46,457
My wife makes me get out of the Navy

952
00:54:46,458 --> 00:54:47,791
'cause it's too dangerous.

953
00:54:53,708 --> 00:54:55,416
(sighs) I say we make a play

954
00:54:55,417 --> 00:54:56,999
for this knucklehead right now.

955
00:54:58,542 --> 00:55:00,166
- Take it easy.

956
00:55:00,167 --> 00:55:01,957
He's high as a kite,

957
00:55:01,958 --> 00:55:03,582
and don't think he won't shoot.

958
00:55:05,208 --> 00:55:06,666
- What do we do?

959
00:55:06,667 --> 00:55:09,291
Sit here and wait for a shot in the back?

960
00:55:09,292 --> 00:55:11,874
(gentle music)

961
00:55:19,333 --> 00:55:22,166
(dramatic music)

962
00:55:36,542 --> 00:55:38,499
- His heart's going like a trip hammer.

963
00:55:39,667 --> 00:55:40,957
- Hey, Jess.

964
00:55:40,958 --> 00:55:43,791
(dramatic music)

965
00:55:45,375 --> 00:55:46,416
Let's get some water.

966
00:55:56,125 --> 00:55:59,541
(Pete whistling lightly)

967
00:56:03,125 --> 00:56:06,457
(tense dramatic music)

968
00:56:09,500 --> 00:56:11,624
How far is the cabin?

969
00:56:11,625 --> 00:56:12,457
- Three days.

970
00:56:13,417 --> 00:56:14,832
- That's kind of long, isn't it?

971
00:56:14,833 --> 00:56:17,416
- With a girl and a stretcher
it's pretty good time.

972
00:56:20,292 --> 00:56:21,499
- You hate my guts, huh?

973
00:56:25,375 --> 00:56:27,999
Look, Jesse, if the money was
in a bank or in a store window

974
00:56:28,000 --> 00:56:30,207
or in somebody's pocket
walking down Fifth Avenue,

975
00:56:30,208 --> 00:56:32,457
I’d say, "All right, you leave it there."

976
00:56:32,458 --> 00:56:35,916
But out here in the middle of
nowhere belonging to nobody?

977
00:56:35,917 --> 00:56:38,957
Why you don't pass a
thing like that up, Jesse.

978
00:56:38,958 --> 00:56:39,791
- What do you want me to do?

979
00:56:39,792 --> 00:56:40,791
Pat you on your head, and say,

980
00:56:40,792 --> 00:56:42,457
"That's all right, Sonny."

981
00:56:42,500 --> 00:56:43,832
- Don't get wise, Jesse.

982
00:56:46,542 --> 00:56:48,291
You know why I wiped out that camp.

983
00:56:49,833 --> 00:56:50,666
When I leave these mountains,

984
00:56:50,667 --> 00:56:53,041
I don't have to look over
my shoulder ever again.

985
00:56:54,833 --> 00:56:57,374
Now just don't make me hurt you, Jess.

986
00:56:57,375 --> 00:56:58,874
There's plenty for both of us.

987
00:57:01,542 --> 00:57:03,541
Why, you know, three
days ago we were friends.

988
00:57:03,542 --> 00:57:04,499
- Friends!

989
00:57:04,500 --> 00:57:07,124
(tense music)

990
00:57:07,125 --> 00:57:08,457
You've been planning how to kill us

991
00:57:08,458 --> 00:57:09,957
ever since we left that wreck.

992
00:57:10,875 --> 00:57:13,499
(tense dramatic music)

993
00:57:13,500 --> 00:57:15,374
Here's a piece of friendly advice.

994
00:57:16,333 --> 00:57:18,957
Alone in these mountains
peaks, you're dead.

995
00:57:18,958 --> 00:57:21,499
You're stuck to me as
tight as I'm stuck to you.

996
00:57:23,583 --> 00:57:25,957
Only one of us are gonna
walk out of here alive.

997
00:57:28,125 --> 00:57:30,082
You figure out which one.

998
00:57:30,083 --> 00:57:32,916
(dramatic music)

999
00:57:47,000 --> 00:57:49,749
That coat of yours is
getting pretty beat up.

1000
00:57:49,750 --> 00:57:51,457
- That was the best thing I owned.

1001
00:57:57,708 --> 00:57:59,332
(Red sighing)

1002
00:57:59,333 --> 00:58:01,749
It's a funny thing about a coat.

1003
00:58:01,750 --> 00:58:04,041
If it keeps you warm,
that's all that matters.

1004
00:58:06,500 --> 00:58:07,332
Live and learn.

1005
00:58:08,708 --> 00:58:10,166
- You're quite a gal, Sherry.

1006
00:58:11,125 --> 00:58:12,957
- I just crack up well.

1007
00:58:12,958 --> 00:58:15,374
- Well, how about those
sleeping arrangements?

1008
00:58:19,875 --> 00:58:20,874
Who gets the tent?

1009
00:58:23,792 --> 00:58:25,332
What's your pleasure, Sherry?

1010
00:58:25,333 --> 00:58:26,791
- You giving me a choice?

1011
00:58:29,500 --> 00:58:31,541
- Well, let's look at it this way.

1012
00:58:31,542 --> 00:58:33,541
I’ve got a nice face, money, a future,

1013
00:58:35,042 --> 00:58:36,957
and you've got a nice everything

1014
00:58:36,958 --> 00:58:38,416
but no money and no future.

1015
00:58:40,167 --> 00:58:41,166
Just think about it.

1016
00:58:43,500 --> 00:58:46,332
It's nice to lie on a warm
beach in a $50 bathing suit.

1017
00:58:48,958 --> 00:58:51,416
This is your last chance
to change sides, Sherry.

1018
00:58:53,625 --> 00:58:56,291
- Too bad I didn't know
you before the plane crash.

1019
00:58:57,542 --> 00:58:58,832
- Well, it's not too late.

1020
00:59:00,083 --> 00:59:01,749
(Sheryl chuckling)

1021
00:59:01,750 --> 00:59:03,082
- Oh, yes it is.

1022
00:59:04,833 --> 00:59:08,124
Before I would've gone like
60 for that pitch of yours.

1023
00:59:12,292 --> 00:59:14,124
Now you just make me sick.

1024
00:59:19,458 --> 00:59:21,832
- The little lady wins
herself a plate of beans.

1025
00:59:24,375 --> 00:59:25,666
- [Pete] You people are
gonna have to give up

1026
00:59:25,667 --> 00:59:26,582
eating for a while!

1027
00:59:26,583 --> 00:59:28,541
- How do you expect us to
climb these stinking hills?

1028
00:59:28,542 --> 00:59:30,082
- The way I see it, ladies and gentlemen,

1029
00:59:30,083 --> 00:59:31,416
the hungrier you are, the faster we're

1030
00:59:31,417 --> 00:59:32,957
gonna get to where we're going.

1031
00:59:32,958 --> 00:59:34,749
- Boy, what a childhood you must have had.

1032
00:59:34,750 --> 00:59:35,582
- It was great!

1033
00:59:40,542 --> 00:59:41,541
My mother loved me.

1034
00:59:43,375 --> 00:59:44,582
No sad stories.

1035
00:59:45,917 --> 00:59:47,207
I had everything I wanted.

1036
00:59:48,708 --> 00:59:50,499
I'm a self-made success.

1037
00:59:50,500 --> 00:59:51,832
- Maybe you'd be more successful

1038
00:59:51,833 --> 00:59:53,624
if you kept your mind off that girl.

1039
00:59:54,583 --> 00:59:56,749
- All you have to worry
about is the money.

1040
00:59:58,750 --> 01:00:00,832
- How maybe you never
get a chance to spend it.

1041
01:00:00,833 --> 01:00:03,332
- The law is no problem for me, Mr. Hill.

1042
01:00:03,333 --> 01:00:05,832
You see, I died in that plane crash.

1043
01:00:05,833 --> 01:00:06,999
- Shut up.

1044
01:00:07,000 --> 01:00:08,624
- Sounds like Pete's idea.

1045
01:00:08,625 --> 01:00:11,082
Real easy way to get rid of
you when the time comes, huh?

1046
01:00:12,042 --> 01:00:13,457
(Jesse groans)

1047
01:00:13,458 --> 01:00:14,291
- Why you!

1048
01:00:16,458 --> 01:00:17,916
- All right, take him in the tent.

1049
01:00:17,917 --> 01:00:20,499
(Jesse groans)

1050
01:00:35,917 --> 01:00:36,832
Don't get spooky on me.

1051
01:00:36,833 --> 01:00:38,499
We're still a long way from home.

1052
01:00:38,500 --> 01:00:39,707
- He said you'd kill me.

1053
01:00:39,708 --> 01:00:41,457
Well, why not?

1054
01:00:41,458 --> 01:00:42,666
How do I know you won't?

1055
01:00:49,042 --> 01:00:50,832
- There's your guarantee, Parkinson.

1056
01:00:52,083 --> 01:00:53,082
You shoot first.

1057
01:00:54,875 --> 01:00:56,916
That way you get to keep all the money

1058
01:00:56,917 --> 01:00:58,999
and you get to watch them all by yourself.

1059
01:01:00,292 --> 01:01:01,791
(gentle music)

1060
01:01:01,792 --> 01:01:02,832
You get to figure out what

1061
01:01:02,833 --> 01:01:04,374
Jesse has in the back of his mind,

1062
01:01:04,375 --> 01:01:06,082
because he has something up there.

1063
01:01:07,667 --> 01:01:09,041
You get to stay awake all night

1064
01:01:09,042 --> 01:01:11,416
and walk all day and stay
awake all night again.

1065
01:01:13,833 --> 01:01:16,124
And maybe you get to die
here like Jesse said.

1066
01:01:16,125 --> 01:01:18,249
(coyote howling)

1067
01:01:18,250 --> 01:01:19,666
And that coyote will come down here

1068
01:01:19,667 --> 01:01:21,291
and nibble on your head.

1069
01:01:21,292 --> 01:01:23,124
(light dramatic music)

1070
01:01:23,125 --> 01:01:24,249
So go ahead and shoot.

1071
01:01:29,083 --> 01:01:30,791
Now you know why we need each other.

1072
01:01:34,708 --> 01:01:35,582
You go to sleep.

1073
01:01:37,458 --> 01:01:38,749
I'll take the first watch.

1074
01:01:40,708 --> 01:01:43,541
(dramatic music)

1075
01:01:50,292 --> 01:01:51,499
- The skin's not broken.

1076
01:01:53,208 --> 01:01:54,249
- All the battles I’ve been in

1077
01:01:54,250 --> 01:01:55,707
and for the first time in my life,

1078
01:01:55,708 --> 01:01:57,916
I really wanna kill somebody.

1079
01:01:59,250 --> 01:02:00,582
- Now if you wanna go home,

1080
01:02:02,208 --> 01:02:03,374
you can't fight the rifles.

1081
01:02:03,375 --> 01:02:05,749
- And I can't sit around
waiting to get shot either.

1082
01:02:05,750 --> 01:02:06,957
- Leppich!
- You'll still be

1083
01:02:06,958 --> 01:02:08,707
playing it cool when
you're laying in a ditch.

1084
01:02:08,750 --> 01:02:10,207
- Listen to me.

1085
01:02:10,250 --> 01:02:12,707
We're only a day away from
a mountain artillery outfit.

1086
01:02:12,708 --> 01:02:13,541
- What?

1087
01:02:13,542 --> 01:02:15,791
- They move in the firing range near here.

1088
01:02:15,792 --> 01:02:17,374
- How do you know?

1089
01:02:17,375 --> 01:02:19,166
- They’ll be in position tomorrow night,

1090
01:02:19,167 --> 01:02:20,832
and so will we

1091
01:02:20,833 --> 01:02:23,416
if I can swing Pete away from the cabin.

1092
01:02:23,417 --> 01:02:24,707
- What if he don't buy it?

1093
01:02:26,958 --> 01:02:28,124
- Then we're out of luck?

1094
01:02:28,125 --> 01:02:28,957
- Yeah.

1095
01:02:31,625 --> 01:02:33,624
Something to think about, ain't it.

1096
01:02:35,792 --> 01:02:38,249
(wind blowing)

1097
01:02:38,250 --> 01:02:40,999
(coyote howling)

1098
01:02:45,708 --> 01:02:48,291
(wind howling)

1099
01:02:56,292 --> 01:02:58,999
(dramatic music)

1100
01:02:59,000 --> 01:02:59,832
- Jess?

1101
01:03:05,458 --> 01:03:06,291
Jess?

1102
01:03:10,292 --> 01:03:12,457
Jess, why did you go
looking for the plane?

1103
01:03:13,917 --> 01:03:15,916
You had your life the way you wanted it.

1104
01:03:15,917 --> 01:03:17,124
You didn't even know us.

1105
01:03:19,958 --> 01:03:21,999
But now maybe you're
gonna get killed for it.

1106
01:03:25,667 --> 01:03:27,041
It's a great lesson in that.

1107
01:03:28,583 --> 01:03:30,166
(gentle music)

1108
01:03:30,167 --> 01:03:30,999
- What lesson?

1109
01:03:32,417 --> 01:03:34,082
Like trying to plant that compact

1110
01:03:35,375 --> 01:03:36,957
or turn down Pete's proposition.

1111
01:03:40,417 --> 01:03:42,457
You're not such a tough guy, Sherry.

1112
01:03:44,042 --> 01:03:47,124
(light tender music)

1113
01:04:10,667 --> 01:04:13,291
(dramatic music)

1114
01:04:13,292 --> 01:04:15,874
(wind blowing)

1115
01:04:18,083 --> 01:04:21,082
(suspenseful music)

1116
01:04:25,833 --> 01:04:28,582
(wind whistling)

1117
01:04:32,500 --> 01:04:35,416
(foreboding music)

1118
01:04:39,708 --> 01:04:42,791
(suspenseful music)

1119
01:04:50,250 --> 01:04:51,291
(wind blowing)

1120
01:04:51,292 --> 01:04:54,624
(light dramatic music)

1121
01:04:58,125 --> 01:04:59,041
- We're gonna move fast today.

1122
01:04:59,042 --> 01:05:01,416
I wanna make the ridge by 10 o'clock.

1123
01:05:01,417 --> 01:05:02,416
- Anything you say.

1124
01:05:09,667 --> 01:05:12,499
(dramatic music)

1125
01:05:18,917 --> 01:05:21,291
- Jess?

1126
01:05:21,292 --> 01:05:22,124
Jess!

1127
01:05:24,042 --> 01:05:24,916
- Yeah.

1128
01:05:24,917 --> 01:05:27,749
(dramatic music)

1129
01:05:32,417 --> 01:05:33,249
- You knew he'd die.

1130
01:05:33,250 --> 01:05:35,332
You knew he couldn't stand it!

1131
01:05:35,333 --> 01:05:36,541
- Save your breath.

1132
01:05:37,417 --> 01:05:38,624
- He was dead all the time.

1133
01:05:38,625 --> 01:05:39,999
This just makes it official.

1134
01:05:41,042 --> 01:05:43,874
(dramatic music)

1135
01:05:47,333 --> 01:05:49,499
What are you all looking at?

1136
01:05:50,333 --> 01:05:52,207
Bury him and let's move.

1137
01:05:52,208 --> 01:05:55,124
(foreboding music)

1138
01:06:02,083 --> 01:06:04,666
(wind howling)

1139
01:06:09,583 --> 01:06:11,207
From here it's all downhill.

1140
01:06:12,500 --> 01:06:13,832
- We can't make it.

1141
01:06:13,833 --> 01:06:15,291
- [Pete] We came up.

1142
01:06:15,292 --> 01:06:16,332
- That was two of us.

1143
01:06:16,333 --> 01:06:17,874
We'll have to follow the ridge.

1144
01:06:19,167 --> 01:06:21,249
- And wait for this blizzard
to catch up with us?

1145
01:06:21,250 --> 01:06:24,082
(scoffs) I was never
partial to the long way.

1146
01:06:25,542 --> 01:06:27,541
From here we can almost see the cabin.

1147
01:06:28,542 --> 01:06:30,791
- We'll all be killed going down there.

1148
01:06:30,792 --> 01:06:32,957
- The sergeant's gonna
make it easy for us.

1149
01:06:33,875 --> 01:06:35,249
He's gonna rig a guide rope

1150
01:06:35,250 --> 01:06:37,291
and let us down nice and gentle.

1151
01:06:37,292 --> 01:06:39,874
(wind howling)

1152
01:06:41,083 --> 01:06:42,707
- That's a two man job.

1153
01:06:44,583 --> 01:06:45,416
- Well, let's go.

1154
01:06:47,667 --> 01:06:50,249
Hey, Parky, you play soldier.

1155
01:06:50,250 --> 01:06:52,291
(wind blowing)

1156
01:06:52,292 --> 01:06:54,332
If our friend here gives you any trouble,

1157
01:06:55,833 --> 01:06:56,791
put a bullet in him

1158
01:06:59,125 --> 01:06:59,999
and the girl.

1159
01:07:05,625 --> 01:07:08,624
(suspenseful music)

1160
01:07:41,667 --> 01:07:44,666
(suspenseful music)

1161
01:08:21,958 --> 01:08:23,082
(wind blowing)

1162
01:08:23,083 --> 01:08:25,832
(dramatic music)

1163
01:08:38,958 --> 01:08:41,541
(wind howling)

1164
01:08:48,458 --> 01:08:51,457
(suspenseful music)

1165
01:09:14,625 --> 01:09:17,707
(suspenseful music)

1166
01:09:29,875 --> 01:09:32,374
Jesse, there's no handholds up here.

1167
01:09:33,292 --> 01:09:34,291
- Grab the piton.

1168
01:09:35,167 --> 01:09:38,332
(tense dramatic music)

1169
01:09:38,333 --> 01:09:40,707
(Pete screaming)

1170
01:09:40,708 --> 01:09:41,707
(Pete groaning)

1171
01:09:41,708 --> 01:09:43,082
(wind blowing)

1172
01:09:43,083 --> 01:09:46,166
(suspenseful music)

1173
01:09:54,125 --> 01:09:55,666
Pete, don't struggle.

1174
01:09:56,833 --> 01:09:59,916
(suspenseful music)

1175
01:10:05,042 --> 01:10:06,166
Grab the fixed rope.

1176
01:10:07,417 --> 01:10:10,749
(suspenseful music)

1177
01:10:10,750 --> 01:10:12,249
Now start working your way up.

1178
01:10:14,125 --> 01:10:16,124
(tense dramatic music)

1179
01:10:16,125 --> 01:10:16,957
- I can't!

1180
01:10:17,833 --> 01:10:20,124
- Think of the money, Pete.

1181
01:10:20,125 --> 01:10:23,957
(tense dramatic music)

1182
01:10:24,000 --> 01:10:25,041
All that money.

1183
01:10:26,458 --> 01:10:29,457
(suspenseful music)

1184
01:10:48,167 --> 01:10:50,749
(wind blowing)

1185
01:11:03,375 --> 01:11:05,041
- All right.

1186
01:11:05,042 --> 01:11:06,374
All right, Jesse, you win.

1187
01:11:08,250 --> 01:11:11,041
We'll take the long way.

1188
01:11:11,042 --> 01:11:13,791
(wind whistling)

1189
01:11:21,833 --> 01:11:24,666
(Sheryl gasping)

1190
01:11:27,083 --> 01:11:28,291
- I can't!

1191
01:11:28,292 --> 01:11:30,166
- Not much further we'll
reach a valley in a few hours.

1192
01:11:30,167 --> 01:11:31,541
- (crying) Oh, please!

1193
01:11:31,542 --> 01:11:32,541
- You got to keep going, you hear me.

1194
01:11:32,542 --> 01:11:33,624
Walker or crawl I don't care,

1195
01:11:33,625 --> 01:11:35,291
but you got to keep going!

1196
01:11:35,292 --> 01:11:36,207
Keep going!

1197
01:11:45,125 --> 01:11:47,791
(Stan coughing)

1198
01:11:55,667 --> 01:11:56,707
- Come on.

1199
01:11:56,750 --> 01:11:57,707
Come on.

1200
01:12:04,667 --> 01:12:07,499
(dramatic music)

1201
01:12:15,708 --> 01:12:17,832
- Wouldn't mind passing
that around, would you?

1202
01:12:25,375 --> 01:12:28,457
- Now suppose you show us where we are?

1203
01:12:28,458 --> 01:12:30,332
- I can show you from up on that ridge.

1204
01:12:37,458 --> 01:12:40,874
- You better come along too, sailor.

1205
01:12:40,875 --> 01:12:44,207
(light dramatic music)

1206
01:13:00,125 --> 01:13:01,166
- There's your route.

1207
01:13:02,208 --> 01:13:03,707
That's Pepper Valley.

1208
01:13:03,708 --> 01:13:04,957
We'll stay there tonight.

1209
01:13:07,042 --> 01:13:08,999
Cabin's on the other side of that peak.

1210
01:13:13,958 --> 01:13:16,374
(Sheryl gasping deeply)

1211
01:13:16,375 --> 01:13:17,207
- Ms. Gregory.

1212
01:13:18,708 --> 01:13:19,749
I've come to the conclusion

1213
01:13:19,750 --> 01:13:21,707
I’ll never leave these mountains alive.

1214
01:13:23,167 --> 01:13:25,499
- You don't know how that touches me.

1215
01:13:25,500 --> 01:13:27,207
- I could tell you something.

1216
01:13:27,208 --> 01:13:30,041
Something important if you'd only...

1217
01:13:30,042 --> 01:13:31,332
- [Sheryl] What do you want?

1218
01:13:33,208 --> 01:13:35,207
- You've been admired before by men my age

1219
01:13:35,208 --> 01:13:36,332
and been nice to them.

1220
01:13:39,292 --> 01:13:41,457
- So that's what's been
bothering you, huh?

1221
01:13:46,667 --> 01:13:50,124
You're just another one of the boys.

1222
01:13:50,125 --> 01:13:53,457
(light dramatic music)

1223
01:13:54,708 --> 01:13:58,374
Well, Mr. Parkinson, so what?

1224
01:14:00,625 --> 01:14:03,166
- If things were different
and we were in the city

1225
01:14:03,167 --> 01:14:05,832
and I had money, you'd be different too.

1226
01:14:06,833 --> 01:14:09,624
Well, there's a way you
can have all that money.

1227
01:14:09,625 --> 01:14:11,541
You are young and warm.

1228
01:14:12,667 --> 01:14:15,707
(dramatic music)

1229
01:14:15,708 --> 01:14:18,791
(suspenseful music)

1230
01:14:25,708 --> 01:14:26,541
- Get over there.

1231
01:14:29,833 --> 01:14:32,624
You open your mouth, and I’ll kill you.

1232
01:14:53,292 --> 01:14:54,457
- Nice going, Parky.

1233
01:14:57,292 --> 01:14:58,416
- Lay down your rifle.

1234
01:15:02,208 --> 01:15:03,832
- That's the way to act, Sherry.

1235
01:15:04,708 --> 01:15:06,999
I don't want you to get
the idea I'm so brave.

1236
01:15:08,042 --> 01:15:10,499
It's just that there's no
bullets in Parky's gun.

1237
01:15:11,542 --> 01:15:14,041
(tense music)

1238
01:15:18,542 --> 01:15:21,541
(suspenseful music)

1239
01:15:21,542 --> 01:15:23,957
(gun clicks)

1240
01:15:27,500 --> 01:15:28,749
Just in case you got sloppy,

1241
01:15:28,750 --> 01:15:30,082
I took them out last night.

1242
01:15:32,125 --> 01:15:33,249
So give it back, doll.

1243
01:15:35,417 --> 01:15:36,582
(George screaming)

1244
01:15:36,583 --> 01:15:39,291
(gunfire blasting)

1245
01:15:39,292 --> 01:15:40,791
(gun cocking)

1246
01:15:40,792 --> 01:15:43,791
(telephone ringing)

1247
01:15:46,583 --> 01:15:47,499
- Knowles here.

1248
01:15:49,667 --> 01:15:52,082
- [Jerry] Army search
plane calling us, sir.

1249
01:15:52,083 --> 01:15:54,624
- [Knowles] Relay the message
as soon as you get it.

1250
01:15:54,625 --> 01:15:58,124
(airplane engine roaring)

1251
01:16:00,958 --> 01:16:02,207
- Air to artillery.

1252
01:16:03,167 --> 01:16:06,166
We found the crashed plane
well out of your area.

1253
01:16:06,167 --> 01:16:07,749
No sign of life.

1254
01:16:07,750 --> 01:16:10,291
- We're sorry, but thanks for the word.

1255
01:16:10,292 --> 01:16:13,124
- You're clear to go on
with your shoot. Over.

1256
01:16:13,125 --> 01:16:14,041
- Artillery out.

1257
01:16:15,583 --> 01:16:16,874
All clear, Major.

1258
01:16:16,875 --> 01:16:18,124
- Thanks Lieutenant.

1259
01:16:18,125 --> 01:16:20,749
We'll begin on schedule at 0700 hours.

1260
01:16:20,750 --> 01:16:24,249
(airplane engine roaring)

1261
01:16:32,375 --> 01:16:34,166
(dramatic music)

1262
01:16:34,167 --> 01:16:36,749
(wind blowing)

1263
01:16:42,458 --> 01:16:43,916
- How about it, Jess?

1264
01:16:43,917 --> 01:16:46,457
Where's that great big Army of yours, huh?

1265
01:16:46,458 --> 01:16:49,291
(dramatic music)

1266
01:16:52,750 --> 01:16:53,666
- Get back.

1267
01:17:00,417 --> 01:17:02,499
- We'll camp up in here for the night.

1268
01:17:03,583 --> 01:17:05,082
- Why here?

1269
01:17:05,083 --> 01:17:06,666
- Okay, camp out in the open.

1270
01:17:07,958 --> 01:17:09,416
You'll freeze before morning.

1271
01:17:10,250 --> 01:17:12,124
(wind blowing)

1272
01:17:12,125 --> 01:17:14,874
(dramatic music)

1273
01:17:41,292 --> 01:17:43,582
(dramatic music)

1274
01:17:43,583 --> 01:17:46,166
(wind blowing)

1275
01:17:52,833 --> 01:17:54,041
Sit down here.

1276
01:17:55,875 --> 01:17:57,082
Better get some wood for a fire.

1277
01:17:57,083 --> 01:17:57,916
- Not tonight.

1278
01:17:58,875 --> 01:17:59,874
If we're as close as you say,

1279
01:17:59,875 --> 01:18:01,124
I don't wanna take a
chance on any visitors.

1280
01:18:01,125 --> 01:18:02,082
Sit down.

1281
01:18:02,083 --> 01:18:04,832
(wind whistling)

1282
01:18:09,708 --> 01:18:13,041
(Pete whistling softly)

1283
01:18:17,292 --> 01:18:20,874
(Pete continues whistling)

1284
01:18:28,750 --> 01:18:30,499
Well, where's your blizzard, Jesse?

1285
01:18:31,875 --> 01:18:33,832
I thought you said I wasn't gonna make it.

1286
01:18:35,500 --> 01:18:36,416
- You haven't yet.

1287
01:18:38,292 --> 01:18:39,082
- I will.

1288
01:18:43,125 --> 01:18:44,707
- Somebody might as well say it.

1289
01:18:46,333 --> 01:18:47,291
What about us?

1290
01:18:50,375 --> 01:18:52,166
- Well, look at it this way, Sherry.

1291
01:18:53,292 --> 01:18:54,957
You should have died in the crash.

1292
01:18:56,208 --> 01:18:57,916
You got a few extra days
and a couple of kicks

1293
01:18:57,917 --> 01:18:59,624
because you found somebody you liked.

1294
01:18:59,625 --> 01:19:00,832
- Pete, you don't have to kill her.

1295
01:19:00,833 --> 01:19:03,041
I'll make you a deal.
- I make my own bargains Jess!

1296
01:19:03,042 --> 01:19:04,457
- Bargain day was yesterday.

1297
01:19:11,750 --> 01:19:13,332
And you, Jesse, you
would've died in the war

1298
01:19:13,333 --> 01:19:15,041
if it hadn't been for me,
so the way I look at it,

1299
01:19:15,042 --> 01:19:16,832
you both came out ahead of the game.

1300
01:19:19,333 --> 01:19:20,666
All I have to worry about is whether I can

1301
01:19:20,667 --> 01:19:22,666
climb that mountain there all by myself.

1302
01:19:23,542 --> 01:19:24,582
- [Jesse] Maybe you could.

1303
01:19:24,583 --> 01:19:25,874
- Mm-hmm.

1304
01:19:25,875 --> 01:19:27,041
- Maybe I lied to you.

1305
01:19:27,042 --> 01:19:27,916
Maybe there's a lot of nothing

1306
01:19:27,917 --> 01:19:29,457
on the other side of that hill.

1307
01:19:29,458 --> 01:19:31,957
(wind blowing)

1308
01:19:31,958 --> 01:19:32,957
(Stan chuckles)

1309
01:19:32,958 --> 01:19:34,374
- What's so funny.

1310
01:19:34,375 --> 01:19:35,416
- It just come to me.

1311
01:19:36,708 --> 01:19:37,832
You're in a tough spot.

1312
01:19:41,042 --> 01:19:42,832
- Ask yourself some questions, Pete.

1313
01:19:44,083 --> 01:19:45,624
If I told you the truth, you're home free,

1314
01:19:45,625 --> 01:19:46,666
but if I lied to you,

1315
01:19:48,167 --> 01:19:50,582
you never needed anybody
as much as you need me.

1316
01:19:53,542 --> 01:19:54,832
Why don't you sleep on it?

1317
01:19:58,292 --> 01:20:01,041
(dramatic music)

1318
01:20:12,958 --> 01:20:15,582
(wind howling)

1319
01:20:20,500 --> 01:20:23,332
(dramatic music)

1320
01:20:33,542 --> 01:20:36,041
- I'm so afraid.
(dramatic music)

1321
01:20:36,042 --> 01:20:37,957
He's going crazy up there.

1322
01:20:37,958 --> 01:20:39,499
- He's afraid too.

1323
01:20:39,500 --> 01:20:41,999
That's all we've got to
go on till seven o'clock,

1324
01:20:45,458 --> 01:20:46,916
- About four more hours,

1325
01:20:46,917 --> 01:20:48,916
and even if the Army opens
up that like you say,

1326
01:20:48,917 --> 01:20:50,457
what good will it do us?

1327
01:20:50,458 --> 01:20:51,582
They'll never see us.

1328
01:20:51,583 --> 01:20:53,207
- We've got to be out of here by then.

1329
01:20:53,208 --> 01:20:54,416
Moving out in the valley,

1330
01:20:54,417 --> 01:20:55,832
that way we've got a chance.

1331
01:20:57,375 --> 01:20:58,957
- You wouldn't kid a girl, Jess.

1332
01:21:02,083 --> 01:21:04,166
- Now how could I kid a girl from Hepwith?

1333
01:21:06,083 --> 01:21:08,832
(gentle music)

1334
01:21:08,833 --> 01:21:10,666
- You know, if we do get out of this,

1335
01:21:10,667 --> 01:21:12,124
I'm not gonna do what I said.

1336
01:21:15,292 --> 01:21:17,666
Life's too short to be ashamed of it.

1337
01:21:19,708 --> 01:21:22,291
(gentle music)

1338
01:21:29,625 --> 01:21:32,457
(dramatic music)

1339
01:21:39,750 --> 01:21:42,749
(suspenseful music)

1340
01:21:48,250 --> 01:21:51,082
(birds chirping)

1341
01:21:56,792 --> 01:21:57,791
- Sherry.

1342
01:21:57,792 --> 01:21:59,416
Chief.

1343
01:21:59,417 --> 01:22:00,249
Let's go.

1344
01:22:05,333 --> 01:22:08,374
(wind blowing)

1345
01:22:08,375 --> 01:22:10,832
We better get going if we
wanna make that mountain today.

1346
01:22:13,458 --> 01:22:16,166
- I thought you said there
was nothing behind it, Jesse.

1347
01:22:18,625 --> 01:22:20,499
That's all folks.
(gun barrel cocks)

1348
01:22:20,500 --> 01:22:21,832
I have to be moving along.

1349
01:22:25,500 --> 01:22:28,082
- You fire that rifle,
Pete, you're finished.

1350
01:22:28,083 --> 01:22:30,582
There's an Army bivouac
behind that mountain.

1351
01:22:30,583 --> 01:22:31,416
They'll hear you.

1352
01:22:31,417 --> 01:22:32,832
You'll never get out of the valley.

1353
01:22:34,250 --> 01:22:36,249
- The Army, Jesse?

1354
01:22:36,250 --> 01:22:38,207
Now why didn't you make it the Marines?

1355
01:22:39,250 --> 01:22:40,332
In case there's any regrets,

1356
01:22:40,333 --> 01:22:42,457
you died for a good cause.

1357
01:22:42,458 --> 01:22:43,624
(crate creaking)

1358
01:22:43,625 --> 01:22:46,374
(dramatic music)

1359
01:22:53,375 --> 01:22:56,207
(Sheryl laughing)

1360
01:22:59,208 --> 01:23:01,666
- Parkinson said he wanted
to tell me about the money.

1361
01:23:01,667 --> 01:23:02,957
He hid it!

1362
01:23:03,000 --> 01:23:04,749
- Shut up.
- Why don't you ask him, huh?

1363
01:23:04,750 --> 01:23:06,166
Ask Parky where it is.

1364
01:23:06,167 --> 01:23:07,874
- He told you, huh?

1365
01:23:07,875 --> 01:23:08,916
He told you!
- Did he?

1366
01:23:08,917 --> 01:23:10,082
- He did tell you!

1367
01:23:10,083 --> 01:23:12,457
(dramatic music)

1368
01:23:12,458 --> 01:23:17,457
(tense dramatic music)
(artillery blasting nearby)

1369
01:23:19,500 --> 01:23:22,499
(suspenseful music)

1370
01:23:26,792 --> 01:23:29,541
(dramatic music)

1371
01:23:29,542 --> 01:23:31,874
- Leppich, get over there and stop him!

1372
01:23:34,875 --> 01:23:37,916
(artillery blasting nearby)

1373
01:23:37,917 --> 01:23:40,916
(suspenseful music)

1374
01:23:42,208 --> 01:23:47,207
(wind blowing)
(suspenseful music)

1375
01:23:55,667 --> 01:24:00,666
(cannons rumbling)
(artillery blasting)

1376
01:24:00,667 --> 01:24:03,166
(bombs whistling)
(suspenseful music)

1377
01:24:03,167 --> 01:24:06,249
(explosions booming)

1378
01:24:12,417 --> 01:24:15,416
(suspenseful music)

1379
01:24:16,458 --> 01:24:21,457
(bombs whistling)
(explosions booming)

1380
01:24:24,208 --> 01:24:26,957
(dramatic music)

1381
01:24:36,083 --> 01:24:39,582
(suspenseful music)
(cannonfire blasting)

1382
01:24:39,583 --> 01:24:41,749
(bombs whistling)

1383
01:24:41,750 --> 01:24:45,624
(explosions booming)

1384
01:24:45,625 --> 01:24:48,624
(suspenseful music)

1385
01:24:53,500 --> 01:24:56,791
(gunfire blasting)

1386
01:24:56,792 --> 01:24:59,707
(cannonfire whistling)

1387
01:24:59,708 --> 01:25:02,791
(explosions booming)

1388
01:25:04,000 --> 01:25:06,916
(ground rumbling)

1389
01:25:06,917 --> 01:25:09,916
(suspenseful music)

1390
01:25:14,292 --> 01:25:17,707
(tense foreboding music)

1391
01:25:21,375 --> 01:25:22,416
- Ceasefire!

1392
01:25:22,417 --> 01:25:23,249
- [Lieutenant] And go!

1393
01:25:23,250 --> 01:25:25,957
(cannonfire blasting)

1394
01:25:25,958 --> 01:25:30,957
(suspenseful music)
(cannonfire whistling)

1395
01:25:30,958 --> 01:25:33,916
(explosion booming)

1396
01:25:33,917 --> 01:25:36,749
(dramatic music)

1397
01:25:48,917 --> 01:25:50,457
- You call that artillery, huh?

1398
01:25:52,000 --> 01:25:55,332
On the battle wagon we use
those for slingshot practice.

1399
01:25:55,333 --> 01:25:58,082
(dramatic music)

1400
01:26:07,583 --> 01:26:09,207
But you sure shoot good.

1401
01:26:09,208 --> 01:26:12,207
(upbeat orchestral music)

1402
01:26:12,208 --> 01:26:14,124
- Where's your coat?

1403
01:26:14,125 --> 01:26:16,291
- I don't want it.

1404
01:26:16,292 --> 01:26:19,791
(tender orchestral music)

1405
01:26:41,500 --> 01:26:44,957
(bright orchestral music)

1406
01:26:54,083 --> 01:26:57,582
(bright theatrical music)

1407
01:27:05,083 --> 01:27:08,582
(upbeat orchestral music)

