(upbeat music)
Everybody loves a parade,
and the Chinese Nationalists
on Formosa are no exception.
An impressive display
of modern military might
passes in review for
Generalissimo Chiang Kai-shek
in a dramatic demonstration
of readiness in the Far East.
(upbeat music)
In Miami Florida, belles
work out with dumbbells.
(upbeat music)
And if they have any energy left,
they try a few tricks on the pogo sticks.
(upbeat music)
They do this by the hour,
seeking that hour glass figure.
(upbeat music)
Philadelphia, the city of homes.
The city of brotherly love
is the scene of dedication ceremonies
that will turn the palatial mansion
of dead millionaire Bartram Jonesworth
into a spiritual research
centre for Sister Sarah,
who is widely known for her
remarkable occult revelations.
In order to start a movement
that would put within
the reach of everyone,
the tremendous untapped resources
of the collective spiritual, unconscious,
devoted followers of Sister Sarah
have showered her with the money and gifts
so necessary to transform
a vision into a reality.
Now, for a few words from Sister Sarah.
Excuse me a moment, please, Sister Sarah,
won't you say something
for our newsreel audience?
They're all interested to
know just how you feel.
Well, I should like to say a few words
about the late Bartram Jonesworth.
Well, feel perfectly free to do so.
When Batram Jonesworth first
came to me six years ago,
he said, quote, "I do
not believe in charity."
"I am a businessman," unquote.
So I made an agreement with Mr. Jonesworth
that I would never ask him for
a donation, not even a dime.
However, if he wished to sell something,
I'd be glad to talk business.
For these automobiles,
I paid Mr. Jonesworth
the total sum of 85 cents.
For this fur I'm wearing, 40 cents
and this priceless necklace, 60 cents.
And finally, this magnificent mansion,
this 17 acre estate,
the price asked was $1,
not a cent more.
I think this all proves something
that while Barton Jonesworth
did not believe in charity
as a businessman, he
was very, very generous.
(upbeat music)
(audience applauds)
(train whistling)
(train engine revving)
(soft music)
(birds chirping)
(bell dings)
(soft music)
(birds chirping)
Hello.
[Butler] Hello.
What can I do for you?
I wanna see Sister Sarah.
[Butler] What about?
I wanna make a donation.
[Butler] Oh.
(birds chirping)
(TV chattering)
Sister Sarah?
What is it, my child?
(birds chirping)
(coins jingle)
Thank you sister
Sarah, thank you so much.
(birds chirping)
Tell me, did you have lunch?
Well, you are having lunch
with me and dinner too.
Now come along, come along.
(door opens)
How'd you make out?
(footsteps approaching)
-It's cased.
-Good girl.
I told you she could handle it.
Boy, that's some castle she's got there.
I got tired counting the rooms.
The layout. What's the layout?
It looks good, there's only one hitch.
We'll have to time it to the split second.
You have exactly 15 minutes.
What do you mean 15 minutes?
What's this 15 minute business?
We got to talking about this and that,
and she tells me she's
crazy about John Facenda.
John Facenda?
He's a news report on
television, he's on every night.
At 11 o'clock for 15 minutes.
All right, so every night
she watches John Facenda
and he's on for 15 minutes. So what?
The television sets
downstairs, upstairs
Will you get to it?
Where does she keep the necklace?
In her bedroom in a wall safe.
(papers ruffling)
(soft music)
[Baylock] I don't know.
I don't know, that ain't much time.
Especially not on this
one, our first big job.
(soft music)
(suspenseful music)
(car engine revving)
(soft music)
30 Seconds.
Would you cut it out?
-Cut what out?
-You're breathing down my neck.
20 seconds.
18, check the light.
(crickets chirping)
[Producer] 10 Seconds. Mr. Facenda.
Settle down, boys.
Standby please.
(feet jumping)
(crickets chirping)
Russia said today that it
rejected a recent US offer
of surplus farm products
because America refused
to include any strategic
goods in the deal.
The official news agency
said that a commercial treaty
was annulled by the United
States several years ago
and accused the United States of erecting
international trade barriers.
(window opens)
We got a new round of hard bargaining
on each west arm cut.
The proposals were in one
blueprint from Russia,
two from the west.
After three weeks of
preliminary introductions,
the real negotiating is expected soon.
After the five power
talks reconvene today.
Most details of the plans
have been leaked to the press
by formal announcements, by delegates,
or through publication and
official communist newspapers.
Even though this is a
so-called secret conference.
Cape May, New Jersey, coast guard,
bethels from New York
deliver with Delaware,
searched today for a Navy aeroplane
with three men aboard, which vanished
in last night's windstorm.
The missing crash is a
Twin-engine Beachcraft,
which left El Toro, California.
Last night the pilot of the craft reported
that it was about 15 miles
northwest of Red Bank
and had sufficient fuel
for three more hours.
The pilot gave no indication of trouble.
Western Statesmen were pleased
with the construction progress
of the unified air rate
screen across Western Europe
from Norway to Turkey.
The defence ministers of NATO predicted
that the jam proof communication
and warning network
will be completed early next year.
(TV chattering)
(mortar whirring)
(crickets chirping)
(car engine revving)
(dramatic music)
(car door closes)
(suspenseful music)
Come on, let's go.
I'm tired I wanna check in.
Wait a minute.
(suspenseful music)
I don't like where that car is parked.
There's no law against parking here.
Yeah, yeah, I know. I know.
Let's stick around a little while. Huh?
(suspenseful music)
(crickets chirping)
(dramatic music)
The necklace, you've got it?
Not yet
(suspenseful music)
Wait here.
What are you doing? Where are you going?
(suspenseful music)
Philadelphia, a lovesick
boy was wounded fatally today
in a gun battle with 35 policemen.
They trapped him in a woodland
hideout in Fairmont Park
where he had fled after
killing his sweetheart
and three members of her family.
(crickets chirping)
Is this your car?
Yeah, but I sure wish it wasn't Officer.
What are you doing around here?
You know where there's
an all night mechanic?
No.
What's wrong with it?
Stalled on me. Won't start.
Let's see your cards.
Yeah.
(crickets chirping)
I must have walked three miles. Nothing.
Not one gas station opened.
Places close up pretty
early around here.
You know what time it is?
(crickets chirping)
Look, maybe it's the battery.
If it is, I'll give you a push.
No, it isn't the battery.
She turns over all right.
I don't know what it is.
(cricket chirping)
(hood opens)
(crickets chirping)
Okay, let me try it. You got the key?
(door opens)
(car engine revving)
(car door opens)
(hood closes)
How's the cards?
(door closes)
They're in order.
Some nights a man shouldn't go out.
That all depends on what he's out for.
(crickets chirping)
How many drinks you had?
Not a drop. I never touch it.
(crickets chirping)
No. Let's get a whiff.
Look, what's your line of work?
Instalment business.
-Door to door?
-Yeah.
How's business?
Oh, I break even.
You know how it is, it's a struggle.
What ain't?
What you gonna do now?
Climb in the back and go to sleep.
That is, unless you wanna drive me home?
Does that look like a taxi?
Come on, let's get going.
(crickets chirping)
(car door opens)
(car door closes)
(car engine revving)
(crickets chirping)
(car door opens)
(car door closes)
(crickets chirping)
At least one indictment may be returned
by the federal grand jury investigating
the million dollar tax
case of Roger T Lee's.
The grand jury has been
sitting in special session
inquiring into why the
famed industrialists
had been able to evade filing
income taxes for six years.
(motor whirring)
One minute, 26 seconds,
25 seconds, 24 seconds.
-23 seconds.
-What are you timing him for?
You think he can hear you?
(clock ticking)
(mortar whirring)
Have a nice night and a good
day tomorrow. Good night all.
(footsteps approaching)
(bell chimes)
(suspenseful music)
(footsteps approaching)
(necklace clanking)
(suspenseful music)
(leaves rutting)
Come on.
(throat gargling)
(footsteps thudding)
(Sister Sarah gasps)
(car engine revving)
(tyres screeching)
(crickets chirping)
(metal clanking)
(car door opens)
(car door closes)
(car engine revving)
(crickets chirping)
(dramatic music)
(car engine revving)
(car doors open)
(car door closes)
(dramatic music)
(car engine revving)
(door opens)
(footsteps approaching)
Nat?
How'd it go?
Okay.
(feet running)
Sick?
Nerves.
You don't look so good yourself.
Still racing, it's
going a mile a minute.
You want a drink?
-I'd choke on it.
-Coffee?
Not for me. Nothing for me.
I just wanna sit here, just let me sit.
You Nat?
Nat?
I'm talking to you.
You want some coffee?
Yeah.
(soft music)
Wow.
What's it read?
(soft music)
(bright music)
Hey, you're in the light.
Come on, let's have it.
What's the story?
Get out of the light. Move will ya?
How can I see what I'm doing?
(bright music)
(dramatic music)
It's merchandise, Nat.
(soft music)
It's very expensive merchandise.
-How much?
-We really made a haul.
We got a piece of property here.
All right. All right.
What's the figure?
Oh.
Coming around.
One and a half.
What?
That high?
150,000.
That's the store price.
How much can we get for it?
From a fence,
around 80, 85.
What are you talking about?
That's more than 50% off.
Alright, you sell it,
take it to Tiffany's.
It's worth 150, we sell it for 85 grand.
We'll be giving it away.
You'll be getting 20,000.
That buys a lot of lunches.
You gotta get more than 80.
Here. Feel it.
Watch out.
It'll burn your fingers.
Get that drift?
It's hot dough.
It's scorching hot.
A fence gets a hold of this
right away he's got worries.
Right away, he's gonna start thinking,
how he can get rid of it.
The setting, it's platinum,
it's gotta be melted down.
Stones have to be cut,
recut, maybe cut again.
Not by no second-rater.
A job like this needs a high-grade
engineer, special talent.
You don't buy that with peanuts.
Someday we'll sit down and I'll teach you
the jewellery business.
Better get busy right away.
There's a fence I know in Baltimore.
Call him.
Make it fast.
Sooner we get this thing off our hands.
No. No phone calls, no
wires, no night letters.
Not even in code. Nothing.
Why not?
This trinket needs a market,
we gotta turn it into cash.
Relax.
Cool yourself.
Why the slow motion?
What are we waiting for?
A drop in the temperature.
You think that's hot?
It's hotter out there, boiling hot.
The law, Baylock.
The local authorities, the blue boys.
What do you think they're
doing right now, sleeping?
(dramatic music)
Tell me.
Have you had any visitors, any strangers?
Doorbell, ringers?
What are you getting at?
Did you invite them in?
Show them through the mansion?
Sure I did.
When you live in a place like this,
you want people to see it.
You want 'em to have a look.
One of them had a good look.
- You don't mean-
- Yes I do Madam.
This mansion was cased.
It was thoroughly and efficiently cased.
(train engine revving)
(kettle whistles)
You hear it boiling, you turn it off.
(bell dings)
(car engine revving)
He made a mistake so
obvious, I can't understand it.
Fundamental error in criminal technique.
I don't follow.
What did he do?
Let them see his face.
It's almost as if he wants to get caught.
You out of your head?
We can't just sit here with this thing.
When things cool off out
there, we'll be ready to move.
I wanna move it now.
I wanna get my split and take off Nat.
Please. Can't you see it my way?
No.
(hands banging)
You wanna get off that track.
We all gotta move one way.
We're an organisation.
Try to remember that.
-And forget me?
Forget there's a 30 year
rap staring me in the face?
Can't you see my only move?
I gotta take a stroll, Nat.
I got a stroll clear out of this country
and the quicker I get started
the better chance I'll have.
I've always wanted that chance.
Hoped for it.
Dreamed about it.
The one juicy haul that
puts the money in my pocket.
The money that takes me
on a long, long trip.
Central America.
(upbeat music)
I'll stay there.
I will have what it needs to stay there.
(upbeat music)
20,000 in George Washingtons.
20,000.
(upbeat music)
Enough to buy some ground, grow something.
Bananas.
(upbeat music)
Anything.
For years I've had it
up here, the picture.
A lot of pictures.
(upbeat music)
All dealing with transportation.
Begins with me at the travel
agency, buying the ticket.
From there I go to the airport.
(upbeat music)
And I'm walking through the gate
And there she is.
(upbeat music)
Waiting for me.
Big, fat, beautiful job with four engines,
80 passengers
and I'm one of them.
(upbeat music)
We taxi across the field, we
get second of the takeoff.
Then we're picking up speed.
Faster and faster.
Next thing I know, I'm going up, up.
I'm up there.
I'm off the ground
going up higher, higher.
Heading South,
far South.
Farthest south, you'll
get is South Philadelphia
10th and Reed, they call
it Moyamensing Prison.
(suspenseful music)
[Officer] Sorry Captain,
there doesn't seem to be anything here.
Not even close, huh?
George?
-[George] Yeah.
(door opens)
Find more photographs George.
Now bring in those
latest files we received
from Oregon and Arizona,
the ones from the F.B.I too.
(door closes)
What a dump.
$45 a month.
Well, they sure take
advantage of us tourists.
Where's Gladden?
In the kitchen.
Yeah, she's in the kitchen.
You know why she's in the kitchen?
So you can't look at her.
You are always looking at her.
What am I supposed to do, look at you?
More on the temples.
Yeah, right there. That's right.
Now the chin. Can you
shorten up on the chin?
Yeah. You know that
lip, that bottom lip,
that ought to be a little thinner.
-You sure?
-Yeah.
Looks good to me.
(phone buzzes)
Yeah?
Well we're giving it a try,
it's the only angle we have.
Yeah, I'll give you a
call as soon as we get it.
If we get it.
(phone clanking)
How's it shaping up?
-It's coming closer.
Nat?
(soft music)
You want a sandwich or something?
Maybe later.
We got some chicken in the ice box.
How about a chicken sandwich on rye bread?
We got rye bread.
Thanks Gladden but I'm not hungry.
Well, you should be.
You didn't have no dinner, you gotta eat.
This'll do for now.
(soft music)
Stop it.
-Stop what?
-You know what?
Don't sit there looking
like you don't know.
All I'm doing is sitting.
Looking at me, looking at me.
You're always looking at me.
So what?
What's wrong with that?
Can't I look if I want to?
(dramatic music)
-You beast.
-[Nat] Cool it.
I'll scratch your eyes out.
Cool it.
(suspenseful music)
Lay off. Leave her alone.
(soft music)
(cards flicking)
(footsteps thudding)
(soft music)
Why don't you grow up?
You stay out of it.
You're over 21, you act like 12.
Wanna do me a favour?
Sure.
Climb into bed.
Go to sleep and don't wake up.
(hand tapping)
Why don't you let it drift?
No. I got something to tell her.
You're gonna quit talking to me like that.
I won't have any talk like that.
Next time you open your mouth to me
Then stay out of my face.
Keep your rotten pulse to yourself.
I was only giving you advice,
but you are a stubborn
child, you won't listen.
Listen to you?
I'd rather hear a cat yelling in an alley.
Now move, will you get out this kitchen?
[Baylock] Now you're gonna
hear what I got to say.
[Gladden] I told you to get out.
[Baylock] Put down that
pitcher, you throw that at me
[Gladden] You dried up lizard,
you gonna leave me alone?
[Baylock] All right throw
it. I dare you to throw it.
(pitcher clanking)
Why you.
(Gladden screams)
(utensils clatter)
(train engine revving)
(Gladden screams)
Leave me alone.
(train engine revving)
(train honking)
I don't get it.
Tell me one thing, what
do you need her for?
All right, she does a job.
She knows how to case a layout.
But you know as well as I do
need she ain't no expert at it.
I know a hundred skirts
can operate better.
So I know that ain't the reason.
(soft music)
Another thing I know for sure...
it ain't as if you got eyes for her.
If you were sweet on the
chick, I could understand it
but you're not.
You hardly even look at her.
You don't even know she's around.
What is it?
(soft music)
Why can't you let her go?
We are an organisation,
she's a charter member.
Now he's calling from the rule book.
Why do you hold onto her?
Why can't you let her go?
(soft music)
There's got be a reason.
(dramatic music)
[Officer] Perfect. That's him all right.
Printing office,
please hurry.
This is Keebler, burglary unit.
Can you send a messenger
up here right away?
I have a pencil drawing
here, a man's face.
I'll need at least a thousand copies.
This is going out to 13 states.
(train honking)
(train engine revving)
[Nat] It began a long time ago.
Just another orphan in an orphanage.
You didn't like that high gate,
one day you climbed over, you got away.
(suspenseful music)
They wouldn't stop, they
didn't even look at you,
made you feel lonesome, not wanted.
(suspenseful music)
(car engine revving)
(tyres screech)
[Gerald] Come on, kid. Hope in.
[Nat] And that was the start of it.
That day when he picked you up,
from that day on, you had a home
and a father.
You'll never forget his face.
That's him.
That's Gerald.
And the little girl
that's Gladden.
(suspenseful music)
He put food in your belly.
He put clothes on your back,
a roof over your head.
He was good to you.
He was kind, gentle.
He was so gentle.
(soft music)
You'll never forget his voice.
That soft voice.
You could hardly believe
it when you found out,
when you asked him what
kind of work he did,
and he answered, "I break into places."
"And I steal."
"I'm a burglar."
(soft music)
But no gun.
He never used a gun, no weapons at all.
That was the first thing he taught you.
You do a job, you do it clean.
(soft music)
And that night, that night
he took you out with him
your first job.
He asked you to make a promise,
to give me him you word,
your word of honour.
If anything ever happened to
him, you'd take care of her.
His little daughter.
You promised, you gave him your word.
(soft music)
Three years later, something went wrong.
It was your fault, it
was your first mistake.
(alarm rings)
(door opens)
(whistle blows)
[Officer] Stop.
I'm warning you, I'll shoot.
(alarm rings)
(whistle blows)
(gun fires)
(alarm rings)
(whistle blows)
[Nat] You ran.
You ran like a rabbit.
Gotta get Gladden.
Gladden. Gladden. Gladden.
Gladden.
(door opens)
(train honking)
(train engine revving)
Nat?
(soft music)
(wood clanking)
Why aren't you asleep?
I couldn't sleep.
Why not?
I don't know, I just
couldn't close my eyes.
What about you?
(soft music)
-Gladden?
-Yes Nat.
(soft music)
I've been thinking.
What is it?
(soft music)
You need a change.
You ought a go away for a while.
(soft music)
Thanks.
Thanks a lot.
Now don't get me wrong.
It's alright Nat,
you want me out of the way,
I'll step out of the way.
Will you quit twisting it around?
All I said was
that you needed a-
- Don't Nat.
Don't work on it.
You'll only get yourself in deep.
(soft music)
So Nat.
I'll do anything.
Anything you say.
After all, you're in charge.
You are the babysitter.
Quit that talk.
You're the legal
guardian, the foster father.
I don't want to hear it.
Why not? It's what it amounts to.
(soft music)
Unless you'd rather not see it that way.
Please. Will you let me explain.
It isn't necessary.
Listen to me.
It's Dohmer, he won't leave you alone.
And Baylock, you're always
fighting with Baylock.
-I can handle them.
-I don't know, they're getting jittery.
(suspenseful music)
Besides, the trip would be good for you.
You're pale.
It'll be good for your health.
There's nothing wrong with my health.
Now, let's not argue.
I'm not arguing.
(suspenseful music)
This trip I'm taking,
where do you want me to go?
It doesn't matter.
New York, Boston.
They ain't exactly health resorts.
You said, I'm going for
my health, remember?
How about the seashore?
Wildwood, Atlantic City
Does it make any difference?
Atlantic City, is that all right?
Yeah, sure, it's all right.
You'll have all that
salt air and sunshine.
You can sit on the beach, go swimming.
Okay. Okay. When do I leave?
There's no use waiting.
(soft music)
Should I start packing now?
Now look, I didn't say that.
You don't have to rush it.
-Don't I?
(suspenseful music)
I'll leave first in the morning.
I'll take you to the station.
(footsteps thudding)
(car engine revving)
[Announcer] Attention.
Will Mrs. Helen Burnat
please report to the
baggage room immediately.
[Announcer] The Atlantic City Express
will leave at 7: 15 from
stairway number eight.
Attention please.
The morning congressional
arriving from New York
on platform number three
will leave for Wilmington,
Baltimore and Washington at 7:25.
The Atlantic City Express will at 7: 15
from stairway number eight.
(train engine revving)
(waves whooshing)
(soft music)
(upbeat music)
♪ You are mine ♪
♪ Even the angels know ♪
♪ I thought you knew ♪
♪ It's only you ♪
♪ Yes you are mine ♪
♪ I love you ♪
(fingers snapping)
(hand banging)
Nat?
When are we going to do something?
I want to get busy.
Why don't you weave a rug for your head?
(Dohmer laughs)
(hand tapping)
Look, I say we move.
You say we wait, that makes it an issue.
It needs talk.
Alright, let's talk.
Let's kick it around a
bit and see what happens.
It comes to this, if I'm
staying, I kill my nerves.
I gotta get moving, I need travelling.
I need it bad.
Nat, please let me call Baltimore
and make a quick transaction.
We'll get ourselves some finance.
Then we can split the
cash and I can take off.
What for?
You're comfortable here.
If you stay put, you'll stay comfortable.
I don't see it that way.
What I got to do is travel.
And I don't mean no 40 mile bus ride.
A place I got in mind is Central America.
All right. Let it be Central America.
But that comes later.
-It's gotta be now.
-Later Baylock. Later.
Later he says, as if it's
just a matter of killing time.
Look, Nat, I'm on probation.
I can't afford another stretch.
With you it's different.
You've never been nabbed, never booked,
never printed, never mugged.
You see the way it is, you
can walk a wide street.
I'm on a tight rope.
(Dohmer laughs)
(soft music)
(water splashing)
My name's Della.
(soft music)
I said my name's Della.
What goes here?
It's a situation.
You do this all the time?
No, of course not.
You know, I've never done it before.
How would I know?
You just know that's all.
You're looking at me and you know.
(upbeat music)
(plates clatter)
(glass thuds)
(plate thuds)
(cup thuds)
(napkin thuds)
(upbeat music)
(crowd chattering)
What's your name?
Nathaniel.
Say, what is this?
What do you want?
Basically, basically I'm
out to find myself a man.
(crowd chattering)
Wait for me outside.
Are you kidding?
No.
No. Nathaniel, I'm not kidding.
Well, that's tough on you.
Sorry.
(coins jingle)
No sale.
(hand slapping)
(upbeat music)
Just to let you know,
I'm not selling anything.
(upbeat music)
Nathaniel.
Nat.
You know, I like the feel of that name.
Soft but it has a snap to it, a soft snap.
(crowd chattering)
It's a patent leather name.
(upbeat music)
(crowd chattering)
Later tonight, I'll be home.
You needn't even ring the bell.
The door will be open.
(soft music)
Light me Nat.
(drink pouring)
That's three.
(glass clanking)
Three what?
Three drinks in the last half hour.
(soft music)
Tell me something.
Who hurt you?
(soft music)
Answer me Della.
You sure hauled that in from left field.
Come on, let's have it.
What's the point?
You've heard it before,
it's same sob story.
All right. If you'd rather skip it.
(soft music)
No, Nat.
I'll tell you.
You ask me, so I'll tell you.
(soft music)
It's like this...
the girl comes from a wonderful family.
Really wonderful.
The old man's a no good loafer.
Mother drinks bootleg whiskey,
50 cents a pint, when she can't steal it.
Where was this?
Youngstown, Ohio.
Had four brothers, three sisters.
We were a very close family.
We had to be close, we lived in two rooms.
When did you pull out?
When I was 17.
I went to Chicago.
Great city, Chicago.
The city of opportunity.
(soft music)
First three, I turned down.
(match lights)
And along comes Sir Galahad to the rescue.
(soft music)
Turns out he runs a model agency.
At least that's what he called it.
(soft music)
Best thing I know there's a
bunch of creeps with camera.
Somehow I landed in show business.
I was a dancer.
What's known as a high kicker.
(soft music)
One night I kicked a booking
agent right in the mouth,
broke his jaw.
(soft music)
Finally it happened.
I meet an eligible bachelor.
Nice guy, real nice.
So completely different
from all the others.
So clean.
(soft music)
I married him.
And I was happy.
I was so happy, I couldn't believe it.
(soft music)
Then comes the left hook,
right between the eyes.
He took off?
Jet propelled.
Why? What did it?
A photograph.
Some joker showed him a photograph of me.
One of the specials from
the modelling agency.
(soft music)
He didn't even bother to hit me.
His name was Gerald.
He had a daughter, Gladden.
Gladden?
That's a strange name for a girl.
Well, she was a strange kid.
Always so quiet,
lonely, bewildered.
Tell me more about Gerald.
He brought me up.
He was a father to me.
He taught me everything I know.
You feel obligated?
It runs deeper than that.
A lot deeper.
(soft music)
One thing he drilled into me.
You make a promise, you gotta keep it.
I gave him my word I'd
always take care of Gladden.
You know, it's sort of weird.
A lot of things come back to me now.
Like the times I wanted to
pull out of that bargain,
get a job, be legitimate.
What stopped you?
I don't know.
I've never been able to figure it out.
Like something inside me, steering me.
Gerald.
Della?
You don't get it from him.
I'll get it from my little blonde doll
down in Atlantic City.
(Charlie laughs)
Better be getting back
there, you have work to do.
You'll get the necklace baby.
Find me some inspiration.
Later.
(crickets chirping)
Let's save that for later.
(suspenseful music)
(crickets chirping)
Competition.
A business rival.
I knew this would happen.
This is what we get for waiting around.
We should have gone to Baltimore days ago.
Nat it's still not too late,
we'll go to Baltimore now.
I'll contact that fence.
-No.
What do you mean, no?
We're going to Atlantic City.
For what?
Are you crazy? What do we need her for?
You don't get that point.
She needs us.
(car engine revving)
(tyres screeching)
(car hooting)
(car engine revving)
(TVM dings)
(sirens wailing)
That's for us.
(tyres screeching)
(sirens wailing)
(car door opens)
(car door closes)
(footsteps thudding)
[Radio] White Horse Pike Highway.
Let's see your papers.
[Radio] GRM 3642. Eighth Harbour,
west of the White Horse
Pike, Hospital case.
667 report.
(crickets chirping)
You know what you were doing?
The speedometer read 50.
Yeah, but you were on the left side
of that white line over there.
I'm sorry Officer, I guess
I must have been dreaming.
Well. Don't let it
turn into a nightmare.
Stay on the right side.
Thank you Officer, I will.
[Radio] Questioning in a burglary.
Three white men in a light grey,
four-door Chevrolet, '51 model.
Pennsylvania one, M, Mary, Z zebra, 7-0.
Last seen crossing
Turn off the ignition
and get out of the car.
Hey Steve.
(gun fires)
(dramatic music)
(car engine revving)
I always thought you were
a moron, now I know it.
Why'd you have to shoot in the face?
Why not the arm, the shoulder?
Save it. He can't hear you.
(tyres screeching)
(printer printing)
The above men made
their escape in a 1951
light grey Chevrolet.
Pennsylvania One, M, Mary, Z, zebra, 7-0.
Last seen going east on the
White Horse Pike from Hamilton.
Use caution, they are armed and dangerous.
(sirens wailing)
(soft music)
(car door closes)
Where we at now?
Take a whiff.
(Baylock sniffs)
(soft music)
-Salt.
-From the ocean.
Let's go.
-What about the car?
We're gonna need it.
What for?
So they'll see it again.
It's number one on their list.
Come on.
(dramatic music)
(car door closes)
Let's see, where'd that
gun battle take place?
Black Horse Pike, 31 miles from here.
That's makes it one mile
this side of Hamilton.
Here. Right here.
I guess you know about the trooper?
They said he got in the
face, died immediately.
The other trooper emptied
his revolver at them.
Chased them. Lost them.
Radioed headquarters.
They got on it right away
and set up roadblocks.
One here. Here.
One at this point in this road.
Is that what you guess?
I'm not guessing. I'm calculating.
See this tiny intersection right here?
The trooper passed it and
three miles up the road,
he came in the first road
block. That's obvious.
There's only one turn
at this intersection.
It's a right hand turn.
There's another turn there.
Another one there.
No more roads.
That'd put 'em somewhere in the woods.
How could they drive a
car through the woods?
-Wagon paths.
-Very slow, very bumpy.
Well put yourself in his place.
You gotta keep moving,
you can't turn back.
Finally the woods get too thick.
No more paths.
So what you do is abandon the car
and walk through the woods
to this point, right here.
Marshlands the Bay area.
In the distance you see Atlantic City,
playground of the world.
Huge crowd of visitors from
every state in the union.
Get it?
This man I'm looking
for is a professional.
He's extremely intelligent.
He knows that his best hiding
place is in a crowded area.
An area where he is
surrounded by other faces.
(birds chirping)
(water splashing)
(net whooshing)
(birds chirping)
(feet shuffling)
This looks okay.
(footsteps approaching)
Wait here for me, I'll be back.
Where are you going?
Gladden.
(footsteps thudding)
(soft music)
(phone rings)
Hello.
I'm calling from downstairs.
Now look, don't talk, I'll do the talking.
I've gotta see you.
Well get rid of him.
I don't care what you tell
him, just get rid of him,
it's important.
And wait there for me, I'll
be up in a few minutes.
Yes.
(phone thuds)
(soft music)
I think you better go now.
(footsteps thudding)
(suspenseful music)
(dramatic music)
(door opens)
(door closes)
Pack your things, you're checking out.
Why, what's happened?
Complications.
Come on. We gotta move.
Not Me.
(suitcase clanking)
I like it here.
Plenty of sunshine, all that salt air.
It's good for my health.
That's why you sent me here, remember?
For my health.
What are you getting at?
I'm feeling very healthy these days.
His name's Charlie.
Charlie?
Yeah, Charlie.
That's his name, Charlie.
Really?
Tell me about him.
He likes me.
He likes me very much.
Very, very much.
It's a good thing you are sitting down
because you are gonna hear something.
Your boyfriend Charlie, he's a cop.
He wears a badge, he's a blue boy.
What are you giving me?
You think I'm stupid of something?
Get with it will ya? He's a cop.
That's not all of it.
He's also in business for himself.
And what he wants, he wants 100%.
Here's what he wants.
(bright music)
It checks Gladden. It figures.
What do you mean, it figures?
How does it figure?
Downstairs in the lobby, I saw his face.
I remembered him.
From when? From where?
The night we pulled the
haul, outside the mansion.
The two cops who questioned
me, he was one of them.
Just what are you trying to engineer?
He's the engineer.
He pulled a trace job
that wins the grand prize.
Nat please. Please,
Don't you see, he had it figured.
He knew I was hitting
that mansion for loot.
Stop it.
Stop it. Don't try to sell me short.
He didn't want the other cop to know.
At the station house, he gets
his own car, he doubles back.
He watches us, gives us a
head start and then follows us.
Face it Gladden, he's just
a spider weaving a web.
Trying to pull you in.
Come on, let's get outta
here. Get your things.
-I'm not going.
-What?
I said I'm not going.
Not with you.
I'm done mister. I've had it.
Gladden what is it?
What's the matter?
You don't know.
You really don't know.
Well look at me, I'm a woman.
I'm flesh and blood and I got feelings.
But you never knew that,
you never wanted to know.
I was starving for you.
Night after night I tore
pillows apart with my teeth.
So hungry for you, wanting you so much.
(soft music)
And you, you knew from nothing.
I was just another gadget in your toolkit.
(soft music)
But now it's quitting time.
I'm out of the organisation.
(soft music)
You'll change your mind.
Wanna bet?
(soft music)
(bright music)
You'll come back in, we'll be waiting.
You better stock up on groceries
'cause you're in for a long wait.
We're in a wooden shack near the bay.
Four blocks west of the
Albany Avenue Bridge.
You're talking to the wall.
(soft music)
(door opens)
Go on mister.
Take a walk.
(soft music)
(bright music)
(dramatic music)
(birds chirping)
[Gerald] The only thing
you've got that's worthwhile
is your word.
Give me your word, your
word of word honour.
If anything ever happens to me,
give me your word.
You'll take care of Gladden.
Gladden Gladden.
Take care of Gladden.
Gladden.
(music box plays)
(wings flapping)
(birds chirping)
(crowd chattering)
What'd you do it for?
What did you do it for?
She tells him she wants
out of the organisation.
She wants no part of it, she's out,
She's given us the kiss-off,
so what does he do?
(pants flickers)
He gives her the emeralds.
(birds chirping)
(phone dials)
Operator, I'd like to
make a long distance call
Philadelphia.
Greenwood 3-0-4-5-6.
That's right.
Look, I need you down here right away.
Why? What's happened?
Is he there?
Sure he is here. What do
you think I'm calling you for?
Can I see him? Can I talk to him again?
Not for that. I tried that
angle and it didn't work.
Here on in, we're gonna do it my way.
That's out.
None of that Charlie.
It's gotta be handled my way.
If we don't move in now
we're gonna be all loused up.
Listen, we're playing against time.
Now get that through your head.
I can't keep running back and
forth between here and Philly
didn't even report for duty last night.
I keep making excuses like
that, somebody's gonna catch on.
Charlie listen to me.
No.
You listen to me.
Don't you argue with me.
Put that classy frame of
yours in that convertible
and get down here as fast as you can.
Now listen.
They're hiding out in
a small wooden shack.
I'll tell you where it is.
Come here a minute.
(footsteps approaching)
You see them?
See what?
Boats.
So their boats, so what?
Transportation.
That cabin cruiser.
The white one?
I'm gonna have a look.
How do you know about boats?
They float.
(soft music)
(men fighting)
(dramatic music)
(hand punching)
(birds chirping)
Come on in.
Join the party.
(birds chirping)
Yeah.
But you don't have to leave.
I'm gonna give you a real break.
(Charlie chuckles)
All you gotta do is just
hand it over, that's all.
Alright. That can be arranged.
Yeah, when?
-I'll need a little time.
-No, no, no.
You don't need time.
You're gonna take it out from
wherever it is right now.
And you're gonna slide it across to me.
(gun corks)
Nice and easy.
I haven't got it, Charlie.
You don't?
What a pity.
What a real pity.
Turn around.
Wait, Charlie, don't do it.
Not yet.
-Why not?
Why waste time?
-Charlie, listen.
He's got it. I know he's got it.
Maybe not.
Want me to make sure?
All right, go on, frisk him.
(soft music)
Tell me something pal.
How old are you?
-35.
You wanna see 36?
46?
56?
Look Charlie, if I tell you where it is,
what guarantee do I have that
you won't drill me anyway?
-All depends.
-Depends on what?
On information, whether I buy it or not.
(suspenseful music)
I guess you know I'm not playing.
(dramatic music)
-I know that.
-Good.
We both know if I pull this trigger,
nobody's gonna call it murder.
It's gonna be law enforcement.
You sure dealt yourself a nice hand.
You save the compliments.
All it is I want is that necklace.
Cool yourself Charlie, you'll get it.
Convince me.
(dramatic music)
Come on. Come on, your time's running out.
Ocean View Hotel.
Oh no. No sale.
She's got it Charlie. It's in that room.
How come I didn't see it?
I've been putting in a
lot of time with that babe
and went over every inch of that room
and it wasn't there.
It's there now Charlie.
I put it there for a reason.
Get his gun.
(footsteps approaching)
(birds chirping)
Check it for clips.
Give me the car keys.
(birds chirping)
Brother here moves an inch, drill him.
(footsteps thudding)
Might make you famous.
Get a medal from the police department.
(Charlie chuckles)
(footsteps thudding)
(wind whooshing)
(birds chirping)
(car door closes)
Nice weather out there.
Mind if I take a stroll?
-Don't move.
You don't walk out that
door unless you go with me.
With you?
All the way.
When Charlie gets back we won't be here.
Well? What's it gonna be?
A gamble strictly a long shot.
You better call off that bet.
I can't. Don't you see how it adds.
I'm dealing with time.
I've got to get to Gladden.
Nat, please don't go for that door.
(suspenseful music)
Stay away from that door.
(dramatic music)
Room 42 and hurry.
(phone rings)
(soft music)
(dramatic music)
(car engine revving)
(tyres screeching)
(dramatic music)
(phone rings)
Gladden is that you, are you all right?
Now listen, you gotta
get out of there fast.
Please if you don't leave now,
you'll never get out alive.
(car door closes)
We don't have time to talk,
I'll talk to you later.
I'll meet you on the boardwalk.
The steel pier, in
front of the steel pier.
Wait for me there.
(phone clanks)
(upbeat music)
(door opens)
(feet running)
(upbeat music)
Gladden?
-Oh Nat.
We gotta get off the
boardwalk and back to that bay.
There's a boat there with...
What's this you got?
The music box.
(crowd chattering)
(upbeat music)
Officer you wanna hold it a minute?
I'll take over from here on
end, I already put in the call.
(upbeat music)
(footsteps thudding)
We the dead...
welcome you.
(water splashing)
(upbeat music)
What cop from Philly?
He never checked with me.
(fan spinning)
Okay, skip it. I'll find out later.
No, not yet. Don't move in.
That pier's too crowded.
I don't want anybody to get hurt.
(fan spinning)
(phone thuds)
This is it.
(feet running)
(upbeat music)
(water splashing)
We the dead...
welcome you.
(ghost laugh)
We the dead...
welcome you.
(ghosts laugh)
(water splashing)
(upbeat music)
(water flowing)
(music box thuds)
(music box plays)
(feet running)
(water flowing)
(upbeat music)
(feet running)
(water flowing)
(upbeat music)
(gun fires)
(water splashes)
(audience applauds)
[Announcer] Ladies and gentlemen,
direct from their fabulous European tour,
the sensational Virengaards.
(audience applauds)
Tired?
I'm alright.
We'll stay here a while longer
and then work our way back.
(upbeat music)
I'm worried Nat.
I don't like it out here.
Come on, let's move.
Not yet.
(drum rolls)
(sirens wailing)
Stick around.
(upbeat music)
Enjoy the show.
(drums roll)
(sirens wailing)
(upbeat music)
(water splashes)
(sirens wailing)
(upbeat music)
(water splashes)
[Announcer] Well ladies and gentlemen,
that's our show for tonight.
Thanks for coming and please come again.
Goodnight.
(upbeat music)
(sirens wailing)
(car door closes)
(upbeat music)
(footsteps thudding)
(wind whooshing)
You want it Charlie?
Big joke.
Yeah, I want it.
Buy it.
(wind whooshing)
What's the price?
You let her go.
(wind whooshing)
She can talk?
She won't talk.
She knows better than that.
Whatever happens is
her word against yours.
And you are a cop, remember?
If she opens her mouth,
they'll send her up.
(wind whooshing)
All right.
All right, it's a deal.
Please Nat.
Can't you see what he's gonna do?
As soon as he has it, he'll plug you.
He'll claim you reached for a gun.
Go on. Do what I'm telling you.
I'll catch up with you later.
(wind whooshing)
All right pal.
Go on.
You take a walk.
(wind whooshing)
(suspenseful music)
(feet running)
[Officer] Wait a minute, miss.
Where you coming from?
(suspenseful music)
(gun fires)
(feet running)
(Nat falls)
(dramatic music)
(whistle blows)
Nat?
Nat what has he done to you Nat?
(suspenseful music)
Nice work Charlie.
What did he do, reach for his gun?
No.
(suspenseful music)
It wasn't that at all.
He tried to get away.
Oh, you rotten liar.
(suspenseful music)
[Keebler] How's he doing?
[Officer] He's done.
Well, call the coroner and put it on ice.
(suspenseful music)
He had the necklace on him all right.
What do you mean he had it?
He was afraid of getting
caught with it on him.
(suspenseful music)
He threw it away in the ocean.
No he didn't Charlie.
(suspenseful music)
Tell him to hand it over.
(dramatic music)
(hand punching)
(upbeat music)
(dramatic music)
[Keebler] Take him down to
headquarters, I want them held.
(dramatic music)
(footsteps thudding)
[Officer] What do we mark him Captain?
(car engine revving)
[Keebler] You mark it victim.
(soft music)