♪ One, two, three o'clock
Four o'clock, rock ♪
♪ Five, six, seven o'clock
Eight o’clock, rock ♪
♪ Nine, ten, eleven o'clock
Twelve o'clock, rock ♪
♪ We're gonna rock
Around the clock tonight ♪
♪ Put your glad rags on and join me, hon ♪
♪ We’ll have some fun
When the clock strikes one ♪
♪ We're gonna rock
Around the clock tonight ♪
♪ We're gonna rock, rock, rock ♪
♪ Till broad daylight ♪
♪ We're gonna rock, gonna rock
Around the clock tonight ♪
♪ When the clock strikes two
Three and four ♪
♪ If the band slows down
We’ll yell for more ♪
♪ We're gonna rock
Around the clock tonight ♪
♪ We're gonna rock, rock, rock
Till broad daylight ♪
♪ We're gonna rock, gonna rock
Around the clock tonight ♪
♪ When the chimes ring
Five, six and seven ♪
♪ We’ll be right in seventh heaven ♪
♪ We're gonna rock
Around the clock tonight ♪
♪ We're gonna rock, rock, rock
Till broad daylight ♪
♪ We're gonna rock, gonna rock
Around the clock tonight ♪
♪ When it's eight, nine, ten, 1 1 , too ♪
♪ I'll be goin' strong and so Will you ♪
♪ We're gonna rock
Around the clock tonight ♪
♪ We're gonna rock, rock, rock
Till broad daylight ♪
♪ We're gonna rock, gonna rock
Around the clock tonight ♪
[indistinct chatter]
[slow big-band music playing]
[music stops]
[all applauding]
Well, that's it, Georgie.
The band's through here.
We're cancelled out.
That's the third time on this tour.
What kind of a manager are you?
How do you expect to draw crowds
in a town of this size?
This wouldn't have happened
if you'd listened to me a long time ago.
I tell you, all the big bands
are breaking up.
People aren't dancing anymore,
they're listening.
Oh, so I’m supposed to break up my band?
The public's going in for sounds, Georgie.
They want to hear small groups,
vocalists, novelty combos.
Sure. That's right, Steve.
Put the blame on everyone but yourself.
As the band's manager,
you do a bad job of selling--
A bad job of selling?
Listen to me.
The only thing that's up to date
in this band of yours is your watch.
Why don't you get wise to yourself?
Look at the figures on record sales,
and then look at the size
of the crowds you've been drawing.
I should book you
into a schoolhouse during fire drill.
You'd be able to clear 'em out fast
with the music--
-You're fired.
-Good.
I wouldn't want you to say
I was disloyal by quitting.
But take my advice, Georgie.
You wait around long enough for a proof
that the big band business is dead,
you'll be paying the funeral expenses.
Good luck to you.
Steve.
Steve's giving you the right hop, Pop.
I don't like funerals, either.
See you around the cemetery.
Corny, look, there's no reason
for you to cut out on the band.
Maybe Hiller can still get some work.
Stevie-boy, the handwriting's on the wall.
So I either hock this thing
or turn it into a ferryboat.
Where we goin'?
New York.
I think I can get a job
with one of the big booking offices.
You thinkin' of Corinne Talbot?
I wasn't thinkin' of anybody.
-Do we leave in the morning?
-Ready at 8:00.
Soon as I put on my travelling clothes
and Lulu-belle here. . .
-[bass twanging]
-. . . puts on her G-string.
-All righty?
-All righty.
[big-band music playing]
Awful lonesome up here.
You sure you know where you're goin'?
Well, according to the map,
and it's been right the past three days,
we should hit a little town
called Strawberry Springs
in time to stay over for the night.
-Sort of a shortcut.
-Hmm.
Sounds good enough to eat.
What does?
Strawberry shortcut.
Aw, Corny, go back to sleep, will you?
[chuckles]
Hey, Corny, wake up. We made it.
"Strawberry Springs, population 1 ,472."
This is a cute little town, wasn't it?
[indistinct chatter]
-[horn honks]
-If we can find a hotel or a motel.
An old barn, anything. I’m beat.
-[horn honking]
-[girl yelling]
[boy 1] Move the wheels.
You're blockin' the road.
[girl] Come on, daddy-o! We're in a hurry.
Looks like we're holdin' up the works.
We go for 1 50 miles without seeing a car.
The minute we stopped, road hog.
-[chuckling]
-[all yelling]
-[boy 1] Come on!
-[boy 2] Let's go, let's go, come on!
[all shouting]
Steve, the whole 1 ,472
must be out at once.
Yeah, look at 'em.
Hey, there's a motel up ahead.
-Let's hope they have a room.
-Yeah.
-With hot and cold--
-Hot and cold running, I know the joke.
[indistinct chatter]
-Evenin', neighbor.
-Evenin'.
-Your sign says you have a vacancy.
-Yep.
We don't get many tourists
in this neck of the woods.
Stayin' long?
Nah, just overnight.
Probably pull out in the morning.
Say, Pop, where's everybody goin'?
Uh, the young 'uns?
This is Saturday night, neighbor.
The young 'uns wouldn't
miss their dance at the meetin' hall.
They're all going to a dance?
This is Saturday night.
Maybe nobody told them
that dance band music was dead.
It's probably a dance for squares.
-Square dance?
-That's what I said.
They've probably been doin'
that stuff here
for the last 1 00 years.
Got a match?
Just the same, they dance,
and I'd like to know why.
You think anybody'd mind if we went?
I reckon your money's
as good as anybody's.
Good. Show us to our cabin, will you?
We'll get cleaned up a little bit.
It's over there, 1 2.
She's open. Go right in.
Okay, thank you.
"Dance for squares." [scoffs]
Man, them two cats
don't dig the most at all.
At all.
["See you Later, Alligator"
by Bill Haley and His Comets playing]
[indistinct chatter]
Hey, Steve, we must be
out of our cotton-pickin' minds.
We should be gettin' some sleep
instead of comin' here.
Maybe so.
But something's getting these people
out of their houses.
I’m gonna find out what it is.
[Corny] Ah, what kind of cornball music
can they have in a burg like this?
Probably Joe Grubnic and his "Makes you
want to sit this one out" orchestra.
-They're slaughtering cattle.
-Did you hear that?
All I can say is square dancing
has sure changed.
♪ See you later, alligator ♪
♪ After 'while, crocodile ♪
♪ Can't you see you're in my way now? ♪
♪ Don't you know you cramp my style... ♪
[Corny] I told you, slaughtering cattle.
Corny, how long has it been since
you've seen a dance hall jump like that?
About three years ago at Roseland
when that flea circus act got loose.
What is that outfit playin' up there?
I don't know. It isn't boogie,
it isn't jive, and it isn't swing.
It's kind of all of 'em.
Hey, sister, what do you call
that exercise you're gettin'?
It's rock 'n' roll, brother,
and we're rockin' tonight.
It's rock 'n' roll.
♪ Can't you see you're in my way now? ♪
♪ Don't you know you cramp my style? ♪
♪ When I thought of What she told me ♪
♪ Nearly made me lose my head... ♪
Say, pardon me, friend, would you tell me
what the name of that band is?
Later, man, later.
I’m gone, now. I don't dig nothin'.
♪ But the next time that I saw her ♪
♪ Reminded her of what she said ♪
♪ See you later, alligator
After 'while, crocodile. . . ♪
Miss, pardon me, do you know the name
of that orchestra that's playing?
Crazy, man, crazy.
♪ After 'while, crocodile ♪
♪ Can't you see you're in my way now? ♪
♪ Don't you know you cramp my style? ♪
♪ She said, I’m sorry, pretty daddy ♪
♪ You know my love is just for you ♪
♪ Won't you say that you'll forgive me ♪
♪ And say your love for me is true? ♪
♪ I said, Wait a minute, 'gator ♪
♪ I know you mean it just for play ♪
♪ Don't you know you really hurt me? ♪
♪ And this is What I have to say ♪
♪ See you later, alligator ♪
♪ After 'while, crocodile ♪
♪ Can't you see you're in my way now? ♪
♪ Don't you know you cramp my style? ♪
♪ See you later, alligator ♪
♪ After 'while, crocodile ♪
♪ So long, that's all ♪
♪ Goodbye ♪
-[man] All right!
-[all cheering]
-Say, friend.
-Yeah?
-Nice guitar you've got there.
-Well, thank you very much.
We were trying to find out
the name of your band.
The name?
Hey, guys, we got a couple of
foreigners from the flatlands with us.
[all laughing]
Are you serious? You mean you've never
heard of Bill Haley and the Comets?
Well, I, uh, I've been kind of sick.
[coughing] I don't get out much.
Well, stick around, alligator.
Rockin' will cure anything you have.
-Ready, boys?
-Yeah.
["Rock-a-Beatin' Boogie"
by Bill Haley and His Comets playing]
♪ Rock, rock. . . ♪
Say, friend, you back in this world yet?
Descending, daddy-o. Comin' in on a cloud.
How come nobody's dancing?
♪ Rock, rock, rock, everybody ♪
♪ Rock-a-beatin' boogie beat ♪
♪ You take a rock, you take a beat ♪
♪ You take a boogie, you make it sweet ♪
♪ You take a rock-a-beatin' boogie ♪
♪ Rock-a-beatin' boogie beat ♪
♪ Well, the rock-a-beatin' boogie ♪
♪ B-O-O-G-I-E. . . ♪
Dig, man, when the most
is on the floor, we give 'em room.
♪ Shakin' to the rhythm
Of the rock-a-beatin' boogie ♪
♪ Jumpin' to the rhythm
♪ Rompin' to the rhythm
Of the rock-a-beatin' boogie ♪
♪ B-O-O-G-I-E ♪
♪ You gotta jump, you gotta jive ♪
♪ You gotta dance, to be alive... ♪
[hoots] Look at that crazy hop.
Hey, those two are good.
-Square, huh?
-You mean you didn't know?
♪ Well, you're rockin' to the rhythm
Of the rock-a-beatin' boogie ♪
♪ Dancin' to the rhythm
♪ Shakin' to the rhythm
Of the rock-a-beatin' boogie ♪
♪ Jumpin' to the rhythm
♪ Rompin' to the rhythm
Of the rock-a-beatin' boogie ♪
♪ B-O-O-G-I-E ♪
♪ Rock, rock, rock, everybody ♪
♪ Roll, roll, roll, everybody ♪
♪ Rock-a-beatin' boogie beat ♪
[whistling]
-Say, uh, that was real keen.
-Thank you.
Would you mind telling me
what you fellows were playing?
Well, it's easy, alligator.
All you do is play the music upside down.
[all laughing]
I suppose for waltzes,
you play it sideways?
Waltzes? Watch your language, man.
There are ladies present.
-[all laughing]
-Haley. Mr. Haley.
-Mr. Haley?
-That's right, friend.
And I can make them call you
"Mister" from coast to coast.
-How'd you like to make a fortune?
-In money?
[chuckling] You kidding?
'Course I ain't kiddin'.
All depends on how the crops go.
Sometimes we get paid off in turnips,
sometimes in onions--
Okay, in money.
What do we have to do?
-Well, you're musicians, aren't you?
-Just on Saturday nights.
The rest of the week,
I’m a tractor mechanic, Billy has a farm,
-Johnny sells seeds, Al--
-Okay, listen.
What if every night was Saturday night?
It'd be all right, I guess.
It'd sure mess up the rest of the week.
[all chuckling]
What if you fellows were musicians
all the time, and never did anything else?
Something wrong, Bill?
Oh, nothing's wrong, miss.
Incidentally, you were very good.
Thank you.
-You work with the band?
-Yes.
Then you're in on the deal, too.
I beg your pardon? Who are you?
Well, I’m Steve Hollis.
I manage orchestras.
You're also managing to be very vague.
Maybe I should start from the beginning.
Perhaps you can tell me when and where
we can have a little talk?
We can talk here, I guess.
The dance ends at 1 2:00.
All right, Cinderella.
This is one twelve o'clock
when you won't turn into a pumpkin.
We'll hang around. Come on, Corny.
Hey, are these two guys for real?
[indistinct chatter]
["A.B.C. Boogie" by Bill Haley
and His Comets playing]
Goin' off your rocker, Steve?
What do you expect to do
with an outfit like that?
Corny, we've been kiddin' ourselves
too long.
If there's no dance band business,
we don't work, right?
So let's find a high bridge and jump off.
No, that's what we're gonna do
if my idea doesn't pan out.
You know what we're gonna do first?
Jump off a low bridge?
We're gonna try to get
the people dancing again.
I figure if Haley's combo
can do this in Strawberry Springs,
maybe they can do it
in the rest of the country.
Buster, is that a long shot.
What have we got to lose?
Well, we got, uh. . .
Nothing.
I don't know, Mr. Hollis.
What might be good for us here
might not be the answer someplace else.
But I’m not asking the boys
to give up their jobs. Not yet.
Not until I get them a concrete offer.
But, of course, once we get started,
they're gonna have to forget
about tractors and seeds.
It sure is a big step.
Lisa usually does
that kind of thinking for us.
Well, they have security here, Mr. Hollis.
Do you call it security,
being perched up on a mountaintop?
Why, you kids have talent.
Talent's something
you can sell for big money,
not just onions and turnips.
I hadn't thought dancing
the rock 'n' roll was talent.
Take my word for it, honey.
Any gal that can make a guy's eyes pop out
the way you can has plenty of talent.
And nobody can demonstrate this dance
better than you and your brother.
What do you say?
Do we ride the gravy train together?
How much gravy do you expect
for your trouble?
Well, we'll. . . We'll split, 60-40.
-Corny and I'll take 40.
-Forty percent?
You shouldn't get more than ten.
Now where did you get
that kind of information?
I’ve read Variety.
Then you should know, my dear young lady,
that I’m not an agent. I’m a manager.
It's a common thing for managers
to get 40%, sometimes even 50.
-We'll have to think about it.
-All right. How long?
Until you come down from that 40%.
In that case, we'll both think about it.
My name, incidentally, is Lisa Johns.
This is my brother, Jimmy.
-Hi.
-My father owns the motel.
That's where you can find us
when you've made up your mind.
Let's go, Jimmy.
Don't look at me, Mr. Hollis.
If Lisa won't go for the 60-40,
there's nothin' I can do about it.
-Well, what does she want?
-You got me.
All I know is we always get
1 00% of the onions and turnips.
[both chuckle]
Leave it to a woman
to make all the trouble.
Look, why don't you forget
the whole thing?
How are you gonna get booking
for a new outfit like that
without going to Corinne Talbot?
Don't worry. I'll find a way.
Sure.
Corinne's agency has every top hotel
and nightclub tied up for bands
and acts from New York to California.
You won't get anywhere selling
the Comets into some broken-down dive.
In that case, I'll just go to Corinne,
that's all.
Definitely.
You know she won't even let you in
her office unless you agree to marry her.
Oh, she's probably forgotten
all about that by now.
Besides, what's one thing
got to do with the other?
Business is business.
Corny, I’m so sure about
that Haley bunch and that girl.
If I could just get 'em signed
to a contract and promote 'em right,
we got a sensation on our hands.
You want to take it from old Cornball?
With the face and the figure
on that Lisa doll. . . [scoffs]
she's probably been promoted by experts.
Oh, I’m not talking about that kind of--
Hey, maybe I am. Sure.
Sure. Romance, Corny.
That way, I may be able to soften her up
into making the deal.
Hey, now, wait a minute.
These farmers up here have shotguns.
Ugh, get off of it.
She's no farmer's daughter.
You heard her say so yourself.
Her father owns the motel.
In that case,
he probably has two shotguns.
-Eh?
-Eh.
[chuckling] Oh, boy.
Ah.
[breathing deeply]
Get a load of that air.
Take it easy, lad.
What do you wanna do?
Frighten your lungs to death?
[Steve chuckles]
[hinges squeaking]
There's your shotgun bait.
Lisa.
-Good morning.
-[Lisa] Good morning.
You're up and around
kind of early, aren't you?
It's 9:30. Most folks have been up
since 5:00.
5:00?
I told you. It's the air.
Nobody can sleep.
Mr. Hollis,
-this is my friend Holly Jenkins.
-Hi.
-Corny Lasalle.
-Hello, Mr. Lasalle.
-How do you do?
-How about showing me the town?
Oh, I’m sorry.
I was just on my way for a swim.
-Oh, you have a swimming pool?
-You might call it that.
I'd be glad to show you the town.
I'll tell you what, Holly.
You show Corny the town,
-and Lisa will show me the swimming pool.
-Uh--
I'll get my trunks, huh?
Does your friend always do things
on the spur of the moment?
Depends on who's wearin' the spurs.
[Corny and Holly chuckling]
[Lisa] That didn't take long, did it?
No, just long enough.
I was wondering
how you'd look in a bathing suit.
I bet you were.
I must have my imagination overhauled.
You, uh, even look better
than what I had dreamed up.
Thanks.
Smell the strawberries?
They grow wild around here.
-You come here often?
-Often as I can.
That must be what makes them wild.
You don't waste much time.
It's my imagination. It's in a hurry.
Men's imaginations
are always faster than they are.
Oh, what do you mean by that?
You're leading up to the point
when you think you can kiss me.
Oh, well, I don't know about that.
It's all right.
There, it's finished.
Now we can talk about other things.
-Who wants to talk about other things?
-You do.
To you, I’m just a silly, romantic girl
who'll want to give you 40%
when you should have ten.
No, wait. I didn't say anything. . .
Perhaps you won't mind
starting your argument at 30%?
Oh, now, young lady,
if you think you're gonna. . .
Twenty percent?
You're taking advantage.
Isn't that what you wanted to do to me?
And you're also too suspicious.
Ten percent.
Now, look, if you think
I’m a silly, romantic guy
who's gonna take ten percent
when he should have 40. . .
Okay, you said it.
That's where I heard it.
Do you object to the way I do business?
I don't know yet.
[Steve] Twenty percent?
Let's be fair about this. 25.
Then we have a deal?
-Mr. Hollis.
-Steve.
Steve.
You are levelling with us?
Honey, managing bands is my business.
If I don't get them work, I don't eat.
All right, it's a deal.
I'll leave for New York
the first thing in the morning.
Now, Corny'll stay here and work out
some more routines with you, hmm?
I think I'm scared.
There's a lot of world
outside of Strawberry Springs.
Ah, don't worry, honey.
Why, the public will dig you the most.
ls that the way you say it?
Yeah.
Remember what
Christopher Columbus once said.
"The world is no square."
-[laughing]
-Oh, I’m sorry.
[Lynn] Why, Mr. Hollis.
-Hi, Lynn.
-It's good to see you again.
Nice seeing you.
I hope Miss Talbot feels the same way.
Well, we can find out.
Mr. Hollis to see you.
[Corinne] Send him in.
No earthquake. Go right in.
Said the spider to the fly. Thank you.
[Corinne] Hello, stinker.
You didn't throw it back out,
so I guess it's all right to come in.
-Hi.
-I thought you'd be sore.
-What about?
Men refuse to marry me every day.
Only those in the home for old men.
And you.
Steve, something's been bothering me.
Why did you lead me
to believe you loved me?
Well, let's put it this way.
Why did you lead me to believe you loved
all of this more than you could any man?
What's wrong with it? It's made me rich.
I offered you $20,000 a year and a chance,
if you worked out right,
to become a partner.
ls that bad?
No, it's good.
Except that I had my own ideas
on how to become a success.
[Corinne] Or failure.
Yes.
Except that I at least had my choice.
You're stubborn.
You know, Talbot Enterprises
is the biggest agency in show business.
I don't go around offering a deal
like that to every man I meet.
Perhaps you should.
You're a cinch to come up
with something better than old Steve.
-Then why did you come here?
-[Steve] Business.
A favor?
No, I. . . I think I can
make some money for you.
I never discuss business
during business hours.
[chuckling] That's logical.
How about over dinner?
I have to go to the Chez Suzette tonight
to talk to Tony Martinez
about his new booking.
Oh, don't worry about it. It's on me.
A business expense.
Okay, you've got a deal.
I have a new gown that shows off
my vanity in the right places.
I know what you mean.
Don't be too stubborn, Steve.
I'd hate to see you
in the home for old men.
["Cueros" by Tony Martinez
and His Band playing]
[Tony Martinez singing in Spanish]
Well, my pet, I hope
you haven't forgotten your mambo.
No, it's a little bit like swimming.
You throw a man in the water, he'll swim.
He doesn't want to drown, you know?
-I’m not sure I like the comparison.
-[both laugh]
Steve, you're trying to be a crusader
with an unknown band such as the Comets.
Tony Martinez is going to be
the top novelty outfit in the country.
That's why he's doing business.
After he finishes here,
he goes to the West River Club
with The Platters vocal group.
It's a hot group.
Martinez gave the public something new.
That's why they want him.
Now Haley's got something new, too.
Look, Corinne, I. . .
I’m not an amateur
in this business, you know?
I didn't just get off of the bus.
I've been around a little while.
I think I can pick a winner
as well as the next guy.
You've picked a few in your day.
Then why don't you do this?
Book the Haley combo into the right place.
Give 'em a showcase.
And give Lisa Johns and her brother
a chance to demonstrate the dance.
This Lisa's a doll, you know?
Looks great, young, fresh, sparkles.
She can't miss.
Just how old is this doll?
Well, she's 20, 21 . What's the difference?
I’m not sure I know.
Suppose we forget about the dance act
and talk about the band.
But they work together.
Look, it takes a great dance team
to demonstrate rock 'n' roll.
The young folks all over the country
want to see how it's done,
so they can do it, too.
Now, if it's demonstrated right. . .
And if I don't book the band and the act?
Then there's other agents.
You know better.
We'll manage.
Shall we leave now?
Still stubborn.
Let me think overnight
about Mr. Haley and the Comets.
We can decide in the morning, huh?
They're playing our song.
I never heard it before.
Then from now on, it'll be our song.
Come on, darling.
-Mike?
-[on intercom] Yeah.
-Will you come in, please?
-Mmm-hmm.
[door closing]
That booking for the Mansfield School
for Girls up in Hartford,
-two weeks from today.
-A graduation prom.
Tony Martinez plays the date
before he goes to the West River Club.
We still need an inexpensive band
to alternate with Martinez.
Yeah, something high-class.
This Mansfield School
is the most exclusive in the country.
Calls for a real sweet combo.
You know, heavy on the violins,
light on the brass.
-The booking mean much to us?
-One shot.
Some of these one-nighters
are more nuisance than they're worth.
That's what I was thinking.
I have the alternate band.
Who are they?
A new combination.
They're called Haley's Comets.
Soft music, sweet, refined.
Just the thing for
the dear little girls of Mansfield.
Okay, boss, if you say so.
You know how they'll be received
as well as I do.
I think I know just
how they'll be received.
You know, these, uh, these
lily-white hands are working too hard.
[Corinne] So you'd rather
put 'em in dishwater?
Maybe you'd like playing housewife.
Look, boss, we're in the right business.
We could write beautiful music together.
We could book ourselves
into heaven 52 weeks a year.
[Corinne chuckles]
Such nice words.
Steve could never think
of something like that to say.
-Steve Hollis?
-He's in town.
Well, I suppose I can wait for you
as long as you can wait for him.
I’m changing my campaign.
I’m going to play rough.
-You think that'll get him?
-I don't know.
But I'll know a lot more
when we go to Hartford in two weeks
to hear Haley's Comets.
[horn honking]
[Steve] Lisa!
-Steve.
-Hi, honey.
Oh, Steve.
[laughing]
Hey, you did that like you meant it.
We greet all our guests here like that.
-Stevie-boy.
-Hi, Corn.
-[Jimmy] Hi, Steve.
-Hi, Jimmy.
Well, are we big Broadway stars,
or aren't we?
Well, let's just say that, uh,
you'll be close to Broadway.
How close?
-Hartford, Connecticut.
-Hartford?
Yeah, it's a one-night stand.
It's a high school prom.
-Tony Martinez and the Band will be there.
-No kidding.
I found somethin' else
while you were gone.
Another outfit. With Lisa and Jimmy,
the Comets,
and this new bunch,
we have our own unit.
-What's the act's name?
-Freddie Bell and the Bellboys.
When they don't work nights at the mill,
they come to our Saturday night dances.
-Are they good?
-Oh, yeah.
All right. Now, look,
this is a solid chance.
The top booking agent in the country
will be at Hartford to see you.
The top booking agent. Corinne Talbot.
Yeah, Corinne Talbot.
You sold your soul to the devil.
You sold out for a mess of porridge.
Who's Corinne Talbot?
I told you, porridge. Only, she's no mess.
Ah, Corny's crazy.
Look, this is a great opportunity.
This can be the start of everything
for you kids and the band.
Steve, we're in no hurry.
If you don't want to do business
with this woman,
we can find other ways.
That's what I told her. No, it's all set.
Now, we're gonna rehearse
every night until we leave.
-Corny, you tell Haley and the boys.
-Yeah.
Come on.
You can use the phone in the office.
Bully.
You know, when you get there,
Hartford will be closer to Broadway
than ever before.
[slow Latin music playing]
[indistinct chatter]
[inaudible]
Steve, I’m worried. This doesn't look
like a rock 'n' roll crowd to me.
You're right.
Still, the Talbot agency should know
what they're doing.
I wouldn't trust that Corinne
as far as I could throw Lulu-belle.
Maybe they just want
a contrast in the music, huh?
Man, is it going to be a contrast.
When do we go on?
As soon as Martinez finishes this number.
I'll go get the boys ready.
Senor, if we keep on
playing music like this all night,
we'll have much trouble in staying awake.
Just remember what we've been told.
There is to be no exciting music.
Just music.
Si, senor. It's a living.
Why did you wait until tonight
when we get to Hartford
to tell me that Haley's Comets
are a jive outfit?
Those school people
will throw 'em out bodily.
I own Talbot Enterprises, Mike.
I think I'm entitled
to tell you what I please.
This'll make fools out of us.
Just out of Steve Hollis.
You weren't kidding.
You are playing rough.
I want Steve broken,
in pocketbook and in spirit.
You think you'll want a man
who has to crawl to you on his knees?
I'll decide that when the time comes.
I want that band to fail,
and I want that girl to go back
to wherever she came from.
A girl you've never even seen.
I heard Steve talk about her.
It wasn't what he said.
It was the way he said it.
[exhaling]
I wonder if you'd, uh,
go to all of that trouble for me?
You mean, you'd still want me
after what I just said?
Some people love murderers.
There's the hotel.
[slow Latin music playing]
Well, that's it. The Comets go on next.
-Steve, I’m scared stiff.
-Ah, relax, honey.
Just imagine you're still
in Strawberry Springs, hmm?
[indistinct chatter]
The Bellboys set to go on?
Soon as we call 'em.
Okay, the Comets
will warm 'em up first, huh?
Well, everything looks normal.
Our friend Mr. Haley is just
about to cross over the bridge.
-[Bill] On your mark!
-[band] On your mark!
-[Bill] Get set!
-[band] Get set!
-Now ready!
-[band] Ready!
[all] Go!
♪ Everybody, razzle dazzle ♪
♪ If it's all night long ♪
-♪ Now here's a dance ♪
-♪ Wack-a doo. . . ♪
-Infamous.
-Barbaric.
-♪ It's the hipster's dance ♪
-♪ Wack-a doo. . . ♪
We're dead. They're not dancing.
Everybody's afraid to break the ice.
Come on.
But, Lisa, they'll crucify you.
♪ Wack-a doo, wack-a-doo ♪
♪ You just take your baby ♪
♪ Don't you leave that spot ♪
♪ Then you dance like crazy ♪
♪ Give it all you've got ♪
♪ That's the razzle dazzle ♪
♪ If you're ready or not ♪
-♪ On your mark ♪
-♪ Get set ♪
-♪ Now ready ♪
-♪ Ready ♪
♪ Go! ♪
♪ Everybody, razzle dazzle ♪
♪ If it's all night long ♪
[audience clapping to the beat]
-♪ Let's get together ♪
-♪ Get together ♪
-♪ One, two and three ♪
-♪ Jumpin' to the center ♪
-♪ To the center ♪
-♪ Just you and me ♪
-♪ Put your best foot forward ♪
-♪ Wack-a doo, wack-a-doo ♪
-♪ Baby, can't you see? ♪
♪ When you hear them holler ♪
♪ And you ain't nowhere ♪
♪ Honey, you just foller ♪
♪ Cos we're sure not square ♪
♪ That's the razzle dazzle ♪
♪ Well, it's everywhere... ♪
Stop them. Stop them.
Mr. Gilfillan, do something.
[girl] Just a minute, Miss Dunlop.
My father's going to donate
a new library to this school.
You stop the dance, I'll stop the library.
Oh!
♪ Everybody, razzle dazzle ♪
♪ If it's all night long... ♪
Shall we dance, Miss Mullen?
Oh!
♪ Everybody, razzle dazzle ♪
♪ If it's all night long... ♪
So the Comets are going
to be thrown out bodily, huh?
♪ That's the razzle dazzle. . . ♪
Pardon the expression, boss,
but you goofed.
♪ Razzle dazzle song ♪
[song stops]
-[Steve] Hi, Mike.
-Steve.
Thanks for the big break, Corinne.
Regardless of what's happening
here tonight,
the-- the big hotels and clubs
will never buy the Comets.
Maybe if it was part of a revue
with real talent.
Are you kidding?
You see what Lisa and her brother
are doing out there.
[Corny] Besides, we have a revue.
I'll get the Bellboys.
[all cheering]
You kids were wonderful.
Thanks, Steve. It was awful lonely
on that floor for a while.
Excellent. You succeeded
in making a bunch of whirling dervishes
out of girls who were brought up
to be ladies.
Now wait a minute.
You were fine.
Miss Talbot didn't expect
that sort of reaction.
Would you mind telling me
what she did expect?
I’m sorry we pleased
the audience, Miss Talbot.
I thought that's what
we were supposed to do.
Hey, Lisa. Uh, th. . . There's the Bellboys.
Oh, let's watch.
♪ Hello, everybody ♪
♪ I mean everybody ♪
♪ We're gonna teach you to rock
Yeah, We're gonna teach you to rock ♪
♪ Yeah, We're gonna teach you to rock ♪
♪ Yeah, so come on and rock with us ♪
♪ We're gonna teach you to rock ♪
♪ Yeah, We're gonna teach you to rock ♪
♪ Yeah, so come on and rock with us ♪
♪ If you can't swing, get out of the Way ♪
♪ Well, We don't Want no squares ♪
♪ Once you learn
And you get in the groove ♪
♪ You'll jump around
And you Won't have no cares ♪
♪ We're gonna teach you to rock
Yeah, We're gonna teach you to rock ♪
♪ Yeah, We're gonna teach you to rock ♪
♪ Yeah, so come on and rock with us ♪
♪ I said one, two, three, four ♪
♪ Five, six, seven, eight, nine, ten ♪
♪ Rock, rock, rock, rock ♪
♪ We're gonna teach you to rock ♪
♪ Well, We're gonna teach you to rock ♪
♪ I'm not Arthur Murray
Teach you in a hurry ♪
♪ Teach you mighty slow ♪
♪ Once you learn
And you get in the groove ♪
♪ You'll jump around
And you'll stop the moon ♪
♪ We're gonna teach you to rock ♪
♪ I said one, two, three, four ♪
♪ Five, six, seven, eight, nine, ten ♪
♪ Come on and rock with us ♪
Well, you heard the Bellboys, Miss Talbot.
What do you have to say now?
There it is, Corinne.
That's our whole unit.
The band, the kids, and the Bellboys.
You can book all three acts together.
Sorry, Steve. I don't think
the agency can sell your people.
These sort of acts aren't in our line.
See you back in town.
Good night, Miss Johns.
I think she's dead wrong about all of you.
I hope you make it on your own.
-Good luck, Steve.
-Thank you, Mike.
If the Bill Haleys and the Bellhops
can make like they make,
why can't we make like we make?
Because the professors have taken
the "cha" out of our cha chas.
So we sneak back
a couple of little cha chas, maybe?
We sneak.
[speaking Spanish]
["Mambo Capri" by Tony Martinez
and His Band playing]
[singing in Spanish]
Steve, maybe it's my fault. I shouldn't
have talked to her the way I did.
Ah, no. Get one thing straight, honey.
It's. . . It's really my fault.
She's out after me,
and all of you are gonna suffer for it.
We're not licked yet.
Maybe, maybe not.
I just think you'd be better off
without me around, that's all.
Steve, that's not fair.
You got us this far,
you can't pull out now.
Sure, we made cats
out of these squares tonight,
and you proved we could do it.
You gonna admit
that a dame like Corinne beat you?
Well, look, I’m perfectly willing
to keep trying if you want it that way.
Crazy, man.
He's stayin'. Give me some skin.
Yeah.
Yeah, but make no mistake about it now.
There's gonna be
a lot of tough sleddin' ahead.
We're headin' for New York
right after this shindig's over, okay?
[singing in Spanish]
[in English] ♪ Rocking and rolling
The cha cha cha ♪
♪ Rocking and rolling
Rocking and rolling the cha cha cha... ♪
[singing in Spanish]
[audience cheering]
I know that precious conscience
of yours, Mike,
so I’m not going to ask you
to take care of this.
Must be pretty bad
if you don't entrust it to my conscience.
I shudder at myself sometimes
when I think of the things I do.
It's so nice to have power.
Okay. Okay, I'll be your straight man.
What are you cookin' up this time?
The agency has a lot of friends, Mike.
And you're going to use them
to keep the Comets from working.
You're going to blackball Steve.
In impolite circles, it's known as
"lowering the boom."
Corinne, Confucius say,
"Woman who want man thinks
of 1 ,000 ways to make him love her
"and no ways to make him hate her."
That's because Confucius was a man.
When Steve hates me enough,
he'll know that he can't live without me.
[Mike chuckles]
[blues music playing]
Well, so what's the score?
We've been in New York about two weeks.
We've had about two dozen turndowns,
and we got about two dozen bucks
left to our name.
You put two and two together,
and what do you get?
Too, too depressing.
If I were old enough to believe in fate,
I'd say it was against us.
How do you like that?
Even the radio's singin' the blues.
They make a fortune singin' about trouble.
We spend a fortune getting into it.
In short, we spent our roll
on rock 'n' roll.
[on radio] This is yours truly,
Alan Freed,
the king of the rock 'n' rollers,
-speaking to you from the West River Club. . .
-Alan Freed.
...Where We're broadcasting
our rock 'n' roll party.
Doesn't that ring a bell?
-Appearing here in person ...
-If it does, I didn't hear it.
-I’ve been counted out, pal.
-No, no kidding, Steve.
Alan Freed is emceeing the show
at the West River Club.
Remember when he was running
the Alamo Theatre down in Texas?
The Alamo Theatre, yeah.
Well, you loaned him
1 ,000 bucks to put on a show.
Corny, you don't think often,
but when you do,
you make up for lost time.
Run to your place and put on
something pretty, we're goin' steppin'.
-The West River Club?
-Yeah.
There's just one thing
I’ve got to say to Mr. Alan Freed.
What's that?
Remember the Alamo.
[laughs]
-Forget it.
-[blows]
[audience applauding]
Good evening,
and welcome to the West River Club.
We're very happy to have you
with us tonight
and we're gonna rock 'n' roll.
This is Alan Freed,
the old king of the rock 'n' rollers.
You're gonna meet
two of the most exciting combinations
you've ever met in your life.
And here they are. The Ernie Freeman Combo
with the sensational recording group,
The Platters.
[audience applauding]
["Only You" by The Platters playing]
♪ Only you ♪
♪ Can make this world seem right ♪
♪ Can make the darkness bright ♪
♪ Only you ♪
♪ And you alone ♪
♪ Can thrill me like you do ♪
♪ And fill my heart With love ♪
♪ For only you ♪
[band scatting]
♪ Only you ♪
♪ Can make this change in me ♪
♪ For it's true ♪
♪ You are my destiny ♪
♪ When you hold my hand ♪
♪ I understand ♪
♪ The magic that you do ♪
♪ You're my dream come true ♪
♪ My one and only you ♪
♪ Only you ♪
♪ Can make this change in me ♪
♪ For it's true ♪
♪ You are my destiny ♪
♪ When you hold my hand ♪
♪ I understand ♪
♪ The magic that you do ♪
♪ You're my dream come true ♪
♪ My one and only you ♪
♪ One and only ♪
♪ You ♪
So that's-- That's about it, Alan.
I don't know whether Corinne Talbot
really blackballed our group or not.
I. . . I just don't know.
I do know that if you'll give our unit
a chance here, you'll never regret it.
Well, Steve, you don't have to
sell me on rock 'n' roll.
I'll tell you what we'll do.
Uh, Ernie Freeman and The Platters
leave for Miami the end of this week.
There's another outfit coming in,
but I think we can push 'em back.
And I think we can get your guys in here,
and I know they're gonna do a great job.
You just remember one thing,
that Alan Freed did remember the Alamo.
All right? It's a deal.
♪ One, two, three o'clock
Four o'clock, rock ♪
♪ Five, six, seven o'clock,
Eight o’clock, rock ♪
♪ Nine, ten, eleven o'clock,
Twelve o'clock, rock ♪
♪ We're gonna rock
Around the clock tonight ♪
♪ Put your glad rags on and join me, hon ♪
♪ We’ll have some fun
When the clock strikes one ♪
♪ We're gonna rock
Around the clock tonight ♪
♪ We're gonna rock, rock, rock
Till broad daylight ♪
♪ We're gonna rock, gonna rock,
Around the clock tonight ♪
More telegrams.
Boss, you can't go on ignoring
this rock 'n' roll stuff anymore.
Every hotel and club in the country
is wiring for information.
The only information you can give them is
that we don't handle that kind of music.
Corinne, for Pete's sake.
How far are you gonna carry
this feud with Steve?
An agency has to keep up
with the times, or fall on its face.
Corinne, listen to me.
Steve's in love with Lisa Johns.
He's not even looking at other women.
So you think it's all decided.
Lisa wants a ring on her finger.
You want to put a ring
through Steve's nose.
Which do you think he'd rather have?
The thing to do, dear Mike, is to see that
Mr. Hollis doesn't have a choice.
Call Steve and ask him
to come over this afternoon.
Tell him it's very important.
Still playing rough?
Dear, dear Mike, just leave
those telegrams on your way out.
Fellas, I'll tell you what.
Let's try this.
[guitar strumming]
[scatting]
-Okay?
-[all] Okay.
-[Bill] All right. Let's try it.
-[music playing]
All right, I think we've got it now.
Let's do it, huh?
♪ R ♪
♪ O ♪
♪ C ♪
♪ K ♪
♪ R-O-C-K, rock ♪
♪ Take an "R" from an eight
To the bar 88 ♪
♪ "O" from the tone
Of the sax syncopated ♪
♪ "C" from the key
Of a six-string guitar ♪
♪ "K" from the kick of a rim shot meter ♪
♪ That's how they made it
That's how they played it ♪
♪ R-O-C-K, rock ♪
♪ I know my As and my Bs and my Csies ♪
♪ Ps and my Qs, and my X, Y, Zsies ♪
♪ Know how to lose
All the blue, blue, bluesies ♪
♪ Jump in a pair of my dancin' shoesies ♪
♪ Date With my baby, rock With my baby ♪
♪ R-O-C-K, rock ♪
♪ Oh, Strauss discovered waltzes ♪
♪ The handy man found the blues ♪
♪ Then Haley came along
With a rockin' song ♪
♪ Crazy, man, crazy, crazy news ♪
♪ "R" you Would hop
Hear the band, it's a movin' ♪
♪ "O" more than that
It's a go, go, groovin' ♪
♪ "C" what I mean
It's a honky-tonk action ♪
♪ "K" like a kiss
It's a cool attraction ♪
♪ Who Will getcha, I'm gonna betcha ♪
♪ R-O-C-K, rock ♪
♪ R ♪
♪ O ♪
♪ C ♪
♪ K ♪
♪ R-O-C-K, rock ♪
♪ Oh, Strauss discovered waltzes ♪
♪ The handy man found the blues ♪
♪ Then Haley came along
With a rockin' song ♪
♪ Crazy, man, crazy, crazy news ♪
♪ "R," you Would hop
Hear the band, it's a movin' ♪
♪ "O" more than that
It's a go, go, groovin' ♪
♪ "C" what I mean
It's a honky-tonk action ♪
♪ "K" like a kiss
It's a cool attraction ♪
♪ Who Will getcha, I'm gonna betcha ♪
♪ R-O-C-K, rock ♪
Okay, fellas, that's it. Take five, huh?
Hey, Steve, phone call for you.
-Oh, thank you.
-You're welcome.
Hello.
Oh, Mike? Hiya, Mike.
-It's Mike Dodd.
-[all murmuring]
Yeah, boy, how are you?
Oh, yeah, it's goin' great.
Yeah, things are really lookin' up
for the kids.
No, no, we haven't set any engagements
after the West River Club. No.
We've been holding out
for the right spot. Yeah.
Oh, Corinne?
Yeah, I could get in
to see her this afternoon,
if it's strictly business.
All right, you tell her
I'll be in this afternoon.
Okay, Mike.
How do you like that?
Corinne's after us now.
-[all talking]
-What do we need her for?
For one thing, Jimmy.
She handles class bookings.
I don't want to see you kids
working in dives.
Hey, wait a minute.
Oh, I don't mean here. [chuckles]
I suppose from now on we won't be
able to afford you guys anymore.
Well, first of all, we don't even
know what Corinne's deal is yet.
Whatever it is, we'd work for nothing
if you'd ask us, Mr. Freed.
Thank you, honey.
You kids have all been just great.
And you made more money for this place
than they've ever made in their history.
Don't forget
to tell Corinne Talbot that.
She'll hear it so many times,
she'll think it's a broken record.
Wonderful. Congratulations, everybody.
Thank you.
-[piano playing]
-All right,
so I was wrong about the Comets
and your Lisa Johns.
I'll tell you what I'll do.
I'll make you a deal.
Turn your contract
with the unit over to the agency,
and you come in as a partner.
Split 50-50 with me on everything.
Sell my outfit to you,
so you can sell them down the river?
You'll never get a deal like that
anywhere else.
Maybe not.
No, Corinne,
I think your idea of a partnership
has too many strings attached.
Then it's no soap?
No soap.
What do you want?
Bookings. The best you've got.
What if we make a three-year deal
without a partnership
for the Comets, the dance team,
and the Bellboys?
With a good chance
that I'll get them on records.
You're startin' to make a little sense.
I’m prepared to make such a deal
with the unit opening in San Francisco.
Tell you what I'll do. I'll talk
to the kids, and I'll get back to you.
If they're smart, they'll take it.
It'll guarantee their future.
Hmm.
It won't do your future
any harm, either, hmm?
-See you later, hon.
-Okay.
Get me Lisa Johns on the phone, please.
I’m sure you didn't ask me to have lunch
for social reasons, Miss Talbot.
-Steve told you about the deal.
-Yes.
You know what that three-year contract
could mean to you and the boys?
$1 00,000 the first year, $200,000
the second, and $300,000 the third.
It seems almost too good to be true.
There's one thing, however.
You're an investment, Lisa.
You'll become an idol of the teenagers,
you'll develop a big public,
hundreds of fan clubs.
College boys will be voting you
the girl they'd most want to get caught
in a compromising situation with.
My agency will be spending a fortune
on your publicity and exploitation.
The bigger you and the boys become,
the more money we'll all make.
But you're the only girl with the outfit.
The only one that means S-E-X.
Like a movie star.
I want my investment protected.
Of course, I can understand that.
All right, then. These are the facts.
If you get married, you won't be
worth a dime to me or yourself.
The kind of public you're going to get
won't want to think of you
as a married woman.
In short, you will have to sign a clause
that for the life of the contract,
three years, you will not marry.
For the life of the contract,
I’m not to get married.
-That's what the contract will say?
-Exactly.
I don't know why you're worried.
-No one's asked me to marry them.
-He hasn't. . .
I mean, they haven't?
Just the same.
You never know when some man
is going to come out from under a rock
and pop the nasty question at you.
You'll have to sign that clause,
or the deal is off.
If I kept all the boys
from making a lot of money
just because I wanted to be married,
I'd certainly be a terrible heel,
wouldn't I?
The heeliest heel that ever was.
How long will it take
to make up the contracts?
Four days, five, perhaps.
I'll get on them right away.
All right, Miss Talbot, I'll sign
the contracts. Just the way you want them.
I knew you were smart.
Then it's all settled.
You and the boys leave for San Francisco
-at the end of the week.
-Fine.
Just one word of advice, Lisa. Have fun.
You'd be amazed at the number of men
around the country
who don't want to get married.
["Happy Baby" by Bill Haley
and His Comets playing]
♪ Happy baby, happy, happy baby ♪
♪ Happy, happy baby ♪
♪ I got a baby
And my baby's happy With me ♪
♪ Happy baby ♪
♪ I got a baby
And my baby's happy With me ♪
♪ Happy baby ♪
♪ A slick little chick
And she treats me tenderly ♪
♪ Happy baby ♪
-Hi, ball of fire.
-[Corinne] Morning.
-Oh, boy.
-Hmm, with all that hustle in your bustle,
you must be taking your vitamins.
Corinne, I came up with an idea
last night that wouldn't let me sleep.
About me, I hope.
-About money.
-Well, that's second best.
Now, the returns are in.
You and I both know
what rock 'n' roll has done.
It's got people
on their feet again, dancing.
Druggists are selling
more corn plasters than ever.
So what's your big idea?
A rock 'n' roll jamboree.
Keep goin'.
Now for weeks, I’ve had other bands
and vocal groups
making up rock 'n' roll arrangements.
Now as I see it,
we take a bunch of these good acts,
put them all together into one big show,
and we'll give them a night of jive
they've never seen before.
Now to get the movement
going coast to coast,
I think I can talk one of the big networks
into televising us on a national hook-up.
Son, you hit the jackpot.
Now, look, Los Angeles
should be the right spot for this.
They go for these big jazz concerts,
and I think they'll eat this one up.
Who do you want to stage it?
Alan Freed.
You know, he's handled a lot of big shows.
Sold.
Freed can leave for Los Angeles
immediately and work with my coast office.
Now the first week in July,
we rent a great big hall.
All the kids will be out of school
and I think every kid from six to 96
will go for this in a big way.
July it is.
Freed goes to the coast,
I stay here in New York,
set up the networks.
You're a genius, lad.
-Oh, it's nothing, really.
-[both chuckle]
Now that there are 3,000 miles
and three years
between you and Lisa Johns,
how about thinking over
that offer I made you?
My dear young lady,
one jamboree at a time.
I gotta go. I got a lot to do.
["Mambo Rock" by Bill Haley
and His Comets playing]
♪ Hey, mambo ♪
♪ Mambo rock ♪
♪ Everybody's doin' it, mambo rock ♪
It's a sellout.
Two more minutes
and the jamboree goes coast to coast.
We've had some big deals
in the agency, Steve,
but this puts the icing on the cupcake.
You know, I think I'm more nervous
than our kids must be.
Drink. Numb your reflexes.
It's a shame that
Mike Dodd isn't here to see this.
[Corinne] Darling, who needs him?
Why don't you marry the guy
so he can forget you?
He works for me. Let's not talk business.
[Steve chuckles]
One minute.
I suppose you think
I'm seven kinds of a witch
for the things I did to you.
Eight kinds.
But considering why you did what you did,
I suppose I should be flattered.
Naturally.
[chuckles]
You know, Corinne,
you're not really a bad sort at all
if you would, uh,
not try to run everyone else's life.
It's the mother instinct.
Mothers always do the thinking
for their children.
That really puts the icing on the cupcake.
No, I mean it.
Every time the alarm goes off
in the morning,
I begin to wonder about this idea
of being a career woman.
Well, you're the boss. Why set the alarm?
You're being evasive.
[Steve chuckles]
Five seconds.
[buzzer sounds]
-[Alan] Hi, everybody!
-[audience] Hi!
Yours truly, Alan Freed,
welcoming you all to our gigantic
rock 'n' roll jamboree
at famous Hollywood Hall
here in Los Angeles, California.
Welcome to the big new beat
in popular music,
and we've got a tremendous array of
rock 'n' roll talent here for you tonight.
So here we go with
Freddie Bell and the Bellboys.
[audience applauding]
Go, man.
["Giddy-Up-A-Ding-Dong" by Freddie Bell
and the Bellboys playing]
♪ I said, giddy up ♪
♪ Giddy-up-a-Ding-Dong ♪
♪ Giddy up, giddy-up-a-Ding-Dong ♪
♪ Giddy up, giddy up, giddy up ♪
♪ Well, now
I Went ridin' the other night ♪
♪ I picked out a horse
Oh, my, what a sight ♪
♪ The name of the horse Was Ding Dong ♪
♪ While I was ridin'
I Was singin' a song ♪
♪ I said, giddy up ♪
♪ Giddy-up-a-Ding-Dong ♪
♪ Giddy up, giddy-up-a-Ding-Dong ♪
♪ Giddy up, giddy up, giddy up ♪
♪ Well, now, we rode and we rode
The Whole night through ♪
♪ The horse was tired, and I was, too ♪
♪ I had a date With my gal at 8:00 ♪
♪ Come on, Ding Dong, we can't be late ♪
♪ I said giddy up, giddy-up-a-Ding-Dong ♪
♪ Giddy up, giddy-up-a-Ding-Dong ♪
♪ Giddy up, giddy up, giddy up ♪
♪ Giddy-up-a-Ding-Dong ♪
[drum rolling]
♪ Come on, horse, roll along ♪
[audience cheering]
Wonderful. We're gonna
really rock 'n' roll tonight.
And now, America's number one
vocal group, with two great record hits,
here are The Platters.
[audience applauding]
♪ Oh, yes ♪
♪ I'm the great pretender ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Pretending that I'm doing Well ♪
♪ My need is such ♪
♪ I pretend too much ♪
♪ I'm lonely, but no one can tell ♪
♪ Oh, yes ♪
♪ I'm the great pretender ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Adrift in a World of my own ♪
♪ I've played the game ♪
♪ But to my real shame ♪
♪ You've left me to grieve all alone ♪
♪ Too real is this feeling
Of make-believe ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Too real when I feel ♪
♪ What my heart can't conceal ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Yes, I'm the great pretender ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Just laughin'' and gay like a clown ♪
♪ I seem to be what I'm not ♪
♪ You see ♪
♪ I'm Wearing my heart like a crown ♪
♪ Pretending that you're still around ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Too real is this feeling
Of make-believe ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Too real when I feel ♪
♪ What my heart can't conceal ♪
♪ Yes, I'm the great pretender ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Just Iaughin' and gay like a clown ♪
♪ I seem to be what I'm not ♪
♪ You see ♪
♪ I'm Wearing my heart like a crown ♪
♪ Pretending that you're ♪
♪ Still around ♪
[audience applauding and cheering]
And now, for the thrill
you've all been waiting for.
Here is one of the most phenomenal acts
in the history of show business,
Bill Haley and his Comets!
[audience applauding]
[Bill] Thank you, Alan. Thank you, kids.
Let's rock 'n' roll
with a real swingin'
little tune called "Rudy's Rock".
["Rudy's Rock" by Bill Haley
and His Comets playing]
It's a hit, Corinne. It's a big, fat hit.
[laughing]
Now, let's talk about us.
Oh, everything's been said, Corinne.
From now on, there's nothing more
to talk about.
Why not?
Watch the stage.
[audience applauding]
Buddy-buddies,
before we go into our big finale,
I'd like to introduce that living doll,
that real cool rock 'n' rollin' chick
who wants to say a few words,
Lisa Johns and her brother, Jimmy.
Thank you, rock 'n' rollers.
I just want to say how thrilled
everybody is backstage
with the way you've received our show.
And I especially want to thank
our wonderful emcee,
Alan Freed, who helped us
put the show together.
And an equally wonderful man
without whom, there would be
no rock 'n' roll at all,
my husband, Steve Hollis.
What was that child talking about?
She said "husband."
She ought to know.
Then you are married?
Legally.
I have a contract with that girl.
I'll sue you, Steve,
for every cent you have.
I'll ruin you and her, and that band.
They'll never make
another appearance on a stage.
No one breaks a contract
with Corinne Talbot.
Oh, I don't think
you'll sue anyone, Corinne.
If you recall, it took five days
to draw that contract.
And there's a clause that says
Lisa's not to be married for three years.
Well, she won't.
-But you just said that--
-She can't.
You see, we were married
before the contracts were signed.
Outsmarted by an amateur
from Strawberry Springs.
I'll tell you one thing.
I think you and Mike
will be very happy together.
You know, you wouldn't be such a bad guy
if you didn't try to run
everybody else's life.
[both chuckling]
-Then you're not angry?
-No, what good would it do?
Hmm, Mike Dodd, huh?
Well, it's a good thing I had another man
warming up in the bullpen.
[chuckling] Touche.
Touche yourself.
♪ When the chimes ring five
Six and seven ♪
♪ We’ll be right in seventh heaven ♪
♪ We're gonna rock
Around the clock tonight ♪
♪ We're gonna rock, rock, rock
Till broad daylight ♪
♪ We're gonna rock, gonna rock
Around the clock tonight ♪
♪ When it's eight, nine, ten, 1 1 , too
I'll be goin' strong and so Will you ♪
♪ We're gonna rock
Around the clock tonight ♪
♪ We're gonna rock, rock, rock
Till broad daylight ♪
♪ We're gonna rock, gonna rock
Around the clock tonight ♪
♪ When the clock strikes 12
We’ll cool off then ♪
♪ Start a-rockin' round the clock again ♪
♪ We're gonna rock, gonna rock
Around the clock tonight ♪