MAN:
Oh, here we go, here we go.
Closer, guys.
(BOYS LAUGH)
We never looked that young, did we?
CHRIS:
The camera never lies, you old sod.
JOHN:
I don't believe it.
And getting between a boy's legs
at such a tender age! Dear me!
Oh, don't I look a prat, eh?
- Yeah.
- What do you mean, yeah?
Nearly broke the camera that time, an' all.
CHRIS:
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Oh, showing off your zoom, eh, Mal?
Hey you, behind the projector!
- Didn't know we had a zoom.
- (THEY LAUGH)
MARK:
Oh, it's embarrassing, isn't it?
- It is, yeah.
- Hey, do you remember this?
- Hey! Drunk again!
- (THEY LAUGH)
Who's this?
(THEY LAUGH)
Oh, yeah!
- Woo-hoo!
Spare a penny for Old Jack Tar, love.
- Note the walk.
- (THEY LAUGH)
CHRIS:
Oh, disgusting!
MARK: Yeah, no standards.
Any old nobbler will do.
- (THEY LAUGH)
- Show-off.
Gosh, a year's a long time though, innit?
MALCOLM:
Yeah.
We've been some places, haven't we?
JOHN:
Yeah, it's true.
- Hey, you know what, Mark?
- What?
MALCOLM:
I think you've grown shorter.
- (THEY LAUGH)
- MARK: Oh piss off, you bastard.
Woo!
CHRIS: Oh, zooming again, Malcolm.
I don't like your technique.
- Eh...
- (THEY SING)
♪ Da, da, da, da, da, da, da ♪
♪ Well, life on the ocean wave ♪
♪ But you never have time to shave ♪
♪ Life on the ocean wave,
she never got time to shave ♪
(HE LAUGHS)
Remember that?
Yeah, you always had
a bee in your bonnet.
MARK:
Yeah, must get that laugh fixed.
- Yeah.
- (THEY LAUGH)
JOHN:
Hey, Mal, who's that?
(CAR HORN BEEPS)
BOUNCER: Sorry, son,
you can't come in here.
Union Street?
(INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER)
(INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER CONTINUES)
(STREET CHATTER)
Take it easy, pal.
- (BOYS SHOUT)
- (DISCO MUSIC PLAYS)
Thanks. Hello.
(INDISTINCT NOISY CHATTER)
♪ I'm feeling proud
and I'm walking tall ♪
♪ My heart is filled with harmony ♪
♪ Yes, I want some windows
all around me ♪
♪ Bringing happiness close to me ♪
♪ With the troubles
of the past behind me ♪
♪ I'm feeling kind of breezy and free ♪
Move it.
♪ It's a sweet sensation,
just to be alive ♪
♪ Sun shining down on me, yeah ♪
Cor, bloody hell, that must've hurt.
(THEY LAUGH)
Sue, right?
Right?
She's there for good, OK?
PAUL:
Tattoos in your mouth?
Bloody hell, Sean, that's horrible.
She's the fucking best I ever had.
No one's taking her
away from me, right?
Yeah.
There you go. Hey.
Who's a naughty boy then?
♪ Grab your things
and come along with me ♪
Rating, are you?
You naughty little bastard.
You're out too late.
You fucking Raleigh ratings
should stick to the rules
tucked up in bed by 1 :00.
Piss off.
- MAN: Ooh!
- (THEY LAUGH)
♪ It's the first sweet day
of the rest of my life ♪
♪ And no one's going
to take it from me, yeah ♪
♪ Moving up, I'm moving out ♪
This is the friend
I was telling you about.
What friend's that?
Would you like a drink?
Hmm, rum and black, thanks.
Same please.
Right, let's get the drinks in then.
Who the fuck are you?
(DISCO MUSIC CONTINUES)
♪ All the tears of yesterday ♪
I can dance.
Pure balance, see.
I can fucking dance!
Piss off and dance then.
(HE SIGHS)
I've remembered today
what I wanted to be.
Not this.
He's waiting.
See if you black out.
I don't want drinks from him.
Don't push your luck, son.
He might have knocked
your teeth out.
♪ Feels so good, I wanna shout it ♪
♪ Yes, I do ♪
(MUSIC AND VOICES BLUR)
(DISCO MUSIC CONTINUES)
Alright.
Hey, you!
MARK:
I’m listening.
I wanted to be an acrobat.
♪ Shout, movin' up, movin' out ♪
An acrobat.
It's your round.
♪ Movin' up, movin' out ♪
♪ Shout, movin' up ♪
(WATER RUNS)
MAN (VO): Ladies and gentlemen,
we commence the second half
of our performance with our
sensational flying act from Hungary.
Will you please welcome
the sensational...
Beros!
(BANGING ON DOOR)
(BANG ON DOOR)
(HE GRUNTS)
Couldn't make you hear me.
Are you a fucking queer?
You blacked out. I’ve been banging
on the fucking door for hours.
Tired.
Up all night...
hitching.
Where you from then?
(DISCO MUSIC PLAYS)
♪ When you're in love ♪
♪ You see through... ♪
Are you Gail?
No. Why?
Looking for Gail.
It's her night off.
♪ ...on the road ♪
♪ You travel, still you roll the dice ♪
My mum and dad
are coming down tomorrow.
Better sober up by then.
You in trouble?
No.
Last day, see?
I'll be going.
I'll be going!
Come on then,
let's see you dance then.
♪ Nothing it seems, will change ♪
(INDISTINCT CHATTER AND LAUGHTER)
♪ But should you wake one day ♪
♪ And find she's flown away,
my friend, love will come again ♪
♪ Love won't be denied ♪
♪ Not long as there's a spark inside ♪
♪ As you say ♪
(NEW DISCO SONG STARTS)
(GLASS SHATTERS)
(GLASSES SHATTER)
STAN:
Frank, get him out of here!
(WOMAN SCREAMS)
(GLASSES SHATTER)
Get out of here!
What are you bloody playing at?
You should've had him out of here
long before this! Long before this!
(HE VOMITS)
Get him out!
- You fat bastard!
- (SHE SOBS)
STAN: The bloody hell do you think
I pay you for, fat bastard?
Argh!
This is where you puke.
Here!
(HE VOMITS)
(HE GASPS)
(DISTANT DISCO MUSIC CONTINUES)
God be with you, young man.
(DANIEL GASPS)
DANIEL: Stop!
(HE COUGHS)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(AMBULANCE SIREN WAILS)
(ENGINE STARTS)
(SIREN WAILS)
I mean, he's a bastard,
that bouncer.
Do you know what I mean?
He made a real mess
of that poor bastard.
Who is this?
Well, listen.
OK, I mean...
he's a stupid asshole,
asking for it...
but even so...
Even so, Paul.
Even so, fucking what?
Daft bugger.
Well, maybe we'll have a bit
of vengeance tomorrow night, eh?
It's last night ashore, Dave, pal.
Last night ashore.
Oof!
(HE GRUNTS)
Come on, give us it here.
There we go.
(HE SIGHS)
That's it.
Shouldn't have left him.
(GULLS SQUAWK)
(SHIP'S HORN BLARES)
(DISTANT CHILDREN SHOUT)
(RADIO JINGLE PLAYS)
SINGING ON RADIO:
♪ Weather, sound, news ♪
NEWSREADER:
This is Des Fahy.
Ulster Secretary, James Prior
met his police and army chiefs today
in a full-scale review of security
in the province.
Mr Prior has made another appeal
to Protestants not to...
Have you got any bread?
In the fridge!
REPORTER:
Mr Prior spent more than two hours
with the Chief Constable
at the Royal Ulster Constabulary
and Sir Richard Lawson, the general officer
commanding troops in Northern Ireland...
Any milk?
SUE:
Try the doorstep!
...in a message clearly aimed
at the Protestant population
Mr Prior said...
(RADIO FADES)
(GULLS SQUAWK)
One MP, John Dunlop, says more SAS men
are needed in the border areas.
He also wants to see
a volunteer police force
set up to support
the police and army.
At the moment, he says,
the security forces...
- You found it then?
- Yeah.
(RADIO CONTINUES INDISTINCTLY)
(RADIO CLICKS OFF)
Quite a domesticated bloke,
aren't you?
I thought you were
going to have a lie in.
- Sorry.
- Do you want anything?
No.
Thanks.
(SHE GIGGLES)
- You are funny.
- Am I?
Yes.
(KETTLE WHISTLES)
Kettle.
Shame you've got to work.
You have too.
- Come here.
- Oh, what are you doing?
I don't start till 10:30.
Hey, what time is it?
It's not that late.
Come here.
Oh, bloody hell, it's gone 9:00.
Look...
- I'll see you later, alright?
- Alright.
I finish at 5:00.
See you then!
GAIL:
He's in a hurry.
He's doing some diving practice.
Going with that bloke.
Paul, is it?
Look at some old sub
in the dockyard.
Oh, that would be Uncle Paul.
They call him that.
Don't you know him?
He's a mate of Sean's.
Well, that's his problem, isn't it?
I think I'll make a cuppa tea.
Don't want to eat nothing.
One too many last night?
We went to this club up in town.
You know, Cigale?
I see.
Steve looked a bit sweaty
when the bill came.
Said he'd stay down on Union Street
with his mates next time.
Well, won't have no choice tonight.
Patrols don't let you out.
I wanted to go to this party.
Girl I knew at school.
Her dad's loaded.
Should be posh, you know?
You might be alright
just the two of you.
Go in a cab.
SUE: Malcolm getting
an early train is he, Gail?
I hope so.
I rang him last night.
He sounded really fed up.
He always does
when he goes home.
Why did he go then?
I don't know.
His brother's on leave.
They're quite close, aren't they?
At least, he's supposed
to be on leave anyway.
I don't know.
You know what he's like.
He's a bit of a one for stories.
I'll sort him out, you'll see.
(INDISTINCT TRAIN ANNOUNCEMENT)
(DISTANT MUSIC PLAYS)
Gail?
It's Malcolm.
Look, I'm on the... the 9:50, OK?
No, he didn't show up.
(MACHINES BEEP)
MALCOLM:
Yeah, I can't talk now.
See ya, OK?
Listen, I'll tell you something
about that area.
It's Irish, mate.
That's what it is around there.
Don't start going on
about the Irish.
CHRIS:
IRA. Know what I mean?
You don't want to go down there, mate.
If you have to have one
order your Stag by phone.
You daft prat.
Go down there with a haircut like that,
you'll lose your fucking knees.
It's not a joke, Chris.
Mal, old son!
John, this is Malcolm.
Malcolm, this is John. John, this is Malcolm.
Malcolm, this is John.
- Oh, shut up.
- It's not a joke.
A Triumph Stag is, old son.
The IRA.
Well, you know what they say, Mal?
Three's a crowd.
You don't look well, Mark.
Got a hangover, Mum.
Typical.
You can shut up for a start.
Watch your manners.
ls that a wig?
Course not.
Stupid.
Don't you get in trouble at school?
Vegetable dye, innit?
Washes out.
Am I going right?
Yeah, it's just down the end
of this road, on the left.
Number eight.
- OK?
- Yeah.
You look rough.
They're all sitting in the car.
Yeah, OK. Won't be a sec.
Your sister coming?
Yeah.
You don't have to come.
VINCENT:
What?
You can change your mind
about coming.
I want to come.
Gill 16 yet?
Piss off.
Your mum and dad coming?
Going shopping.
Even better.
(HE CHUCKLES)
Refreshments.
MARK'S FATHER:
Come on! We've been waiting.
Wouldn’t stand for you
if you were my old man.
Bad-tempered old sod.
- (SHIP HORN BLARES)
- (GULLS SQUAWK)
Come staggering out the main gates
this morning feeling really putrid
and there he was,
camera at the ready.
Yeah, it looks a nice one.
Yeah, he's just bought it.
Pride and joy.
I'm gonna get one in the States, cheaper.
Bloke I know got one last trip.
Real beauty, it were,
electronic and all.
Here.
Best thing for a hangover
is a bit more.
TOUR GUIDE ON PA: Good afternoon,
ladies and gentlemen.
Welcome aboard the Plymouth Bell.
- We'll do our best to...
- I got on with Dave's crowd.
More fool you, mate.
I got through 30 quid.
30 quid!
Anyway, where'd you get to?
I didn't see you.
White Swan.
- It's boring.
- Get stuffed.
TOUR GUIDE ON PA: The lighthouse
is the old Eddystone lighthouse.
The monument with the green ball on top
is the naval war memorial
for the two World Wars.
I've been up since 7:00.
These people come and woke me up...
started firing questions at me.
What have you been up to,
young Mark, eh?
- There was trouble last night.
- Oh yeah?
I met this bloke, a young kid.
What, old as you, were he?
Oh look, Vincent, just listen, will you?
I met this kid.
Pissed out of his head he was,
all on his tod.
Well, he got slung out.
That big bouncer, Frank,
he took him out.
Oh, he's the worst.
MARK:
They thought it was a fight.
Put 'em right on that anyway.
Doesn't sounds as if you were in a state
to know what the fuck went on.
(HE SIGHS)
Well, he couldn't fight anyone.
He was legless.
Except when he was dancing.
You've been dreaming, mate.
They don't know who he is.
Nothing on him.
He's still unconscious, see?
Head injuries.
Yeah, well, you can't do nothing.
Just keep out of it.
TOUR GUIDE ON PA:
It fires the Exocet missile.
It carries a helicopter.
It's a very fast ship,
which is powered
by Olympus Rolls Royce engines
which are gas turbines.
It gives this ship or this class of ship
a speed of around 34 knots.
This trip's for your benefit, not mine.
I weren't asked.
I can think of better things to do
on my last day ashore
than look at bloody ships.
I'm cold.
Christ.
It's the age.
ls it?
My sister was like that, her age,
when she were older than me.
Nearly drove me fucking mad.
She get better, did she?
Don't know.
Don't see her no more.
TOUR GUIDE ON PA:
This ship was built here, at Plymouth.
It carries a helicopter.
You see the missile platform
on the bows of the ship quite clearly.
I've been looking forward to this trip.
You always do.
Got nothing to stay home for, have I?
West Coast, eh?
California.
California!
TOUR GUIDE ON PA: This is the new
nuclear refitting yard here at Devonport.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Alright?
Better?
Better keep off the tea.
(THEY CHUCKLE)
Well, it's quicker here to Plymouth.
I still don't quite believe
this is all happening.
Ah, well,
we can't be lucky every time.
You try doing an exchange when you want
to be away for a few months.
It's a doddle.
There's blokes queueing up to stop you
for your shore posting.
It's harder this way 'round, love.
Oh, it'll be alright.
You're never gonna wear them,
are you?
Of course I am.
The sun shines
all the time on the West Coast.
Beach Boys, all that stuff.
You look like a bloody poof.
Laid back.
That's what these are, my son.
(HE LAUGHS)
Drink up, young Malcolm White.
Your round next.
Oh, I'm taking it easy.
Fucking skinful last night.
Not matching vodkas with that mum of yours?
You naughty fellow.
(POP MUSIC PLAYS)
Who's winning?
- It's a bit hard to say.
- At the moment.
You going past to Plymouth?
- Penzance.
- MALCOLM: That's nice.
You sisters?
No.
MALCOLM:
I like Cornwall. It's nice there.
When were you in Cornwall then?
Holidays.
Yeah.
I went there every summer
as a kid. It's really good.
Whereabouts did you stay?
Uh... it's, um...
Well, it's a little place near... St. Ives.
Nice, uh, cottage was it, eh?
Wake in the morning
to the cry of the gulls?
(HE LAUGHS)
In college?
Yes, that's right.
MALCOLM:
I bet you're older than me.
I've been in the navy
since I was at school.
I'd say they were younger.
It's your round.
(HE LAUGHS)
You alright, Steve, our son?
Yeah, of course.
You're doing well.
(HE SIGHS)
I was having a drink
with Sean McKay last night.
- Oh yeah?
- Mm.
He's a bit upset.
Well, he's very upset
about you and that bird of his.
Sue, is it?
Look, I'd leave it out if I was you.
Well, last night ashore and all.
Look, it's all finished
between her and McKay.
She told me.
Well, if he sees you down Union Street
with her tonight, he'll have you.
He's a fucking nutter.
He can be a bit nasty.
OK... it's just you're gonna be on ship
with him come tomorrow
whether you like it or not.
So what?
He can't do nothing there, can he?
Come on.
Right.
Let's get on with it.
- Yeah.
- Right.
(GULLS SQUAWK)
MARIE: If you're waiting
for the Spanish Armada
you've missed it.
Look, we come into town
for a night out.
We spent five minutes in my club.
Why am I a fucking villain?
It was him who threw up
all over you, wasn't it?
Yes, Stan.
Wasn't it?
That doesn't mean he deserves
to end up in hospital.
I'm sorry about the boy.
Really, I am.
That's not good enough, Stan.
I mean, they're all still there,
aren't they?
Frank and his like,
your employees?
They're all still there,
getting ready for another night
and I suppose the hospital's getting ready
for another night too.
Marie, love,
both sides get hurt in a war.
Oh, yes, right.
The wards fill up
with injured bouncers, do they?
Oh, for Christ's sake!
MARIE:
Oh, you know that's not true.
You're just trying to make out
it's a fair fight.
Well, it's bloody well
not a fair fight.
Most of them are too drunk
even to defend themselves.
They start it, every fucking time.
I know what they're like.
One of them happens to be my son.
It's no answer, Stan.
It's no answer at all.
I mean, suppose it was Vincent
lying out there with his face
all smashed in. What would I say?
That boy of yours hasn't been
in my club for two years.
That's how much he hates me,
remember?
Just be thankful for small mercies.
TOUR GUIDE ON PA:
This complex was only completed
handed over to the Royal Navy,
around two years ago.
It was opened by Prince Philip.
Thank you, my dear.
Ark Royal’s scrap will pay
for the desks in there.
Surface ships are a waste of time.
Glamour, they are.
Icing on the cake.
Eh, Gill?
I went around this sub last year,
Navy days.
Stink, don't they?
They don't.
Anyway, I reckon I'd go around the bend
if I was stuck in one of them
for months on end.
Crews do go around the bend.
You can recognise deeps
straight off.
(HE CHUCKLES)
That and the round shoulders.
Would you go in subs?
Wouldn’t mind.
Don't get to see the light of day much
in a frigate, do I?
Besides,
don't always get the choice.
How do you mean?
They can't get the numbers, see?
They draft you
from the surface to the subs.
As long as you fit, you're in,
there ain't no two ways about it.
I'm going for fresh air.
Found our little sea legs, have we?
I got to go up the hospital
this afternoon.
See about that bloke.
They want me to talk to him.
Creepy, innit?
Frank ditched his wallet.
There's no identity on him.
What's the police attitude?
Usual. Don't want to know.
He is serious, is he?
Coma.
Shit.
Police might change their attitude,
you know, if he dies.
I'm not an idiot, Alf.
The MPs are asking questions.
- Yeah?
- It's the identity thing.
The hospital are making the running.
They'd leave it alone otherwise,
wouldn't they?
Frank's such a bloody fool.
He panicked.
Helped himself to some cash,
more like.
Stupid boy.
Stupid little idiot.
He should never have been there.
OK, Alf, thanks.
- Keep in touch, alright?
- OK, Stan.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
I'm sorry, I got to go.
Go? Go where?
The hospital.
Well, I got a mate
had an accident at work.
I said I'd visit.
This is our last day together
for six months, Mark.
I’m sorry.
I promised I would.
Well, how long are you going to be?
- I'm buggered if we...
- Well, it won't be long, Dad.
I’m buggered if we're going to just
stay here while you go off visiting.
Well, you can go to the Barbican,
can't you?
MARK'S MOTHER:
Perhaps we should go home.
I like the Barbican.
There's that tea shop
we went to once.
I know the one.
MARK'S MOTHER:
Oh, I don't care for that.
Oh, go on, Mum.
Half past three, alright?
OK.
That's settled then.
NAVAL OFFICER:
Maybe he isn't Navy.
But he's certainly military personnel.
Well, put calls out to the other
services then, can't you?
I want his parents here.
Do you understand?
I want somebody
who knows him really well.
Well, it could be crucial.
(MACHINES BEEP)
You were as drunk as he was,
is that the problem?
He's not my mate or anything.
He didn't talk much.
Who else were you with?
Just a couple of birds.
Can you remember them?
Yeah.
Talk to him about them.
Mark...
please try.
Do you remember
the two birds I was with?
(BEEPING SPEEDS UP)
You bought them a drink or two.
One was...
Well, she was awful, wasn't she?
The other weren't so bad.
They were waiting for someone,
they kept saying.
Do you remember?
No one ever come.
(BEEPING CONTINUES)
Ask him questions.
You kept saying
you were a good dancer.
Do you remember how you kept saying
you were a good dancer?
And I kept saying...
I kept saying, you ought to...
go and dance then?
Didn't I?
You went and danced.
I fell asleep.
(BEEPING CONTINUES)
I do that when I’m pissed.
But you kept on about something.
Something you wanted to do.
Something you wanted to be.
"I wanted to be a farmer."
It was like that.
Something you wanted to be.
You know, when you're a kid
and you want to be something.
Like a fireman or spaceman...
or something.
You know?
(BEEPING CONTINUES)
(BODY THUDS)
ANNOUNCEMENT:
The 9:10 from Birmingham New Street
to Plymouth due to arrive
on platform four at 12:10.
This train is reported to be running
approximately 45 minutes late.
(MUSIC: "THE THINGS DREAMS ARE MADE OF"
BY HUMAN LEAGUE)
Mal, I was getting worried.
Where'd you get those from?
He had an emergency supply.
You cunning bastard.
Have a drink, girls.
No, thanks.
Go on! It's good stuff, that, you know.
"Probably the best lager in the world."
Come on, do you good.
Alright.
I accept, thank you.
- There you go.
- There, see?
Didn't hurt, did it?
Hurt me. I bought it.
JOHN: Your reward
will be in heaven, my son.
Get off, will you?
I'm sorry. I have this weakness
for boy's knees.
Sorry, no cups.
Oh, Chris, don't you bring
any cups for guests?
Are there complaints?
It's OK.
This is how we usually drink it.
HE IMITATES HER:
"It's OK."
ALL:
"This is how we usually drink it."
Fuck you.
Excuse me.
RADIO:
♪ ...two or three friends ♪
♪ These are the things,
these are the things ♪
♪ The things
that dreams are made of ♪
Reminds me of a bird
I used to know.
You know,
either vacant or engaged.
Are you going to get engaged,
Malcolm?
We expect some happy news.
Oh, give over.
Nice, steady girl.
Meeting you at the station, is she?
Goes on a bit, don't he?
Yeah.
Pack it in, you bastard.
♪ Take a lift to the top
of the Empire State ♪
♪ Take a drive
across the Golden Gate ♪
Ah, it'd be great
if we were fishermen, eh?
It'd be good, that.
Eh?
Yeah...
little fishing boat, waiting for us
bobbing about Penzance Harbour.
Yeah, instead of a big fucking boat
in Plymouth Harbour.
We cannot reveal the name
of the ship we will be joining.
NATO.
Shh!
MALCOLM: When I get out,
I'm gonna get a fishing boat.
Oh, yeah? Saving up, are you?
Yep.
As from now, this trip,
I'm going to be absmee...
- (THEY SCOFF)
- ...absteemious.
You'll go blind.
Gonna have a sign over me bunk
embroidered, hanging on the wall, saying
"Save it, you stupid idiot."
- Don't start till tomorrow, will you?
- No way.
- MALCOLM: No way.
- (THEY LAUGH)
ANNOUNCEMENT:
This is the 1 3:26 from Penzance
to London Paddington.
- This train is due to depart in...
- Hold on, John, look.
I said wait.
...calling at Exeter St. David's, Taunton...
- (INDISTINCT CHATTER)
- Yeah, alright.
See you later.
♪ Then I'll be gone and you'll forget ♪
- Hello.
- (RADIO CLICKS OFF)
- OK?
- Yeah.
Did you meet Chris?
Yeah.
He really winds me up sometimes.
He's with another bloke.
It's OK.
Missed you.
Yeah, get off.
How's your mum and dad?
Well, we had a bit of a row last night.
Me dad wanted to
take all three of us down the pub
all jolly together.
(HE SCOFFS)
No way.
You should've gone.
I wanted to stay in,
in case Danny rang.
Which is right.
Did he?
Checked with a mate of his.
Leave's been cancelled, apparently.
His regiment's off to Belfast.
(MACHINES BEEP)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Oh, shit!
What?
It's me flatmate's dad.
(TAXI RADIO CHATTER)
Hello there, John.
- Alright?
- Need a hand?
- Vincent's out, is he?
- Aye.
Any ideas?
No.
You can come in
and wait if you like.
Oh, thanks.
(ARCADE GAME BLARES)
Morning, Jimmy.
Hello, Vincent. Alright?
Yeah.
BARTENDER:
How's young Vinny then?
OK. Been out on a boat.
BARTENDER:
Never.
You know, cruise around the dockyard.
Real laugh.
BARTENDER:
You're one of the keen types, m'lad.
Something to do.
BARTENDER:
Packed up then?
Yeah, you know me.
Travel light, I do.
Right.
- Good afternoon.
Mr and Mrs Rowson.
- Mr and Mrs Rowson?
- Yeah.
- Would you sign that for me, please?
- Yeah, sure.
Thank you. That's room 108.
- First floor.
- Ah, lovely, ta.
- (PHONE RINGS)
- (HE CHUCKLES)
- It's here, eh?
- Yeah.
Shall I go on in?
(WATER RUNS)
OK, love?
Bit of a backache.
There's not much time.
Don't keep saying that.
You glad I come?
Yeah.
It's gonna be ever so dull.
Plenty of other chances
to go on the piss, stateside.
Oh, got it all worked out then?
(HE CHUCKLES)
Tonight...
just be the two of us.
(DISTANT RATTLING)
Nice view.
Hmm?
The kitchens.
(CAR HORN TOOTS)
(TRAIN HORN BLARES)
I enjoyed the evening otherwise.
So did I, love.
It's always a treat,
night out in a hotel and everything.
ls it?
Yes, really.
Haven't forgotten, you know,
the life I had before.
Said goodbye to Vincent?
It's funny.
We're that much apart.
Whether he's here in Plymouth
or someplace on the other side of the world
it doesn't seem to make us
less apart or more apart.
We're just the same.
Occasional letter.
Occasional phone call
from the phone box in Plymouth
or one in Hong Kong.
You're talking rubbish, Marie, love.
Can I send you some money
to buy something in America?
Tea?
Oh, thanks, son.
(MUSIC PLAYS ON RADIO)
- Tea?
- Ta.
Look, don't let him come in
and hang about for me.
OK?
Yeah, yeah.
Oh, thanks.
Well, last night ashore then?
Going on the razzle?
Don't go on razzles, Dad.
Just a few pints with me mates.
Navy suits you pretty well,
doesn't it?
- Money's good.
- I don't mean that.
What then?
Well, coming and going, travel.
How long you going this time?
Six months.
A lot of lads don't like that.
Always trying to get exchange posting,
stay ashore.
I don't miss anything when I'm away.
People might miss you.
No.
- Your mum misses you.
- No.
So do I, Vinny.
Look, I don't want to talk about this.
You don't look after yourself.
I get by, thank you.
Time you bought some new clothes,
smarten yourself up a bit.
I don't have the money you've got.
Try keeping out the boozer for a week.
Leave me alone, Vin.
I can say the same for you and all.
Why'd you come anyway?
What you here for?
You're my son.
You don't fucking know
why you come around here
sit about and make me miserable.
Half an hour ago, I was having
a couple of pints with me mates
and I was up, you know?
And now with you in this
pissing awful room, I’m down.
Sod you.
(DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR SLAMS)
(GULLS SQUAWK)
Sailing tomorrow?
That's right, yeah.
What would old Plymouth do
without Jack Tar, eh?
Certainly be a bit quieter, I'd say.
Plymouth does well out of the Navy.
Lived here for years.
Worked in the dockyards.
I've seen it grow.
Yes... Plymouth does well
out of the Navy.
Did well out of the war too.
Bombed flat, wasn't it?
Bombs don't destroy money.
Good life, in the Navy.
I had a lad in the Navy.
Good life.
Sailed all over the world.
Got in a few scrapes, mind.
Goodness me.
(HE CHUCKLES)
Had a wife in every port,
I don't doubt.
(DOG PANTS)
He won't hurt you.
No, I know. I know.
Know about dogs.
Was brought up with 'em.
He needs feeding.
(CHATTER ON TV)
...the opening minute of the second half,
to take the score
to 1 3 points to nil for Australia.
Paul McLean coming into the line...
(TV SWITCHES OFF)
OK then?
Yeah.
Going into town for a pint.
You're starting early.
Oh, I said I'd see Steve.
So?
What's the matter?
(SHE SIGHS)
Can't wait to go, can you?
Eh?
All mates together.
I'll see you at the restaurant then.
You and Sue, me and Steve.
That'll be good, eh?
Doing right by the womenfolk.
MAN:
But God does not need to look into my eyes
to see what wickedness I harbour there!
No, he does not!
For God is not mocked!
Yes!
I can hurry on my way!
(PHONE DIALS)
- VINCENT ON PHONE: Hello, Mum?
- Hello, Vinny.
Where are you talking from?
Are you on your own?
MARIE:
Well, I'm with Stan, of course.
I don't want him to hear us.
Oh, really?
It's private.
Alright, Stan's left the room now.
Good.
Stan and I have been together
for two years, you know?
How much longer are you going to be
so unpleasant about it all?
Vinny?
I don't want to talk about Stan.
Then what do you want to talk about?
Dad come 'round today.
(SHE CHUCKLES)
Well, that explains your bad temper.
Look, he knows when I’m here.
He knows when I'm ashore.
Vinny, what's the matter, love?
He'd know if I didn't
ever write to him again.
He'd look it up in the paper,
see where my ship docked
find out which ship I...
he'd phone the fucking Admiral of the fleet.
Vinny, please.
Hello?
I'm sailing tomorrow morning.
If only you'd contacted me a week ago.
Why the hell haven't you contacted me?
Mum?
What?
Come into town.
We could have a meal or something.
There's a problem.
Well, you can do that, can't you?
No. I can't. I...
Bloody hell, he can do without you
for one evening, can't he?
Explanations always sound so...
Look, there's been some trouble
down at Stan's disco, I...
I don't want him
down there tonight.
Especially tonight.
It'd be dangerous.
Oh, what is all this?
If I let him out of my sight,
he'll be down there.
Oh, my God, Vinny, you're so unkind.
Always, always, you make
these impossible suggestions
then when I can't make it work,
you go off in a bloody rage
and then of course it's all my fault.
I... want to see you.
I do.
Yeah, yeah.
Vinny, I'm just too frightened.
Don't you see?
Stan is for every day,
not just for once or twice a year.
You...
Vinny, do you know what I'm saying?
Yeah.
Fuck off.
(HANDSET CLATTERS)
Where have you been?
Was out walking.
- You been awake long?
- Yes.
It was a long walk.
Doesn't matter, does it?
Well, I'm glad you finally
remembered me.
What's the matter?
It's not much fun, that's all.
Waking up here, all by myself.
I'm sorry, OK?
Where are we gonna eat?
Oh, I booked a table at the Ganges.
- You know, the Indian, where we...
- Where we ate last time.
It was good, wasn't it?
Bloody hell.
Oh, I meant to hang this up.
Bugger.
(HAIRDRYER WHIRS)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
TV PRESENTER:
Tonight we are pleased to welcome
one of the senior officers
from HMS Impregnable
Commander Phillip Masterson RN.
He's talking in our studio.
MASTERSON:
Ah, yes, I think we shall have
a fairly active social life.
Good, eh? Tokyo.
Great.
PRESENTER: Have you had much
in the way of female company?
Oh gosh, yes. The ladies fly out
to join us in Los Angeles
to keep an eye on us.
That must make a long tour
that much better, I'm sure.
Seriously, yes it does.
Frankly, the Navy has moved
a long way on these matters.
I mean, let us not forget
that the Navy is recruiting
in competition with industry
for the best brains
and chaps with top management ability.
We really have to look to our laurels
in matters of welfare
conditions of work, and so on.
PRESENTER: Commander, how many men
are there on Impregnable?
MASTERSON:
About 500.
Ready, Mark, old son?
Yeah.
We heard you were legless last night,
you naughty boy.
Jumping the gun.
Let's go.
MASTERSON:
It's a lot of people in a confined space.
We jolly well have to learn
to rub along together.
And we do, you know,
most of the time.
(MACHINES BEEP)
(NOISY CHATTER AND LAUGHTER)
(CAR HORN HONKS)
(MUSIC: "ARMED AND READY"
BY MICHAEL SCHENKER GROUP)
A pint of lager please.
A pint of bitter, please.
♪ Are you feeling right? ♪
♪ Cos I need you now
like I never did before ♪
♪ Is it hard enough? ♪
♪ Is it long enough? ♪
CHRIS:
We're not staying here long.
MALCOLM:
It's a laugh, here, bikers' pub.
Here, you know that bloke
who got done over
at Dol's last night?
- Yeah, he's from Raleigh, weren't he?
- No, he weren't.
He ain't Navy.
They told me at the hospital.
Been up there with flowers then?
Piss off.
Well, it don't matter, does it?
- What?
- If he ain't Navy.
Those shits at Dol's deserve
everything they're gonna get.
And what are they gonna get?
Ah.
Oh, we adopting him, are we?
We might not know
who the fuck he is.
But for tonight...
he's Navy.
♪ I want to see you jump
like hell when I call ♪
I'm pissing off.
- I want to talk to the landlord.
- What for?
Well... forget it.
Right.
Pint of bitter, a pint of lager, sir?
- Snakebite.
- JC, snakebite.
And a snakebite.
Another one in there, ta.
Did you hear about the trouble
last night, down at Dol's Disco?
What about it?
Your mate, was it?
Well, sort of, yeah.
BARTENDER: I wouldn't employ
a bloke like Frank.
I sort things out myself here.
Anyone see it happen?
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(MUSIC PLAYS ON GAME MACHINE)
He didn't seem to be bothered,
I must say.
Didn't he? If I was him,
I'd be fucking bothered.
He's only a kid.
Cocky, you know what Steve's like.
That's that Paul, you know?
Thinks it's just a fucking joke.
Thinks I'm just a fucking joke.
I'll tell you, I’m not crying
my fucking heart out for some tart.
There'll be others, you know?
- That's no problem for me, you know?
- Come on, Sean.
- You know you like the girl.
- Don't tell me what I feel about her
or anyone else, OK?
I'm telling you, she's over now.
It's between him and me now, OK?
OK, Paul?
- Dave's recruiting.
- Yeah, I heard that.
Yeah, the kid's pretty bad.
Raleigh he was, so I hear.
He's a bit of a daft bugger,
it seemed to me.
I'm no friend
of Frankie the bouncer's
but it was provoked just a bit. Yeah?
Wouldn’t you say?
Dave wants a bit of vengeance.
A bit of damage.
Well, I'll tell you something, Paul.
That's what I'm after too.
If that wee shit's gonna be up there,
I'll be there too.
Mark it all in really neat.
Just take it easy, pal.
He's only a kid, you know?
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Steve?
I'd stay in bed if I were you.
He's just arrived with his mates.
Don't worry, Mal.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
One thing's for sure.
He won't dare do anything in here.
Won't he?
No.
But don't leave till after he does.
I don't wanna be out there
with him creeping up behind me.
I mean, not... no way
is he gonna do nothing
but he's going on like he's
the biggest shag artist around
and then he starts yelling at these birds,
telling them to get their knickers off
and all that sort of carry on.
Well, they just wet themselves
laughing at him, don't they?
I mean, it's sad, isn't it?
He must be getting on now though?
- Yeah.
- He's getting old, isn't he?
He's 40, here...
HE IMITATES PAUL:
"I'm 40, Johnny, m'lad. I'm finished."
"Fucking 40 and fucking finished."
"Queen's fucking Navy.
I've had it up to here." Hey...
- (GLASS SHATTERS)
- Oh, shit.
I've had enough listening
to that prat.
I’m going.
(INDISTINCT YELLING)
Shut up!
(CAR HORN HONKS)
(INDISTINCT YELLING)
(MEN SING)
SEAN:
Stop those bastards!
Please!
No fighting!
You fucking rabbit.
I'll have you.
(HE PANTS)
What is this?
ls it money or a woman?
BREATHLESSLY:
Woman.
(HE BREATHES HEAVILY)
(SITAR MUSIC PLAYS)
Bloody hell.
SUE:
I don't rely on Steve.
Don't you?
Less disappointments.
It's time Malcolm grew up.
We can have a meal together,
can't we?
Two coffees, please.
Sean rang up again this morning.
So?
Sorry I spoke.
He's a nutter, you know.
Round the bend.
If you say so.
I used to think it was
really exciting, you know
to be wanted that much.
By the end, I couldn't breathe.
Not my type.
I wondered.
You never said.
You wouldn’t have listened anyway.
He used to send me flowers.
I can't do this justice, Doug.
I’m sorry.
DOUGLAS:
Tastes all right, doesn't it?
There's nothing
wrong with the food.
You feel OK, do you?
Yes, I do.
Of course I feel alright.
What do you mean?
Am I gonna throw up or something?
- I just meant...
- Look, I'm pregnant, that's all.
I've got a baby inside me.
I’m not ill.
Alright, keep your hair on.
Look, I'm not an invalid.
It spoils everything,
the way you treat me.
(HE SIGHS)
Let's go, shall we?
I'm buggered if I'm paying.
I can't. I haven't got a penny.
- Hello, Dougy.
- DOUGLAS: Alright?
Where the bloody hell have you been?
- (HE LAUGHS)
- Gail!
CHRISTINE:
I'm sorry, Doug.
- Hello.
Really sorry.
Something to remember me by.
Oh, thanks.
(MUSIC: "YOUNG TURKS"
BY ROD STEWART)
♪ Young hearts, beat free tonight ♪
CHRIS:
So I was over there at the arcade.
And he's playing pinball.
And he comes in, he says...
IN SCOTTISH ACCENT:
"OK, you tell him from me."
"Just you fucking tell him from me."
Right, Paul, didn't he?
Just leave it out, will you?
He says, "OK, you tell him,"
"If he's got his tool in ma bird,
ma Suzie..."
(THEY LAUGH)
"I'll take... I'll take it off
with a hatchet."
"I'll chop it off, piece by piece."
"And I'll make the runt eat it too."
(THEY LAUGH)
He didn't say that at all, Chris.
- He did.
- Fucking did not.
(INAUDIBLE CHATTER)
Joe?
Joe, are you?
My child.
Doreen at The Two Trees
said I'd find you here.
Oh, yes.
I'm trying to find out about this bloke
who got beaten up last night.
Doreen is...
Mr Andrew’s daughter, yes.
This... this bloke down The Antelope.
He said that she...
knows what goes on, like.
Mr Andrews is a good man.
He has charge
of the sailor’s rest home.
Aggie's. Aggie Weston's.
I've been there.
Mr Andrews is a man of God.
Well, Doreen said you'd help me.
- She said...
- Have you given in to God Almighty?
Have you, my child?
- Look, please...
- You've no right, you see.
There've been many...
good Christian men here in Plymouth.
They have broken bread
together for centuries.
Did you know that now?
Men of steel.
In Plymouth, we've been blessed
in having such men.
Many, many have worshipped,
my child.
But many have been
just so much cordage.
And when the devil has sent his storms,
his gales of hard times, his...
his reign of grief...
many have frayed, worn,
and rotted away.
But the ship holds.
It does not break from its moorings.
It does not drift to destruction
because the men of steel
hold the ship of God.
Here in Plymouth,
in the midst of so much evil
drunkenness...
and all manner of sin...
there are men of steel, you see?
This bloke...
he's in a coma.
The hospital, when I went up there,
they said that he had nothing on him.
And they don't know who he is.
They don't know who he is.
What has this little tragedy
to do with me?
You've got his wallet.
Well, Doreen says you have!
It was in the dustbin.
Heh?
(MUSIC: "LITTLE T&A"
BY THE ROLLING STONES)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Evening, John.
Uh, he ain't shown up yet.
Oh.
Having a drink?
Well, I don't want to be in the way.
It's alright. I’ll get you one.
What about you then?
- Rum and black?
- Rum and black. Mm.
Oh, bitter then, John, thanks.
A pint.
Go on, sit yourself down then.
DAVE:
Two lagers.
CHRIS:
You're Vin's dad, aren't you?
That's right.
There you are, told ya.
Fucking doubles.
What's your Vin been up to then?
Nothing.
I bet he's a handful.
(THEY LAUGH)
Alright?
Your old man's here.
What does he want?
How the hell should I know?
Tell him I'll meet him outside.
You tell him!
Vin's outside.
Wants to talk to you outside.
Oh, right.
Sorry, John.
I expect I’ll be back.
What you want?
Your mum rang me.
Look, for fuck's sake!
No, listen.
There's trouble down the disco.
And you heard about that, didn't you?
Vaguely, yeah.
There's retaliation being planned.
I want you to keep out the way.
You're a bit too close in.
You understand?
Look, I don't think my mum being
shagged by the gaffer
puts me very close in at all.
Do you?
Good old Dad!
Dad, can I borrow your car?
Tonight?
It's important, really important.
You be careful now.
- (KEYS JINGLE)
- Ta.
(MUSIC: "ROXANNE"
BY THE POLICE)
Hello?
Is that Exeter 34427?
Yeah.
I'm sorry, I'm in a pub.
Yeah, I can't hear.
(MUSIC AND CHATTER CONTINUES)
I've found a wallet.
I said, I've found a wallet.
Hi, Gail.
- Evening, hello.
- STEVE: Good evening.
They'll let us in free then, Gail?
- Hello, Bob.
- Alright then?
(INDISTINCT WHISPERING)
Who are these people?
They're just some friends.
They want to stay...
You're lucky the gaffer's not here.
Don't worry, mate.
We'll be back later with plenty of cash.
Fuck off.
See you later, Gail.
- See you, Gail.
- Fuck off!
Charming.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
They got no brains, those bouncers.
I apologise for the language he used.
- He can't help it. Well...
- (SUE MUTTERS)
STEVE:
Hadn't really thought about it.
What's all this about, eh?
(CAR HORN BLARES)
Where are you off to?
We're just going up the Fiesta.
Roller skating, you know?
Sorry, mate.
- STEVE: What's wrong with that?
- You know the rules.
What rules?
Don't get funny with me, son.
(INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER)
We've got to find some bloke.
Tonight?
You've got to be joking.
Priority.
We've got to find him
and break some bad news and all.
STEVE:
Christ.
May as well be in a fucking cage.
Alright!
(LAUGHTER AND INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Go on, Steve.
You said we could.
I didn't.
You did!
You said we could after the restaurant.
OK.
Hey, Mal, see you later, yeah?
See you.
(INDISTINCT TAXI RADIO CHATTER)
(DOORBELL RINGS)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Have you got an invitation?
Yes.
After you.
- Evening.
- Hello.
(MUSIC: "BEHIND THE LINES"
BY PHIL COLLINS)
Food and drink are in there.
(LOUD CHATTER)
♪ Give me the strength
so I can help you ♪
♪ I can be strong now,
they don't frighten me ♪
I'll put the coats outside.
Right. I'll get the drinks.
Statistically,
most men who are tattooed
are either sailors or criminals.
♪ Well, I believe we can make it right ♪
♪ It's time now ♪
(MUSIC: "IF LEAVING ME IS EASY"
BY PHIL COLLINS)
♪ I read all the letters ♪
♪ I read each word
that you've sent to me ♪
♪ Though it's past now ♪
♪ And your words start to fade ♪
Cheers.
- Good, isn't it?
- That was her.
Well, many happy returns to her then.
Her boyfriend threw up
on the sheepskin rug.
She's angry cos her dad
locked him out in the garden.
You know what?
This lot make me feel old.
♪ I hide my feelings ♪
Hello...
sailor.
I didn't mean to be rude.
I thought you were
looking rather superior.
I am.
WOMAN:
That's a bit arrogant, isn't it?
What do you want?
I don't want anything.
Are you sure?
You don't give a damn
about any of us here, do you?
You've come waltzing in here
in the tow of some girl or other
thinking you'll drink our drink
and eat our food
and then you'll trot off back
to the strip clubs or wherever
and have a good laugh about it all
with your little toughie sailor friends.
I haven't had quite as much
to drink as you have.
And what do you do for a living?
I'm a teacher.
Well, I'm in the Navy, see?
And that's work...
- I know that.
- Shut up.
I said, that's work
of national importance.
That's why we can't go on strike.
That's why we have to sign
on for fucking years.
With the money you earn,
I can't imagine you'd want to.
I don't want to, as a matter of fact.
I'm proud of what I do.
Very commendable.
Just listen, you.
You don't have any idea, do you?
Oh, piss off.
Listen.
Tomorrow, I have to spend I don't know
how many fucking weeks
floating around in some steel box
all in the cause of defending
frustrated old bags like you
from the Communist menace.
- I know what you are.
- None of that, thank you.
You're one of those CND wankers,
aren't you?
- I want you out of here!
- She's getting up my nose!
You ought to be grateful, you bitch!
We're taking risks for you!
We get killed in peacetime,
let alone wartime!
We get knocked down in hangars
and break our fucking necks!
We get caught in fires
and fucking incinerated!
That's how it's going to be,
you know!
- That's what radiation is.
- SUE: Come on!
- Sorry.
- Fire!
And you're not coming
back in here either.
(HE LAUGHS)
Excuse me, Chief.
Continental Hotel near here, innit?
(CHRISTINE SOBS SHAKILY)
I want you to be there.
I want to be there too.
That's separate.
ls it?
You see, I found this number,
and I rings up.
And that's where he stayed
last night, in Exeter.
A friend or something.
He went from Birmingham
to Exeter yesterday.
And he had his wallet stolen
in a service area, he reckons on the M5.
So that receipt can't be his.
Continental Hotel, see,
yesterday's date.
His wallet, but not his receipt.
I see.
You know about the bloke
I'm looking for?
He stole the wallet, did he?
I don't know.
Well, seems probable, doesn't it?
He got done over at the back
of Dol's last night.
He's in the Royal, in a coma.
Nobody claimed him, I gather?
Well, that's why I brought the wallet.
All helps, don't it?
I don't know.
I'm not sure I care.
Bloody Navy, bloody Union Street...
pain in the arse, the lot of it.
What's that?
Circus ticket.
(MUSIC: "WE'RE THROUGH"
BY THE HOLLIES)
♪ I should be better off without you ♪
♪ You take a pride in making me blue ♪
♪ I'm telling you, my friend ♪
♪ It's got to be the end ♪
♪ We're through ♪
♪ I told you time and time again ♪
♪ You told me he was just a friend ♪
♪ But I found out some way... ♪
(DISCO MUSIC PLAYS)
I've seen bigger tits
on a pregnant dog.
You two ready?
Oh, God.
(MAN VOMITS)
Look at this here.
Never mind, sunbeam.
(HE CHUCKLES)
- Oh dear.
- Do you live here?
Almost.
I search for Josephine's.
Many people send us wrong ways.
Search no more, my son.
It's just back there.
This side of the street?
Yes, you stupid git.
Look, there's a sign, right,
twinkling in the night sky.
The show is good?
Sensational.
Yeah, not a dry crotch in the place.
Birds wrestling in the nude.
In mud.
With a donkey.
Donkey?
Donkey.
(HE SNIGGERS)
Donkey is good.
Yeah.
(HE LAUGHS)
What a bunch of saps.
(MUSIC CONTINUES ON CAR RADIO)
(RADIO SWITCHES OFF)
(HANDBRAKE CREAKS)
Look...
he said he'd phone, didn't he,
if anything happens?
Bloody lot of good that'd be.
I should be there.
It's my responsibility.
Well, if you're so sure
something's going to happen
why don't you just shut up shop
for the night?
For God's sake, woman,
what do you think you're talking about?
One night like this, there's up to 1 ,000
of them in Union Street.
Bloody hell, I lose money
night after night in that place.
Alright.
Alright, forget I said anything.
I mean, we both make a living off
of my business, don't we?
We both benefit.
Jesus, I've had it up to here
from you today.
MARIE IN DISTANCE:
Alright.
STAN:
Street's dying bit by bit anyway.
There's people I could name in this city
just biding their time
waiting to knock the whole lot flat.
Put up car showrooms,
do-it-yourself supermarkets.
Why don't you just shut up?
Mind you, come to think of it
cars are rather dangerous, aren't they?
Perhaps I shouldn't sell them.
Shut up.
And what about do-it-yourself
electrical saw attachments?
They're real killers.
It's all blood money, Marie.
Shut up. Shut up! Shut up!
- (GLASS SHATTERS)
- (SHE YELLS)
(CAR DRIVES AWAY)
(HANDBRAKE CREAKS)
(MUSIC: "COME BACK TO ME"
BY DESMOND DEKKER)
I'm gonna miss you, Stevie.
I told you before,
don't call me Stevie.
Steve.
I am, anyway.
What?
Gonna miss you.
(FANFARE PLAYS)
ANNOUNCER ON PA:
Festival of Remembrance.
(TRUMPET FANFARE PLAYS)
(CROWD APPLAUDS)
(CROWD CHEERS)
That's me brother!
Fifth one!
(FLAT-LINE SIGNAL SOUNDS)
(CAR HORNS HONK)
(ARCADE GAMES BLARE)
(DISCO MUSIC PLAYS)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
♪ Every day is sweeter ♪
♪ Than the one before ♪
PAUL:
Well, you and me are mates, right?
CHRIS:
Piss off, eh?
PAUL: No, no, listen to me.
What's your fucking name anyway?
- Chris. So what?
- Well...
Chris, well,
let me tell you something.
- Are you Gail?
- Why ?
I'm looking for a bloke called White.
Mal?
Malcolm?
I’ll start it.
You understand me?
Right.
PAUL:
I'm fucking 40, Chris.
I'll tell you something.
I'm fucking 40
and I'm fucking finished.
Right, Queen's fucking Navy, pal...
excuse me.
- Sorry, Chris.
- SEAN: Now!
(GLASS SHATTERS)
- (WOMAN SCREAMS)
- MAN: Oi!
(GLASS BREAKING)
Who the fucked started?
You're too soon, you bastards!
- (GLASSES SHATTER)
- (WOMAN SCREAMS)
(INDISTINCT YELLING)
MARK:
Malcolm!
Malcolm White!
(SIRENS BLARE)
MARK:
Malcolm White!
(SIREN BLARES)
(SIRENS BLARE)
(ROWDY YELLING)
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
(SIREN BLARES)
POLICEMAN:
Hey! Excuse me!
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(MAN YELLS)
(HE SOBS)
(SHIP HORN BLARES)
(CLOCK TICKS STEADILY)
(ALARM RINGS)
(INDISTINCT TRAIN ANNOUNCEMENT)
I can still get round you.
(HE CHUCKLES)
It's kicking you.
ANNOUNCER:
Train arriving at platform seven now
is the 7:1 3 from Penzance.
This is the nine o'clock
from Plymouth to London Paddington.
Calling at Totness,
Exeter St. Davids, Taunton...
(WHISTLE BLOWS)
Morning.
Ta.
Going to see me off?
I haven't had a lot of time...
Thank you very much.
Ah. Oh, no.
(GULLS SQUAWK)
Mark?
Mark!
Sorry, mate.
Ferry's going to dock in a minute.
You OK?
Maybe it was cos I sort of
recognised him.
I didn't really know Malcolm White.
He was just leaving Raleigh
when I started there.
But he was at that Remembrance Day
service we had to go to.
The one with the cinecamera.
It was his brother
who was in the Army display team.
I must've recognised him
in some weird way.
That's why I started
talking to him and that...
you know, down at Dol's.
Well, he'd gone AWOL
from his camp in Dorset.
Hitched all the way to Plymouth.
He was scared to go home
so he came down here
to find his brother.
That's why he was
hanging around on his own.
He didn't know anyone.
He was too scared to say
who he was.
That's the brother, is it?
Yeah, Malcolm.
Yeah.
You know, I do know him.
I mean, vaguely.
NAVAL OFFICER:
Come on, lads, ferry's leaving.
Can you see this gets to White?
He's the one up at the hospital.
He's still there, ain't he?
His brother died during the night.
NAVAL OFFICER:
Right, I’ll see to it.
You mean he's dead?
Christ.
Why'd he go AWOL?
Dunno.
Leave cancelled or something.
Off to Belfast, probably.
Perhaps it was just to say cheerio.
That's important sometimes.