♪♪
[chattering, shouting]
Woo!
Woo.
Hey.
[siren chirps]
'Sup, man?
Where are you going, huh?
What's happening?
Ah!
Uh-oh. Uh-oh.
Uh-oh.
Can't nobody get me.
Ah! Ah! Ah!
[bell ringing]
One, two, three, four, five,
six, seven, eight, nine, ten,
eleven, twelve...
I want chocolate.
You gonna get yours.
Everybody gonna get theirs.
-I want chocolate.
-All right. Here you go.
You got a rhyme or something?
I got a rhyme or something.
I kick rhymes automatic.
Addicted to changes
like leaves.
My black is gold like bees.
So stingray on a sunny day
while the little kids sit
out and play or converse.
Getting ready for
the ice cream "trunk."
Blah-blah-blah.
[laughing]
You wrote somethin'?
No, I just know
a little something.
-What you got?
-I got a little something.
My name is little Troy,
and I'm known as a big boy.
I gotta put some more
at the end, though.
-All right.
-Finish it off.
I’ll help you with it,
if you want.
So, yo, what's up with Keisha?
Yo, yo.
The chick is bugging yo.
She keeps hitting me.
Yo, yo.
[laughing]
Look, I need something
to get my head right,
know what I'm saying?
You gonna share
some blessings with me?
Oh, yeah. I got you, man.
-Please. Please.
-Medicine for you.
This is my prescription.
Here you go.
-Ah, that's what I'm talkin'.
-Yes, yes.
This is that Maui-Waui, right?
This is the truth.
So help you God.
So, uh, after smokin' this,
I’ll understand some of
that shit you be talkin' about
in your
rhymes, right?
Probably not.
-Good luck.
-All right.
-I'll holla, all right?
-Cool.
Peace.
Them brothers is strong.
-He pulled that trigger, too.
-He didn't pull that trigger.
[overlapping dialogue]
Hold up, though.
Ain't nobody comin' up
in Dodge City like that, man.
If I have to go through there,
if I have to go through there,
somebody gonna
be like Biggie and Tupac.
Look, you handle your business.
Don't let your business
handle you.
You know what I’m saying?
Them niggas ain't
gonna hurt us.
Yo, that's bullshit, you know?
[laughing]
Hit me with that.
I'll tell you what...
-What's up, yo?
-Hey, what's up, man?
[chattering]
-What's going on?
So, I got some good things I'm
tryin' to invest in, you know?
-I hear. I know.
-I gotta make it big.
I’m writing every day.
Every day. You gotta
give me that.
'Cause I’m going with you on
that, you know what I'm saying?
Definitely.
So, you gonna start the label?
Yeah, I want you to
do that record label.
I got the money invested in it.
Look, I want you to
do me a favor.
-What's that?
-I got this new chick, right?
I want you to give me some
little...
some little good shit
to tell her, you know?
Slick shit to say to her.
You know what I’m saying?
I'm serious, man.
You got to do that for me, man.
You want me to write
poems and shit?
Man, no, I don't want
to read that junk, you know,
I just want to remember
something.
Nigga, if I write it,
you better read that shit.
I don't want you to write
no heavy poems and shit.
Want me to write
a song for her?
Hell, no, I ain't gonna
be sittin' there
singin' to the bitch.
I ain't no R. Kelly.
Know what I'm saying?
I want you to sit there
and give me a little something.
You know what I’m saying?
It's like that.
You my man.
You gotta look out for me.
-I got ya. Look...
-What's up?
I’m runnin' low,
can you look out for me?
Yeah. I got that.
I'll look out for you.
But, look, come back later on,
meet me at Dodge City,
around about 10:30.
-And I got you, okay?
-And I got you then, too.
-Get me, get me.
-All right, yo.
Peace.
♪♪
It's gonna be a hot one
tonight. I can feel it.
I’m gettin' too old
for this shit.
Tell them to get some
additional units because,
they been actin' kind of
silly, know what I mean?
These young boys, you know,
that daggone rap music they
got is drivin' 'em crazy.
Come in, EC-1 .
Let all units know that...
be heads up.
You got it, EC-1 .
You remember that song,
"What's your name?"
-Oh, yeah, yeah.
-Remember that one?
Why don't you hit it?
♪ What's your name ♪
-♪ ls it may... ♪
-♪ Have I met you before... ♪
You don't remember
that song, man?
It's "I have seen you before,"
goddamn it.
So, how does it go?
ls it "What's your name?
I have seen you before?
May I walk you to your door?"
-All right, that's it.
-You know? Jesus Christ.
You talkin' about, you
know the daggone' song.
Hit it.
♪ What's your name? ♪
♪ I have seen you before ♪
♪ May I walk you
to your door? ♪
♪♪
[chattering]
What's up, nigga?
I'm right here.
-What's up?
-What's goin' on?
How you doin', man?
Here you go.
-Be careful with that.
-Thank you.
-What's up, baby?
Thank you.
-Everything all right?
-Yeah.
Look, I want you to do
what I asked you.
I got you.
This is what you're gonna say:
"You massage
the universe's spine,
the way you twirl through time,
and leave shadows on the sun."
-You got that?
-You a bad motherfucker.
I ain't got that though.
Give me that shit again.
"You massage
the universe's spine
"the way you
twirl through time,
and leave shadows on the sun."
That's all right.
[gunshot]
[screaming]
[siren blaring]
[chattering]
Hey!
[shouting, clamoring]
[siren blaring]
I ain't do anything.
-What's this?
-It's just weed.
Just weed?
It's illegal weed.
What makes you think you
can use drugs in our city?
-What's your name?
-Raymond Joshua.
-Raymond what?
Buddy, let me tell you.
You're in deep shit.
Let's go, man.
Matter before the court,
number 47 on the lock-up,
United States
vs. Raymond Joshua.
Your Honor, the defendant
was apprehended
fleeing the scene of a shooting.
A man was shot in the head
during a drug transaction
in which this man was involved.
My God, what a way
to start a Monday morning.
Here you have
the Congress taking
a lot of power from
the city counsel
and the office of the Mayor,
the Board of Education,
and the people of Washington
and then we have Mr. Joshua.
Without getting into whether
you're guilty or not,
I just know that these drugs
are killing our community.
Mr. Prosecutor, what's the
government's position on bail?
The government feels
that this defendant
poses a substantial risk
of flight, Your Honor.
He was apprehended fleeing
the scene of a shooting.
We would like to see
the bond set
in the amount of
$10,000 surety.
This court will enter
a plea of not guilty
on behalf of Mr. Joshua.
And this proceeding is adjourned
until Monday morning,
11 o'clock.
-Thank you, gentlemen.
-Thank you, Your Honor.
♪♪
Watch your step.
-Watch your step.
-Ow!
Turn on the fucking
air conditioner.
AC, motherfucker.
Give me some fucking AC.
Man, will you
shut the fuck up back there?
My name is fucking Jimmy Huang.
Get me the fuck off this van.
Hey! You, up there
in the front.
I shouldn't fucking
be in this van, man.
You know who my dad is?
Shit. It's hot
in this fucking van.
You scared, man?
Shut the fuck up.
[sighs]
It ain't nothing but sweat
inside my hands
So I dig into my pockets...
There's an MC in the van.
Great.
Another Black rapper.
Thinking of the master plan
So I walk up the street,
whistling this
feeling out of place,
'cause, man, do I miss,
a pen and a paper,
a stereo, a table...
Would you shut the fuck up?
Get this guy to shut up.
[gate buzzes]
I'd like to find out who's gonna
keep this little thing quiet.
Shake his hand
and say, thank you.
Damn. I miss Italy.
Do you miss Italy?
You ever listen to Wu-Tang?
♪♪
[chattering]
All right.
Let's go. Let's go.
[chattering, shouting]
What's up, man?
-You heard about Mike?
-Yeah, I heard about it.
So, what happened?
I don't even know.
I can't call it.
You know, the word in here
is, "watch your back."
All right.
[chattering]
-What's wrong with me?
-China dog.
What's wrong with me,
China dog?
I shouldn't even be in this
fucking jail, man!
I don't want to be here!
I shouldn't be here
with you motherfuckers!
Get the fuck away from me!
I shouldn't have to
get the fuck away from you!
Fuck you, motherfucker!
Hey, man, y'all need to shut up!
I ain't trying to
hear all that.
Just get me some toilet paper.
What do you want with me, man?
Get off of me.
-China dog...
-What's up, China dog?
What's up, yo?
What, what the fuck
do you want with me, man?
I’ll fuckin'
kill all of you! Shit!
Get the fuck off me,
I’ll kill you!
-Sit the fuck down, man.
-Fuck you, man!
Sit down. Sit down.
All right?
Shut up, nigga.
What's your fuckin'
problem, yo?
You're about to get fuckin'
killed up in this piece.
Yeah? I guess I am.
[chattering]
What the fuck you tryin' to do?
Why don't you just sit down,
all right?
If you're not supposed to be
here, then you won't be here.
Give it a second
and you'll disappear.
-Hey, Mr. Huang, let's go.
-That's me.
I told you I was out
of here, man.
Time to go.
I told you guys.
What?
Remember when
you spit on my buddy?
We got a
goin' away present for you.
-Let's go.
-A what?
A what? No!
Fuck this, let me-- Ah!
[muffled shouting]
I'm your attorney.
I've been assigned by
the court to represent you.
I’m a public defender.
I’ve been asked by
the prosecutor
to see if we can cut a deal,
which means plead guilty
or cop out.
Let me ask you this:
Are you guilty?
Of what?
Of the marijuana,
possession of marijuana.
Uh, I mean, I don't know.
I can't get a trial
or something?
Well, you can get a trial.
They call that cop or rock.
You can take the cop,
we plead,
or you can rock, which means
we can take it to trial.
But if you lose,
you're looking at ten.
Mandatory ten. You have to do
85 percent of ten.
Which means eight
and a half years.
So wait. If I try to fight it,
I have to serve more time
for just trying to fight it?
If you get found guilty,
you would.
And usually, the success ratio
of convictions on drug cases,
man, is about 90 to 95 percent.
If you lock up ten people,
nine, nine and a half
go to jail.
But the chances of beating it,
is like trying to throw a...
a snowball into an elephant's
mouth at a hundred feet.
You can't make it.
You are in trouble.
You are a victim,
a casualty of war.
You got two options, three:
You can plead guilty
to a simple possession,
which is two to three years,
you do eighteen months
to two years.
You can go to trial and
run the risk of
doing ten years
if you get found guilty.
Or, you can cooperate.
Which means you can rat, snitch,
blow the whistle
on whoever you want
to blow it on,
in order to get out.
Cop, cooperate, which
I'm not gonna do.
You say I can't even fight it
'cause I'll serve more time.
This doesn't make
any fucking sense.
None whatsoever, man.
It don't make any sense at all.
There's niggas out there
doing mad shit.
My man is down, you know?
They shoot my man,
they're running free.
There's niggas out there
selling all types of shit.
I got a quarter pound of weed,
and you're telling me here
I got to serve five to ten years
and there's not shit
you can do for me?
I don't have any choices?
Fuck this old
casualty of war shit, man.
I’m saying,
I’m just out there surviving.
What can I do?
I know it sounds
like a lot of time,
but most guys get
a lot longer than that, man.
The best or most I can do
is try to get you two or three.
Even if you were innocent,
I could only get you
two to three.
You are a victim, brother.
You're Black, you're young,
you come from the Southeast,
you're in the inner city.
You don't have a chance.
Your best chance now is to see
how little time you get
before you get back to society.
It ain't about beating it.
When they lock you up, you dead.
Raymond Joshua, step out.
When you're in this building,
I want you to stay alive.
So listen carefully to me.
Nobody in here is your brother.
I don't care if they're
as Black as you are,
or as light as daylight.
They are not your brother.
You mind your business, son,
and you'll stay alive.
Every day somebody
gets shanked in here.
gets beaten up in here.
We got predators in here, son.
We got people that'll
cut your throat
for nothing at all but
a pack of cigarettes.
You mind your business
in here, son.
Do you understand where you are?
Have a seat in here.
What's up, Mike?
Raymond Joshua.
Right over here, come on.
Put everything on the table.
Open your mouth.
Lift your arms.
Lift your tongue.
Lift your balls.
Turn around and
spread your cheeks
with both hands at
the same time.
Show me the bottom
of your feet.
Turn around and face me.
Bend over at the waist.
Run your fingers
through your hair.
Hold this under your chin
just like this.
Your number is going to
be given to you.
It's a sequential number.
It's not a random set
of numbers, son.
That number means something.
It's yo' number.
It's yo' number now.
Know what that
number represents, son?
276,000. Now
listen carefully to me,
and you'll understand
a little bit
about what makes me so angry.
We only have less than
500,000 people
in the District of Columbia.
Now only 70 percent
of them are Black.
Now what's 70 percent
of 500,000?
Do the math. We got about
350,000 Black people in DC.
Of the 350,000, half of them
are female, aren't they?
What's that?
Use the math, son, the math.
Less than 1 75,000 people
are males like yourself.
Now all of 'em aren't
over 21 years of age.
Half of 'em are kids.
Now how the devil if we got only
75 to 80 thousand adult males
in the District of Columbia,
is this number 276,000 today?
Figure it out for yourself.
We've exhausted the
21-year-olds,
20-year-olds, 19-year-olds.
We're working on 1 8.
We're moving on down
the line, son.
By the time we cross 300,000,
we'll be down to
16 and 1 7-year-olds.
We're wiping out our race
in Washington, D.C.
And here you are in here
playing these silly ass games.
Well, we got something
for you, son.
Welcome to the D.C. jail.
You might make it outta here,
you might not.
Door three. One gate.
[door buzzes]
[chattering, shouting]
[shouting continues]
♪♪
[gunshot, screaming]
[siren blares]
[drumming]
♪ Well bakey bakes,
niggas better fuckin' run, ♪
♪ Pack the guns leavin' niggas
numb, motherfuckin' run, ♪
♪ Lookin' at hoods lookin' like
thugs life at the stoplight ♪
♪ Get up in their guts,
only little fuckin' put put ♪
♪ Psychopath nut, bet they get
a bigger fuckin' case ♪
♪ Cuz my love the nigga's
down for a double name case ♪
♪ What the fuck did they want,
it's a motherfuckin' gun ♪
♪ From the G's APC's
where the fucker's from ♪
♪ Niggas better run,
if they don't catch up ♪
♪ They just get fucked
by my motherfuckin' focus ♪
♪ Knock you off your
motherfuckin'ass ♪
♪ Not afraid to pass ♪
♪ Get me all of that cash,
so I can quit my fuckin' gash ♪
♪ Die, foci, then
the motherfuckin' gangs ♪
♪ Selling cocaine roll my
fuckin' brain like Jesse James ♪
♪ Yo sun, as in solar, simply,
because we are, we be ♪
♪ The rising stars and the sun
that never set ♪
♪ Word up, Jack
Wanna make a bet, Black? ♪
♪ I got the formula ♪
♪ Throw me in the sky,
and I’ll warm ya ♪
♪ Get your sun block
Throw me in the cell block ♪
♪ Indeed, I got
the science you need ♪
♪ Lessons more ancient
than Greece ♪
♪ Apollo never my creed,
my creed ♪
♪ Obatala will battle you ♪
♪ So bring your troops
if you wanna ♪
♪ Satellites in the sky ♪
♪ Some selling clouds
on the corner ♪
♪ But, we livin' for the land,
from the soil to the sand ♪
♪ And the water in the sea
be the essence of me ♪
♪ If you ain't
ready for this fruit ♪
♪ Than put it back on the tree ♪
♪ Uh. Give me the strength
to bend back these bars ♪
♪ Got the locks of Samson
I’m Sam's son, he's my father ♪
♪ Tried praying to the Father,
Son, but Holy Ghost ♪
♪ I miss my
motherfucking sanity ♪
♪ Never been here
and never planned to be ♪
♪ But my own plans
had plans for me ♪
♪ And now that man's
hands got plans for me ♪
♪ And now that man's hands
got plans for me ♪
♪ And now that man had plans,
so I jetted and ran ♪
♪ The mic cord pulled me back ♪
♪ I should have dropped
it from my hand ♪
♪ And left it at the
scene of the rhyme ♪
♪ Now we all serving time ♪
♪ Even my prose
is on probation ♪
♪ Refugees they ain't
just Haitian ♪
♪ Come on. Fucking shit.
Come on. ♪
♪ Keep it going now.
Ba bam, ba bam bam... ♪
♪ And what the fuck. ♪
♪ You're fuckin' with
a psychopath nut ♪
♪ Put on my fucking glasses
and 'bout to bust a nut ♪
♪ In your ass
motherfucker ♪
♪ As I blast in
your motherfucking gut ♪
♪ Put a motherfuckin'
mask on your face ♪
♪ You should of never fucked
with a nigga from the base ♪
♪ So now I'm packing steel ♪
♪ Keeping the shit
really real ♪
♪ Motherfucka you ducked trying
to hop up in the truck ♪
♪ Got blocked down ♪
♪ So motherfuckas
really want the judge ♪
♪ To understand my
motherfucking deal ♪
♪ I’m packin' steel ♪
♪ Slam dunkin'
like Shaquille O'Neal ♪
♪ ...bam, ba bam, ba bam bam ♪
♪ I had to be strong... ♪
That shit is dope, yo.
Damn, man. You got some
talent with you man.
-Oh, definitely.
-That shit was tight, yo.
-Good lookin' out, son.
-Aight.
[tapping, rapping inaudibly]
Come on!
What's up, partner?
Thanks for the tray, slim.
I know you ain't
want'n that shit.
Come on, nigga. I ain't trying
to play this shit.
What's up, partner?
I ain't eaten all day.
I ain't trying to play.
I ain't trying to
play this shit.
-What's up?
-Get the fuck off me, nigga.
It's my motherfucking tray.
It's my tray.
I’m eating this tray.
Nigga, you don't know me.
I ain't about to sit here
and let you eat my shit.
I ain't got to know you.
You ain't gonna eat
unless I say you eat.
This is my motherfucking tray.
Any problems?
Nah.
If I don't eat,
don't nobody fucking eat.
Oh shit. Here we go.
[buzzer sounds]
Break it the fuck up.
[shouting, clamoring]
Get the fuck back to your cells.
Shit. Lock it down.
[chattering]
Hey...
Wakey, wakey.
Hands off snakey.
Open 20.
Grab your shit.
We're leaving.
Behave yourself, all right?
-All right, man.
-Peace, Black.
-Keep it real, man.
-Mm-hm.
Some get by,
but they never get away.
Catch you, dawg.
First cell to your left.
-Stand right here.
-Yo.
How ya' doin' G?
-Where the fuck's my paper at?
-Your man's here to see you.
-Who's that?
-I got a 32 ready for him.
What's happening?
Come on in, man.
Take a seat.
I’m Hopha, man.
-What's going down?
-Mike told me a lot about you.
He told me a lot
about you too, man.
You know what I’m saying?
So what the cops is
telling you, man?
I know they been trying to
ask you questions about Mike.
They asked me a few questions,
but I don't know shit, y'know.
So I just told 'em
I don't know shit.
You sure you ain't
telling 'em nothing?
I didn't tell them shit, yo.
See, this is the problem, here.
People think you did.
-What?
-Tell them something.
That shit that happened,
you probably don't
know nothing about this,
but you're the
center of attention now.
What do you mean?
Everybody wants a
piece of you, man.
How's that?
Because they think
you set Mike up.
I didn't do that shit, yo.
I didn't do that.
Motherfucker, I know you
didn't fucking do it.
They don't know that shit.
They coming for you, man.
You got every
motherfucker in here
ready to take a
piece of your ass.
And if I take the fucking veil
down, it's gonna fucking happen.
You stepped right
into the frying pan now.
So be ready to get down.
You want some treats?
I got some sweets.
Some cookies or something?
Here, let me hook you up.
Take some of this.
Where's the guard at?
Where's my fucking newspaper at?
That son of a bitch.
That nigga brings me
some shit, too.
I ain't saying you're sweet,
want some baby powder?
Here, get yourself some
Kool-Aid, or something, man.
Take what you want, man.
Take what you fucking want.
You home, man. You home, baby.
You know what I’m saying?
[laughs]
You home here now.
You with us.
Word. Let the boys know that
we got a new member now.
Everything's gonna be
all right now.
You like that book?
"Most of all, I must see to it
that I do not lend myself
to the evils which I condemn."
Yeah, well, you know what
I say about that?
Stay the fuck out our way.
That's all I got to say
about that shit.
You know what I mean?
Hey, I love people,
but I don't tell them that shit.
You know what I mean?
And when it comes
to me and mine,
I defend mine very well.
Fuck that.
I want to get out
of the game, yo.
On the real?
That's all I want.
Ain't no way out of this, man.
If you move into records,
if you move into shit,
with us, man,
you are taking
the game with you.
It's all in sync, man.
I ain't trying to be a part of
the whole game, gang bullshit...
-Listen, listen. Fuck that.
-I'm trying to write.
-I need a pen and some paper.
-I don't wanna hear that shit.
Nigga, you are in jail, man.
Bottom line.
You down with us.
Ain't no coming
out of this shit.
This shit's the same shit
on the fucking street.
The beef ain't
gonna stop for you.
Who the fuck is you?
You gonna stop this beef?
You can't stop it.
You help us stop it.
I'm trying to think
straight, you know?
I need a pen and a pad.
I hear you, man.
It's gonna be all right.
You know what I mean?
Don't worry about it.
Just wait until you get here.
Guess y'all gonna have to
make me secretary of state.
Or secretary of defense.
How's that?
What, you don't like that?
Minister of defense, then.
Minister of information,
but can fight. How's that?
You know what I mean?
'Cause you gonna
have to fight, cuz.
Make no mistake about it.
This is jail.
Yeah, we got to handle that.
When he come out,
we got to take care of that.
It's motherfucking personal.
It's personal.
'Cause you know
that nigga we beat down?
Yeah, you know
he down with Hopha, right?
What?
Yeah, and they
going against us.
'Cause ain't nothing gonna stop
this motherfucking drug game.
You know? Stop none
of my motherfucking business.
'Cause we ain't
having that shit.
It's Thug Life for life.
I got the word he's
down with Union Crew.
We gonna get him.
He's down with Union Crew.
And I don't like
no bitch-ass nigga
cutting into
my motherfucking business.
You get what I'm saying?
-Dig.
-We dig it.
Fuck that.
If I got to push the steel
in the motherfucking nigga,
we gonna do that.
♪♪
We got some problems.
-See them niggas over there?
-Check 'em out.
You know what I’m saying?
Yeah, I see them, niggas.
Man, there's a difference
with us and them, man.
You know what I’m saying?
We organized.
That bunch of
stupid motherfuckers, man.
They can't handle no business.
We already did that drug shit
and that fucking
hand-to-hand bullshit, man.
I want cake, B.
Don't you want cake?
We want fucking cake, man.
If y'all want some cake, man.
We do this shit, make this move
on these motherfuckers, man.
I don't give a fuck
what happens.
♪♪
Even your man don't
fucking like you, faggot.
Fuck you.
Yeah, fuck y'all.
If you was fucking smart,
you'd be over here, too.
We wouldn't have
to be doing this.
Y'all trying to rap?
We wouldn't have to
be doing this.
Fuck these niggas, man.
Fuck them niggas, man.
Nah, nah, nah, nah.
You stay back.
Lay back. Lay back.
You make the choice who
the fuck you gone to be with.
You get your ass
over there with Union Crew.
-Fuck Thug Life.
-Fuck you.
-Fuck you, nigga.
This mother fucker!
Fucked up.
♪♪
[shouting]
[buzzer sounds]
Hey, how you doing?
ls it hot enough
for you out there?
[metal detector beeps]
Just my keys in my front pocket.
Okay.
♪♪
What's up?
You see him there?
Man, I want you to do
the right thing, man.
What the fuck is
the right thing?
The right thing is for me
to just be my fucking self.
You know what I’m saying?
Do you know what I’m saying?
I mean, it's not about...
It's hard to be
yourself here, man.
Look around, man.
It's hard to be yourself
in here, man.
My crew gotta know
where you stand.
I know where they standing at.
What the fuck, nigga?
This ain't no rites
of passage or some shit.
Ain't nobody gonna cross
that shit.
You see them lined up?
We got our shit
locked over here.
Ain't nobody coming over here,
fucking with this shit.
There's a place
for you over here.
If not, go the fuck over
there with your friend, then.
All right, look,
let's not get too close,
you know what I mean?
It's going down.
-It's going down today.
It's going down today.
He gots to go.
Hopha got his corner.
Pass that joint.
I want everybody high.
Everybody high.
It's the thug in us.
Fuck you.
I stand on the corner
of the block
Slinging
amethyst rocks,
drinking 40's of Mother
Earth's private nectar stock
Dodging cops
'Cause five-oh be the 666
And I need a fix
of that purple rain
The type of shit that
drives membranes insane.
Oh, yeah, I’m in the fast
lane, snorting candy yams
That free my body and soul
and send me like Shazam
Never question who I am
God knows
And I know God personally
In fact, he let's
me call him me
Yeah, I'm serious B.
Doggonned niggas plottin'
shit, lovely,
But the Feds
is also plottin' me
They're tryin'
to imprison my astrology
Put our stars behind bars,
our stars in stripes
Using blood-splattered
banners as nationalist kites
But I control the wind
That's why they
call it the hawk
I am Horus, son of Isis,
son of Osiris
Worshipped as Jesus,
resurrected like Lazarus
but you can
call me Lazzie, lazy,
Yeah, I’m lazy,
cause I'd rather sit
and build than work
and plow a field
Worshipping a daily
yield of cash green crops
Stealing us was the smartest
thing they ever did
Too bad they don't teach
the truth to their kids.
Our influence on them
is the reflection they see
when they look into
their minstrel mirror
And talk about
their culture
Their existence is that
of a schizophrenic vulture
Yeah. There's no repentance
They are bound to live an
infinite consecutive
Executive life
sentence
So what are you
bound to live, nigga?
So while you're
out there serving the time
I'll be in sync with the sun
while you run from the moon
Life of the womb
reflected by guns
Worshiper of moons
I am the sun
And we are
public enemies number one
One, one, one
One, one, one.
I forgot what
the fuck I was thinking.
Are you all right?
-Are you okay?
-Um, yes.
I just saw what you
did out there.
Do you need any help?
-No.
-You're cool?
Um, hi.
My name is Lauren.
Lauren Bell.
I teach writing here.
Where did you get that from?
I’m sorry, um...
The poem that you did out there.
Did you, did you write that?
Yeah.
-Excuse me.
-Um...
-Are you okay?
-Yes, I’m fine.
What are you doing
out here in the hall?
He's just talking to me.
He's on his way to...
Okay. But he's not supposed
to be out here.
North three, let's go.
Right now. Right now.
You have no right to be
out here. Let's go.
All right you're in north three.
I’ll put in a request for you.
You have to tell the CO
that you want to come to class,
and he'll let you come down.
You are out of place.
Let's go.
I’ve been searching
myself, man.
I know you all have too.
The world is fucking
leaving us behind, man.
What Ray said was right.
I didn't agree with his methods,
you know what I'm saying?
-You know...
-What the hell was that?
I still don't fuckin'
know entirely, man.
But what that nigga did
out there
was just fucking fascinating.
I ain't fucking coming
back here, man.
Fuck that shit.
I love y'all and all that shit.
I ain't coming
the fuck back here.
You know what I mean?
I ain't turning on y'all.
Like I said, I love y'all,
but I'm telling it
the way it fucking is, man.
Them motherfuckers
outside this glass
don't give a fuck about us.
We started off fighting,
we gonna end off fighting.
But how we fight is the fight.
That's the way it goes.
If I’m gonna die
for something,
I'm gonna die for something
that's worth it, dig?
We've been discussing
the chapters
as we've been
going along...
but now we've finished
the whole book.
And what I want to know is...
what came to
your mind last night
when you were lying in your cell
and you were
reading the assignment?
What was the first thing
that came to your mind?
I mean, sure, I know I want
to stay on the street.
I know I want to be a positive
person to my family, right.
But I know that, me personally,
if the situation arose
where it was either starve
or my children starving,
or doing the right thing,
then, you know, it's Trey Ball.
It's got to be.
Or Monster Kody got to
do what he got to do.
I do not agree with Joseph.
Sadly, too many of our brothers
got the mentality of Joe,
and come here and say,
because of this and that,
I’m gonna put this in my hand
using my family for an excuse.
When all the time,
like you said,
you got to
be responsible for you.
So you gonna use, "My family was
hungry so I went out
and shot a motherfucker,
take some money."
Fuck no.
You still coming to jail.
I don't know whether
you know it or not, brother,
but we are capitalists.
Whether we're capitalists
on a small scale,
but we live in
a capitalist country.
And that is what we are.
We are born to learn how
to capitalize on whatever it is.
It's about money.
So Joe and John
are saying that
there are not enough
resources out there
to help you change your life.
Is that true?
We just happened
to be born our color,
and we at the bottom of
the ladder. You understand?
Now, if I could make it out,
and have me some real dough,
yeah, then it wouldn't
be like this.
All right. Y'all ready
for the poetry reading?
Yes.
I didn't hear everybody.
I said are y'all ready
for the poetry reading?
Yes.
-Tyrone, you ready?
-Yeah.
Let's go.
The name of
my little piece is, uh, "Why."
"I shot three motherfuckers,
but I didn't know why.
"I guess I just wanted
to see something die.
"You see, I bought this gun
for a few rocks
"just to get even, so I thought,
with those shit-eating cops.
"Holding the cold, blue steel
in the palm of my hand,
"not quite sixteen,
yet totally a man.
"My only plan was
money in my hand.
"I wore Falacci, Gucci,
Nikes, and Eddie B.
"I was the coolest
motherfucker in Southeast D.C.
"School? What the fuck.
"That was a thing
of the past.
"Getting paid, school and
all that other square shit
"could kiss my ass.
"Mad at my bun,
toying with my gun,
"tipped on over to my favorite
poolroom just to have some fun.
"Rips was at full blast,
so I chalked up my cue,
"ready to kick some ass.
"I played a few hours,
beat all the old timers
"and was about to go.
"Until the three...
"One of the three 'bama
motherfuckers stepped on my toe.
"A split second later,
whip, bam, it was on.
"The ass kicking begun.
"I ducked a few pool balls
and eased out my gun.
"Ratta-tat-tat and that was
that. Three was whacked.
"Ten years later.
"As I sit here in my
jail cell about to cry,
"I’m thinking,
I shot three motherfuckers
and I don't know why."
[applause]
Thank you, Ron.
Oh, I, um, I don't know
if all of you guys know,
but, um,
today's my last day here.
No.
Oh, God.
I’m gonna miss you guys.
-We gonna miss you, too.
-Especially me.
Um, they, um,
it's so wild that we had this
conversation today, because,
they have,
they cut this program.
And it's just brought home
the fact that, you know,
it really isn't about
rehabilitation anymore.
You know?
And you were right, Joe.
Like I was trying
to tell you earlier,
yeah, it's gonna be hard
when you leave here.
It's gonna be real hard.
It's really fucked up that
you were born in Southeast,
in the ghetto.
It's really fucked up
that you were born Black.
It's really fucked
up that you've had
the hard time
that you had in your life.
Whatever your story is,
whatever it is that brought
you here in your life,
that shit is really fucked up.
If you keep shoving the anger
and the pain
and the frustration down,
and you keep
saying that's all right,
fuck it, I’m-a do what
I gotta do
and you don't let it come out,
that keeps pushing you down.
That is your prison.
You gotta let that shit out
'cause once you let
that frustration out,
it doesn't hold
you back anymore.
It doesn't lock you down.
And then you can stand up
with some courage.
You can say, okay,
yeah, it's fucked up,
but I am not gonna
live like this.
I am going to take my destiny
into my own hands.
That's the only way to go now.
I grew up with guys
just like y’all.
All of y'all.
My brother was sitting
in your seat.
My brother's not here anymore.
He grew up in your era,
Joe, in your era, Ronald,
when everybody wanted to
be Superfly. Remember that?
It was all about being Superfly
or the Mac, remember that?
Now it's about being
a gangsta or OG.
He had a good heart
just like y'all.
I know y'all are good guys.
The people out there,
they see your face in the paper,
they think y'all,
they think you're monsters.
I know you're good guys inside.
My brother had a good heart.
I know your dreams.
I've been there.
But chasing them, thinking you
can achieve them
by selling drugs...
that's just a part
of the trap, y'all.
That's just a part of the trap.
And yeah, you're right, Ronald.
The cycle just
keeps continuing.
Who's gonna stop it?
Y'all got to stop it.
Y'all been in.
Y'all can go back out,
change your life
and show the young brothers
that they don't have to
come back in here like this.
Freedom isn't out here.
It's in here.
You can be free
anytime you want.
Anytime.
Never give anyone
the power to take
away your freedom.
That's yours. It don't belong
to nobody but you.
Remember that.
I’m not going to go
on and on.
Besides, my tissue's
falling apart.
-We gonna miss you, all right?
-I'm gonna miss you too, Red.
And I’m gonna miss you too.
-Give me a hug.
-All right. All right.
I hate bye-byes.
All right, all right.
Reggie, give me a hug, baby.
-Okay.
-You gonna be okay?
I’m gonna be all right.
You gonna be okay?
I'm gonna be fine after
that poem you wrote.
You gonna write me now, right?
I promise.
Okay. Good.
All right, now.
Take care, baby. Bye-bye.
Ray, you hangin'
back for a minute?
Mm-hmm.
So what did you think
of the class?
I think you're a wonderful
teacher.
Ray, what are you
doing in here?
I sold weed.
So you just happened
to be selling weed?
I mean, I don't know.
I don't know.
I got caught.
Yeah, I know you got caught.
I know you got caught.
I mean, it's that simple.
It's not...
-I mean...
-What, are you in school?
No.
So you sell weed for a living?
That's it?
And you write poetry.
And you read books.
I never really thought of
myself as writing poetry.
You know, I write,
I'm here on,
I'm really here on
a petty weed charge.
Although, I’ve been told
that I have to cop a plea.
And if I do,
I may be looking at
like a couple of years,
but... I don't know.
-I don't know how to say...
-Just stay in touch.
Just stay in touch.
You never know.
You never know, you know?
I gotta go.
You got me thinking.
You remember that book
that was in my cell?
"The Art of War?"
Guy named Sun Tzu.
Some old guy.
Chinese guy a long time ago.
The man said it's about
learning to lead people.
It's about being able
to win wars without violence.
You know what I mean?
He wasn't no sucker, now,
he'd get ready
to get down, you know?
But he won wars
from the beginning
without ever having
to use violence.
He said that's where
the real battle is.
Shit bugged me the fuck out.
I thought what the fuck's
this nigga talkin' about?
I mean, I thought about it.
But how many people
really do that, you know?
How many people really do that?
You did that.
I’m telling you, man,
you got more talent
than maybe even you know.
You got a hell of a
lot of decisions.
I can't help you
with the decisions, man.
You know, but I’m always
there for you.
I've made my decisions, yo.
You can see.
There's no fear in
my heart no more.
There's no fear.
I don't give a fuck.
I’m scared every day,
but I’m not afraid.
You dig?
To me there's a difference.
To you there's a difference.
You showed that.
You gonna be a great man.
You got great things
to fucking do.
And one of them is to pass
this to an old friend of mine.
This is something a friend of
mine gave me a long time ago.
I’m gonna get you out of here.
All right?
How you gonna get me outta here?
You're not listening
to me, man.
You're not listening to me, man.
I'm gonna put up
the bail for you. All right?
If you do this piece
of work for me, I'm here.
-What's your name?
-Raymond Joshua.
Okay. You're being released
on cash collateral.
Take your suit off
and put it in the basket.
-Yo, where's my shirt?
-It got lost. Shit happens.
I don't have a shirt.
Take that.
You going home anyhow.
Let's see your arm band.
Hold it right there
so I can see it. Okay.
Hey, Ray, this is your
last time in here, right?
I want you to take something out
the door with you
when you leave.
Those six digits
on that band I told you about,
they'll be here waiting
for you if you ever come back.
Now get your ass
out of my jail.
Door.
All right,
going out with one.
-What's your name?
-Raymond Joshua.
-Your number?
-274001 .
Okay. Officer, what's
he going out on?
He's going out
on cash collateral.
-Good luck. Take care.
-Thanks a lot.
All right.
♪♪
-How you doing, Ray?
-Hey, Ray, where you been?
-What's up?
-Where you been, Ray?
-I saw a police car, Ray.
-Yeah?
-What's happening?
-Nothin' much.
Where you been at
for a couple of days?
-We ain't seen you.
-Bye, Ray.
Everything cool, man?
How did they treat
you in camp, man?
-All right.
-Just hold on for a second.
-I got something for ya.
-All right.
All right.
[laughing]
-What's up, man?
-Yo!
What's up, man?
What's up?
-I'm alive, man.
-I cannot believe this shit.
You been all right
in there?
Yeah, I been cool.
You...
I been great.
Well, I’m all right, man.
You know what?
I'm blind now, man.
I can't see shit, man.
Somebody in Dodge City gonna
have to take care of that.
-Take care of what?
-Man, I’m hurtin', man.
And the only thing I can do
to feel better is to know that
somebody else is hurtin'.
What we gonna do is
handle this.
Handle this how, nigga?
What the fuck are
you talking about?
-Are you fucking real or what?
-No, no, no, no. What...
I got a motherfucking
bullet in my head,
and whoever put it there,
they gonna pay.
Now is you with that or what?
Man, we've been doing
this for years. For what?
I don't understand it.
I understood it before,
but I don't understand
that shit.
'Cause you know what?
When I was inside,
I realized something.
I was blind for a long time, yo.
I see now.
And I see that
this shit has to end.
There's not shit you can do.
There is no one you can shoot,
not even the fucking doctor,
that would give you your
fucking vision back.
There's nothing,
no one you could shoot.
You could shoot the sun,
and everybody else
would just be blind.
I spoke to your man inside, yo.
-You what?
-I spoke with your man, yo.
-Hopha.
-What'd he say?
What'd he say?
He said the same shit
I'm saying.
That this shit is silly.
He don't want any type
of retaliation.
Man, that's bullshit.
Fuck that bullshit you talking.
It's not bullshit.
Man, Hopha ain't
say nothing like that, man.
He know Dodge City sticks
together no matter what.
Anybody in Dodge City go down,
the motherfucker's
being dealt with.
-What's this?
-What is this?
Where the fuck you
get this from, man?
Your boy. He knew you wouldn't
believe shit I was telling you.
And what the fuck
are we retaliating for?
We don't need
this shit any more.
So what are you saying?
Dodge City is breaking up?
What the fuck you talking about?
This ain't The Temptations
or some shit.
We ain't breaking up.
What makes you think me and
you can go talk to somebody
that tried to kill me, man,
and tried to kill you?
The fucking mayor can't
even talk to these people.
The government can't even
talk to these people.
I ain't talking about the mayor.
I ain't talking about
the government.
Nigga, I love you.
I love you.
I just don't wanna
see you go out
like a million other
niggas before you.
Man, I'm scared.
-I know you're scared.
-Can you help me out, man?
-I'll help you.
-Help me, man.
♪♪
♪ Time is running out tick-tock
like grains of sand ♪
♪ Every man sharpens man,
like steel sharpens steel ♪
♪ The threat of a war is real ♪
♪ Where my soldiers
for the battlefield ♪
-What's up, man?
-What's up, babe?
-What's up with you?
-Aight.
-Shit.
Man, look, man.
What the fuck is up, dude?
I'm trying to get back.
Motherfuckers.
Man, they blinded you, man.
I’m trying to blind
one of them other niggas.
-They drew first blood, baby.
-I understand.
And they know me.
You know what I’m saying?
They know all of us.
They know how we go.
You gonna go over there and
take one of them out, right?
-Pow pow baby.
Live by the sword,
I’m gonna die by the sword.
-You know what I’m saying?
-For who?
Who the fuck you fighting for?
What are you fighting
to protect?
For my man.
Dodge City.
You live in the motherfucking
projects. It's an experiment.
Projects, experiment.
Government experiment.
You serving time outside
of the penitentiary
doing exactly what they
want you to do. Pow pow all day.
That's the motherfucking
master plan, nigga.
master plan.
Let's see what Mike
got to say about it.
What you say, Mike?
-Mike, make the house call.
-I’m making the call, man.
You know, I want the guns down.
I want the guns down.
You heard what he said.
Let's put the guns down.
-Put the guns down.
-I want the guns down.
There was one last bullet
that was shot around here,
and that was the bullet
in my head.
[gunshot]
♪ Time is running out tick-tock
like the grains of sand ♪
♪ Every man sharpens man,
like steel sharpens steel ♪
♪ The threat of a war is real ♪
♪ Where my soldiers
for the battlefield ♪
-I can't believe you made it.
-I did.
Well, come on in.
Hey, Imani, hold on.
Ray, meet Imani.
-Hi.
-How ya' doing?
-Ray. Ray, this is DJ.
-Yo, what's up
-This is Ray, a friend of mine.
-I’m DJ Renegade.
DJ's a phat poet.
You got to hear his work.
Actually, tonight you probably
hear some of his work because
we're gonna do
a little poetry reading.
Brothers and sisters, love
will leave you melancholy
as a muted trumpet.
Bluer than a cloudless sky,
bluer than a Viking's eye.
You see, love is
a blue-bottle fly
flitting between
blue and green.
Wings raggedy as
a pair of old jeans.
Merci beaucoup.
Love is Winnie the Pooh
doing voodoo in
corrective shoes.
[laughing]
-Yo, you write?
-Um, a little bit.
Oh, okay.
You gonna kick a piece later?
Um, I don't know.
Yeah, he's gonna
kick a piece later.
I have a million things
going on in my head.
Oh, okay.
Oh, so you gonna free-style?
No.
His intergalactic free-style
jazz licks... my ears.
As I ride his tongue and groove
to the sound of chords
no man has ever touched.
His touch tempts me to taste
flesh of my flesh
from which he is made.
His invisible strokes are felt
as he stands on
the stage in front of me.
A mic and a million
miles away from me.
Everything is kind of new now.
Like I wouldn't want to read
anything I'd written before.
It's too old.
It's nice to have
you on the outside, truly.
It's good to be on
the outside. Truly.
It's all right.
I'm not tripping.
You massage the universe's spine
the way you twirl
through time
and leave shadows on the sun.
My love is the wind song.
If it is up to me,
I’ll never die.
If it is up to me, I’ll die
tomorrow a thousand times
in an hour
and live seven minutes later.
If it is up to me, the sun
will never cease to shine
and the moon will
never cease to glow
and I’ll dance a
million tomorrows
in the sun rays of
the moon waves
and bathe in the
yesterdays of days to come,
ignoring all of my afterthoughts
and preconceived notions.
If it is up to me,
it is up to me.
And thus, is my love.
Untainted.
Eternal.
The wind is the moon's
imagination. Wandering.
It seeps through cracks,
ripples the grass,
explores the unknown.
My love is my soul's
imagination.
How do I love you?
Imagine.
I can't believe
you actually came.
Glad I came.
Very glad I came.
I have thought of you.
Um, and, um...
What else?
What else is there?
Today, now.
There's tomorrow.
And the next day and the next.
Not today.
-Not now.
-Yeah. Well...
Tomorrow and the next day
and the next for me
is not exactly like...
I’m sorry, I mean...
-Ray...
-If, if you want me to go...
I don't know what I want you to
do to be quite honest with you.
Um, today you're here.
Tomorrow and the next day,
I mean, you still,
you still have to go to court.
I mean, you still have
to possibly, um, go away.
I still have to try to get back
into prison to do my job.
No. I really can't.
I can't go there right now.
I just can't.
It's really difficult, Ray.
Who you telling?
You made an
impression on me.
And, um, it's funny,
I wasn't certain of when
I'd be able to see you again.
But...
This is all I’m asking for, now.
Thank you.
Hey, this'll do.
Look at the little one
with the ponytail.
So you coming to
the slam tonight?
Um, I don't know.
I may.
-You should.
-I want to.
You should. You should.
I can get you up on stage.
I just, yeah. I'm not trying,
I'm not thinking about performing.
I need to think.
You know, I just...
I have to go
to court on Monday.
Wow, that soon?
Damn, you just got out.
Have you thought about
what you're gonna do?
I have no clue.
I need time to think it over,
'cause I can't see what it is
I'm supposed to be doing now.
None of this makes sense to me.
You only have until
Monday though, right?
-Yes. I only have...
-What did your lawyer say?
My lawyer told me to cop a plea.
He told me that's
the best thing I should do.
He said if I fight it,
I’ll probably just end up
getting more time.
-It's...
-What's, what's your charge?
Possession of illegal substance.
Are you guilty?
Did you do it?
I had it on me.
What's going to be
is going to be.
You stand up and you face it.
It's a lot to face.
It's a hell of a lot to face...
...for some weed, you know.
Man, they caught you with
the shit red-handed.
-What are you gonna do? Run?
-No, I...
I think there has
to be another way out.
I pray there has
Copping a fucking plea?
That shit is not my way.
I can't, I can't feel that shit.
I can't see that shit.
Wait a minute. You acting
like you did not do this shit.
Like copping a plea would
be like lying to yourself.
Well, you...
you did that shit, Ray.
I did do the shit, but I don't
feel guilty about it.
I don't feel guilty.
I'm sorry,
but I don't feel guilty.
But you did it.
So the fuck what?
I don't care.
-I did it. I did it.
-Yeah.
But what the fuck did I do?
And what are they doing to me?
What the fuck is the punishment
for that shit?
There, there has
to be magical doors.
I’m looking for
the fucking magical doors.
That's what I need.
That's what's gonna get me
out of this shit, you know?
I mean, yesterday, I sat...
I woke up in a fucking prison.
I woke up on a fucking ship.
I woke up there, you know?
I woke up there.
And then I went home.
And I saw that for what it was.
And then, I came here,
and it was like, it was like
a fucking new world to me.
It was a new world.
And I was like, ah,
this is fucking home.
This is where I need to be.
This is the shit that I've
dreamt about, you know?
This is the shit
that I can feel.
This is the new world
that I want.
But I don't want to
have to go to
the fucking middle passage
to get to the new world.
That's not for me.
Look, Ray, all I’m saying
is you made a mistake, baby,
I mean we all make mistakes.
I’ve made mistakes.
All you got to do is
just walk up in that court
with your head up high.
Accept responsibility for
what you've done. Go to jail.
Do your time.
Make the most of your time.
Read, write, do whatever
it is you gotta do...
What the fuck are you saying?
What are you saying?
No, no, no, no, no.
This isn't class now.
My only responsibility
is to my fucking dreams.
You know what I’m saying?
That's my responsibility.
Not to no other shit
like that.
You know, I...
This is a part of
your dreams, Ray.
You cannot have your
dreams if you don't--
This is not a part of
my fucking dreams.
This is not no fucking metaphor.
This is my life.
Motherfucker, who you
think you jumping up on?
You don't know this.
I know about your dreams.
And I know about not being
able to get your dreams
and wanting them and
having them and seeing
all these roadblocks
in your way.
I know something about that
shit, Ray. It doesn't...
I haven't been in jail.
I haven't done time,
but I know something
about that, Ray.
And all I'm saying is,
this thing that
you're going through right now
is what is going to catapult
you into a fucking dream.
You can't see that right now
because you haven't been there.
I’ve been there.
You haven't fucking
been there.
Where the fuck have you been?
Don't you fucking tell me
I haven't been there before.
You don't know me.
You don't know my fucking
life story, motherfucker.
And you know mine?
Oh, yeah. You just spilled
it all right here.
You don't know what kind of
prisons I’ve been a part of.
You don't know what
it's like to sell your ass
on the street for
a hit of crack.
You don't know what
that's like, motherfucker.
I’ve been a slave.
Fuck being a prisoner.
Oh, don't come for me,
motherfucker.
Let me tell you something.
You don't know me.
Remember that.
You don't know
where I come from.
But everything you telling
me right now? I know it.
I know it like the back
of my motherfucking hand.
What the fuck do you mean
I don't know?
You've been a fucking slave?
What do you think I’ve been?
You don't know.
Where did you think I was
in that fucking metaphor?
Where do you think I was, huh?
When you were the fucking slave,
who was the fucking overseer?
Where did you think
I was then?
Who was the one
giving it to you?
selling that shit?
-That was me.
-Oh, oh. Awareness.
Bing. Say that shit again.
Say it again, goddamn it.
Say it again. Who was it?
Who was it?
Who was it that put
me in my prison?
Who was it that enslaved me?
Who was it, goddamn it?
Who the fuck was it, huh?
Who was it? Huh?
It was you.
You wanted to be there.
It ain't easy, baby,
escaping it.
It hasn't been easy.
It hasn't been easy
for none of us.
You ain't the first motherfucker
to be up in this piece,
like this.
And you won't be the last.
All I'm trying...
All I'm trying to do, Ray,
is help you, baby.
'Cause I've been there.
That's all.
That's all I’m trying to say.
That's all that was.
That was just to show you
that I’ve been there.
I know what it's like.
I know what the fear is like.
I know what the pain is like.
I know what it's like to...
I know what it's like
to be cornered.
I know what it's like.
Just trust me, baby.
Just trust me.
All you gotta do
is go through it.
Don't fall into their traps.
Don't fall into their game.
Please, just go.
'Cause if you run away from it,
you just gonna
get caught up later.
Trust me.
Your freedom is there.
It's waiting for you.
And oddly enough, baby,
it's waiting for you
in the goddamned prison.
It is.
I know you can't see it.
I know you can't see it,
but it's there.
It's there. It's there.
Ray...
Ray. Ray?
Ray!
Damn.
♪♪
Come on, lets' hear it
for the other guys, huh?
[applause]
Welcome to the Poetry Club,
where the words you say
are the thoughts you live
and where nothing ever happens
unless you say it first.
Tonight, let's see
who our first poet is.
Who's gonna be coming up
here for the slam tonight?
Please bring up
Liza Jessie Peterson.
Ice cream.
[cheering]
I used to be an
ice cream fiend.
Mm-mm, mm-mm-mm-mm.
Mmm. Mmm.
Mmm.
You see it all started
when I had
a large scoop of
Rain Forest Crunch
with extra walnuts.
Would you like a cup
or cone, Miss?
Cup or cone?
Hmm...
Cup or cone.
Cup or cone?
I was in a zone
where I had to make a wise
choice between a cup or a cone.
You see, it's more
fun with a cone,
because I lick the tip
and then I crunch
and munch the cone.
And then I lick the tip again,
and I crunch and
I munch the cone
until there's one sip
at the bottom tip
and I pop it in my mouth and
grin because I like that game.
You never cared
about my mother...
♪♪
[P.A. announcements]
I'm writing the poem
that will change the world.
And it's "Like Lilly,
like Wilson at my office door."
Lilly Wilson, a recovering
"like" addict.
The worst I’ve ever seen.
So "like-bad"
that the entire eighth grade
started calling her,
"like Lilly like Wilson like".
Until I made my classroom
a "like-free" zone,
and she could not
speak for days.
Look at the scores.
A ten to the fifth power.
Another 9.5. Don't tell me
there's synchronization here.
-Can I help you?
-Yeah.
I’m supposed to be
meeting someone here.
Every slam is a finality.
Every slam is the end.
And tonight there's
no other way
to end this slam,
but to bring up here
one of the true
heroes of poetry.
Do y'all remember
when Lauren started out here?
Yeah.
Let's please bring
Lauren up here
to make it happen
for us right now.
There's nothing else
that can happen in the word
but to make the word
be the word itself.
Something that you've
heard before.
Come on, Lauren.
This is, um, a poem
that I found
when I was
drowning one day.
This is, um, for a friend
of mine who's um,
goin' through
a hard time right now.
I feel like my back
is against a brick wall,
and I've got a Mac truck
two inches from my face.
Every cell in my body
is screaming run.
But I can't.
I’m kicking and stomping
and running and jumping,
wreaking all kinds of havoc,
creating a bloody mess
and I am going nowhere.
Somewhere in my mind
I think I am moving.
Somewhere in reality
I am running.
Somewhere inside myself
I am oh-so-still.
Quiet, dead.
My soul is not rising.
My spirit is not lifting.
My life is not living.
But I am running.
Moving through the universe,
a whirling dervish with no end,
no purpose, no means,
no life left to live.
And yet still I want to go
to that place where I can run.
Run free my mind tells me.
But those two words
cannot occupy
the same space in reality.
Run, free.
My back is against a brick wall.
I got a Mac truck two
inches from my face!
Well run free, baby.
Run now.
It just looks hard,
but it would be so easy.
Just turn around and go.
Clip all the wires,
hookups and hangups,
and then you're home free.
You can give birth
to an excuse so easily,
you'll believe
it's always been there.
Part of the natural order,
made to order by your
forever clever mind.
Constantly protecting you
against things you no longer
need to be protected from.
And I believe.
I believe like a Holy Roller,
singing, sweating, preaching,
go tell it on the mountain,
while speaking in twenty
different tongues,
while diving in ten thousand
feet of baptismal water
without a life preserver.
I believe like my bullet-ridden
brother out there somewhere
right now gurgling blood
through his last breath,
spitting out a red ripe prayer
so new, so sweet, so baby fresh,
so full of truth, he
thinks it can save his life.
God does not exist
in desperation
and hope is lying dead somewhere
in the sewer down the street,
around the corner, in the alley,
underneath the feet of somebody,
itching, scratching, trembling,
jonesing for their next hit
and sucking somebody's dick.
I got two minutes, y'all.
I got two motherfucking minutes
before I run free or die, y'all.
Two minutes
before I smash my face
into the grill
of a Mac truck.
Before I get ten thousand
bricks shoved up my ass.
Before I run free or die.
[cheering]
Oh my God!
Oh my God.
Lauren Bell. Lauren Bell.
Get her back up here.
I need an encore.
You know what? You know,
it's about spreading love.
And I met somebody
recently who, um,
who touched me, who moved me.
And I hope he does
the same thing for you.
Um, this is his
first time reading,
and he's a big, big talent,
and he needs our
love and our support.
And I give you, Ray.
Come on up here, Ray.
Come on, baby.
Come on
Come on.
Yeah, come on, Ray.
Everybody, come on.
Give Ray a hand.
Yeah, come on, Ray.
-Do it, now.
-Take your time.
[crowd shouting]
If I could find the spot
where truth echoes,
I would stand there and
whisper memories
of my children's
future.
I would let their future
dwell in my past
so that I might live
a brighter now.
Now is the essence of my domain
and it contains all
that was and will be
because I am and I will...
I'll try it again.
[applause]
If I could find the spot
where truth echoes,
I would stand there and
whisper memories
of my children's future.
I would let their future
dwell in my past
so that I might live
a brighter now.
Now is the essence of my domain,
and it contains all
that was and will be.
And I am as I was
and will be because I am
and always will
be that nigga.
I am that nigga.
I am that timeless nigga that
swings on pendulums like vines
through minds of booby-trapped
minds that are enslaved by time.
I am the life that
supersedes lifetimes, I am.
It was me with serpentine hair
and a timeless stare
that with immortal glare
turned mortal fear
into stone time capsules.
They still exist
as the walking dead as I do,
the original suffer-head,
symbol of life and
matriarchy's severed head.
Medusa, I am.
I am that nigga.
I am the Negro.
Yes, Negro.
Negro from necro.
Meaning death. I overcame it,
so they named me after it.
And I’ve been spittin'
at death from behind
and putting "kick me"
signs on its back.
Because I am not the son
of sha clack clack.
I am before that.
I am before.
I am before before.
Before death is eternity.
After death is eternity.
There is no death.
There's only eternity.
And I be riding on
the wings of eternity like,
ya, ya, ya,
sha clack clack.
But my flight
doesn't go undisturbed
because time makes dreams defer
and all of my time fears
are turning my days
into daymares.
And I live daymares
reliving nightmares
that once haunted
my past sha clack clack.
Time is beatin' my ass.
And I be having dreams of
chocolate-covered watermelons
filled with fried chickens
like pinatas.
With little pickaninny
sons and daughters
standing up under them with big
sticks and aluminum foil,
hittin' them trying
to catch pieces
of fallen fried
chicken wings.
And Aunt Jemima and Uncle Ben
are standing in the corners
with rifles pointing at the
heads of the little children.
"Don't shoot the children!"
I shout.
But they say, "It's too late.
They've already been
infected by time."
But this shit is before my time.
I need more time.
But it's too late.
They start shooting at the
children and killing them.
One by one, two by two,
three by three, four by four,
Five by five, six by six.
But my spirit is growing
seven by seven.
Faster than the speed of light
because light only penetrates
the darkness
that's already there.
And I’m already there.
I'm here at the end of the road,
which is the beginning of
the road beyond time.
But where my niggas at?
Oh, shit.
Oh, shit. Don't tell me
my niggas got lost in time.
My niggas are dying
before their time.
My niggas are serving
unjust time.
My niggas are dying
because of time.
[cheering, applause]
Look, um...
I just, uh...
I just want to apologize
for what happened earlier.
I didn't, you know,
mean for it to get out of hand.
Look, no, no, look,
I just want to you
know that, um...
no matter what happens
on Monday...
no matter what you decide to do,
I'm gonna be here for you.
[crowd chanting "Ray"]
Go home and write your own
goddamn poems. Goddamn it.
Let's get back out there.
Can't you hear them?
Just one more.
I need to get some air.
-Then you'll come back?
-Yeah.
Okay. Well, I’ll hold the fort
down till you get back.
Thank you.
[crowd chanting "Ray"]
♪♪