(dramatic music)
(dramatic music continues)
(instrumental music)
(dramatic music)
(knuckles rapping)
(door clicks)
I'm Mark Sheldon sir,
reporting for duty.
Oh, yes, glad to meet you, Mark.
Have a nice trip?
Well, I lost a lot of sleep
worrying about this meeting.
(chuckles) Yes, I
felt the same way myself
the first time I reported for duty.
But I got over it, so will you.
-Sit down.
-Thank you.
Now, we'll have our first
and possibly our last talk.
How's everything in Kansas City?
Fine, thanks.
You, uh, you know what
you getting into, Mark?
Yes, sir.
In joining our under cover staff,
you'll have to burn all
your bridges behind you.
I've done that, sir.
You're joining an army.
An army, where there are no banners,
no medals for heroism,
and death is the only
honourable discharge.
When you walk out of that door
you're starting on a lonely road.
You get into trouble, we won't help you.
We'll deny that you're one of our men.
I understand.
Well, I'd hoped you
would let me talk you out.
(drawer rattles)
Your full instructions.
Of course, you'll have to
use various names from now on
depending upon where and
what you are working on.
Now, with us you will
always have a number.
It'll never change, remember, 64.
64.
[Man] Your opposite number will be 46.
My opposite number?
Yes, you see, wouldn't
be fair or even sensible
to send you out on your
first assignment alone.
Now, 46 is been with us a long time,
he's a good man, you'll like him.
May I ask what he's working on?
Well, I won't know
until his work is finished
and he's made his report.
You, uh, you can still change your mind.
All right, good luck, 64.
Thank you, sir.
Raise your right hand
and repeat after me.
I, Mark Sheldon do solemnly swear.
(footsteps tapping)
(knuckles rapping)
(door clicks)
What do you want?
The office is closed.
It's too bad.
I came a long way to talk business.
A long way?
Kansas City, by way of Washington.
Oh, uh, come in.
(door clicks)
All right, what is it you want?
Wanna find out the market
price of National Debentures.
Those Washington specials.
-Are you a stockholder?
-Yes.
For how long?
Since last Tuesday night at 9:46.
How many shares do you own?
64.
How many do you wanna buy?
46.
I have exactly 46.
I think we can make a deal.
Certainly glad you got here.
(door clicks)
Let's go into my office,
we'll get acquainted.
(footsteps tapping)
(door thuds)
Well, you ready to go to work?
-Yes, sir.
-Now look, we're partners.
None of that sir business with me.
Come on, sit down.
(footsteps tapping)
I've been working on
this case for six months.
I've got a lot of information
but so far I haven't been
able to prove a thing.
Now, I'll tell you one thing.
You and I are gonna try to
smash the dirtiest racket
any man ever invented.
Don't tell me there's a new racket?
Yeah, right here.
That is an island, Dead Man's Island.
And a very good name for it too.
It's United States
territory but it's so small
and unimportant nobody
pays any attention to it.
Except the man we're after, he owns it.
Did you ever hear of a
man by the name of Danel,
Stephen Danel?
I don't think so.
Well, Stephen Danel is our
man, Lincoln freed the slaves.
Mr. Danel is back in the trade,
doing very well at it too.
[Mark] What's his nationality?
I don't know, might be anything.
He's an American citizen now
and that makes him our problem.
He deals in paroled men.
Convicts, who think he's giving
them a new start in life.
But what they really get
is a slow, living death.
(gunshot bangs)
(gun thuds)
(body thuds)
(blinds rattles)
(ladder clatters)
(gunshots banging)
Stop it,
(gunshot bangs)
Stop shooting.
(gun thuds)
(bell clangs)
Hello, hello.
Information?
Get away from that telephone.
Don't you know any better than that?
You've got to have a doctor.
Beat it, the fire escape.
If they catch you in
here, spoil everything.
Remember, Danel.
Good luck.
(body thuds)
(crowd chattering)
(door clattering)
[Officer] Get back.
Get back, come on.
Get back now.
(crowd chattering)
All right, stand back.
Will you please?
(footsteps tapping)
Get back.
(glass shattering)
Watch it.
All right, stand back there.
Get back, get back.
(door clicks)
(blinds rattling)
(footsteps tapping)
Come on, come on.
Why did you kill him?
-I didn't.
-Then who did?
I wish I knew.
Who are you?
What's your name?
Okay, we'll find out.
Your fingerprints are on that gun.
I told you I used that gun.
Shooting at whoever
was on the fire escape.
You burnt something here, what?
That's my business.
[Man] You admit you were
here when this guy was killed?
Yes.
All right.
You're locked in this office with the guy,
he gets shot in the back.
Your fingerprints are
on the gun, nobody else's,
we catch you trying to make a getaway.
-That's right.
-And you didn't kill him?
-No.
-And you haven't got a name.
If you want a name, make it John Smith.
All right, wise guy.
Maybe you'll change your story tomorrow.
Come on, Mr. Smith.
(crowd chattering)
What happened, sir?
A guy just killed somebody.
Shot him down like a dog.
Oh, but that's shocking, isn't it?
They're bringing him out now.
Say, I never saw a
murderer before, did you?
No.
All right folks, break
it up, let him get out.
Break it up, come on, get out.
Back up, get off.
All right, come on, get back you.
(footsteps tapping)
Is everything okay?
Of course.
Police just took the
unfortunate gentleman away.
Why should an old story affect
you so deeply, Mr. Brand?
This were the first time
but, uh, of course, it isn't.
Chicago was the first time, wasn't it?
And then San Francisco?
(match hisses)
You ought to do something
about your nervous condition, Mr. Brand.
(Stephen blows)
Nervous men sometimes talk too
much and they make mistakes.
And you mustn't make mistakes, Mr. Brand.
And you must never talk too much.
But I got a right to
know what's happened.
Oh, yes, of course.
You see, Mr. Brand,
the man who was so interested
in my personal affairs is quite dead.
And a gentleman who came
to see him is under arrest
for murder. (chuckles)
But maybe know something.
You don't have to worry about that.
I'll watch this case.
Good night, Mr. Brand
and, uh, pleasant dreams.
(door clicks)
(door thuds)
(dramatic music)
Before imposing sentence I
must say to you, John Smith,
I feel as I'm sure the jurors felt
that much of the real story of
your crime is not been told.
And I must add that your
refusal to tell the true story
to identify yourself or to
offer any believable defence
probably had much to do
with the jury's verdict.
No evidence was introduced to show
there was any gain for you
in the crime you committed.
The peculiar circumstances of this case
justify the jury in returning
a verdict of guilty.
Under the law, I must sentence you
to be committed to the State Penitentiary
and there to serve a term
of from one to 20 years.
Have you any statement you
wish to make to this court?
[Mark] I have nothing to say.
(gavel thudding)
(dramatic music)
(footsteps tapping)
(hammers thudding)
(stones clattering)
(dramatic music continues)
(prisoners chattering)
We're all set, Mr. Danel.
Thank you, Captain.
I trust you understand why it is necessary
to punish this young man.
Where men live and work together
discipline is essential.
Quite essential and, uh,
sometimes an object
lesson becomes necessary
as it has today.
Unfortunately, this is causing all of us
to lose valuable time from our work.
20 lashes, Captain.
-Yes, sir.
Eddie, I hope I'll hear good reports
on your conduct hereafter.
Come, Doctor.
(whip cracking)
(Eddie whimpering)
(birds chirping)
(gate clicks)
(footsteps tapping)
Oh, come on, shake
hands, now shake hands.
Come on, give me your
hand, give me your hand.
[Stephen] Siggy.
Yes, sir.
Don't you have any work
to do for Mrs. Danel?
(monkey chittering)
Keep that monkey away from me.
Yes, sir.
(door clicks)
(door clatters)
Very lovely, these flowers.
I had a very annoying afternoon.
Please Lorraine, put on something
else, I don't like that.
Then come back, I want you to play for me.
(glass clattering)
I wouldn't, if I were you.
(glass thuds)
(matches rattle)
Your hands, Doctor.
(fire crackles)
You really ought to keep yourself cleaner.
I'm sorry. (blows)
(drawer rattles)
You know, I am leaving for
the mainland tomorrow, Doctor.
Yes?
Yes.
To bring back some friends
I've kept track of.
Friends like Mr. Smith.
The young man is made repeated
applications for parole.
Naturally, he wants to get
out of prison, all convicts do
but, uh, in his case he
might've a special reason
for wanting out
and I think I ought to help
Mr. Smith to get his parole.
What do you think, Doctor?
Mr. Danel, I probably
shouldn't say this.
I don't want you to be
offended, but I wonder.
You're trying to say I should stop, uh,
shall we say, recruiting
paroled men for my island?
Yes, yes, it's dangerous.
Yes, very dangerous.
But not as dangerous, Doctor,
as if I were to employ ordinary workmen
who might be able to tell too much.
Also the work is very hard.
Men who could leave, would.
No, Doctor, I think,
for our purpose paroled
men are much better.
Men like yourself.
Yes, Mr. Danel.
I'm so glad you agree with me, Doctor.
Yes, Mr. Smith,
I shall talk to you very soon.
(door thuds)
(footsteps tapping)
You may go, Doctor.
(door clicks and thuds)
My favourite gown.
(piano gentle music)
And one of my favourite pieces of music.
How did you know I like
the "Nocturne" so well?
Oh, you told me, a long time ago.
I, I didn't wanna play it for you until,
until I was sure I knew it perfectly.
It's very thoughtful of you, Lorraine.
(gentle piano music continues)
You going away tomorrow, aren't you?
I wish I could go with you.
(gentle piano music continues)
I get so lonely when you're away.
Do you?
Please take me with you this time.
I remember when I saw you
the first time on the stage.
You were beautiful.
Very beautiful.
But your acting was
always unconvincing to me.
I can't stand staying here, I can't.
You afraid to take me
with you, I know too much.
Afraid?
But darling, don't you know
that a man's wife can
never testify against him?
And you are my wife.
Yes.
Because I was a fool.
Of course, you'd leave me if you could
once we reached the mainland
but I couldn't let you do that.
I need you here.
Remember when,
when you met me and told me
how much you'd love to leave
the stage and come with me?
Remember, Lorraine?
For rich and for poorer,
for better and for worse,
in sickness and in health.
Stop talking about it.
I don't regret my bargain, you do.
You must get over that.
This is your home and a man's wife
must always be in his
home and waiting for him,
isn't that right?
Lorraine, you mustn't walk
away when I'm talking to you.
(dramatic music)
Look, my dear.
The largest and finest diamond
ever found on my island.
I'm going to give it to you.
[Lorraine] I don't want it.
I know that, but I want you to have it.
You are enjoying this
so much, aren't you?
I'm a prisoner here.
You'll never let me leave, you don't dare.
All right, I'm here, aren't you satisfied?
Isn't that enough?
Stop torturing me.
(dramatic music)
(door thuds)
I believe in giving
deserving men decent jobs
in pleasant surroundings,
a chance to earn peace and contentment.
The men who work with me
are free of all the things
that make criminals out of paroled men.
I've gone over the list of
applicants before your board
and, uh, I'm especially
interested in a young man
who calls himself John Smith.
I ask you to parole him in my custody
and I promise you, gentlemen,
if you let him come with me
he'll never again be a burden
on your taxpayers or on society.
(plane engine revving)
Here gentlemen, is my little island.
You better fasten your belts.
(cart wheels rattling)
(hammers thudding)
(whistle blows)
(plane engine revving)
[Cort] Line up.
[Man] Line up.
Come on, come on.
Come on, out of there.
(plane engine revving)
(footsteps tapping)
What you want?
Mr. Danel will want you in
the picture with the new men.
-How many this time?
-Five.
And how long will they live?
(footsteps crunching)
One moment gentlemen.
We have no police on the island,
so one has to take certain precautions.
Oh, I wouldn't touch those
wires if I were you, Mr. Smith.
There's a slight electric
current passing through them.
To keep out the animals and snakes,
you see, the jungle comes
awfully close to us here.
Gentlemen.
(footsteps crunching)
(footsteps tapping)
(birds chirping)
My dear, I've missed you.
Gentlemen, my wife.
-Hi.
-How do you do?
I think we will all
remember this day and, uh,
as a souvenir I thought we'd
all pose for a little picture.
Sort of record of the
visitors to my island
which I'd like to keep.
Over here, I think would be all right.
You don't mind gentlemen, do you?
No, no.
My dear, I think it would be nice
if you pose shaking hands with Mr. Smith.
Lorraine, please.
All ready, Doctor?
All ready, Mr. Danel.
Now, let's all have a
nice happy smile, huh?
(camera clicks)
(chuckles) I think I moved.
(men chuckling)
Thank you, gentlemen.
Let's all be seated over there, Mr. Borgo.
Sit right down please, over there.
Mm.
Siggy, I want to compliment you
on this charming arrangement.
Have you lived here long, Mrs. Danel?
Three years.
[Mark] You visit the
mainland sometimes, don't you?
I, I never leave the island.
Oh, I should think you'd
enjoy going on these trips
with Mr. Danel.
Lorraine, your guests are waiting.
(birds chirping)
Thank you, Mr. Smith.
You're very fortunate man, Mr. Danel.
I think so, Mr. Smith.
This reminds me of old times before my.
Before my trouble.
You can forget all about
your troubles here, Mr. Ames.
I don't imagine you
greatly enjoy sitting
at a table with convicts,
do you, Mrs. Danel?
You like your lunch, Mr. Smith?
Very much.
(gunshot bangs)
(footsteps tapping)
(utensil clatters)
Eat fast, it's the last
square meal you'll get.
(footsteps tapping)
You dirty, slave trading rat.
(gunshots banging)
(platters clattering)
[Stephen] How did he get in here?
Made a break and slugged the guard.
I'm sorry, Mr. Danel.
[Stephen] Take him away and hurry up.
Help them, Doctor.
Brand, watch these men.
But why they do shoot him?
They'll shoot you too
if you don't do exactly
what you're told to.
-But, Mr. Danel.
-Get away from me.
Put your hands up, all of you.
Step over here.
[Brand] Come on, get going.
Let go of my wife, Mr. Smith.
You heard Mr. Danel, put your hands up.
Move.
Go into the house, Lorraine.
Captain.
I'm sorry, gentlemen,
you didn't have time to finish your meal.
But you'll have to go
with Captain Cort now.
And remember, you'll be shot
if you ever dare to come
near this place again.
Take them away, Captain.
[Cort] Come on, move.
(footsteps crunching)
(dramatic music)
(footsteps tapping)
Clean up that mess.
Yes sir, yes sir.
Was Mitchell, Doctor, wasn't it?
Dead?
Not yet.
Don't forget to have some extra prints
of the picture we just took.
Promised I'd send one of our
friend Mr. Smith to the Warden.
What do you plan to do about him?
What do I plan to do about him?
I've many plans for Mr. Smith.
(dramatic music)
(door clicks)
(door thuds)
I've been away for a long time.
You should be very glad to see me.
I hate the sight of you.
I know that.
Lorraine, you've been in Mr. Smith's arms.
Nothing like that must ever happen again.
It embarrasses me.
You are my wife and he's a murderer.
And what are you?
I'm your husband.
Lorraine, remember this stone?
You can't bribe me with that.
Why should I bribe you?
You've tried everything else and failed.
No matter what you do, you'll always fail.
I've never failed and I will never fail.
I won't wear that, you can't make me.
Of course, you will.
(dramatic music)
So Mr. Smith approves of my taste, eh?
There's only one thing that
Mr. Smith doesn't know.
What I own I keep, but he'll learn.
So will you.
(door clicks and thuds)
Take off your irons.
Hurry up, hurry up, in front of your beds.
(footsteps tapping)
Come on, move along, move along.
(man groans)
Why don't you get the doctor
for him, if he is a doctor.
What's that to you?
Nothing, only he's dying.
You don't wanna lose any
good hard workers, do you?
Come on, quit faking.
I'm not faking.
Maybe need a taste of this.
Well, if he ain't better in the morning,
he's gonna get it.
And you'll wanna stop talking
so much, now get to your bed.
Lie down.
(footsteps tapping)
Chains.
(chains clattering)
Captain, Mr. Danel wants to
see Mr. Smith up the house.
Huh?
What is he want with you?
Maybe wants a new captain.
Mr. Danel said to
bring him up right away.
Okay, go on.
I'll be walking right behind
you, so don't start anything.
Why should I?
I like it here.
(gentle piano music)
Go on.
Sure, Captain.
I just wondered who is playing.
You see, I'm quite a music lover.
(footsteps tapping)
[Cort] Hold it.
(knuckles rapping)
Go to your room, Lorraine, please.
I've never had a chance to hear
how you talk to your other prisoners.
You mind if I stay?
It might impress me.
Go to your room.
(door clicks)
(door thuds)
Come in, Captain, Mr. Smith.
You'll forgive me if I don't
ask you to sit down, Mr. Smith,
but your clothes and my furniture,
I'm sure you understand.
Were you actually stupid
enough, Mr. Smith,
to believe you were fooling me?
I don't know what you mean.
You see, I had an office in a building.
Across the hall a man was killed
and you were convicted of murder.
I know who that man was, Mr. Smith.
So does anybody who
read about the trial.
His name was Jackson.
Jackson wasn't his real name.
Oh, wasn't it?
I want to know how
much that man told you
and who else knows what he told you.
He didn't tell me anything.
Don't lie to me, Mr. Smith.
You saw a man shot today.
I can have you shot too,
and no one will ever know.
I know that.
But I can also let you live
and you may live for a long time.
I know that too.
And, uh, don't you
think you better tell me?
I don't know what you're talking about.
Captain.
Yes, sir.
[Stephen] This man
is a government agent.
You got a great imagination, Mr. Danel.
Shut up.
Thank you, Captain.
Oh, Captain, I think you
know what would happen to you
if outsiders found out about our island.
And, uh, this gentleman seems to believe
we can't make him tell.
Who else besides himself knows about this?
I'm afraid you'll have to
use your ingenuity, Captain.
And, of course, uh,
we don't want him to die until
he is told us what he knows.
Take him out, Captain.
We have plenty of time, Mr. Smith,
all the time in the world.
(door clicks)
(door thuds)
(footsteps tapping)
(Mark panting)
Get on there.
Lock him.
(chains clattering)
(scoffs) Maybe you'd better
call out the US Marines,
come on, let's get some sleep.
(Mark panting)
(chains clattering)
You're wasting your time.
(Mark panting)
There's only one way out of here.
Make them kill you.
Don't die day at a time.
Get it over...
then you can rest.
Dead men can't work.
Never get out until you die.
Then you get parole to a pine box.
(Mitchell coughs)
(hammers thudding)
(cart wheels clattering)
Here, let me take it, Eddie.
(hammers thudding)
How long have you been here?
Three years.
[Mark] You must know
a lot about the island.
I ought to.
Anybody ever try to get away?
Sure.
Lots of them, nobody ever made it though.
It's 480 miles to the nearest island
and sharks are all around the island.
Some guys have tried to build a raft
or a boat but they always get caught.
Maybe they went at the wrong way.
What you mean?
Well, there's plenty to know.
There's a couple of guards.
If you boys had worked together
maybe something might happen.
Take the island away from them.
What will we use, our hands?
What do you two guys talking about?
Not a thing.
(stones thudding)
(door clicks)
(monkey chitters)
Siggy, would you do something for me?
Yes, ma'am, if I can.
You can get out of
here sometimes, I can't.
You know the new man who
just came, John Smith?
I got to talk to him.
Oh, but you're not
allowed to talk to the men.
I got to talk to him.
Siggy, you wanna get off
this island, don't you?
-Don't you?
-Oh, sure, sure, I do, but.
Well, I'll do the best I can.
I'll be down there when
they are feeding the men,
and maybe I'll get a
chance to talk to him.
Try, will you?
(door clicks)
(monkey chittering)
I've asked you not to come
in the kitchen, Lorraine.
I just wanted to make sure
everything was perfect for dinner.
I know how anything imperfect upsets you.
It's very thoughtful of you, thank you.
(monkey chittering)
(fire hissing)
What did Mrs. Danel really want, Siggy?
Oh, just what she said, Mr. Danel.
(monkey chittering)
I've told you I don't want the monkey
in the house, didn't I?
Yes, sir, yes, sir.
Come on.
Step up, step up.
(plates clattering)
Come on, step into it, step into it.
Second line move in.
Come on, move in, move in.
Hurry up, back there, hurry up.
I can't eat this stuff, the
smell of it makes me sick.
It's better nothing, I guess.
Come on, move on, move on.
What you standing there for?
(insects chirping)
Come on, move up, step up, step up.
I got to talk to you.
What about?
Mrs. Danel wants to see you.
What?
Now look, I got to talk fast, so listen.
She doesn't like it here
any more than we do.
And she wants to get out too.
She thinks maybe you can help
her, I told her you couldn't.
Danel sent you, didn't he?
Oh, no, no.
If he even knew I was talking to you,
they'd tie me to the post.
She's awful anxious to see you.
That's all I know and I
got to get out of here.
(insects chirping)
(monkey chittering)
(knuckles rapping)
(door clicks)
I did like you told me to.
What did he say?
Nothing.
Well, I'd better get out of here.
If Mr. Danel knew I was
talking to you like this,
I don't know what he'd do.
I did the best I could, honest I did.
Good night.
(monkey chittering)
Didn't I tell you about that monkey?
I'll teach you.
(monkey chittering)
-Don't.
(gunshot bangs)
Throw that thing out.
Didn't you hear me?
You're so brave, against
things that can't fight back.
Don't.
Don't make me do anything else, Lorraine.
Please don't.
Oh, yes, I.
Have a little business with Mr. Smith.
I'll be back.
(insects chirping)
Don't overdo it, Captain.
There's a lot Mr. Smith
ought to tell me and, uh,
and may want to tell
me before you finished.
Oh, and be sure that he's
able to work tomorrow.
Goodnight, Mr. Smith.
(whip cracking)
Okay, you can beat me to death, so what?
Danel gets another man to take my place.
You two, if your foot slips,
he gets another man to take your place.
And what do you get for it?
Danel sits up on his hill
with his safe full of diamonds
and you do all his dirty work.
(whip cracks)
Just a big, dumb ox.
You do all the work and
Danel gets all the gravy.
(whip cracks)
(Mark groans)
Why don't you get smart?
You silly ape.
(door thuds)
(footsteps tapping)
(bed creaks)
(Brand exhales)
Come on, wake up, come on.
(man groans)
-[Doctor] What's the matter?
-Got a patient for you.
And take good care of him, Doc.
You know, he's Danel's pet prisoner.
Hate to lose him.
[Doctor] You're not going
to leave me alone with him.
What's the matter with the gun?
Come on, let's go.
(Doctor sighs)
(footsteps tapping)
(glasses clattering)
(Mark panting)
(Mark breathing heavily)
(Doctor groaning)
(both grunting)
(body thuds)
(fist thuds)
(Mark panting)
(footsteps tapping)
(dramatic music)
Lorraine?
(dramatic music continues)
(door thuds)
Crying, Lorraine?
Many men are whipped on this island,
you've never cried before.
Mr. Smith...
you've only seen him once.
He's tall and dark,
and quite attractive, I suppose.
Why speak about it?
It so unimportant.
(dramatic music)
(door clicks)
(birds chirping)
(footsteps tapping)
(leaves rustling)
Captain.
What's the matter, Captain?
The man is on the island,
can't you find him?
We've been looking for
him all night, Mr. Danel.
And you'll keep looking for
him every day and every night
until you do find him.
Or I'll get a captain who can.
Come on.
(footsteps tapping)
(birds chirping)
(leaves rustling)
(stone thuds)
(stone clatters)
(birds chirping)
-Don't touch those wires.
-I know.
You said Mrs. Danel wanted see me.
Tell her I'm here, if
she's got anything to say,
she can come out.
Tell her I won't be here long.
[Siggy] They'll get you,
you better get away from here, quick.
Maybe, go on now, go on.
(birds chirping)
(footsteps tapping)
(leaves rustling)
Hey, look.
You follow his trail,
I'll be back at the house.
(footsteps tapping)
Over there.
Talk fast, Mrs. Danel,
you said you wanted to see me, why?
Are you really working
for the government?
What difference does that make?
I'm as much a prisoner here as you are,
as any of the men down there.
Oh, I was a fool, I.
I wanted a good home and security.
That's why I married Stephen Danel.
I've been a prisoner ever since
and I'll be a prisoner
until he kills me or I die.
Can you help me get away?
Can I help you whatever
you're trying to do?
Has he got a radio sending set?
-[Lorraine] No.
-Any guns in the house?
Yes, in a locked room,
I've never been in it.
[Mark] You're taking a big
chance being with me now.
Will you take a bigger one?
I'll do anything.
We got to get guns.
I'll pick men I can trust
among the prisoners,
wait for our break,
open up on the guards
and take over the island.
It's the only way.
Can you get your husband's keys?
I don't know.
[Mark] Would you try?
Yes.
(footsteps tapping)
I'm going back now.
I can't swing this alone.
We got to take our time
but you take your time too.
We've got to have those keys.
(footsteps tapping)
Psst, psst, psst.
Go back in the house now, hurry.
(footsteps tapping)
(door thuds)
(door clicks)
Lorraine.
Where are you, Lorraine?
(door thuds)
-Here I am.
What is it?
You look breathless and upset.
I wonder why.
I'm just happy, because
my husband is home.
I don't like you when
you talk like that.
I'm so sorry.
Of course, you know that
Mr. Smith is at liberty.
Mr. Smith?
Yes I, I remember.
Where were you right now, Lorraine?
-Why, in my room.
-Alone?
Of course.
(footsteps tapping)
(leaves rustling)
Listen, you, stand
still, I got you covered.
You got a strong trigger
finger but a weak mind.
Listen you.
One minute isn't
gonna cost you anything.
Now, you do some listening
and some thinking.
Your boss wants to know who I am.
Well, I'm a smart guy.
I killed a guy that was after Danel, sure.
But I found out what he knew first.
I found out where there
was a stack of diamonds
just waiting for someone
to come along and get them.
He thinks I'm a government man.
Well, I'm not, I'm on my own.
I had a tough time getting here
and it's gonna be a whole
lot tougher getting out.
So if I can get off this
island and back to the States,
I got connections.
I can sell Danel's stuff for more cash
than you'd see if you
live a million years.
Unless you get smart.
-What do you think you're doing?
-If you work with me,
we can make the biggest
cleanup that ever happened.
Or you can take me back,
whip the life out of me,
and tell Danel what a fine boy you are.
And sooner or later you'll be dead.
Well, if you're such a big
shot, what do you want with me?
I want a partner,
a chance to move around
and figure the angles.
You're a swell target.
I didn't have to talk to you, you know.
Go on, take it.
But if there's any brain in
that thick head of yours,
use it.
Come on, start walking.
(leaves rustling)
You claim you got big ideas.
Tell them to me and make it fast.
-And you wanna make a deal?
-Now, I don't know what you got to sell.
Well, if we're gonna
take over the island,
we've got to get rid of Danel.
We got to be able to get
at the guns he's got in the house
and the plane he's got
locked up in the hanger,
and the stuff you want from the house.
How can you do that?
I've got an angle.
Yeah?
What angle?
Mrs. Danel.
What do you mean?
Mrs. Danel is trying
to get his keys for me.
That's all we need.
But why should she'd be working for you?
What do you think?
She's waiting for me out there now.
Look, Cort,
you didn't bring me back
here to put me in solitary,
you did it because you
wanna throw in with me.
All right.
If you wanna gamble, play the whole hand.
Fix it so that I can
get out of here tonight
and roam around.
Then let me get out of here
a couple of hours every night
until I can get to Mrs. Danel.
Then what?
Then, when we're all set, we take over.
You and me.
Oh, what if Danel gets wise?
You're in the clear.
What could you do with a million dollars?
How about it?
Put your hands up there, go on.
I ain't gonna lock them.
I'm gonna take a chance once.
But if you double cross me.
-Why should I?
I'll be here at four in the morning
to get you off to work.
And you better be here.
I'll be here.
(door clatters)
All set?
Yeah, all set.
(door clicks)
(cuffs clatter)
(dramatic music)
(door clicks)
(leaves rustling)
(intense music)
(intense music continues)
(footsteps crunching)
(lock clicks)
(leaves rustling)
Let's get away from here.
(intense music continues)
Here.
How did you do it?
I, I just took them.
What we going to do?
It's about a half a dozen
men I can trust down there.
I'll get them loose, then
try to get guns for them.
Cort thinks I'm working with
him, had to do a lot of lying.
You will take me with you, won't you?
Let go of my wife, Mr. Smith.
(intense music)
(leaves rustling)
Let go of my wife.
Give me the keys.
(keys jingle)
Lorraine, you should've remembered
I'm a very light sleeper.
Go home now, Lorraine.
(intense music continues)
For the sake of my wife
don't force me to have you
killed in front of her.
Go home, Lorraine.
(leaves rustling)
I'll give you orders
about him in the morning.
(intense music continues)
Captain, give me your gun.
You're a very clever man, Mr. Smith
but unfortunately, Cort
wasn't clever enough.
He didn't realise that
Brand had a suspicion
and told me everything.
You take charge from
now on, Captain Brand.
(intense music continues)
All right, get going.
(intense music)
(gate clatters)
You better lock me up
with the other prisoners
or you better kill me,
because there's nothing in the world
you can do to make me stop hating you.
(dramatic music)
(door thuds)
(footsteps tapping)
(dramatic music)
Come on, pick up your irons.
(footsteps tapping)
Make it snappy, move.
In front of your beds.
Come on, keep going.
(metals clattering)
(footsteps tapping)
How do you like finding out
how the other half lives, Cort?
Stand back.
Lie down.
Chains.
(chains clattering)
You sure look good there, Cort.
Hurry up.
(prisoners shouting)
(chain thuds)
All right, now we're getting out.
But the first thing we
got to do is get Danel,
he's got guns up at the house.
You're gonna follow me,
do what you're told and
play the game my way.
If this works, we all get out of here.
(footsteps tapping)
Hold it.
Oh, you're a great talker
and you got a great line.
But I don't like you and
I'm running things now.
You know, I've been talking
to a few of the boys myself.
And you know what you
gonna do, Mr. Smart Guy?
You're gonna talk to Mrs. Danel
and you gonna get us in
that house if you can.
And if you can't, I'm
gonna blow you apart.
Borgo, Durkin, you know
what I promised you
if you'd go along.
Now then the first thing we
got to do is to get Danel.
You keep your hands off that woman,
I'll take care of her myself.
Now come on, get going.
Come on, hurry up.
(insects chirping)
No possible way to
get through that fence.
-You're wrong, Doctor.
-What you mean?
I'm gonna play ball with you, Cort.
I think I can get through.
Are you crazy?
It's sure death.
And if you do, then what?
After I get through, I get Danel.
Then I'll open the gate.
You can relax, you got nothing to lose.
(leaves rustling)
(dramatic music)
(electricity crackling)
(dramatic music continues)
Would you like to try it first, Captain?
Go on.
(dramatic music continues)
-I'll see you in a minute.
-Don't try to pull anything.
Don't worry, you're the boss.
He'll never get into the house.
(dramatic music continues)
(door clicks)
(floor creaks)
(intense music)
Good evening, Mr. Smith.
I was waiting for you,
I was hoping you would come soon.
Cort is out there,
Cort and a couple of men.
They're armed and they're coming in.
But you didn't come to see
me, you came to see my wife.
Come, Mr. Smith, I'll get her for you.
(footsteps tapping)
Wait.
Lorraine?
Lorraine.
Forgive me, Mr. Smith,
she'll be here in a moment.
(intense music)
[Cort] Come on.
(intense music continues)
You must stand very
close to him, very close.
Yes, Lorraine.
Smile.
(footsteps tapping)
He likes you when you smile, Lorraine.
Listen to me, that gang
is coming in after her.
When I find a flaw in a
diamond, I throw it away.
(intense music)
It's so hard to remember,
it's a long time ago.
Everything on this island belonged to me.
Everything.
And it was beautiful.
My wife, beautiful,
(intense music continues)
So beautiful.
And then, you came...
and you touched my wife.
(footsteps tapping)
(door thuds)
(gunshot bangs)
Drop that gun.
(gun thuds)
Come in gentlemen, come in.
Want you to meet my wife.
Don't touch her.
(intense music continues)
You'll forget him, Lorraine.
You'll forget everything after a while.
I want you to meet these
gentlemen, Lorraine.
They are your friends, you like them.
I'm going to let you go back with them.
Want you to be happy...
but you must say goodbye to Mr. Smith.
(intense music continues)
I'm not going to kill you, Lorraine.
I want you to live.
Live for a long time.
(knife thuds)
(Stephen groans)
(Stephen panting)
(gunshot bangs)
(Siggy groans)
(body thuds)
(Stephen panting)
Everything
on this island belonged to me.
(gun thuds)
Everything.
Everything belongs to me...
as long as I live.
(body thuds)
(dramatic music)
(plane engine revving)
(gentle music)
The last of Dead Man's Island.
(instrumental music)