(dramatic orchestral music)
(music continues)
(music softens)
- [Narrator] Many years ago
when the Commodore built it,
it had been one of the
show places of New Bristol,
11 Crescent Drive.
That's how the house was still
listed in the city directory,
but it was a dead address.
It had been barred, locked, and
shuttered for over 12 years.
Thousands of days had dawned without a ray
of sunshine striking through its windows.
It stood among the neighbouring
homes, dark and blind,
and almost forgotten.
From a certain window
in the house next door,
the crescent seemed deserted,
yet not quite deserted.
An old woman was crossing the street,
bundled against the rain.
In front of the empty house,
suddenly she paused, surprised,
and stared at something she saw,
a light in a place where
no light should have been.
It moved behind the boarded windows.
It reached the wall.
It should have stopped
there, but it didn't.
It went on through into
the house next door,
and then she saw why.
Below her, dimly through
the rain stained window,
a man appeared.
She saw him stoop and lift something heavy
and set it in place.
(gate creaking)
He must have heard her,
for suddenly he turned.
When the light hit her face,
she stumbled and dropped something.
(watch thuds)
A small gold watch.
It was probably the only thing
of value she had to her name.
Frightened as she was,
she stayed to look for it
just a little too long.
Above her, a door opened.
The door of number 10 Crescent Drive.
(dramatic music)
(music intensifies)
(Alberta panting)
(pensive music)
(Alberta gasps)
(suspenseful music)
(Alberta screams)
(dramatic music)
- Taxi?
Number 10, Crescent Drive.
(anticipatory music)
(train rumbling)
(light music)
(suspenseful music)
(bell rings)
- What do you want?
- She wants in.
What do you think she wants?
- [Liz] I'm your new governess.
- We've got a governess.
- Sure you gave the right address, Miss?
- There it is.
Fielding, number 10, Crescent Drive.
- And they got a governess.
- Yes?
Oh, you should be Miss Howard.
Come in.
- [Liz] Thank you.
- You'll find Mr. Fielding in the library.
He's expecting you.
- Mr. Fielding?
- What is it?
- I'm Elizabeth Howard.
- Take a chair, Miss Howard.
(phone ringing)
- Shall I answer it?
- Why?
It'll stop ringing after awhile.
(ringing stops)
See?
- Perhaps you don't remember.
The agency in Boston sent
me here as a governess.
- [David] Uh huh.
- Well, aren't you even
going to look at me?
- Sure.
You're too young to know
anything about children.
- I'm sure I'm not.
- The agency said you were 25.
- You're not 25, are you?
- Well, no, I'm not.
- You're nothing like 25.
Have you ever had a job
as a governess before?
- No, but-
- Have you ever had any kind of a job?
- Yes, I have but-
- Don't you ever finish a sentence?
- Yes, if I'm allowed to.
- Okay, let's start all over.
Sit down, tell me about yourself.
- My home was in Sharon.
I went to Boston a year ago
and worked on a newspaper,
then I tried advertising for awhile.
- You didn't like it?
- I was fired.
- I see.
- I was never really trained for anything.
My father died suddenly
while I was at college.
- [David] And your mother?
- She died when I was a child.
- Well, Miss Howard,
you're young and pretty,
and you seem intelligent.
What makes you wanna be a governess?
- I'm fond of children, Mr. Fielding.
- You think that's enough?
- Yes, I do.
- You don't know my children.
- Well, I've seen them.
- But seeing them's one thing,
and making them behave as something else.
- I'd like to try if you'll let me.
- Well, let's go up and meet them.
I did hope you'd be a
little more motherly.
- I'll be 22 in March.
- Remind me to congratulate you.
That's where they belong, behind bars.
After my wife died,
they went to live with their grandmother.
She didn't discipline them.
She bribed them.
(Liz chuckles)
That's my room and that's the nursery.
And this is your room.
- Lily?
Lily?
- Were you wanting me, Mr. Fielding?
- Is there anyone else in
this house called Lily?
Why hasn't this room been done?
- Hasn't it?
- When?
Last year?
- Well, I'll...
I'll go and get the sweeper.
- Do you know how to run
a house, Miss Howard?
- Yes, of course.
- I wish you'd run this one.
A cheerful view, isn't it?
- [Liz] Cheerful?
- That's the Tygarth place.
It's been boarded up for 12 years.
Around here we call it
the Commodore's Folly.
I used to work for the old devil once.
This is Ellen's room.
Come on in here you two,
and say how do you do to Miss Howard.
This is my little girl.
- Hello, Ellen.
- Hello.
- Barney?
- This is Dumbo.
- Hello, Dumbo.
- [David] Barney?
- Barney's a very disobedient boy.
- [Liz] Really?
- Mm hm.
- What are you doing, son?
Playing hard to get?
Come on, let's go out and be friends.
- Don't want to.
- Come on, she's all right.
Let's give her a chance.
- This is Teddy, and this is Virginia May.
- This is Barney.
- How do you do Barney?
- Well, I'll leave you to get acquainted.
I'll be downstairs if you need me.
- Maxine was prettier.
- Maxine was mean.
She wouldn't do my curls.
- And who is Maxine?
- Maxine's our governess.
She's coming back.
She told me so.
- I'm glad you're going to
live with us, Miss Howard.
I like you.
- Well, I hope you're
both going to like me.
(door closes)
- Would you like to see
my scrapbook, Miss Howard?
- I'd like to very much.
♪ There'll be some changes made ♪
- Barney's always playing that old record.
Maxine gave it to him.
Look, that's Donald Duck.
(Liz chuckles)
And that's Dopey,
and that's Grumpy, the cross one.
Snow White.
Isn't she pretty?
- She's lovely.
- He was in love with her.
- He was?
- Mm hm.
- And what's this Ellen?
- Salem Alley.
That's Alberta.
- [Liz] Alberta?
- That's her there.
She's dead.
The man from the empty
house isn't in the picture.
- [Liz] What man?
- The man from the empty house.
He lives next door in there,
and he just goes out at night.
- Nobody lives in there, Ellen.
- Oh, yes he does.
Truly he does.
He comes into our house, too.
Barney's seen him, and
he hasn't got a face.
- [Liz] Well, that's silly, Ellen.
Barney was just telling you
a story to frighten you.
- I never did!
- Oh, what a fib.
He did so, Miss Howard.
- [Barney] Did not.
- You did so.
You know what he told me?
- You shut up!
You just talk and talk.
(door closes)
(big band music playing)
- Ellen, if you'll get your curlers ready,
I'll put your hair up.
- Oh, will you, will
you really, Miss Howard?
♪ Never do ♪
♪ When you grow old you don't last long ♪
♪ You're here today and
then tomorrow you're gone ♪
(music stops)
- Do you mind if we turn
this off for a minute?
- Let it alone.
- What's the matter, Barney?
Won't you tell me?
- I want Maxine to come back.
I love her.
- That's all right.
There's no reason why you
shouldn't love Maxine,
but can't we be friends too?
- Why did you come here?
We don't want you here.
You're my enemy.
I hate you.
♪ There'll be some changes made today ♪
♪ There'll be some changes made ♪
(gentle music)
(paper rustling)
(anticipatory music)
- [Charles] Yes, yes.
Yeah, I know, yes.
- [Liz] Oh, excuse me.
- Oh, please don't go.
But I saw her two hours ago.
What's the matter with her now?
I see.
Well, hold on a minute, will you?
You're looking for David?
- [Liz] Yes.
- I thought the house looked
a little brighter this evening.
You're the new governess?
- Yes.
- Well, Dave is in the living room
with a creature named Goodwin.
- Well, if Mr. Fielding has company, I'll-
- Oh, I'd hardly call Goodwin company.
He's one of the local pests.
Oh, you go on, I'll join you.
Huh?
Yeah, well you better phone her
and tell her I'll drop round
about 9:30 to put her to bed.
- Besides this other
place being more modern
and easier on servants.
Not near the shipyard too.
- [David] Oh, come in.
This is Mr. Goodwin, Miss Howard.
- How do?
- [David] Sit down, won't you?
I'll be through in just a moment.
Look, it takes me exactly 10
minutes to get to the shipyard.
- You understand, Mr. Fielding,
I'm just looking out for your interests.
If you'd listened to me,
you would've gotten rid
of this house long ago.
It's gloomy, it's damp.
It's old fashioned.
- It's full of cockroaches,
the roof's falling in and
the plumbing's coming apart.
- This is a private conversation
if you don't mind, Dr. Evans.
- Why wouldn't I mind?
I was asked here for a game of cribbage.
- You understand, Mr. Fielding,
it's of no consequence to
me one way or the other.
- Except for your commission.
- Just a minute now, Dr. Evans.
In the whole 15 years I've
been in business in this town,
have I ever let a commission
get between me and a client?
- I wouldn't know.
I haven't been watching you.
- Night all.
- [David] Goodnight, Goodwin.
- You're pretty.
The last one was pretty, too.
- Subtle little fellow, isn't he?
What's he up to this time?
- You heard him.
Would you care for a drink, Miss Howard?
- Thank you, I don't drink.
- Well, you don't have
to make a virtue of it.
- Well, why not?
It's a refreshing touch around here.
- Is it?
Oh, you two haven't met?
- [Liz] Yes, we have.
- In the library, quite
casually, but very pleasantly.
- How'd you make out with
the children, Miss Howard?
Everything all right?
- I think so.
Ellen and I read all
about the Cowardly Lion
and I put her hair in curlers.
- How 'bout Barney?
- Barney and I had a talk, too.
- You mean you had a talk?
Let's have it, Miss Howard.
What do you really think about Barney?
- He seems very intelligent.
- He is very intelligent.
- He's also tricky and overemotional.
If you cross him,
he'll find a way to pay you back double.
On top of that, he has a vile temper
and he's an unprincipled little liar.
- You make him sound
like a little monster.
- Do I?
I thought I made him sound like my son.
- Miss Howard has hardly been here long
enough to see the resemblance.
Don't believe a word he says.
- Oh, I don't.
Just seems so unfair.
- Does it?
You have time for another
game of cribbage, Charles?
- No, I'm afraid that I
must be getting along.
- Where too?
- To the hospital.
I have to look in on Mrs. Dexter.
- Oh, good.
You can give me a lift.
I'm going that way.
You're not the nervous sort I hope?
You'll be alone here a great deal.
- Mr. Fielding?
- Yes?
- I meant to give you this.
- Where'd you find it?
- The dressing table in my room.
- I see.
- Are you from Boston, Miss Howard?
- We lived in Sharon.
- Oh, well then you're
used to small towns.
You won't be too bored here.
- I'm sure I won't.
- Miss Howard, if you'd
like something to read,
you'll find it right in there.
Just to help yourself.
- Thank you.
- When I'm out at night,
this light is always left on.
I'll turn it off when I come home.
- [Charles] Goodnight, Miss Howard.
- [Liz] Night.
- Goodnight.
- [Liz] Goodnight, Mr. Fielding.
(pensive music)
- Well, what did you think of her?
- Well, for once in his
life, Goodwin was right.
She is pretty, very pretty.
- That's not what I meant.
- Still, it doesn't do any harm, does it?
(engine rumbling)
(music continues)
(doorbell rings)
(anticipatory music)
- [Marian] Oh, good evening.
I'm sorry to disturb you.
I wonder if I might choose
your telephone to call a cab?
I think it's going to rain again.
- Of course.
Come in.
It's in here.
- Oh, thank you.
There are no public
telephones anywhere near here.
- Shall I call it for you?
- Oh, please do.
- I'll do it, I promise I'll do it.
She's downstairs.
She came this afternoon,
but I'll do it honestly.
- [Maxine] Be sure now Barney or I'll-
- [Barney] Cross my heart and hope to die
in a cellar full of rats.
- [Maxine] You're a good boy, Barney.
- Who is that?
Hello?
Barney, who are you talking to?
Barney, who was that?
Will you excuse me a moment?
Perhaps you better call a taxi yourself.
- I've got to go now.
That was her.
She's coming. She heard us.
(dramatic music)
(music softens)
- Who was that on the phone, Barney?
- [Barney] Who?
- Barney, I heard you.
You were talking to somebody.
You said, "I'll do it."
What did she tell you to do?
- She told me to be a good boy.
- I don't believe that, Barney.
If you wanna use the phone again,
you're to ask my permission.
Do you understand?
- Yes, Miss Howard.
- And you shouldn't be reading.
You should be asleep.
- [Barney] Yes, Miss Howard.
(gentle music)
(pensive music)
- [Liz] Did you get your cab?
- Oh, I hope you don't
mind my coming in here.
I wanted to see the back garden,
but I'm afraid it's too dark.
- Our garden?
- No, my garden.
- But I thought that-
- I'm Marian Tygarth.
- Oh, that was your father's house?
- No, the Commodore was my husband.
- Oh, I thought of him-
- As an old man?
- Well, yes.
- He was, a mean old man.
He was the meanest man I've ever known.
When he was gone, I tried to feel sorry,
but he died abroad, you know?
Does David Fielding still live here?
- [Liz] Yes.
- Is he as handsome as ever?
- Yes, he's-
- He looks younger than I do, doesn't he?
- Yes.
- He is.
Are you his second wife?
- No, I'm not Mrs.
Fielding, I'm the governess.
- Then he didn't marry
again after the accident?
- No.
(bell rings)
That must be your cab.
- Do you like it here in New Bristol?
- I've only been here a few hours.
- Oh, you're lucky.
I was born here.
I was married here.
I came to that house next door as a bride.
I was just about your age.
Now it's all I have left in the world.
(bell rings)
- Anybody call a cab?
- Oh, yes I did.
- Okay, it's here.
- Oh, it is raining.
- I'll get an umbrella.
(rain pattering)
- Look at it, sealed up like a vault.
The day before we left,
my husband had Mr. Goodwin's
men boarded up so tight
not even a ray of light to get into it.
Mr. Goodwin was the
commodore's agent, you know?
- [Liz] Yes, I've met Mr. Goodwin.
- Ladies, I'm not getting
any drier standing here.
- Oh, I'm coming.
Well, goodbye.
You've been very nice to me.
I hope to see more of you.
(door closes)
(pensive music)
(dog barking)
(anticipatory music)
- [Ellen] Miss Howard?
- Yes?
Yes, Ellen?
Still awake, dear?
- Do you always leave the door open
in between our rooms at night?
- If you want.
It's time for little girls to be asleep.
- Miss Howard, what did they call you
when you were a little girl?
- I'm afraid they called me Liz.
- May I call you Miss Liz?
- Of course you may,
beginning tomorrow morning.
Would you like Dumbo to sleep with you?
- Barney's got him.
- I'll get him for you.
(water splashing)
(intriguing music)
Is Barney taking a bath?
- Oh no, he leaves the
water running to keep awake.
You see, he's not allowed to go to sleep.
Oh, please don't say I told you, Miss Liz.
(gentle music)
(water splashing)
(splashing stops)
(dramatic music)
(gentle music)
(anticipatory music)
- Here's Dumbo, and I'll
leave the door open.
Now, go to sleep.
- Goodnight, Miss Liz.
(anticipatory music)
- [Barney] Gimme that.
I told you I needed him.
- [Ellen] Barney!
(music continues)
(water splashing)
(bright piano music playing)
(off note key chimes)
- (sighs) No dear, it's
G natural, not G sharp.
Try it again.
(playing continues)
- Bravo.
(Charles applauding)
And when did we give our first concert?
- [Liz] Soon now.
- Good afternoon.
And how is Miss Fielding today?
Cough better?
- It's entirely gone.
Thank you, Doctor.
- [Charles] That's very gratifying.
- Wanna listen to my chest?
- What would that get me?
- Ah!
- Oh, go on beat it.
You're as strong as a horse.
- A horse?
(Barney imitates horse braying)
- Stop that Barney and
go put your coat on.
Aren't you going to
finish your piece, dear?
- Yes, Miss Liz.
(bright piano music playing)
- I see you've made someone
in this house happy already.
I only hope you can do
as well for the others.
- Thank you.
- I hope you'll be happy here yourself.
- I'm sure I will.
- They need someone like you.
David isn't the easiest person
in the world to get along with.
And since his wife was killed-
(playing stops)
- I finished, Miss Liz.
- All right, dear.
Get your things on.
- That was two years ago.
He's never really got over it,
but are days when he's the
most charming man I know.
And other days he's not quite so charming.
And since you're going to be in the house,
you are to be the victim.
- [David] The victim of what, Charles?
- I wish you wouldn't
creep up on people, David,
especially when they're talking about you.
Here.
Here are your sleeping pills.
If these don't work,
I'll buy you a hammer.
- Come on, Chip,
(Chip barks)
we're going out.
- Wait for me!
- I can run faster than
anybody in the world.
I can run faster than you can.
- No, you can't!
- Where are the children going?
- I'm taking them for a walk.
- How 'bout a game this evening?
- I'm dining out.
If I get home early, I'll call you.
- [Ellen] "Slayer's still at large."
- Ellen!
- "No clues say police in brutal murder."
- Give that to me.
- I'm afraid this is
one of those other days.
Have a good time.
♪ Step on a crack ♪
♪ Break your mother's back ♪
- Barney!
♪ Step on a crack ♪
♪ Break your mother's back ♪
Barney, Daddy told you never to say that!
He did, Miss Liz.
- Sneak!
- He's just impossible.
- Hello.
- Well, well, the whole family.
Good afternoon.
- Come on, Chip.
- Out seeing our little town?
- Yes, the children are showing me around.
- Not very much to see, I'm afraid.
Not at first.
You have to have lived here.
You have to know things about people.
- I'm not very inquisitive, Mr. Goodwin.
- Aren't you?
I am. In my business, I have to be.
- Barney, wait for me!
- Now, take that young lady I
mentioned to you last night.
- Barney!
- She was pretty all right, but
I could see she was trouble.
- Excuse me, Mr. Goodwin.
- Don't walk too far.
- Look, Mounties.
Can we go?
Can we see the movie?
- I don't know, it's after four.
- [Ellen] Oh, please Miss Liz.
Let's see the movie.
- I didn't bring any money.
- Barney's got money.
- [Liz] Not that much.
- I have too, look.
- That is a lot of money.
Did you open your bank?
- No.
- It's his wages.
- Wages?
Barney, where did you get so much money?
- [Barney] Oh, I had it.
(Ellen gasps)
Three, please.
- I'll give it back to you,
Barney, when we get home.
- Sonny, you can take that dog in there.
Leave him with the usher as you go in.
- [Barney] Oh, gee.
(bell dings)
(horn honking)
("Popeye" theme song playing)
- Where's Barney?
- [Ellen] He went out.
- When?
- [Ellen] He's probably calling her again.
- Come on, Ellen.
- [Ellen] Oh, please, Miss Liz.
- Shh, shh!
- Come along.
- Yes, I do.
Tell me again, quick.
I'll do it.
Cross my heart, I'll do my best.
I did tell her to go away.
Please, please, I've got to go now.
She's coming.
Hello.
- What did I tell you about
telephone calls, Barney?
- I wasn't calling anybody.
- You were too, and I know who.
- You shut your big mouth.
Come on, Chip.
- We'll have to hurry.
It's getting late.
(pensive music)
Barney, I thought you
said you knew the way?
Barney, it's so late and
we're nowhere near home.
- Yes, we are.
This is a shortcut.
- Barney, you're sure?
- Right down here.
It comes out near the house.
- Oh, Miss Liz, he's-
- Yes, Ellen, what were you saying?
- Nothing, Miss Liz.
(dramatic music)
It's dark and I'm scared.
- Shh, darling.
There's nothing to be afraid of.
- There is too, Miss Liz.
He's up to something, I know he is.
- Barney, where are we?
What is this street?
- We're in Salem Alley.
- Salem Alley?
Barney, come back here.
There's nothing to be afraid of.
You brought us here and
we're going through.
Come on, children.
(eerie music)
- It's him, he's out for us!
(dramatic music)
(music softens)
Open the door, let us in.
Hurry, hurry! Quick!
(Ellen speaking indistinctly)
(fists banging)
- Close the door, Dad,
close the door!
- Faster, faster!
- What happened?
The children are scared to death.
- We were walking through Salem Alley.
- Salem Alley?
What for?
- [Liz] To get home.
- But it's clear outta your way.
- [Liz] But I didn't know that.
- Well, you know what
happened there, don't you?
- A woman was murdered.
- Is that a place to take children?
- I didn't take them, they took me.
- [David] I see.
- Mr. Fielding?
- Yes?
- I'm trying to do my best for them,
but you have to help me.
- [David] How?
- How much pocket money
do you give Barney?
- A quarter a week if he
brushes his teeth regularly,
and he lives right up to his income.
- Quarter a week?
- Perhaps you don't think that's enough?
- Of course, only-
- Only what?
- Why did you discharge Maxine?
- She was a bad influence on the children
and she took too much interest
in my private affairs.
Satisfied?
- Barney still telephones her.
- [David] Why don't you stop him?
- I told him not to do it again.
- Well, see that he obeys you.
And from now on, suppose you
keep your mind on the children
and off things that don't concern you.
Goodnight.
I said Goodnight, Miss Howard.
(anticipatory music)
(engine rumbling)
(door opens)
- Mr. Fielding?
Mr. Fielding?
(mysterious music)
(music continues)
(footsteps scuffling)
(suspenseful music)
- [Chester] You got beer?
- Beer?
(flashlight clicks)
- [Chester] The other one gave me beer.
- Who are you?
- Smoke?
I'm Chester.
- Were you...
Are you the man I saw in
the garden last night?
- [Charles] Sure.
I'm here every night.
I fix the furnace.
- Oh.
- And I fix it good.
You tell that cook if she
leaves the damper open again,
I'll get mad.
I'll break something.
Hm?
You tell her?
- Yes, I'll tell her.
- [Charles] What are you scared for?
I'm a nice guy.
(Chester spits)
Ask Maxine.
She knows.
Next time beer, hm?
(soft music)
(door closes)
(music stops abruptly)
(pensive music)
(objects crashing)
(music continues)
(stone thuds)
(light music)
- [Liz] Mr. Fielding,
would you like some...
(music continues)
Oh!
- What's the matter?
- You startled me.
I didn't expect to see you.
- I live here, remember?
- Why yes, but-
(David sniffing)
- Coffee.
Who's the second cup for?
- For you.
- Great, I'm starved.
We had squab for dinner, wharf squab.
And some awful dessert
with lemon jelly in it.
- I thought you'd gone upstairs.
- Expect me to go to
bed with the children?
- Of course not, but...
(sighs) That's not the way to carve.
- Yeah, well, it's this knife.
- Are you sure it's the knife?
- You try it.
Oh, well, you carve it on the side.
- You think that's unfair (chuckles)?
- I wasn't very civil
to you this afternoon.
- [Liz] No, you weren't.
- Sorry.
- Well, I don't blame you.
I must seemed a little silly rushing in
that way after the children.
- Well, I didn't have to growl at you.
- [Liz] Why not if you felt like growling?
- Dr. Evans was right.
This house does need somebody like you.
Needs you very much.
- Thank you.
- You know, I almost sent you
back to Boston yesterday.
- Why didn't you?
- Well, I guess I liked
the way you talked.
It sounded like the truth.
- You mean because I told you I was fired?
- Mm hm.
And the way you spoke up
for Barney last night.
I like that too.
I like your smile, the way
your hair falls outta place.
I even like the way you carve.
(swelling orchestral music)
What have I done now?
- Oh, nothing.
I just wondered why you
had your overcoat on.
- Well, it's cold outside.
How's the coffee coming?
- I'll see.
It's gone.
- What's gone?
- [Liz] It was here under this.
- What was where under what?
- A 50 cent piece under the shaker.
I thought it was left for
the milkman or somebody.
- Well, don't look at me.
I didn't take it.
- But it was here just before
I went down to the cellar.
- What were you doing in the cellar?
- I heard a noise.
- What sort of a noise?
- I'm trying to tell you.
I heard something so I made
myself go down and look.
Then when I saw what it was-
- Is there any reason
why you shouldn't tell me
what you're talking about?
- I'll show you what I'm talking about.
It's not there anymore.
The coal was all over the floor.
That was the noise I heard,
one of the sacks falling.
- Chester cleaned it up.
- Chester had already gone.
- He must have come back.
- He couldn't.
I'd have seen him come in.
- [David] You didn't
see me come in, did you?
- I heard you in the front hall.
I called down to you.
- But I came in through the garage.
I wasn't even near the front hall.
- Then who put out the light?
- Perhaps I forgot to turn it on it.
- It was on when you left, I saw it.
- Maybe the bulb went out.
- Mr. Fielding, I heard
someone come in the front way.
- [David] You seem to have
heard a lot of things tonight.
- I haven't heard anything
that wasn't there.
I tell you, someone's been
in this house tonight.
- Do you have these
hallucinations often, Miss Howard?
- [Liz] Will you stop treating
me like a mental case?
- Then stop acting like one.
- Why won't you believe me?
I'm telling you the truth.
I'm frightened.
- I think you'd better
stop talking nonsense
and pull yourself together.
- I see.
Very well, goodnight.
I said goodnight, Mr. Fielding.
(train rattling)
(Barney imitates train horn blaring)
- Now look what you've done!
You've wrecked my train.
(Barney imitates train horn blaring)
You're a nasty, destructive little boy.
- Ellen!
- He is, Miss Liz.
He's killed all my passengers.
- I wanna talk to you.
- Yes, Miss Liz?
- Ellen, what was the name of
the woman in your scrapbook?
- Snow White.
- Not Snow White, dear.
The other one.
- I don't know, Miss Liz.
- [Liz] Ellen, bring me
your scrapbook, please.
- Here it is, Miss Liz.
- Thank you.
(Barney imitates train horn blaring)
Where is the picture of Salem Alley?
You've torn it out.
(Barney imitates train horn blaring)
Barney, be quiet and stop that train.
Ellen, what was the name of
the woman in that picture?
And don't pretend you don't know.
- Her name was-
- She doesn't know her name.
- [Liz] Yes, she does.
So do you, Barney.
- I don't either.
- Ellen, you told me her name was Alberta.
- [Barney] She made it up.
She's always making things up.
- Barney, I'm talking to Ellen.
Ellen, you didn't make it up, did you?
- Yes, I did, Miss Liz.
I made it all up out of my own head.
- Go to your room,
Ellen, and shut the door.
I'm very angry with you both.
You're not to talk to each
other nor play together.
- Miss Liz?
- [Liz] Yes?
- Aren't we friends anymore?
- [Liz] Not until you tell me the truth.
(door closes)
- She did make it up.
- Did she?
♪ Nobody wants you to know ♪
♪ There'll be some changes made today ♪
♪ There'll be some changes made ♪
Oh, Mrs. Norris?
- You want me?
- Would you keep an eye on the children?
- Yes.
- I'm going over to talk to the doctor.
The number's 23, isn't it?
- Across the crescent,
first house on the left.
Be gone long?
- Just a few minutes.
- I hope so.
I don't reckon to be here after dark.
Not the way things are.
- What do you mean, Mrs. Norris?
- You ought to know.
Just get back before dark, that's all.
- Oh, I will.
- You must remember that David's children
have been left to
themselves more than most.
It was an unhappy marriage
and had a tragic ending.
Since then, they've seen much
too little of their father.
Now, next door to them is this
huge empty, shuttered house.
Do you wonder that it fascinates them?
That they make it the setting
for whatever play story
they happen to be acting
out at the moment?
- They weren't acting
yesterday in Salem Alley.
They were terrified,
and those telephone
calls were real enough,
and that murder's real.
- Yes, it is.
- [Liz] And they knew that
dead woman's name two days
before it was in the paper.
Can you explain that?
- No, I'm afraid I can't.
What does David think?
I suppose you told him.
- I tried to tell him what
happened last night, but-
- He wasn't very helpful, eh?
Would you like me to talk to him?
- No, please don't.
I'd much rather you didn't.
- Oh, come now.
David is not that unreasonable.
(Miss Budge knocks)
Yeah?
- Excuse me, Doctor.
- Yes, Miss Budge?
- Miss Gardner is still waiting
and Mr. Ellis has an appointment for 4:30.
- [Charles] Thank you.
- I'm sorry, I shouldn't
have kept you so long.
- That's quite all right.
- I think I've told you all there is.
- I'm afraid I haven't been very helpful.
- You've been very kind.
I don't think even you
realise how worried I am.
Last night I almost thought
of calling the police.
- The police?
I hope you didn't mention that to David.
- No.
- In your place,
it's the last thing I'd do,
before consulting David that is.
- Oh, I wouldn't really.
It's just that I, I
didn't know where to turn.
- I know we all feel that way at times.
If it happens again, I wish you'd call me.
Miss Budge, if Miss Howard
phones when I'm not here
I want you to get in
touch with me immediately.
- Yes, Doctor.
- Goodbye, Miss Howard.
- Thank you, Doctor.
Goodbye.
- Can't figure why you'd be
gettin' sentimental all of a sudden.
- But can't they put it
off just for a few days?
- I think they wouldn't.
I wouldn't care to ask him.
(light music playing)
- Oh, Miss Howard?
Good afternoon.
- Well, how do you do?
- You are not ill, I hope?
- No.
- I just wondered seeing you
come out from the doctors.
How's David?
- Mr. Fielding's quite well, thank you.
- You might tell him I'm
a little annoyed with him
for not coming to see me.
We used to be such good friends, you know?
(light music playing)
Mr. Goodwin is handling
the opening of my house.
- You're opening it?
- I have to.
That's why I came back from abroad.
I hate that tune.
Stop playing that.
Please stop it at once.
Here.
Go and play somewhere else.
- Thank you.
- I just can't bear that tune.
Somebody was playing it,
I heard it coming across the garden
the night the Commodore died.
- Well, goodbye, Mrs. Tygarth.
- Oh, there you are.
I thought you were never coming.
- I'm sorry, Mrs. Norris.
- Well, it's happened.
- What's happened?
- She's gone.
- What are you talking about?
- That Lily? I just looked in her room.
- But this is her day off.
- Her day off, is it?
She's moved out back in baggage.
- You mean she isn't coming back?
- What do you think I mean?
What's more unless you get
somebody to take her place,
I'm not coming back either.
- But Mrs. Norris, you can't do that.
You can't leave me all
alone in this house.
- Can't I?
If you had any sense, you'd go too.
- And leave the children?
- That's your business.
Seen this?
- Yes, I've seen it.
- A day worker like me lying all alone
in the gutter with a broken neck.
- Mrs. Norris, please come back.
- I'll come back when
you get a maid, maybe.
- I'll call the agency the
first thing in the morning.
- You'd better.
(pensive music)
(light music)
- Miss Liz?
Miss Liz?
Please don't be mad anymore.
- I'm not mad at you, Ellen,
but I can't talk to you
until you tell me the truth.
- I'll tell you, Miss Liz.
I'll tell you how I knew her name.
It was in the watch.
- In the watch?
- Mm hm.
Barney found it outside on the steps
after the woman ran away.
He hid it in that drawer there.
- Come on, dear.
You must go back to bed.
- Can't I stay here with you, Miss Liz?
- Hm mm.
- Aren't we friends again?
- Yes, of course we're friends.
Now you have to be a good
girl and go to sleep.
It's very late.
- [Ellen] I'm not tired.
- You'll go to sleep all right.
Barney's in there sleeping
like a little door mouse.
- Barney doesn't have
to stay awake tonight.
He's earned his wages.
- Ellen, Ellen, how does
Barney earn his wages?
- He opens the front door
so the man from the
empty house can come in.
Maxine tells him when.
After he's opened the door,
he puts Dumbo in the window.
- All right, dear.
Now let's forget all about that
for tonight and go to sleep.
(suspenseful music)
(anticipatory music)
(music intensifies)
(dramatic music)
(Liz gasping)
(footsteps approaching)
(doorknob rattling)
(unsettling music)
(anticipatory music)
(dial spinning)
- Hello?
Miss Howard?
Yes, he just got back from the hospital.
- Would you ask him to come over?
It's very important.
Thank you.
(dramatic music)
- Did you find what you were looking for?
I see you did find it.
- It has her name in it.
- Really?
- The woman who was murdered.
- You're quite a detective, aren't you?
- Barney found it outside this house.
- [David] I don't like people
prying into my affairs.
I told you that.
- He found it the night she was killed.
- And I won't have you
or anyone else going through my desk.
I thought I made that clear, too.
Now, give it to me.
I said give it to me.
(doorbell ringing)
- Hello.
- What are you doing here?
- You all right, Miss Howard?
- What makes you think she isn't?
- Well, when a doctor gets called
in the middle of the night,
he usually assumes that
something is not all right.
You did call, didn't you?
- If she did, she seems
to have forgotten why.
- What is this, a game?
- Perhaps Miss Howard was
nervous in the house alone
and wanted someone to talk to,
or maybe she had something to show you.
Was that it?
- No.
- While I was out, she made a discovery,
didn't you, Miss Howard?
You wouldn't want the doctor
to make a trip for nothing.
Show him what you found.
- What is it, Miss Howard?
You did send for me, you know?
- [David] Go on, show it to him.
- Leave me alone, both of you.
- Jumpy, isn't she?
What would you suggest?
- Don't be a fool, David.
Now, if either one of you
has another brainstorm before morning,
please leave me out of it.
Goodnight.
- Well, you called him and he came.
You satisfied?
Can't you say anything at all?
- I haven't anything to say,
except I'm sorry I opened your desk.
Here's your watch.
And why did you pretend not to
believe me last night
when I told you somebody
had come into this house?
- Do you think I was pretending?
- You said you hadn't
been near the front hall,
I don't believe that.
And the door was open again tonight
and I know now who opened it.
Barney did.
- So you think my little boy's
letting me into my own house?
- He doesn't know who he's letting in.
- But you do?
Is that what you were thinking
when Charles was here?
Is that why you didn't show him the watch?
Answer me.
- You know why.
- Elizabeth-
- Leave me alone, can't you?
(swelling orchestral music)
- So this is what it was all about.
- That name mean anything to you?
- Oh yes, David.
I read the papers.
- Barney found it.
- Where?
- In front of the house.
What am I gonna do with it?
- Only one thing you can do with it.
Take it to the police.
- No, I won't do that.
- [Charles] You'll have to, David.
They're going to find out.
- Not unless someone tells them.
- Somebody always does tell them.
- She's dead, isn't she?
She doesn't need her watch anymore.
I don't want them swarming
over the place questioning
everyone, even the children.
I don't want anything more
to do with the police.
- Why go back to all that?
That's over and done with.
- It's never done with
once you've seen it happen.
I've seen her lying there
beside the road dead
with her head hanging limp.
- [Charles] Everyone knew
that was an accident.
- What makes you so sure?
The police weren't.
- They don't know you
as well as I do, David.
Come on, let's forget it.
Here, this is what you need.
Maybe you'd better let me give
that watch to the police.
I can say I found it.
- It wouldn't work.
You said yourself, they always find out.
(gentle music)
(bell rings)
- [Sullivan] How do you do?
Is Mr. Fielding in?
- I'm sorry, he isn't.
- [?] Be back soon, won't he?
- Well, I don't know.
- [?] I'll wait.
- Does Mr. Fielding know you?
- Yes, he knows me.
I'll wait in the library.
(intriguing music)
(phone ringing)
- Hello, hello?
Yes.
Yes, this is the Fielding house.
Oh, you wanna speak to Miss Howard?
- Barney?
How many times do I have to tell you
to stay away from the telephone?
- It's for you.
It's the agency.
- This is Miss Howard.
Not until this afternoon?
But please do the best you can.
We need a made as soon as possible.
Thank you.
Goodbye.
- Good morning, Mr. Fielding.
Guess you know why I'm here.
- Do I?
- I'm working on the Salem Alley murder.
We got a phone call about that watch.
Any particular reason why
you didn't bring it in?
- Suppose I haven't got it.
- I heard different.
Come on, Mr. Fielding.
You can't withhold
evidence from the police.
You ought to know that
better than most people.
- I know what police evidence
is worth better than most people.
You taught me that, Sullivan.
- Did I?
Well, your wife's death
had to be investigated. Mr. Fielding,
just like any other death,
for such things as planned
accidents, dark nights,
a road is slick, there's a fog,
car goes over an embankment.
This woman in Salem Alley,
her neck was broken, too.
All she did was fall off the
sidewalk into the gutter.
Well, that couldn't have been an accident.
Could it?
- Why ask me?
You don't think I knew this woman, do you?
I never saw her alive or dead.
- It's possible.
It's the same.
You had her watch.
According to my information.
- Maybe you better check your information.
- Okay, Mr. Fielding.
Don't ever think I won't.
When I do, I'll be back.
- Sure, anytime.
Just break a window and climb in.
- No, I won't do that.
I'll just ring the bell and
somebody will let me in,
just like they did this time.
Bye.
- Mr. Fielding-
- I guess he was right at that.
- Well, I couldn't very-
- Forget it.
How soon can you pack
and be ready to leave?
- Leave?
- Yes, I wanna get Barney and
Ellen outta here right away.
You might have thought a
little about the children
before you called the police.
There's a train at 8:20.
- Very well, we'll be ready.
David?
- Yes?
- Do you really think I called the police?
- What do you expect me to think?
- I'm not going to Grandma's.
- You are too!
- I'm not going anywhere.
- Isn't he difficult, Miss Liz?
- Oh, he's just being silly.
Of course he'll go.
- When we get there. We can ride the pony.
- Has Grandma got a pony?
- It's my pony.
She gave it to me and I
ride him every morning.
(bell rings)
Shall I open it?
- No, I'll go.
- He's my pony too.
Grandma said I could ride him.
- Good afternoon.
Is this the fielding house?
- Yes.
- You're looking for a
general house worker?
- Won't you come in?
- You go upstairs, children.
Start packing.
I'll be with you in a moment.
- Yes, Miss Howard.
- Did you bring references?
- I've never done housework before.
I worked in an office and
then my eyes went bad on me.
- We need somebody to clean and serve.
- Then it's no use.
I couldn't serve.
- Perhaps you won't need to.
There won't be much to do.
Mr. Fielding will be alone
in the house for a few days.
Would you like to try it?
- I might as well.
- What's your name?
- Mary Saunders.
- I'll show you your room.
- Ouch.
Ouch, Barney, you're hurting me.
- Then promise you won't tell.
- I promise.
- Say it.
Say, "I promise, cross my heart,
and hope to die in a cell full of rats."
- I promise, cross my heart and hope
to die in a cellar full of rats.
- David, I have to talk to you.
- Here are the tickets.
I've wired my mother you're coming.
I'll drive you to the train.
- David-
- You'll like my mother.
She'll try and spoil you the
way she does the children.
Be quite a change for you
after what you've gone
through in this house.
- David, listen to me.
I didn't call the police.
- It's all right.
- It isn't all right.
I won't have you thinking that about me.
- Why should you care? What I think?
- But I do care.
(phone ringing)
And what I said last
night, David, wasn't true.
It can't be.
- Hello?
Well, this is Mr. Fielding.
What?
Maybe tomorrow?
Yes, I'll tell Miss Howard.
Right.
- Who was that?
- The employment agency.
Something about a maid they
haven't been able to send.
- They haven't sent anybody?
- Or what's the matter?
- Then how did that girl...
David, what does Maxine look like?
- Maxine?
- You were a good boy
to call me about Lily.
You sure you haven't told anyone Barney?
- I didn't see it work to
anybody, cross my heart.
- You were a good boy.
- Ellen told something.
- Ellen?
What did she say?
- [Barney] Told about the watch.
- What watch, Barney?
- The one the old woman dropped.
I saw her and I saw him run after her too.
The man from the empty house,
that was him who killed her.
- Killed her?
Barney, you didn't see that?
- Did so.
He came out of our house and chased her,
honest he did.
(David knocking)
- Go to your room, Barney.
- So, you did tell him I was here?
- Come on Son, out.
I thought I told you to
stay away from this house.
- Yes.
I like your house.
- I'll give you just five
minutes to get out of it.
- What's the hurry?
You need help, don't you?
The new governess said so.
Not bad is she?
- Come on, get your things together.
Is this all you brought?
- I wasn't intending to stay.
I just dropped in to look around.
I'm a girl that likes
to know what goes on.
- You've done all the
looking around you're
gonna do in this house.
- Maybe. I've done all I need to.
You'd be surprised what I've
got out of this little visit.
The nice thing about information is,
there are such a lot of
things you can do with it,
besides giving it to the cops.
- Well, look out you
don't cut your with it.
Now, get out.
- I'll go when I'm ready.
(dramatic music)
(dial spinning)
- Miss Liz, What I do?
This bag won't close.
- All right, dear, I'll help you.
(anticipatory music)
- Maxine, don't go.
I don't want you to go.
- Get outta my way, tattletale.
- You said I was a good boy.
I told you I would chase the old woman.
- You shut your big mouth.
- I did too, see me come
outta her house and chase-
- Shut up!
- Barney-
- I did everything she told me.
I opened the door for him every night.
I was a good boy, and then she hit me.
- Oh, please don't cry, Barney.
Go to your room dear and
wait 'til I come back...
- She's my enemy.
I hate her.
- David?
(dramatic music)
Maxine?
(music intensifies)
(dramatic music)
(music continues)
Open up, Dr. Evans!
(fists pounding)
- Miss Howard, whatever's the matter?
- She's lying out there.
She's dead!
- Who?
What do you mean?
- Miss Howard, what is it?
What are you talking about?
- I knew something would happen.
He wouldn't listen.
No one would listen to me-
- Stop that!
Now, try and tell me what happened?
- He's killed Maxine.
She's lying out there.
- Okay.
- Know anybody who had it
in for this dame, Doctor?
- I hardly knew her.
- I did.
You seen Fielding around?
- No, why?
- I just asked.
- Don't be a fool, Sullivan.
- Is that what I am?
(brakes squealing)
(engine rumbling)
(doorbell rings)
Mr. Fielding, please.
- [Liz] He went out.
- You know where I can find him?
It's important.
- [Liz] No.
- When did he go out?
- Quite awhile ago.
- [Sullivan] Could you be a
little more definite, please?
- An hour at least.
- Thank you.
(soft music)
- Can we go to Grandma's tomorrow?
- Yes, dear.
Now, go to sleep.
Goodnight.
- Goodnight, Miss Liz.
- Miss Liz?
- [Liz] Yes, Barney?
- You're not my enemy anymore.
- I never was.
You should have known that.
- I'm a bad boy.
- No, you're not.
- Yes, I am.
I'm as bad as I can be.
- Oh, Barney,
- [Charles] Miss Howard?
- Try to go to sleep now, Barney.
- [Charles] Can you come down, please?
- [Liz] Yes, Doctor.
- Did you check all the
windows and the back door?
- Yes, Doctor.
Everything's locked.
- All right, Budge, you
better get back to the office.
- Yes, Doctor.
- Still no sign of David?
- No.
I wish I knew where he was.
- Oh, don't worry.
I can give the police all
the information they need,
and they have till tomorrow.
Mrs. Tygarth is here.
She insisted on coming over.
- You poor dear.
If I'd known you were here
alone, I'd have come sooner.
- Oh, stop fussing, Marian.
Miss Howard will be all right, won't you?
- Yes, thank you.
- Good girl.
You'd better bolt this door.
I'll look in later.
- [Liz] It's so quiet out there now.
And just a little while ago, she-
- [Marian] Close the door, dear.
Try not to think about it.
- It was kind of you
to come, Mrs. Tygarth.
- I was only too glad to.
- There's a fire in the living room.
- Oh, how nice.
It's turned quite cold tonight.
- If only I could have
gotten to her sooner.
- No, please, my dear.
- He must have been
waiting out there for her,
if only she had told somebody who he was.
- You mustn't talk about it anymore.
Why, what a lovely fire.
Nice and cosy in here.
I always did like this house
when I lived next door.
12 years is a long time, isn't it?
- Yes, it is.
(coins clinking)
- You're still worrying, aren't you?
- Yes, I suppose I am.
- It's about the children, isn't it?
Don't you want to go up and
see if they're all right?
- No, I'm sure they're asleep.
- Oh, well do go.
You mustn't treat me
like company, my dear.
(phone ringing)
You better answer that.
It might be David.
(anticipatory music)
(ringing continues)
(music continues)
(music intensifies)
- I'm going to give him back my wages.
- Do you know where he is?
- No.
- Then how will you
give him back his money?
- I'm going to leave it
for him in the empty house.
(music continues)
(dramatic music)
(light piano music playing)
- Was it David?
- No, it wasn't.
That's the tune the
hurdy-gurdy was playing.
But I thought you said you hated it.
- Oh (chuckles), I was just being silly.
It's really a lovely old tune.
Do you know it?
- I haven't played it in ages.
(light piano music playing)
Now I remember it.
- That's it.
Please play the rest of it.
(playing continues)
That's lovely, my dear.
Even though it does bring
back that last night,
my husband and I had
been quarrelling all day.
It was horrible.
And all day the sound of
the hammering had gone on.
- Hammering?
(playing stops)
- Oh, please go on playing.
They were boarding up the windows.
We were leaving early in the morning.
The Commodore had sent the servants away.
It was almost as though
he'd planned it himself.
The next morning I locked up the house
and said that my husband
had gone on ahead.
- But Mrs. Tygarth, didn't you tell me
your husband had died abroad?
- How could he?
He never went abroad.
He never went away at all.
He died in that house,
and the man who killed
him is in there now.
(playing stops)
Don't stop, even for a moment.
I told him I'd keep you playing.
If that piano stops,
he'll start back here.
He'll kill us, the way
he killed the others.
(playing continues)
The murderer's never sure.
He had to go back just once more.
And tonight was his last chance.
He made me help him.
He thinks I wouldn't dare give him away.
He thinks I'm afraid.
He'll find out how afraid I am.
Keep right on playing.
I'm going to call the police.
It's our only chance,
the only way to keep him
in there until they come.
(playing continues)
(pensive music)
(music continues)
(playing continues)
(suspenseful music)
- Miss Liz?
- Ellen, what are you doing here?
- I'm lonely.
- [Liz] Where's Barney?
- He's gone to the empty house.
- The empty house?
Are you sure?
- Mm hm.
- Sit down, Ellen.
Now play your piece, the
one you play so nicely.
- Yes, Miss Liz.
(light piano music playing)
- That's right, dear.
Now, just keep on playing
until I come back.
(pensive music)
(playing continues)
(music intensifies)
- Blood isn't so easy to get rid of is it?
Even after 12 years.
But you've done it, haven't you?
It's all gone.
Every trace of it.
And when they open these windows tomorrow,
nobody will ever dream
that an old man was murdered in this room.
It was worth coming back for, wasn't it?
One last time to be
sure, to feel quite safe.
You'd feel even safer if you killed me
the way you killed that old woman
when she saw you come out of here
and that girl tonight
because she knew too much.
I'd be next, I suppose.
Well, it isn't going to be like that.
They're going to find you
here with this gun beside you
and that'll tell them
all they need to know.
Take that light-
(shots firing)
(dramatic music)
(Liz blows)
(music continues)
- Barney?
- He's after me, run!
Run!
(dramatic music)
- [Liz] Barney, Barney?
- [Barney] Don't stop.
He'll catch us!
- Barney, Barney!
- He's got a gun.
He'll kill us!
(playing continues)
- [Liz] Ellen!
Ellen, come up here at once!
(pensive music)
- He was after me, I saw him.
- You saw him?
- I saw him just as clear as clear.
- Barney, tell me who is he?
- Miss Howard?
Miss Howard?
What's this door doing open?
I told you to bolt it.
- [Liz] But I did bold it.
- Who opened it then?
David?
Where's Mrs. Tygarth?
Have you you lost your tongue?
Where is she?
(pensive music)
You mean the man who killed
her husband in that house?
- And then she said she was
going to call the police,
but she couldn't have could
she, or they'd be here.
- I'll soon find out.
(dramatic music)
I see.
She didn't call them.
Yes, I know you are.
Well, you'd better get
out here right away.
They're looking for David.
- They're wrong, Dr. Evans.
It can't be.
- Can't it?
I wish it weren't.
I wish it even more than you do.
- [Liz] David?
- I'd like to speak to Dr. Evans, alone.
Please.
- They're looking for you.
- Yes, I know.
Tonight when I saw Sullivan coming
toward this house, I knew what he wanted.
Well, it looks as if
he was going to get it,
doesn't it, Charles?
- Does it?
- You can hide a thing for
just so long, can't you?
And then they find out.
Someone always tells them.
You said that yourself, remember?
- Yes, I remember.
- Here.
Coal dust from the cellar.
- Cellar?
- I wasn't wearing gloves.
- So that's what you were.
- Strange, isn't it, what
fear can do to a man?
Well, not just little things
like keeping a watch from the police.
Fear could do that to
anybody, even an innocent man.
- I dare say it could.
- But if he wasn't innocent,
suppose he'd killed
someone a long time ago.
- David, what are you talking about?
- [David] You mean who am I talking about?
- I wasn't sure until now.
- I'm talking about the man
who helped Marian Tygarth
kill her husband 12 years ago.
You thought she was in love
with you didn't you, Charles?
Then when you found out
the truth, it was too late,
but at least the house
was still locked up and you were safe.
And then suddenly it's gonna be opened
with murder still in there.
And so little time, just days, then hours.
You knew Sullivan would suspect me.
You'd seen to that.
It was so easy for you to use my house,
to bribe my servant, even my little boy.
Barney, get out of here.
- Daddy.
- Go on upstairs, do you hear me?
I was in that house and heard
what Marian said before you killed her.
- [Charles] You're still the
only one that knows, David.
- [Barney] Here, here are my wages.
- Give the money to me, Son.
You're a good boy.
Now, run along.
(coins clattering)
(sirens wailing)
- Sullivan's a little late, as usual.
- About 12 years late.
(door slams)
- Well, I was the one that
called him, wasn't I David?
(bell ringing)
- Where's Fielding?
- You don't want Fielding.
(soft orchestral music)
- [Liz] David?
- It's all right now, Elizabeth.
- Daddy?
Are you coming with us to Grandmas?
- You'd better ask Miss Liz.
She's gonna have a lot to
say about things from now on.
(swelling orchestral music)
(music intensifies)