(MAN WHISTLING
"THE WHISTLER" THEME)
THE WHISTLER:
I am the Whistler.
And I know many things,
for I walk by night.
I know many strange tales hidden
in the hearts of men and women
who have stepped into the shadows.
Yes, I know the nameless terrors
of which they dare not speak.
And tonight,
at this lonely spot on a
highway near a small town,
we find an unusual birthday
celebration in full swing.
CROWD:
♪ A very merry birthday
♪ Merrier than ever before
♪ Congratulations, dear Eileen
♪ May you celebrate a hundred more
♪ A hundred more ♪
-(ALL LAUGHING)
-Thanks a lot.
It was awful sweet of you
to remember me.
Now, how could we forget
with that guy reminding us every day?
Oh, Tommy, you shouldn't have!
Why not, Mom?
It paid off, didn't it?
-(ALL LAUGHING)
-EILEEN: I really made a haul.
How about some more punch, fellas?
I don't know.
You made this pretty strong.
-Ah, that's right!
-I'll take some more, Tommy.
-EILEEN: You think you can handle it?
-I sure can.
-What did you get Eileen, Steve?
-You want to know?
-Yeah, sure, what did you get her?
-Let's take a look.
-An engagement ring.
-Wow, what a rock!
That must have set you back plenty.
-You're a lucky guy, Steve.
-You're telling me.
I'm a lucky girl.
Lucky to win a mug like that?
Are you kiddin'?
Well, anyway, we're glad you picked him
instead of that motor cop.
-You said it.
-Show us what you did, Eileen,
when Steve slipped
that ring on your finger.
-Yeah. Give us a load of that.
-Come on.
-Don't be bashful. Come on.
Well, you asked for it.
-(CHEERING)
-Oh, boy!
Well, so long honey. I...
I gotta make a delivery over at Bayview.
Be seein' ya. Bye, fellas.
So long, Steve. Good luck!
(ENGINE STARTING)
Going toward Bayview, mister?
-Yeah. Hop in.
-Thanks!
THE WHISTLER: Ordinarily, you
don't pick up hitch-hikers, Steve.
But, with a warming
drink under your belt,
and the memory of
Eileen's kiss on your lips,
you're feeling friendly
toward everybody.
It was only a moment's delay,
but those sixty seconds are going to
change the whole pattern of your life.
(TYRES SCREECHING)
Don't drive so fast, Jimmy. Please.
-Fast? Wait until I really open her up.
-Oh, no, don't. Not on these curves.
Relax. Relax.
I'm the best driver in the state.
Look out, Jimmy!
(TYRES SCREECHING)
Bayview is about seven miles
from McCabe's filling station.
But where's McCabe's filling station?
(CHUCKLING)
Oh, it's just around the bend here.
-MACK: Hello, Don.
-Hiya, Mack.
How's tricks?
Everything's under control.
I'm ready to call it quits for tonight.
(PHONE PINGING)
-(HORN HONKING)
-Jimmy!
No, no accidents.
(CRASHING)
Correction.
A truck just ploughed into
McCabe's gas station. I'll call you back.
Nice going, Steve.
Oh, hello, Don.
Well, how did it happen?
I tried to keep from hitting that car.
It was coming right at me.
What car?
Coming round that curve.
On my side of the road, too.
Are you sure there was a car?
Well, if you don't believe it,
ask the guy that's riding with me.
What guy?
Some hitch-hiker.
He was sitting right here
beside me when I crashed.
Yeah?
I'm not lying to you.
A man was sitting there
and a car forced me off the road.
The fellow driving it
must have been drunk.
Hmm.
You're not so steady yourself.
Maybe it was you
that had one too many.
You stopped at Rockpoint to help
celebrate Eileen's birthday, didn't you?
Why, yes.
I had one drink. So what?
It's against the law for truck
drivers to drink on the job, Steve.
You know that.
If you want to be technical,
then I'm as sober as you are.
Well, you'll have to
convince the judge of that.
Maybe he'll believe
the rest of your story, too.
Are you trying to hang something on me
because I beat your time with Eileen?
If I wasn't on duty, I'd do
something about that crack.
And if you didn't have on
that uniform I'd help you do it.
Stick around till I phone in a report.
It's a fine mess.
Somebody's gonna pay for this.
-Thanks for the lift.
-Don't mention it.
-You send someone to tow in the truck?
-Yeah. Bernie.
Glad you didn't get hurt
in the crash, Steve.
But am I in a jam!
Look at that.
-"Drunk driving."
-That's what it says.
That cop's been waiting for a chance
like this. Why didn't you brain him?
Charlie, I'm in enough trouble
without socking a cop.
At least it's a good thing
you're covered by insurance.
I don't dare let McCabe file a claim.
-Why not?
-If I do...
and I'm convicted of drunk driving,
they'll cancel my policy.
-And I'm out of the trucking business.
-Well, what can you do?
There's only one thing I can do
and that's to pay off.
I guess I can borrow
some money on the trucks.
-But you just got them free and clear.
-So what?
I'll be in the red
a little while longer. That's all.
It'll be a couple of hours before
Bernie gets back.
Let's grab a cup of coffee.
Okay.
JUDGE: ...and, since the defendant
has been unable to produce
a single witness
to verify any of his statements,
the court is forced to the conclusion
that the defendant was in no condition
to drive in a safe and sane manner
on the night of September 23rd.
Steven Reynolds.
your sentence will be six months
in the county jail.
However, since this
is your first offence,
and since you've made a satisfactory
settlement with the innocent victim,
sentence is suspended,
on the condition that
your driver's licence be revoked
for the period of probation.
Next case.
Jack Sterling.
Justice, huh?
You're lucky he didn't send you to jail.
He could have, you know.
It'll be just as bad sitting around
for six months twiddling my thumbs
and paying somebody else
to drive for me.
Oh, Steve.
I hope there are no hard feelings.
I only did my duty.
Yeah.
Pleasant duty, wasn't it?
Don, I never thought you'd let anything
personal influence your testimony.
-But I didn't, Eileen.
-Skip it.
Every dog has his day.
Mine's coming.
-Is that a threat?
-Take it any way you want.
Come on, dear.
Please don't get into
any more arguments with him.
(PLANE BUZZING)
Gee, Steve. It dips
and climbs just like a P-38.
-I thought you'd have some fun with it.
-Boy, will I!
It was swell of you to get it for me.
Yeah, you know...
You know, when you...
you grow up, I hope
you follow aviation
as a profession.
I'll sure like that.
Be a lot better than
being a truck driver like me.
Oh, boy, but these
sandwiches are good, Mom.
Anything tastes good at a picnic.
Just the same, I'm glad you
fixed these. Huh, Steve?
They're wonderful.
If you like Mom and you like her cooking
so well, why don't you marry her?
Just eat your lunch, son.
Just eat your lunch.
-Well, you're gonna someday, aren't you?
-Tommy!
You're right, pal. Just as soon as
my business is a little better.
Well, seems to me
you're wasting a lot of time.
Smart boy.
(CHUCKLING)
But...
Well, the vegetables'll rot if
we don't deliver 'em tonight.
Okay, Bernie. I don't want
you to drive if you're sick.
Is the truck loaded?
Well, drive it over here.
Are you well enough to do that?
Okay, Bernie. Fine. Goodbye.
More bad luck. Bernie's sick.
Well...
Maybe you can get Thompson.
Hey, there's an idea.
Hadn't thought of him.
Well, that won't do me any good.
Yeah, I'm sorry, too.
Drivers are hard to get at short notice.
Yeah. Goodbye.
-Hiya, Steve.
-Hello, Jerry.
Sorry to hear about that
raw deal Parker gave you.
Oh, not too sorry, I imagine.
Don't be like that, Steve.
What if we are competitors?
We can still be friends, can't we?
-If you want it that way.
-If I want it that way?
Look, fella.
I had all the trucking business till
you came along and started cutting rates.
Well, you were overcharging
your customers.
So what? Nobody squawked
till you stuck your nose in.
Oh, now let's not
go all over that again.
I got to get a load rolling.
All right, I'll make it brief.
I'd still like to buy you out.
The answer is still no.
Don't say no
till you hear my proposition.
I'll give you part of the business,
employment for you and Charlie,
and I'll assume the mortgages
you gotta place on your trucks.
I don't believe in Santa Claus.
Nothing doing.
Why?
You must think I'm stupid.
My interstate hauls are gonna bring me
in a lot of money in a few years.
Yeah.
If you last that long.
Meaning what?
I've got a strange philosophy
of my own, Steve.
I always try to get what
I want in a nice way.
First.
Well, I'm glad
we understand each other.
So long, Steve.
So long.
Well, if you can't, you can't.
Goodbye.
Believe me, Steve, I wouldn't
let you down if I wasn't sick as a dog.
I know that, Bernie.
Go on home and get a doctor.
Yeah, that's what I'm gonna do.
But I'll be back
as soon as I can make it.
Fine, Bernie.
Too bad I never learned to
drive one of those battleships.
-(DOOR CLOSING)
-Who can you get?
Myself. That's all.
Don't do it, Steve.
If you're caught driving now,
they'll throw the book at ya.
Well, what am I gonna do?
If that load spoils,
I lose the account.
-I can't afford that.
-Yeah, but if Don Parker spots you,
-you're out of the trucking business.
-No, he won't.
I'll wait till it's dark.
I'll stay off Highway 32.
Check the truck for me, will ya?
I'm gonna grab a bite to eat.
(ENGINE SPUTTERING)
(SIREN BLARING)
THE WHISTLER:
Yes.
Don is dead.
You didn't kill him, Steve.
But will anyone believe you?
(ENGINE STARTING)
R38-92.
Write that down, Bill.
(VEHICLE PULLING UP)
NEWSREADER: We interrupt this programme
to bring you a special bulletin.
All citizens in Nevada are requested
to be on the lookout for Steve Reynolds,
a fugitive killer wanted by
the police of California.
Reynolds is approximately
six feet in height,
weighs about one hundred
and eighty-five pounds.
He has dark hair and brown eyes.
Hey, bud.
What's the matter?
You scared the pants off me.
Did you see a man come in here
in the last ten minutes?
About your size, wearing
a brown suit and a hat.
-Yeah. He went up in the elevator.
-Thanks, pal.
Number five, on the right.
(SIGHING)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(GASPING)
What's...
What's the matter?
Just looking for someone.
Take it easy.
Hi, Stack.
-Say hello to Jerry Mason.
-Hello, Stack.
Hi.
WAITER:
What'll you have?
-Two beers.
-Right.
Two beers.
Here you are, sir.
-Corner, please.
-All right. I'll take care of you.
There we are.
What's it gonna be, mister?
What are you gonna have?
STEVE: You have to talk louder.
I'm a little hard of hearing.
I said, what are you going to have?!
Dugan special.
Dugan special!
It's easy dough, Stack.
When you get the cars, all you have
to do is drive 'em over to Bayview.
Isn't that the place where
the cop was knocked off?
Yeah. But don't let that worry you.
That's been taken care of.
Don't sound good to me.
But hot cars are poison right now.
BERGER: There's no risk to this.
We've been operating for six months.
You deliver the cars to
Jerry's garage and collect.
Here we are.
Salt.
Pepper.
Holler if you want a refill, mister.
THE WHISTLER: And so a fugitive
slinks back under the cover of darkness,
clinging to the slim hope
that an old glove and
a man with a missing thumb
will help him prove his innocence.
Tommy.
It's Steve.
Steve!
Gee, I'm glad to see ya.
-Pull down the shades.
-Huh? Oh, sure.
I knew you'd come back.
I had to see ya.
And your mom.
How is she?
She's swell. Only...
Only what?
Well, I...
Tommy. I didn't kill Don.
I knew you didn't.
But, gee, Steve.
You know how women are.
They just don't understand things.
Ask her to come here, will ya?
-Do you really think I should?
-It's okay. It's okay.
(WHISPERING)
Mom.
EILEEN:
You stay here and help Mabel.
-Okay, Mom.
-This goes to the man on the end.
-I'll be back in a few minutes.
-Okay.
Hello, Eileen.
-Steve, why did you come back here?
-I wanted to see you.
I even hoped that maybe
you wanted to see me, too.
I had the foolish notion
that you wouldn't believe
that I could kill anyone.
-Why did you run away?
-Panic, maybe.
Maybe I couldn't forget
how completely
that judge believed my story
the last time.
Oh, Steve.
Everybody's saying
you were driving that truck.
I know.
Do you believe it?
I didn't hear from you.
I didn't know what to believe.
Why do you think
I came back here?
For the pleasure of
getting myself hung?
Do you want to tell me about it?
'Course I do.
Listen, honey.
I'm not guilty.
I didn't kill him.
(SIZZLING)
Watch the griddle, will you, Tommy,
while I get some more burgers?
Sure.
It all happened so fast that I
didn't get a good look at him.
But didn't you try to stop him?
Of course I did.
That's how I got the glove.
It's a pretty thin story, all right.
I don't blame you for thinking
nobody'd believe you.
Well, that's what I am up against.
Will you help me?
Of course I will. But how?
I want you to keep your eyes open
for a man with a missing thumb.
What?
Yes. A man with
his right thumb missing.
Look at that.
TOMMY:
Hey, Mabel.
Hurry up, Mabel.
We've got some new customers.
Take care of it, Eileen.
It's my life insurance.
I wish you could stay here.
Someone'd be sure to see you.
No. I wouldn't think of it.
It's awfully kind, but...
Where can you go?
Oh, Charlie's.
Yeah, Charlie'd be glad to put me up.
Oh, darling, be careful.
I will.
(TYPEWRITER CLACKING)
-Is Mr Mason in?
-Yes.
Just tell him it's Charlie.
MAN:
Yes?
-There's a Charlie here to see you.
-Send him in.
Thanks.
Hello, Charlie. Glad to see ya.
-What's on your mind?
-Well.
Steve's business
has folded up, so I...
I'm lookin' for a job.
Sorry, Charlie. I've got
all the mechanics I need.
Mr Mason, I wish you could use me.
It's tough finding work and I...
I'd do anything.
-I could use a night attendant.
-That'd be swell.
All right. And, if any
small repair jobs come in,
you can take care of them
and get paid extra.
That suits me fine.
Okay. Start tonight at
thirty bucks a week.
Thanks.
Heard anything from Steve?
No. I guess he's gone for good.
(DOOR CLOSING)
(HORN HONKING)
Where shall I put this heap?
I want to store it.
Just leave it here.
I'll park it for you.
You can make your
arrangements in the office.
Okay, bud.
Come in, Stack.
Yeah, all right, all right.
Be sure and call me back.
Yeah.
-Did you bring something for me?
-Yeah. A convertible.
Good. Have any trouble?
Not a bit.
I told you you wouldn't.
There you are.
Any more coming tonight?
There's three on the way.
(ENGINE REVVING)
-Park this crate for me, will you?
-Sure.
Say, er...
can you spare a cigarette?
I'll be glad to.
My hands are pretty dirty.
You'd better take one out for me.
All right.
-Here.
-Thanks.
Now, do you mind
giving me a light?
Not at all.
Want me to smoke it for you, too?
-Anything else I can do?
-Yeah.
You can go in the office and
get your parking check.
Now, that's a good idea.
(INSECTS CHIRRUPING)
(BRAKES SQUEALING)
Steve.
Steve, are you...?
Hey, you're right about Jerry.
They brought in four stolen cars
tonight to have 'em doctored up,
and whaddaya think?
One of the drivers has
no thumb on his right hand.
-What a break. Is he still there?
-Yeah.
And he will be
for about another hour.
Then he and
a couple of other guys
will drive some remodelled jobs
across the border.
Swell.
I'll phone the cops.
Don't you think it would be
smarter to grab the guy first?
Well, maybe you're right.
And besides,
if we're gonna nail him, we...
we oughta have
the glove for evidence.
Okay, I'll get it.
Meet you in the alley at
the back of the garage.
Okay.
-I'll be waiting for you.
-Yeah.
(KNOCKING)
Tommy told me you phoned.
I've been on pins and needles ever since.
I couldn't explain to him,
but Charlie's found the man.
I gotta have the glove.
-Who is he?
-Oh, he's one of Jerry's gang,
down at the garage now.
-Oh, I hope you're right.
-I gotta hurry, dear.
Hide someplace quick, Steve.
Captain Linfield and some
detectives just came in.
Steve. Not that way.
-In there.
-Thanks.
Well, Captain Linfield.
Sorry to intrude this way,
Mrs Blair,
but we got a tip that
Steve Reynolds is back in town.
We figured he might come here.
You don't think
he'd be that foolish, do you?
A man in love does a lot
of foolish things, Mrs Blair.
Do you mind if we look around?
Not at all. You wouldn't
be satisfied if you didn't.
(KNOCKING)
Nobody out there, Captain.
See where that door leads to.
That's mama's and my bedroom.
We don't like anybody
goin' in there.
We'll just take a quick look, sonny.
Nobody in there.
Good night, Mrs Blair.
Thanks for your co-operation.
Good night.
-Good night.
-Night.
Whoa boy!
Now give me the low-down.
Someone must've tipped him and he
beat it through a bedroom window.
-One of the strings was unhooked.
-I thought so.
Well, he won't be back here tonight,
but we've gotta
watch this place from now on.
Charlie.
(PHONE RINGING)
(PHONE STOPS RINGING)
(DOOR CLOSING)
(CAR DOOR OPENING)
Charlie.
Oh, my head!
How'd I get in there?
I don't know.
I guess it was the same guy
that let me have it.
-Where?
-In Jerry's office.
I was in there looking for you.
I remember now.
I was waiting in the alley
for you when I got crowned.
The four-fingered guy must
have got wise to ya.
Maybe. But there could be two.
That Jerry caught me snooping around.
It wasn't Jerry.
I can guarantee ya.
Jerry's dead.
The safe's been robbed.
-Jerry's dead?
-Yeah.
Looks like we missed the boat.
-That glove won't do us any good now.
-Well, I didn't get it anyway.
Some cops almost nabbed me.
Though I'd probably have been
better off if they had.
Forget it, will ya?
Go on home.
I'll call the cops.
They're sure to grab the guy
before he can drive
across the border.
Ah, it's no use.
He's too smart.
My best bet's to give myself up.
Don't be a chump.
If you do, you're really finished.
Well, I can't go on like this.
(SIREN BLARING)
Clear outta here, Steve,
or they'll pin this murder on you, too.
Well, what do you think
I've been talking about?
Come on.
Get outta here, will ya?
Tommy.
-Unhook the screen.
-Okay.
I'll get Mom.
Mabel. Will you tell Mom
I need her a minute?
-Sure, Tommy.
-Thanks!
Tommy wants you, Mrs Blair.
Probably hungry again.
What do you want this time?
Another ice-cream cone?
Heck, no.
Steve's here.
You're taking an awful
chance coming back here.
-Have you been to the garage?
-I got there too late.
The guy had gone.
Killed Jerry and robbed his safe.
-But where was Charlie?
-He got it too.
They slugged him
and threw him in a car.
He was sticking
his neck out for me.
I'm in an awful jam, Eileen.
I'd be better off
if I give myself up
before they blame
this one on me, too.
Do you really mean that, Steve?
Give me the glove. I'll need it
when I tell my story to the police.
Are you sure
that's why you want it?
Of course. Why else?
I told you Steve didn't
know about it, Mom.
Know about what?
I'll show you.
STEVE:
Why, they're the real thing.
Am I stupid?
I've been looking for a
man with a missing thumb.
I guess you're just not
as curious as I am.
Why, these things are worth a fortune.
-I wonder...
-What?
I wonder if they're anything to do
with the police coming up here.
That's impossible. Nobody knew
about them but Tommy and me.
Tommy, what's got into you?
Mabel's been spying on us.
I caught her listening
at the door yesterday.
Now she's calling
somebody on the phone.
Do you think she's working
with the police?
Well, maybe. But my guess
is that she's in with the guy
that killed Jerry and Don.
How long has she been
working for you?
Well, I... I hired her about
a week after you left town.
Well, at that time the cops weren't
looking for me around here.
She must be in with the guy
that's after that glove.
She got a job here so she could
tip him off if I showed up.
(KNOCKING)
My brother just called, Mrs Blair.
He isn't feeling very well.
I wonder if I could get off now.
Of course, Mabel.
I'll be out in a minute or two.
Thanks a lot.
TOMMY:
She's lying, Mom.
Nobody called her.
I saw her dial a number.
Well, that proves it.
-May I borrow your car?
-What are you going to do?
I'm going to follow her.
I've got a hunch she's gonna meet her
boyfriend and give him the low-down.
What if they see you?
Why not let the police handle it?
But there is no time.
They might get away.
Get my keys, Tommy.
They're on the dresser.
Here. I want you to put
these diamonds away.
Put them in the glove
exactly as you found them.
I want to show them to the police.
But if Mabel knows about them,
it won't be safe to keep them here.
I guess I'd better
take them with me.
Here. Here.
I'll put them in here.
Gee, that's pretty smart.
-Now, you keep the glove until I need it.
-All right.
-Good luck, Steve.
-Thanks, pal.
Bye.
(DOOR CLOSING)
Don't worry, Mom.
Steve knows how to
take care of himself.
Go to bed, Tommy.
It's way past your time.
I'm sorry to keep you waiting, Mabel.
Oh, that's quite all right, Mrs Blair.
-Good night.
(VEHICLE APPROACHING)
(DOOR OPENING)
(DOOR CLOSING)
How'd you make out
at the garage?
How much did you get?
Oh, that's great. Now we don't have
to worry about the diamonds.
Are you crazy, sweet? Let's get out
of town while the getting's good.
All right.
How soon will you be home?
Well, you'd better
make it half an hour.
That'll give me time to pack.
(INSECTS CHIRRUPING)
(KNOCKING)
Where you been?
Charlie, I got a surprise for you.
We've been on the wrong track.
I know who killed Jerry and Don.
-You do?
-Mabel's boyfriend.
-Mabel?
-The gal that works for Eileen.
-You sure of that?
-I'm positive.
Now, he'll be over at her place
in about a half an hour.
Now, we gotta work fast, 'cause
they're getting ready to leave town.
How will we do it?
Remember, this guy's a killer.
Now, that's why I need your help.
We'll wait outside
her place in the hall
and when they come out,
we'll jump 'em.
Okay. I'll take my gun
just in case.
MABEL:
Who is it?
Telegram.
Now just keep quiet
and you won't get hurt.
What's the big idea?
CHARLIE: All right, sucker.
Put up your hands.
I said, put 'em up.
But, Charlie, I...
I don't understand.
You're kidding?
Don't be dumb.
-You mean you were the one who...
-Yeah.
I knocked off the motor cop.
But why?
What had Don done to you?
He knew I'd pulled a job back east
and broke out of the pen.
I was payin' him to lay off,
but he got too greedy, so I...
I had to get rid of him.
For good.
Well, why frame me?
You gave me the idea yourself
when you insisted on driving
the truck that night.
All right. Hand it over.
Hand what over?
As if you didn't know.
-Give me that glove.
-I haven't got it.
So it's still at Eileen's.
Seems to me as though you're
making an awful fuss over an old glove.
Now don't try to make me believe
you don't know what's in it.
No, I don't.
Sit down, Steve.
You stay here with him.
If he tries to get away,
let him have it.
-Where are you goin'?
-Over to Eileen's.
Don't take that chance, sweet.
Jerry's dough will keep us for a while.
Forget the diamonds.
-Diamonds?
-Sure, if you didn't really know.
Wait a minute, Mabel.
There's a way to get 'em back
without me stickin' out my neck.
Now, write what I tell ya.
Honey...
That's what you call her, isn't it?
Honey,
Charlie and I...
walked into a trap.
They're...
They're holding me...
while he brings you...
this message.
If you want to see me alive...
do...
do exactly...
as I say.
Give Charlie the glove...
and don't call the police.
Now, sign your name.
Who told you to write anything
about the diamonds?
Nobody.
But if you ask her to trade
an old glove for my life,
she'll think you're crazy.
-He's right, Charlie.
-Yeah.
Yeah. I guess he is.
You'd better find something
to tie him up with.
Now, I'll borrow Eileen's car and
it'll make everything look Jake.
MAN:
You've got a customer, Eileen.
Be right out.
Good morning.
Cup of coffee.
Thanks, boys. Come back again.
Sure. I'll be seein' ya.
-What's wrong, Charlie?
-Steve sent me.
He's in trouble.
There's some cops hangin' around?
There were just a while ago.
What's happened to him?
I think this'll explain it
better than I can.
And Steve and I didn't have sense
enough to take that glove apart.
Yeah.
And we all thought the guy
actually had a thumb missing.
Hello, Charlie.
What are you doing here?
Steve's in more trouble, dear.
Charlie just brought me a note from him.
Let me see it, Mom.
But, Mom, he says here that...
Well, that...
Go ahead.
What were you gonna say?
Steve says not to call the police.
But how do we know they'll let him go
after we give them the diamonds?
Yes. How do we know that?
They don't care a hoot about Steve.
They only want the diamonds.
I hope you're right.
Well, we'd better do
just as Steve says.
-But I'm going with you.
-Well...
Okay, but hurry up.
If those guys think I called the cops,
Steve's a dead pigeon.
You're a smart kid, Tommy.
I guess I took after my mom.
EILEEN:
How are we gonna get there?
I've got your car.
Steve told me to use it.
Good night, Tommy.
You must take care of
everything while I'm away.
Don't worry, Mom.
I'll take care of everything.
You got the glove?
Right here.
So long, Tommy. See ya later.
So long.
(INSECTS CHIRRUPING)
(CAR DOOR CLOSING)
(ENGINE STARTING)
(CASH REGISTER PINGING)
(PHONE PINGING)
(KNOCKING)
-Charlie?
-CHARLIE: Yeah, it's me.
What'd you bring her for?
She just wanted to make sure this
stuff got into the right hands.
You shouldn't have
come here, honey.
It's all right, Steve.
He didn't fool me for a minute.
Smart girl.
Now, let's have that glove.
So you didn't know a thing
about the diamonds.
What did you do with 'em?
What did you do with 'em?!
He doesn't know where they are.
I've hidden them,
and you'll never find them.
I think I will.
Stop it.
I'll tell you where they are.
They're in my tobacco
pouch on the table.
Gee. Am I glad to see those
little beauties again!
-Are... Are they all there?
-Yeah.
This isn't a bad way
to carry 'em.
Thanks for the tobacco pouch.
Let's beat it, sweet.
I'm getting nervous.
Okay.
Take her and lock her
in the bedroom closet.
You heard what the man said.
Now, let's be nice.
And gag her,
so she'll be quiet.
You've been a nice pigeon, Steve.
Sorry I have to do this.
-Are you ready, Mabel?
-MABEL: Be right with you.
That one looks like it.
I'll check the number.
MAN:
Just a minute!
(GUNSHOT)
Charlie!
(SOBBING)
No!
Where's Reynolds and Mrs Blair?
They're upstairs.
Take care of him.
Come on. You can get up.
You can go.
This is your lucky day, Reynolds.
Mabel's turned state's evidence.
Her story clears you of the
murder of Don Parker.
Did she tell you
about Jerry Mason?
Yes. She told us
he killed him, too.
We're rounding up the rest
of the Mason gang now.
Well, Charlie couldn't resist
the money in that safe.
I still don't understand the connection
between him and Don Parker.
Parker had been
a policeman back east.
It was through him
that Charlie was arrested
and sent up for the
Worthing diamond robbery.
But the gems were never recovered.
I remember reading about that case.
It was about four years ago.
That's right.
After Parker joined the force out here,
he accidentally ran into Charlie.
He figured that he still had
the diamonds stashed away.
Then he started blackmailing him?
Exactly.
It cost him his life.
It's unfortunate,
but, of the thousands of men
who enforce the law,
occasionally one turns crooked.
Well, Captain,
I sure want to thank you.
Don't thank me. Thank that boy.
He gave us the licence
number of his mother's car.
Lucky for you
we spotted it so quickly.
I told you I'd take care
of everything, Mom.
I knew I could
depend on you, Tommy.
You know, Reynolds. There's a big reward
for the recovery of those diamonds.
-There is?
-Yes. And you're gonna get it.
And you're entitled to it
after what you have been through.
Steve, that's wonderful.
It'll put you back in
the trucking business.
Put you out of the
lunchroom business.
THE WHISTLER:
Yes, Steve, you were lucky.
Stopping for just sixty seconds
to give a stranger a lift
did change the whole
pattern of your life.
It might have ended in
disgrace or even death.
But fate was kind to you.
(WHISTLING HIS THEME)
SUBTITLES BY POWERHOUSE FILMS LTD