(MAN WHISTLING
"THE WHISTLER" THEME)
THE WHISTLER:
I am the Whistler,
and I know
many strange tales,
many secrets hidden
in the hearts of men and women
who have stepped
into the shadows.
Tonight, I am keeping
a strange rendezvous.
Here is a strange man,
formed in God's image,
according to the Bible.
But how far is
"image" from "mirage"?
The two words sound alike.
This man looks like all others,
but what separates him
from his fellows?
It cannot be seen
by the naked eye.
(WHISTLING)
His name is William Everest,
and he is a man
with a ghastly mission,
which will not let him rest
until it is successfully
accomplished.
But the best-laid plans
which men sometimes make
have a habit of going astray.
Whether in this case
for good or evil,
only the events of
this night can foretell.
(HORN HONKING)
Did it hit you, bud?
I seen it.
Just missed him.
Must have conked his head
on this lamppost or something.
Shall we call an ambulance?
No, no, no.
Don't call. I'm all right.
You must have given yourself
a heck of a whack there, fella.
Oh, it's nothing. It's nothing.
-WOMAN: Are you sure you're all right?
-Oh, quite.
I seen half the
licence number, mister
Maybe you wanna sue him
or something? It's 2-V-6...
It's all right.
Thank you. Thank you.
WOMAN:
Well, I never.
Huh. Put yourself
out for some people,
and you don't even rate
a "thank you".
Or maybe he's still punch-drunk
from that bump on the head
he gave himself or something.
THE WHISTLER:
He hesitated.
A thought must have
run through his mind.
It took no longer
than a second or two,
yet whose destiny may
have been changed
by this sudden impulse,
which took William Everest
through the door
of this little café
down here
in Greenwich Village?
And how will the fate of
William Everest himself be affected?
(BIG BAND JAZZ
PLAYING OVER SPEAKER)
(CHATTERING)
WAITER:
Good evening. Table, sir?
-Gin.
-Again?
Oh, Jean's just good
because the girls
play for their lunches
down the store every day.
She gets all that practice.
Haven't had to buy
a lunch for two weeks.
You'll be sorry when
all that free food
starts showing itself
around the hips.
-(ALL CHUCKLING)
-Fourteen.
Two-fifty. Play another?
Uh-uh.
We oughta get going.
-Let me tell your fortune.
-FRANCIE: No, thank you.
I like to come up
on mine gradually.
Makes it that much
more interesting.
How about you, Charlie?
Save it.
I know my fortune already.
Think I'll tell his.
Whose?
The good-looking man
over at the bar.
-Know him?
-Never saw him before in my life.
Mmm. That doesn't
look so good.
Death.
FRANCIE:
What does it say?
Within twenty-four hours.
(SNAPPING CARDS)
There's that card again.
Within twenty-four hours.
Ah, come on.
Let's go to a movie.
What shall I do?
Oh, don't be ridiculous, darling.
You're not taking this little
parlour game seriously?
Oh, I know it's silly, but...
It's not only silly,
it's childish.
He's going.
Only to another bar.
I'll bet you on that.
Well, where are you going?
Somebody should
tell him something.
Oh, for heaven sakes, Jean,
you're acting like a schoolkid.
"Somebody should
tell him something."
He'd think you were crazy.
Or just trying to pick up
an acquaintance.
-It wouldn't be ladylike.
-I know, but the cards...
FRANCIE: Oh, forget it. He's going
out of that door and out of our lives.
Never even came in them.
FRANCIE: Jean, don't be a fool.
Come back here!
Whaddaya know?
She sure takes her cards seriously.
She's got too much imagination
for her own good.
Oh, don't worry about it.
So, she tells him,
he thinks she's
a first-class screwball,
and then it's all over.
Please, sir. I, er... Well...
I beg your pardon, but two times
the same thing happened.
-I just had to...
-I beg your pardon?
Well, it was the cards. Both times,
the cards said the same thing.
You think I'm ridiculous.
Well, I'd say instead, original.
If you think I'm trying
to make your acquaintance,
-you're very much mistaken.
-Well, I'm disappointed.
Well, I felt I had to tell you,
for your own good.
Well, I'd be very grateful
for your concern
if I knew the reason for it.
-Well, I told you.
-Oh, so you did. But what?
The cards.
Cards? What cards?
You're laughing at me. I...
I don't blame you, but...
You see, I was telling
your fortune in that café.
Oh, playing cards.
I see.
Did my fortune amuse you?
It frightened me.
Why?
Well, I thought
I should tell you...
What did the cards say?
Well, they said...
Well, what did they say?
That you're in very grave danger
for the next twenty-four hours.
Two times, one after the other,
it said the same thing,
and I shuffled the cards
very well, too.
Does that suggest
something to you,
or warn you of someone, perhaps?
It suggests...
nothing and warns me
of absolutely no-one.
Well, please, just the same,
take care of yourself
the next twenty-four hours.
Maybe, er...
Maybe you'll be
kind enough to help me.
Aren't you well?
I...
I'm sorry.
I had a little accident, and I...
I'm all right.
It's just that I'm kind of dizzy.
Oh, come on over here
and sit down.
The owner of this car
won't object, I'm sure.
Let's go in here.
Feel any better?
Oh, I'm all right.
Still a little shaky.
A little.
-Would a doctor...
-No, no.
It's just that...
Well, I'm ashamed
to admit it, but...
I don't seem to be able
to remember my name.
Stupid of me, isn't it?
I hope you're not injured more
than you're willing to admit.
No, it's...
Outside of a little density,
I feel as well as I ever have.
I stopped in that bar
over there for a drink
and thought it would
sorta clear my head, but...
And it failed?
Afraid so.
You remember nothing
about yourself at all?
Well, only that
I had someone to see
and something
very important to do.
But, who and what?
Maybe you have
something in your pockets
that would tell us
who you are.
Oh, I doubt it, or I'd
have known it by now.
Well, let's look at them.
Come on, please.
Very well.
Gee, I wonder
what's taking Jean so long.
Well, he's a pretty
good-looking guy.
Maybe Jean's gone into details.
You'd better get
the check, Charlie.
Waitress.
Well, that's the lot.
JEAN: Cigarette lighter,
doctor's prescription,
and an order
for a birthday cake.
Receipt for two dozen
American Beauty roses.
A Canadian dollar with a...
licence number pencilled in.
A key.
And a railroad schedule
with Woodville checked off.
Doesn't mean
very much, does it?
Um...
-Well, there's a name on this one.
-Yes?
JEAN: Two dozen
American Beauty roses to...
"Constantina...
"Constantina Ivaneska,
Civic Theatre."
-Well, that's marvellous.
-It is?
Well, of course.
Don't you see?
You must have
sent these roses,
and the lady's probably
a friend of yours,
and all we have to do
is visit her,
and it'll all be
straightened out in no time.
I'd have thought of that myself
if I'd had my wits about me.
Each one of these probably
tell us something about you.
All we have to do
is track them down.
You know, you're as ingenious
as you are beautiful and kind.
-What...?
-Oh, I hope you don't mind.
My friend was ill,
and we came in here to rest.
Oh, okay.
Can I drop you someplace?
Well, Civic Theatre?
I'm going right past there.
-Oh, thank you.
-Thanks ever so much.
(CAR ENGINE STARTING)
(CAR DRIVING AWAY)
(WHISTLING)
We'll go round
the stage door, George.
Sure... Why are you
calling me that?
Well, it'll have to do
till we find out
what your real name is.
(BALLET MUSIC AUDIBLE)
Wait a minute.
You can't go in there.
-We'd like to see...
-Let me handle this.
We must see
Constantina Ivaneska.
-She's on the stage.
-We'll wait inside.
Not so fast, young lady.
Are you friends
of Miss Ivaneska?
Oh, but the best.
She didn't say nothin'
about expecting you.
Oh, we wanted
to surprise her.
Yes, I'm sure she would
get a kick out of it.
You certainly
know your way around.
You can't live in New York
long in ignorance.
There it is.
(KNOCKING)
Who would you like to see?
Oh, we're friends of Constantina's.
Yes, ma'am. Miss Constantina's
on the stage right now,
but she'll be
coming along very soon.
-Well, we'll wait inside.
-Yes, ma'am.
Remember this place
at all, George?
-George?
-What?
Do you remember
this place at all?
I don't think so.
Well, Miss Ivaneska
will be here in a minute.
I hear she's very beautiful.
-(AUDIENCE APPLAUSE)
-Is she?
I'm sure you'll remember her.
I doubt a man could forget.
CONSTANTINA:
Flotilda...
Who are you?
What... What can I do for you?
-Are you Constantina Ivaneska?
-Yes.
Oh, well, here's a friend of yours.
What is this, a joke?
You don't know him?
No.
Are you playing a game?
-Don't you recognise her, George?
-Nn-nnn.
Will you please explain
this extraordinary conduct?
How did you
get by the doorman?
-Bribery.
-But... But why?
My friend thought I knew you.
The more you explain, the...
the less I understand.
Well, you see, George
had an accident, and, well...
Oh, now I understand.
I'm sorry, but I cannot
be of any help to you.
I'm positive that this gentleman
and I do not know each other.
Flotilda, where have you been?
I've been fixing
the flowers.
CONSTANTINA:
Well, help me dress.
Those roses.
Who sent them?
Young lady,
you're becoming tiresome.
They were sent to me
by my fiancé.
And now, if you'll forgive me,
I must dress.
Good night.
Thank you
for your kindness.
DOORMAN:
Good evening, Mr Reynolds.
Miss Ivaneska's
in her dressing room.
I'm sure she'll
be out very shortly.
-George.
-Yes?
Are you sure,
very sure you don't
remember that woman?
Oh, believe me, I'm not
trying to be funny.
I'm more anxious to find out
who I am than you are.
-I know, but...
-But what?
Guess we'll just have to try
running down
one of the other articles.
EVEREST:
My doctor's prescription.
JEAN:
It hasn't any patient's name on it.
EVEREST: It has my doctor's
name and address.
Perhaps we should have
tried that first.
Might have saved us
a lot of trouble.
It might have.
Taxi.
-Where to?
-Oh, what is that address?
-Er, 29 Dexter Street.
-Got it?
Okay.
I overshot the place, mister.
I'll back up if you want me to.
No, just wait here, please.
Oh, there it is.
Hello, little lady.
-My, what a pretty kitten.
-Her name is Fritzi.
It's number 29 all right,
but there's no doctor's office there.
Maybe the owner can tell us.
Shall I go with you?
Don't bother. I see you've been
charmed away from me.
I'll be back in a second.
Anybody here?
Good evening.
Oh, good evening.
Could you tell me where
I might find Dr Noel J Hendricks
in this building
or in the neighbourhood?
There is no doctor
in this building
or within a radius
of four blocks from here.
Are you certain?
I have been in business
here for fifteen years.
The neighbourhood is poor,
and, to the poor,
doctors are a luxury.
Well, I have a prescription here
that was...
issued to a friend of mine by a
Dr Hendricks at this address.
Isn't your friend able to say
exactly where he got it?
Well, his memory was
affected by an accident.
He's right out here.
I know little girls
like ice cream.
Oh, thank you.
Will you look after
Fritzi, please?
I'll take good care of her.
Yes, I remember very well.
I have a phenomenal
memory for faces.
He was in here last week.
Oh, you know him, then?
No. He just came in
looking for a book.
Did he buy one?
No.
Just thumbed through it.
"Interested in research,"
I think he said.
Oh.
Great many people
come in here
just to browse around.
Do you recall
the title of the book?
It happens to be
a great favourite of mine.
JEAN:
"Noel J. Hendricks, M.D."
Why, that's the same name that's
printed on his prescription.
BOOKSELLER: Very strange
and most interesting.
This man has been
dead for fifty years.
Well, thank you for your trouble.
Any luck?
It looked so simple
at the beginning.
Well, come on.
The taxi's waiting.
Where to now, mister?
-Just drive.
-Okay.
Thank you for the
ice cream cone, mister.
(SOBBING)
Fritzi! Oh, Fritzi!
Oh, Fritzi!
(SOBBING CONTINUES)
You've tired yourself
too much on my account.
That's all right.
Maybe we should go home
and try again
in the morning.
Good idea, but I don't
remember where I live.
I could go to the police.
Oh, no. I feel too
responsible for you.
But, er...
I have room for you at home.
Well, that's very kind,
but would it be proper?
Quite all right. I share
the apartment with my sister.
What's the address?
I'll tell the driver.
(BIRD TWEETING)
(DOOR OPENING)
Oh, my goodness.
It-It's about time. I...
I've been worried.
Well, I've been out
with Mr, er...George.
Francie, I'd like to
have you meet George.
How do you do?
What have you
been up to, anyway?
Well, it's all my fault your sister's
late in getting home, Miss Lang.
She took compassion
on a poor wayfarer
and tried to help him
find himself.
George is the one at the bar
whose fortune I told.
Yes, I know.
Did it take you half the night
to tell him about it?
I should've known you'd worry,
but I was worried, too.
I'm glad you were at least
that considerate of me.
Oh, worried about George,
I mean.
Why, he looks as if he can
take care of himself.
Well, that's just it.
He can't.
Well, then it's about time
he learned.
What your sister means...
I seem to have forgotten
who I am.
Forgotten?
Then who's George?
Well, that's what I call him.
You see, he was in an accident,
and it left him kind of dazed.
I've been trying to help him
find out who he is.
We didn't realise
the time passed so quickly.
If I'd known you were
going to be worried, I...
I wouldn't have let her
stay out so late.
Oh, it... it's all right,
now that you're here.
But, you see,
Jean means a lot to me.
It's very understandable.
Then you, er...
really don't
know who you are?
No.
I've asked George
to spend the night here.
Well, you couldn't
let a little dog wander
around the street
all night, could you?
I suggested to your sister
I could go to the police.
Oh, I wouldn't hear of it.
Oh, you're welcome to stay,
Mr, er...?
"George," I guess it'll have
to be for the time being.
But I'm afraid you'll have
to sleep on the couch.
Well, that's very kind.
Thank you.
Please sit down now
and make yourself comfortable.
-I've got some coffee on the stove.
-Thank you.
(BIRD CHIRPING)
Francie didn't mean
to be rude.
She's really very nice.
She's your sister, isn't she?
You do say nice things.
Well, you provoke them.
That lighter, a few papers,
and some money
was all he had in his pockets.
Must be pretty expensive
if the diamonds are real.
-'Course they're real.
-How do you know?
Well, you're not the sort
of person to pretend.
You do say nice things.
Hey. There's something
engraved on the bottom.
-Initials.
-Let's see.
No, they don't mean a thing.
"C.C. to J.C."
Why, that's more of a clue
than we've had all evening.
Here, I've been
calling you George,
and your name's probably
Jim or Jack or Joe.
-Is it?
-(CHUCKLING) I wouldn't know.
I'm going to bed.
Coming, Jean?
I want to get a blanket
and a pillow for George.
I'll take care of the dishes.
Oh, thank you.
Time to go to sleep, Barney.
Night.
Night, George.
Er... Kitchen?
Oh, yes, in the sink,
if you please. And thank you.
-Thank you.
-Good night.
(GASPING)
Oh, I didn't hear you come back.
I'm sorry I startled you.
I hope you sleep comfortably.
I'm sure I shall.
Don't bother with that.
Well, good night.
Pleasant dreams, Miss Lang.
If I call you George,
you call me Jean.
It's a privilege.
Good night, Jean.
Good night, George.
(DOOR CLOSING)
Jean, Charlie asked me
to marry him tonight.
You say something, Francie?
Charlie proposed.
-Oh, darling!
-(BOTH LAUGHING)
When are you
gonna be married?
Oh, well, I, er...
Francie, you accepted?
Charlie's a wonderful boy.
He sure is, but I couldn't
leave you alone.
Oh, don't be a goose.
Besides, maybe I have
plans of my own.
Jean, you won't do
anything foolish?
Of course not.
Why, you hardly know him.
Who?
I know you better
than you do yourself.
Marriage isn't to be taken lightly.
Yes, teacher.
But he is charming,
isn't he?
Yes.
And good-looking.
Yes, but
that isn't everything. It's...
It's what a man is,
more than how he looks.
I know.
-What happened tonight?
-Oh, it was very exciting.
Where'd you go?
Well, first of all...
(BIRD CHIRPING)
Then we came home.
-Francie?
-Mm-hmm?
Would you help me?
About George?
Uh-huh.
I mean, take
the day off tomorrow.
It's Saturday and
a half-day anyway.
Well, what can I do?
Well, those things
George had in his pockets.
You could take some of them
and track them down. The, er...
The cigarette lighter,
the doctor's prescription,
and the order
for the birthday cake.
Oh, you bring home
the strangest people.
Oh, George isn't strange.
He's very nice.
How would you feel if you
suddenly lost your memory?
Pretty strange, I bet.
All right, dear.
And then we could meet
someplace in the afternoon and...
compare notes.
Francie...
(SIGHING)
(CLOCK CHIMING)
(BIRD CHIRPING)
(CHIRPING CONTINUES)
(DISTANT SIREN)
Well, who are you
going out to meet?
-Clark Gable?
-I should be so lucky.
Come on, I'm hungry.
George looks too intelligent
to expect a girl
to be so beautiful
at nine o'clock in the morning.
Well, now!
Smells good!
Maybe you've got something
in that guy after all.
Good morning.
After walking about
half the night and waiting,
I figured you'd both
be terribly hungry.
I hope you'll forgive
the liberty I've taken.
Gee, you make me
feel awfully guilty
for leaving those dishes
in the sink last night.
They're all taken care of.
I told you he was nice.
Nice?
He's miraculous.
-May I?
-Thank you.
Well, pile in.
What are we waiting for?
-(CLEARING THROAT)
-EVEREST: "Our Father in Heaven,
"we thank thee for this repast.
"May we enjoy thy benefits
all the days of our years.
"Amen."
Oh, I made these eggs according to
my own taste, sunny side up.
Hope you like them
that way.
To have somebody
serve me,
I'd like them
standing on edge.
-Coffee?
-Please. Thank you.
Oh, I forgot to feed Barney.
Excuse me.
Francie's very fond of Barney.
Her fiancé gave him to her.
FRANCIE:
Jean!
What's the matter, Francie?
What's wrong, Francie?
FRANCIE: There's something
the matter with Barney.
What do you suppose happened?
I don't know.
He was all right last night,
singing his little head off.
Oh, the poor little creature.
Doesn't take very much to...
"3R 16J."
Say, you were here
the other day,
asking about this man's
licence number and address.
-I was?
-Sure.
I gave you that
information myself.
You even wrote the licence plate's
number on this Canadian buck.
Oh, I'm sorry, I forgot.
What is the address again?
522 Harris Street.
"522..."
(MACHINERY RATTLING)
Are you able to tell me
where I can find
the owner of this building?
Metropolitan Bank
owns it, brother.
522 Harris Street.
Judge Nesbitt.
We foreclosed that
property some time ago.
At the time, Judge Nesbitt
was living at
the Forest Apartments.
Thank you.
Is there a Mr Nesbitt
living here?
Yeah, he used to.
He checked out.
No forwarding address.
Thank you.
THE WHISTLER:
It's a bright day in the park.
All nature seems in harmony.
Yet, why should one man
seated on this bench
provide the sole
tumultuous exception?
Does he himself realise
the brash discord?
Do you, William Everest?
What cells, what tissues in
that pounding brain of yours
have now come back to life?
Or have they?
What is it you feel,
William Everest?
Or do you feel?
(SQUIRREL CHATTERING)
-Sorry, lady. This is a skeleton key.
-Skeleton?
That's how they're
known to the trade.
Detectives carry them.
Crooks too.
That's all you can
tell me about it?
Skeleton keys are
kind of secret keys, lady.
They don't tell much.
-Thank you.
-You're welcome.
Been waiting long?
No.
Oh, you've hurt your hand.
What happened to it?
-Oh, a splinter from the bench.
-Oh.
(SIGHING)
Why do you sigh?
Oh, discouraged.
-About me?
-Yes.
Then you haven't been able to
find out anything about me at all?
Nothing. I've tried
everything possible
in the last twenty-four hours.
We've been together
that long?
Don't tell me you're
forgetting that too, George.
George? Why do you
call me George?
What else do you
want me to call you?
'Cause I don't know
who you are.
Aren't you feeling well?
If I don't sound...
normal...
you're to blame.
I?
I've never been
in love before.
Don't say anything.
Your mere kindness is...
more than I ever hoped for.
Even if it remains just that,
I'm content and very grateful.
Shall we walk?
(GASPING)
Look.
Poor little thing.
Isn't it beautiful?
Er... These people
you've been seeing,
they brought nothing
to light about me?
Nothing?
You might just have
been born,
for all anybody
seems to know.
And you? Have you formed
any conclusions on your own?
How could I? On what?
Are you...
Are you a detective?
Why do you ask?
Well, that key
you had on you.
I was told that only
detectives carry them or...
Or?
Or crooks.
Oh. Well, I'm neither.
Didn't have to tell me.
Well, whatever my talents are,
you can rest assured
they don't run
in those channels.
I'm sure I had a lighter.
Oh, I gave it to
Francie this morning
to try to trace down,
remember?
What else did you give her?
Oh, the prescription
and the bakery order.
Oh.
That's mine, too, isn't it?
Yes, the railroad schedule.
I haven't been able to think yet
how it might help us.
It's getting very warm.
Probably storm before night.
Let's get out
of the sun, shall we?
-Please, I...
-Speak to me, miss?
-Oh, she was talking to me, Officer.
-Pardon me, sir.
What did you
want to say to him?
I just wanted to ask the time.
We're supposed to meet Francie.
Well, it's early.
My, you have a strong grip.
You must have been
an athlete.
I didn't mean to hurt you.
But you act
as though you were
frightened of that policeman.
For a moment, I thought you were
gonna ask him to help us,
because you were
discouraged about me.
Jean.
Yes, George.
Promise me that you'll see
this thing through with me,
that you won't give me up
for a bad job.
Of course I'll
see it through, George.
And promise me too, that...
anything that you may
find out about me,
it'll be our secret alone.
Certainly. What could
we possibly find out
that would be so necessary
to keep a secret?
Nothing. Nothing at all.
It's just that your...
Well, your kindness
has meant so much to me.
I couldn't get along
without you now.
You don't know
what it means
to wander through
the darkness alone.
We will see this thing
through together, won't we?
Yes, George, together.
Yes. We did this job.
I remember now.
You see, this is
a business district,
and we don't have any
medical printing trade here.
But about a week ago,
a fella came in
and had a few of these
printed up for him.
He paid me above
the market price for it.
Oh, you don't know
his name?
No. He didn't say.
He just waited here for 'em.
But, er...
Look, the fella across the street
in that cut-rate drugstore
might be able
to tell you his name,
because this fella went in there
after he left my shop.
-Oh, thank...
-I saw him through that window.
-Thank you.
-Glad to be of service.
Hello.
Oh, you want something?
Yes. Did, er, you fill this?
Where did you get this?
It belongs to a friend of mine.
Did you fill it?
Oh, maybe. Why?
I'd just like to know.
Are you from the
Pure Foods & Drug Office?
Oh, no. I'd just like
this information for myself.
Yeah. Reckon I did.
Oh, do you remember
the man who gave it to you?
-Yeah.
-His name, too?
No. I just remember him
by this prescription.
Why?
Is it so unusual?
Look, why are you asking me
all these questions?
-I run a perfectly respectable...
-Yes, I know you do.
It's just that...
Well, it means a lot to me
to get this information.
Could you tell me
what's in it?
Er...
I'm sure you have
nothing to hide.
No, of course not.
Er... Poison.
What did you say?
I said "poison".
What kind of poison?
(CHUCKLING) Look, lady,
you wouldn't know if I told you.
Poison is poison.
Now, just let it go at that.
And this man bought it?
Yes, he bought it.
Is it a common poison?
Well, not exactly.
It's high-powered stuff.
Kind of scarce.
There's not much call for it.
I-I guess it must be
very expensive.
Yeah, kinda.
You can't sell it without
a doctor's prescription, can you?
What do you call this,
a billet-doux?
Well, isn't it supposed to have
the patient's name on it
as well as the doctor's?
Look, lady, I've told you
everything I know.
Now, this shop isn't
a question-and-answer box.
If you don't care to
buy anything, er... good day.
Hey!
Hey, mister! Stop!
Oh, mister.
Oh, I'd like to
ask you something.
Sure, lady.
Step into my parlour.
-Cosy, ain't it?
-Oh.
Now, look, I-I just wanna
ask you one or two questions.
Shoot, baby.
Look, have you ever
seen this before?
Sure. That's one
of our order forms.
Well, whaddaya know?
A five-pound birthday cake.
-Delivered this one myself.
-FRANCIE: Oh, where to?
Railway Express.
What were they doing?
Celebrating an anniversary?
That's where this guy
ordered it delivered
after he brought it
back to the shop.
I don't get it.
Well, this bird orders
a cake and pays for it.
He hauls it off himself.
Back he comes
the same day and says, er,
"Ship it through
the Railway Express."
Oh, ship it to where?
Please try to remember.
Oh, I ain't forgot, miss.
It seemed sort of a funny place
to be sending a birthday cake.
-Funny?
-Peculiar-like.
I don't know why I thought
it shoulda been, but I did.
A guy gets funny notions sometimes,
you know what I mean,
and I figured right then and there
maybe the one who was getting it
wasn't a regular.
-Well, what do you mean?
-The place it was sent to.
-What place?
-The one upstate.
The, er, Hudson Mental Institution.
Hudson Mental?
Never had to ship a cake
to a place like that before.
Guy's name was, er... Crawford.
Yeah. John Crawford.
That's what it was.
Oh, thank you very much.
You've helped me a lot.
Okay, lady. Hope you found out
what you wanted.
Yes, I did. Say, er...
what's your name?
Joe Blainey.
What's yours?
-Thank you, Mr Blainey.
-You're welcome.
-Bye.
John Crawford...
John Crawford.
"J.C."
"C.C. to J.C."
"C.C. to...
"to John Crawford."
THE WHISTLER: Yes, a table at the
Fountain Café at Rockefeller Center
is a cool and pleasant place,
just as delightful as the park
where William Everest
was taking his ease before
and where he suddenly
recalled who he was,
as he sat on that bench
so kindly feeding
a little squirrel.
But why doesn't
he tell Jean Lang
he knows who he is?
Why doesn't he say,
"My name is not George.
"It's William, William Everest"?
Why does he
go on pretending?
It is because he knows
what he has at stake.
Jean.
I remember a name.
Your name? Yours?
The name of a man I know.
Friend?
It's the first actual name
I've been able to remember.
Must have been someone
very close to me.
Does he live in New York?
Woodville.
Well, that's the place you had
marked on the railroad schedule.
-Yes.
-What's the name?
Edward Nesbitt.
That's all you can remember?
All I need to know right now.
We must get there
as soon as possible.
There's a train leaving
at six o'clock,
gets in there at eight-ten.
We'll just have time to make it.
"We"?
Well, of course
you're going with me.
I want you with me
more than anyone else at my...
rebirth.
-Well, I know, but...
-Oh, it'd mean so much to me.
All right, George.
Here, I've just gotten
used to calling you George.
Well, if that doesn't
turn out to be my name,
my real name,
I'll adopt it.
I'll call Francie
and let her know.
-She'll worry.
-Oh, I think you exaggerate her anxieties.
You don't know Francie.
I'll just be a moment.
There's a phone right inside.
Waiter.
(DOORBELL RINGING)
Package for Mr John Crawford.
Mary! Mary!
What is it, Henry?
Another present for Daddy.
Oh. Good.
-MAILMAN: Sign here, please.
-Hold it, dear.
MAILMAN:
Thank you very much.
-Come on, darling.
-Let's open it!
Now, wait a minute.
Don't get impatient.
Take it in the kitchen.
That's it.
-MARY: Oh! Isn't it lovely?
-HENRY: Oh, boy!
Well, your ma didn't forget it was
your daddy's birthday,
even though she's in the city
visiting your grandparents.
-Gimme a taste.
-Now, it's your daddy's cake.
He's got to cut the first slice.
You just wait
till he gets home.
-Ah, Mary, please.
-Now, now...
Try again, Operator.
EVEREST:
Jean.
I'm waiting.
Did you speak to Francie?
She doesn't answer.
Well, you can call her later.
(SHIP'S HORN BLOWING)
Wish I'd been able to tell Francie
where we were going.
Well, we've barely got time to
make the train to Weehawken now.
You can call her from Woodville.
Oh, don't let it disturb you.
She knows you're in good hands.
It's wonderful how you suddenly
remembered that man's name.
I wasn't even making
an effort to think.
Picked up the schedule,
just came to me.
I'm so happy about it.
Woodville. Edward Nesbitt.
I couldn't think of one
without the other.
The one man who can tell me
all I want to know about myself.
It's thrilling.
There's no telling who you may
discover you are after you see that man.
-No telling.
-(THUNDER RUMBLING)
-Did you hear that?
-What?
Distant thunder.
Looks like the storm
you prophesied's coming true.
(SHIP'S HORN BLOWING)
Oh, here we are
at Weehawken.
We've only got a couple of minutes
to make the train.
Hello, Mrs Cassidy?
This is Frances Lang.
Is Charlie there?
Five minutes ago?
Oh. Well, did he say
where he was going?
Oh. (SIGHING)
Oh, thank you.
(GASPING)
Who is it?
Oh, Charlie, I'm so glad.
Say, I didn't mean
to scare you, honey.
The janitor let me in.
What's wrong?
I don't know.
Let's sit down.
What gives with the weeps?
I've been trying to get you.
It's about Jean. I'm scared.
Jean? What's...
She's been out all day
with that man.
She was supposed to
meet me this afternoon,
and she didn't show up.
What man?
Last night at the Salt Shaker,
that... that man at the bar.
She brought him home.
He spent the night? Here?
Yes. He... He'd had
some kind of an accident
and he couldn't remember
who he was.
Jean felt sorry for him
and she left with him
early this morning
trying to find out
something about him.
What's there
to be scared about?
Charlie, there's...
there's something horrible about him.
Oh, he looked okay to me.
I've been on my own all day
trying to help them, and...
You found out something?
What?
I-I don't exactly know.
I don't get it.
These are some of the things
that he had in his pocket.
Cigarette lighter.
-Doctor's prescription?
-It-It's for poison.
-This prescription?
-A deadly poison.
What's wrong with that?
Maybe he wanted to
get rid of a few roaches,
-or maybe...
-(SOBBING) Oh, Charlie.
Look, honey, maybe you'd better
tell me all about it,
right from the beginning.
-(THUNDERCLAP)
-THE WHISTLER: Yes, they are on the train,
and the destination is Woodville.
But does no twinge of unrest,
faint as it may be,
stir Jean Lang's consciousness,
as she trustingly confides herself
to the care of William Everest?
And that cake was sent
to the same person
whose initials are
on this cigarette lighter.
You're going to the police,
young lady.
-Oh, come with me, Charlie, please.
-No, I can't.
-But, I...
-There wouldn't be time.
Maybe this is something we're just
building up in our imagination, but...
Jean means too much
to the both of us
to take any chances.
But what are you gonna do?
Well, the police may need
some convincing
this isn't just
a little pipe dream.
I'll meet you at headquarters
with all the evidence
I can collect.
-Let's get going.
-All right.
(DOORBELL RINGING)
Man, I haven't got wings.
Why you treat that bell that way?
Is, er... Miss Ivaneska in?
-Yes. Who shall I say is call...
-Never mind names. Is she in?
She's fixin' to go out.
CONSTANTINA:
Flotilda, who is it?
Gentleman here says
"are you in?"
I told him you was
fixin' to go out.
Miss Constantina Ivaneska?
-Yes.
-Come with me.
Wha... What is the
meaning of this?
Mm-mmm. I ain't never seen
nothing like that in Georgia.
Well, what's the meaning of this?
-Please let me go.
-I'll explain as we go. I'm sorry, miss.
You'll pay dearly for this outrage.
Stop the car and let me go.
Who are you?
Well, I was kind of
frettin' about bein' took
from out of a swell dish
of roast chicken, too, but...
but from what this
fella tells me,
why, I ain't complainin' now.
Explain to her, Mr Richards.
Yeah, you see, you and me,
ma'am, are being invited
to stop a murder.
A murder?
Maybe more than one.
Mm-hmm.
THE WHISTLER: Leaves at six-ten p.m.,
arrives at eight p.m.
That's what the railroad
schedule states in cold print,
but it means far more
than that to William Everest.
It means far more
than that to Jean Lang, too,
but she does not know,
and there lies the tragedy.
I was told Joe Blainey
would be here.
You were told right, bud.
Hey, Joe!
There's a fella out here
to see ya.
Yeah!
-That him?
-That's him.
Hey, wait a minute, bud.
Where you goin'?
-You'll find out.
-Hey, this is a serious offence!
This is kidnapping!
That's a very unusual story
you've just told me, Miss Lang.
You will help me?
But the question is,
where does fact end
and fiction begin?
I-I know it's true.
I just feel that Jean's in danger.
We actually don't have
one cold fact to go on.
It's all supposition.
Oh, granted, it sounds feasible,
the way you tell it.
On the other hand,
it could be just mere coincidence.
Well, we've got to take
that chance, Captain.
Miss Lang, I can't set into motion
police machinery
on mere assumption.
I understand your anxiety,
but aren't you exaggerating
the situation?
What if something does happen
and you'd had a chance
to prevent it?
I'd be equally embarrassed
if this whole thing
turned out to be
a wild goose chase
set in motion by
an hysterical young woman.
Here we are, everybody.
But you've got to help me.
That's what the police are for.
If we had just one
clear fact to go on.
CHARLIE:
Here are five clear facts.
-Oh, Charlie.
-What does this mean?
-Did you tell him the story, honey?
-He says I'm imagining it.
Miss Ivaneska, tell the captain
the story you told me.
I knew this man
you're all talking about.
Then why did you
deny it last night
when my sister called
on you at the theatre?
I had my reasons.
I met this man a few years ago
at the home of Judge Nesbitt.
He paid a lot of attention to me
and said he was in love with me.
You weren't in love with him?
I liked him. He was charming
and good-looking, but...
but even then,
he showed signs of...
-CAPTAIN: Go on, please.
-Well, of that condition
which eventually put him
in the Hudson Mental Hospital.
That's the place where I told you
he sent the birthday cake.
Yeah, that's right.
I shipped it for him.
Who are you?
I work for the Elite Bakery.
That's where
he bought the cake.
His name is William Everest.
You mentioned a Judge Nesbitt.
Is that the same man
who retired a few years ago?
Yes.
He was in very poor health
and had lost a lot of money
in bad investments.
It was he who signed the papers
committing Everest to the asylum.
Oh. Why didn't you tell
my sister that last night?
I'm about to marry.
My fiancé comes from
a very conventional family,
and he's jealous, too.
When your sister brought
that man to me last night,
he didn't recognise me,
so I pretended I didn't
know him either.
Although, shortly before,
he'd sent me a bunch of roses
in an effort to renew
our old friendship.
And you believe that
this man is up to some mischief?
That's putting it rather mildly.
-(THUNDERCLAP)
-He's an escaped maniac.
He sent that birthday cake
to somebody named Crawford
at the institution.
It was filled with poison.
And here's the man
who sold it to him,
from the prescription
this gentleman printed by order.
That must be why
he came into my shop
and asked for
that book on poisons.
Who is John Crawford?
He's the warden
of the Hudson Mental Hospital.
He must have incurred Everest's
hatred for some fancied wrong.
Everest already had promised
to kill the judge.
Kill the judge?
Yes, he swore he'd do it
when the judge signed
the commitment papers.
(EXHALING)
Oh, Jean. Jean...
Get me the Hudson
Mental Hospital, upstate.
Make it fast.
(RINGING)
Hudson Mental Hospital.
Mr Crawford's gone home.
It's his birthday.
He left early.
You can reach him
at Hudson 421 .
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Hello? Hello?
Now, Henry,
you behave yourself.
That was someone calling
your daddy from New York.
I guess the wires
must have gone down.
-Ah, Mary.
-Just wait. You wait.
Phone's cut off.
Where's Judge Nesbitt
living now?
-Woodville.
-Woodville?
That's the place
that was marked
in the railroad
schedule that man had.
Get me Judge Nesbitt
in Woodville.
He has no telephone.
He has shut himself off
from the world.
Lieutenant, contact the police
at Hudson on the teletype.
Request them to go without delay
to Crawford's home
and seize a poisoned
birthday cake.
Tell them to order a doctor
and ambulance to stand by.
Also, contact the state patrol
division at Woodville and...
(INAUDIBLE)
It's lonely out here,
isn't it?
My friend likes it here.
He's a recluse.
Hope he doesn't mind our
bursting in on him like this.
I guarantee
he won't say a word.
I'll see if I can get a cab.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
CLERK:
Good evening.
Evening, folks.
EVEREST: I wonder if there's
any chance of getting a car.
Nope.
Where you going?
Up to Edward Nesbitt's place.
Oh. Old Judge Nesbitt?
You a friend of his?
Yes.
It's quite a spell up there.
Well, I wonder
if we could, er...
No. No chance, unless
you want to take my car.
Well, I'd be very glad to pay you.
Oh, no. We don't take money
for favours round here.
You're welcome to the car.
It's parked right there.
Just tell the old judge's servant
to bring it down in the morning
when he comes down
for the judge's newspaper.
-Well, thank you. You're very kind.
-You're welcome, sir.
Keys are in the car.
-Thank you.
-I'll join you in a second, George.
I want to send a wire to Francie.
She'll be more at ease
if she knows where I am.
-I'll wait in the car.
-All right.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(TURNS ON RADIO)
(CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYING)
ANNOUNCER: And now for news
on the national scene.
A police dragnet has been laid across
the entire length and breadth
of Markless County
in the state of New Jersey
in an effort to capture
a dangerous homicidal maniac,
William Everest,
who escaped a week ago
from the Hudson Mental Hospital
in New York State.
Known to be
accompanying the madman,
but unsuspecting
of his real identity,
is Jean Lang, twenty-five-year-old
department store buyer,
who had befriended the man
after he met with a slight accident
in New York City last night.
Searchers have been instructed
to shoot to kill the fugitive,
as he is said to be
extremely dangerous.
It is thought that...
(SWITCHING RADIO OFF)
Thank you, Mary.
(DOORBELL RINGING)
Somebody's gonna
get soppin' wet.
HENRY:
Now, Daddy, now?
Yes, Henry.
Mary's told me what a patient
little boy you've been.
Gee, ain't birthdays swell?
Mr Crawford! Mr Crawford!
Oh, no! Henry! Henry!
Oh, Mary, what's the matter?
Are you sure
we're on the right road?
Yes.
-Jean.
-Yes?
I know I can trust you.
Why, yes, George.
I need a friend with sympathy
and understanding.
You'll soon know who you are
and everything'll be fine.
That's right.
Nothing must stop me
from reaching Edward Nesbitt.
Nothing will.
-Yet, I'm-I'm worried.
-Why?
Suppose I do find out
who I am and I don't like it?
I mean, ever since the accident,
I've been someone else.
Suppose before it happened,
I had done something I shouldn't.
You mean, like a...
a crime?
Well, anything.
Will you believe me when
I tell you that, since I've known you,
that my whole life
has changed?
Do you trust me enough to give me
a chance to prove it?
Yes, George.
And it just came over
the teletype from New York.
This cake is filled with enough
poison to kill a dozen men.
I tried to get you
on the phone.
All the wires were down.
Are there any clues
to his whereabouts?
They think he's around Woodville,
over in Jersey.
Hmm.
Judge Nesbitt's living there.
Hope they've warned
the old fella.
Oh, you can count on that.
All the roads are blocked off,
and every state cop
in the county is out.
By the way,
why didn't you report it
when he first broke out
of the hospital?
Well, he'd shown such improvement
that we'd made him a trustee.
Doctors thought
his condition was quite good.
We'd been searching
for him ourselves,
but, as yet, we hadn't
informed the police.
Do you think he was
acting normal
just to get the trustee job
so he could break out easier?
Mmm, it's likely.
Certainly fooled us all
with his madman's cunning.
We found his uniform
under the porch outside.
He'd sneaked in here and
stolen one of my suits of clothes.
Well, I'm sure glad
I got here on time, Warden.
You're glad?
How do you think I feel?
(BOTH CHUCKLING)
(SIREN BLARING)
Good evening.
What's your name?
Where are you going?
Crawford. John Crawford.
I'm glad you men came along.
I'm afraid I'm lost.
Yeah? From what?
Well, I'm, er... looking for the
state police division station.
What for?
Well, I was asked to help in
the search of one of my patients.
OFFICER:
Oh.
-You're Mr Crawford from, er...
-EVEREST: Yes.
This is Miss Carroll,
one of my nurses.
Sorry to trouble you,
Mr Crawford,
but, er... have you
any identification?
Oh, no trouble.
Of course.
I...
Oh, here.
This is as good as anything.
Okay, Mr Crawford.
-Sorry to bother you.
-It's quite all right.
Station's about
five miles down the road.
You're off the track
on this side road.
Turn left at
the next crossroad.
That'll take you on to 66,
then just go straight ahead.
Thank you.
Thank you, gentlemen.
Okay, sir.
Good night, Miss Carroll.
My name isn't Carroll,
and I'm not a nurse.
Nothing is going to stop me
from reaching Edward Nesbitt.
What do you suppose
those policemen wanted?
Doesn't really matter,
as long as we weren't delayed.
That label in your pocket...
Who is John Crawford?
Just a name.
Is that his suit
you're wearing?
I wouldn't know, rightly.
It's his identification
label in the pocket. It...
must belong to him.
Possibly.
Where did you get it?
I don't remember, darling.
You know, there are so many things
that I don't remember.
I happened to glance at it
this morning.
How I got it,
where I got it,
who the man is,
I don't remember.
You showed
great presence of mind
in giving that name
to the policeman.
Found it on
the tip of my tongue.
It sounded almost rehearsed.
Oh, you're letting your imagination
run away with you, my dear.
The policeman acted as though
he knew the man
whose name you gave.
(CHUCKLING)
That's not at all probable.
When you said your name
was John Crawford,
he acted as though he knew
who John Crawford was.
There's nothing strange
in a common name
arousing a familiar memory
in a man, is there?
You gave the feeling, also,
that you expected him to know
who John Crawford was.
Oh, all this is
childish conjecture.
You think I'm lying to you?
We mustn't let
any little misunderstanding
come between us, darling.
We've come to mean too much
to each other for that.
Isn't that so?
Yup. That telegram was filed here
about thirty minutes ago, Sheriff.
Here's a copy of it.
Was there a man with her?
Yeah, mm-hmm.
Nice, easy-speakin' fella.
I lent him my car to go
up to Judge Nesbitt's place.
Him and that girl.
Well, it's them,
all right.
How'd you let 'em
get through?
Said he was Warden Crawford
of the Hudson Mental Hospital.
Showed identification, too.
We'd better get down
to the judge's place, fast.
And you too.
There's the house.
Our troubles
will all be over soon.
All over.
What are you thinking?
Things will all be changed
in a few minutes.
You'll know
all about yourself, and...
I'll know all about you.
Why are we waiting here?
EVEREST: This moment
is set apart from time.
I want to prolong it.
You know all
about yourself now, and...
you don't know
what you may be
after you see Mr Nesbitt.
Is that it, George?
Hudson Mental Hospit...!
You're hurting
my throat, George.
A wonderful throat.
A wonderful channel
through which
the inmost secrets
of the soul
-find freedom to the world.
-George!
Let it live, and it can
tell the world too much.
Destroy it, and its secrets
are locked forever
-from the ears of man.
-George!
(BRAKES SQUEALING)
It's Lem Jayson's car,
all right.
They must be around here.
Spread out, and beat around.
Now, blow your whistles
if you come upon anything.
(TWIG SNAPPING)
(RATTLING)
It won't do any good to hide,
my little sweetheart.
No good at all.
And there won't be
any pain, my dear.
One quick cut,
and it'll be over.
And your throat
will be quiet for evermore.
Oh, I'm very expert.
This knife is very sharp.
I'll be doing you
a great favour.
Look at it like that.
Oh, you'll be spared
so much of life's torments.
Come down, my darling.
Don't prolong your agony.
I'll take you where
it's calm and peaceful.
Why do you want to kill me?
I was your one friend.
I gave you shelter.
And I will return your kindness
and give you shelter from
the things which will destroy you.
I will keep you forever young.
Time and life are your enemies.
I am your friend.
(GROANING)
THE WHISTLER: In a city
full of strange adventures,
this, which happened
to Jean Lang,
has been one
of the most amazing.
Protected by
the resilience of youth,
Jean Lang will carry
no scars on her soul
from her encounter
with William Everest.
And, as time passes,
even the nightmare memory
will not disturb
her innocent sleep.
She will marry in time
a man destined for her
and live long and happily
in the fullness of her years.
I know, because
I am the Whistler.
SUBTITLES BY POWERHOUSE FILMS LTD