(MAN WHISTLING
"THE WHISTLER" THEME)
THE WHISTLER:
I am the Whistler,
and I know many things,
for I walk by night.
I know many strange tales
hidden in the hearts
of men and women
who have stepped
into the shadows.
Yes, I know
the nameless terrors
of which
they dare not speak.
And tonight,
in this obscure section
of a large city,
we find a woman shopping
for an unusual item.
Find anything you like?
Yes. I'll show you.
I want this one.
In marble.
Yes, ma'am, but
executed in marble,
it will be quite expensive
and, er...
around five thousand dollars,
and will require about
three months' work.
Three months?
That'll be all right.
And, er... what will the
inscription be, please?
Edith Marie Harrison,
beloved wife of Ralph Harrison.
Date of birth?
February fourth, 1901 .
Date of death?
I'm not sure yet.
You'll be notified.
And, er, what's your name,
please?
Edith Marie Harrison.
(CHATTERING)
-RALPH: Well, Jimmy!
-Hello, Ralph.
Welcome!
I don't think I've met Miss...
Kay, this is
Ralph Harrison, our host.
Ralph, this is Kay Morrell,
my favourite model.
RALPH: Well, this is
an unexpected pleasure.
Jim always did have
an eye for beauty.
Please go on.
I love flattery.
She isn't just kidding.
I'll take you to the oasis.
Ah! "Loaf of bread,
a jug of wine, and thou."
I'll settle for a tall drink.
Ralph!
Linda! Excuse me.
Well, good to see you.
Meet the boyfriend.
Joe Conroy.
Oh, the super columnist!
This is a pleasure.
The pleasure's all mine,
Mr Harrison.
Well, the bar's over there,
eats are there.
Just go to it.
-Thank you.
-Thanks.
(WALTZ PLAYING)
(MUSIC STOPS)
(UPBEAT JAZZ PLAYING)
Shall we dance?
Why not?
(PHONE RINGING)
You know, I've only
known you five minutes,
and I've got you
in my arms already.
So?
Well, it's very nice.
Your phone's ringing, Ralph.
Oh, so it is.
Excuse me.
Hurry back.
Ralph Harrison speaking.
Yes, Laura.
Your wife has just had
another heart attack,
worse than any of the others.
I've sent for Dr Winthrop.
I'll be right home.
(ROMANTIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(MUSIC STOPS)
Say, folks, I'm awfully sorry,
but I have to leave
for a little while, but...
I'll be back soon.
Just carry on.
(MUSIC CONTINUES)
Wonder where he's going.
Who cares?
Nobody's gonna miss him.
You took the words
right out of my mouth.
I don't see why
everybody picks on him.
I think he's rather nice.
(BOTH CHUCKLING)
Why do you attend his parties
if you don't like him?
Why not? Somebody's gotta help
drink his liquor and eat his food.
It's too good to pass up.
That, my friend, is one
of Ralph's paintings.
JOE: What the devil
do you call that?
Or am I showing
a colossal ignorance of art?
That is the ultra of...
something or other.
He calls it
Autumn Symphony.
You mean he actually
sells things like that?
(CHUCKLING)
No. He doesn't have to.
His wife gives him
all the money he needs.
(MOUTHING)
How is she?
Well, don't stand there
staring at me.
You'll have to ask the doctor.
He's up there with her now.
Well, what brought on
the attack?
She was all right at dinner.
She left the house
shortly after you did.
And?
And she returned
about an hour later
in a highly nervous state.
The attack came on while
she was getting ready for bed.
She say where she'd been?
No, and Jules didn't drive her.
She took a taxi.
What's the good
having a doctor
if she won't take his advice?
I pleaded with her not to go,
but she said it was urgent.
I'd like to speak to you
privately, Mr Harrison.
Come in here.
I'm afraid her life expectancy
will be very limited.
A few months, perhaps,
maybe only weeks.
Well, I couldn't
get along without her.
Isn't there anything
you can do?
There's no cure for
a condition such as hers.
You'd better go up now,
before the sedative I gave her
puts her to sleep.
There'll be a nurse here
presently, and I...
She'll follow my instructions.
(DOOR CLOSING)
Darling.
Hello, Ralph.
I'm sorry I had to
send for you.
I hope they
didn't frighten you.
I'm terribly sorry I wasn't here
when you needed me.
You shouldn't have
gone out tonight, darling.
Supposing you were taken ill
when you were away from home?
Please take better care
of yourself, for my sake
as well as your own.
I won't do anything
foolish again. I promise.
Fred, how about getting me
some breakfast?
Sure will, Mr Harrison.
Fruit juice and a large pot
of black coffee.
Yes, sir.
(SIGHING)
-Hi, Jim.
-Hi.
-Hello, Kay.
-Hello.
Oh, don't look so sour.
I'm only gonna stay
for a minute.
I, er...
wanted to return this.
You left it at
the studio last night.
Thank you, Ralph.
By the way, Jim,
I'd like to borrow Kay,
when you're through with her,
for a while. I, er...
I've looked all over
for a model like her.
I don't know when
I'll finish with her.
Fibber.
You said you'd be through
with me this afternoon.
Well, any time.
I'm in no hurry.
Whenever she's available.
It's a deal.
I'll drop over soon as
Jim is fed up with me.
That's what I wanted to hear.
Well, goodbye, Jim.
Why did you agree
to pose for him?
Well, I have to earn
a living, don't I?
Yeah, but you don't
have to pose
for a slap-and-dab
painter like him.
Where's your pride?
I can't eat pride, darling.
Besides, you said yourself
he pays double the scale.
Well, so what?
You want that beautiful
face of yours
featured in some, er... delirium
like his Autumn Symphony?
(CHUCKLING)
Couldn't be that
you're jealous, could it?
All right. So I am.
I saw the way he went
for you last night.
Don't worry, darling.
He's just a pigeon to me.
Well, maybe so,
but you be careful.
If he gets fresh, why,
threaten to tell his wife.
That'll stop him quick.
If he loses that meal ticket,
he'll have to go back making
sketches at the fairground.
Well, you finally managed
to get here, I see.
Don't pick on me, Mac.
I had a rough night.
I thought you were old
enough to know better.
I am, but Linda
dragged me along
to one of those artist shindigs.
I got a tip on a story here
that's right down your alley.
Yeah? Give.
Recall that unidentified stiff
the coast guard pulled out
of the bay, several months ago?
Yeah, but spare the details.
My stomach is doing
nip-ups already.
Well, Mr X's grave in Potter's Field
now bears a magnificent monument
instead of a numbered marker.
What does it say
on the inscription?
That's the point.
There is no inscription.
Well, that means
somebody identified him
-but didn't want it known.
-Right.
Think I need a little fresh air.
I don't know the name of the
firm that set up the monument.
You ask Parker.
He discovered it.
Thanks, Mac.
Yes, I'll take care of it
right away.
Thank you. Goodbye.
Good morning, sir.
Are you interested
in selecting a memorial?
No, but I am interested
in finding out
who purchased
the beautiful edifice
for that nameless grave
in Potter's Field.
I'm Conroy
of the News-Tribune.
Oh, well, I'm afraid
I can't give you the answer.
You see, we don't know
the name of the purchaser.
How come?
Well, it happened like this.
The order came in the mail
signed "A Friend".
Enclosed with it were twenty-five
one-hundred-dollar bills,
so we filled the order.
It's none of our business
if the friend wishes
to remain anonymous.
Well, certainly not,
but buying a monument
without giving an inscription
sounds screwy to me.
Those sort of things are
common in our business.
Why, only last night,
a woman came in here
shopping for a tombstone.
She'd picked out one of those
"big gates ajar" numbers,
and when I asked her
for the inscription,
she said,
"Edith Marie Harrison,
"beloved wife
of Ralph Harrison."
Ralph Harrison?
Yes.
Do you know him?
I know an artist
by that name.
Well, anyhow, when I
asked her for her name,
she said, "Edith Marie Harrison,"
just like that.
Never batted an eye.
You mean she bought
the monument for herself?
Why, yes.
Isn't that one for the book?
Yeah.
Mm-hmm.
You may have ten minutes
with your husband now.
Oh, how nice.
If you promise to
control your emotions.
I will.
Miss Bailey, would you
please bring me a lipstick
and my diary
from the desk drawer.
Now, now, now. You will have
plenty of time for your diary
-when I permit you to sit up.
-All right.
Let's see how much you can
improve by my next visit, huh?
I will.
-Goodbye.
-Goodbye, Dr Winthrop.
We'll continue
the same medication
-for the next twenty-four hours.
-Yes, Doctor.
You may see her now,
but make it brief.
And wipe that worried look
from your face before you go in.
(KNOCKING)
-Well, darling.
-Dearest.
Oh, I'm so glad you're better.
You know, I didn't sleep
last night, worrying about you.
You're such a dear.
And all the lovely flowers.
Thank you very much.
What did the doctor say?
Oh, he's convinced that
you'll recover completely.
But you're going to have to stay
in bed, perhaps for weeks.
I was afraid he'd say that.
What difference does that make?
We'll make it up
by taking a trip somewhere.
We'll make believe
we're on our honeymoon again.
That'll be wonderful, Ralph.
You better rest a while, Kay.
I'll get you a cold drink.
-There you are.
-Thank you.
You're a most
considerate employer.
Thank you.
Penny for your thoughts.
Oh, they're not worth a penny.
As a matter of fact, I'm not
in the mood for sketching.
What do you generally do
to get in the mood?
Oh, go to Montmartre,
have lunch,
listen to the gypsy music.
Why don't you try it again?
I can find something around here
to do in the meantime.
I want you to go with me.
Oh?
Maybe your wife
wouldn't like it.
Oh, she's not
that conventional.
Well, I am a bit hungry.
Good. Let's go.
(BAND PLAYING LIGHT MUSIC)
What's troubling you, Ralph?
You seem to be brooding
over something.
Oh...
I don't want to bore you
with my troubles.
It might make you feel better
if you got it off your chest.
Well, when I left my party
the other night,
I was called home.
My wife had suffered
her second heart attack.
Oh, how awful!
I came back to the party later
'cause there wasn't anything
I could do.
In fact, I'm afraid there isn't
anything anyone can do.
No wonder you couldn't work.
It must have taken a lot
of courage even to attempt it.
You don't know
the strain it's been,
living day to day,
not knowing what moment
I'll get word that she's
had another attack or...
passed on.
Poor soul.
Think of the strain on her, too,
knowing she's only living
on borrowed time.
Yes, it's getting me down.
Isn't there any chance
for her to get well?
Doctor says not.
That's why
I need companionship,
trying to forget.
I'm so glad you told me,
Ralph.
I only wish there was something
I could do to help you.
There is.
If you'd just be my friend,
dine with me occasionally,
let me confide in you.
It would help a lot.
Left hand for friendship.
Hiya, kitten!
Hi!
Come on, peel off
that Eskimo parka.
I'm taking you to a place
where they make crêpes Suzettes
that are out of this world.
What? At this hour?
It's after twelve.
So what? Suzettes always taste
better along toward morning,
seeing as how they're pancakes.
Come on, come on.
(CHUCKLING)
All right, I'll go,
but you're bringing me
right back after the Suzettes.
No gallivanting around
till dawn. Understand?
-Cross my heart.
-(CHUCKLING)
Say, Linda,
this is a nice job,
this magazine cover
you're doing.
Thank you, Joseph Aloysius.
Your model must have
been a raving beauty.
Did I ever meet her?
You did not.
You're not gonna get
a chance to, either.
(BOTH CHUCKLING)
That's how I lost
my last boyfriend.
Say, wasn't that the model you
said Calhoun was crazy about?
Yes! Kay Morrell.
Maybe Harrison ought to be
painting barns instead of pictures,
but he isn't so dumb
at picking a nifty dish.
Well, I'm not so sure
he did the picking.
Oh?
Kay had a little larceny
in her make-up.
I know, because
she posed for me.
I wonder if she knows
what I know.
Knows what?
Remind me sometime
to tell you the story
the story of
a tombstone salesman.
Ooh!
How do I look?
Perfectly beautiful,
but you always look adorable.
Thank you, Ralph.
Did I take too long
dressing?
-No. We've got all kinds of time.
-(DOOR BUZZING)
I wonder who that is?
-Miss Kay Morrell?
-Yes?
Sign this,
please.
Look what I got.
And it's from you.
You darling!
Like it?
Oh, I'm crazy about it.
It's the most beautiful gift
I've ever received,
but I can't accept it
from you.
Why not?
You know why.
I appreciate your
thoughtfulness, Ralph, but...
I'm sure you'll think much
more of me for not accepting it.
I have no right to say this,
but I've grown to care
a great deal for you.
If I were free,
I would ask you to marry me.
How would you feel
about that?
I had no idea
you cared that much for me.
But you're not free, Ralph,
so let's not even
think about it.
We'll just be friends.
If we don't hurry, we'll be
late for the theatre.
Systolic,
a hundred and fifty-five.
Diastolic,
a hundred and four.
I don't seem to have
any strength.
Well, don't be discouraged.
Your weakness is due
mainly to, er... inactivity.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Goodbye.
It was nice meeting you,
Mrs Harrison.
Thank you, Dr Gunther.
I hope you can help me.
I'm sure I can.
Goodbye.
I'd like to see
a cardiograph of her.
-I presume you have one?
-Several.
I'll show them to you when
we get back to the office.
Good.
Mr Harrison's waiting
to see you in the study.
Thank you.
Mr Harrison, this is Dr Gunther.
-How do you do, Mr Harrison?
-How do you do?
Dr Gunther is a specialist.
-I brought him in for a consultation.
-Good idea.
I believe he'd be able to do
Mrs Harrison some good.
He's been achieving
remarkable results
with heart cases
such as hers.
Well, I'd give anything
if you could help my wife.
Mmm, I'll do all I can.
You may be sure of that.
Let's all hope for the best.
Well, goodbye, Mr Harrison.
-Goodbye.
THE WHISTLER: You're quite concerned,
aren't you, Ralph?
If Dr Gunther can
make Edith well again,
it'll spoil all your plans.
You know you're only waiting
and hoping for her to die
so you'll be free
to marry Kay.
(DOORBELL BUZZING)
Hello.
Well, the queen herself.
Come in.
Miss me?
Don't tell me Ralph's
finished with you.
Ha ha. Finished?
He hasn't even started.
Well, what have you been
doing all this time?
Well, I've posed as
a Mexican peasant woman
and a Chinese sing-song girl,
lady of the harem...
I can't imagine
what I'll be next.
Don't ever let him
see you on a horse.
He'll want to paint you
as Lady Godiva.
(CHUCKLING)
Very funny.
I don't know
what to make of him.
He never finishes
anything he starts.
-Cigarette?
-Thanks.
He's just stalling
to keep you there.
This reminds me.
I bought you something
the other day.
I'm tired of you offering me
cigarettes with the bends.
Am I, er,
to consider this a reward
for introducing you
to Harrison?
It's the general idea.
Doing all right
for yourself, huh?
Well, what started out
as a routine job
has possibilities now of
turning into a career.
Maybe so.
Careers don't always last.
Pigeons can fly away.
Now, if I were you, Kay,
I wouldn't give up
all my old friends
before I made sure that I
wouldn't have to
fall back on them someday.
Don't worry, darling.
Little Kay isn't going
to burn her bridges.
Well, thanks for
your interest.
Bye, Jimmy.
Mrs Harrison!
I've been walking
a little every morning
for the past ten days.
We've been keeping it
a secret.
I'm so happy
to see you up again!
And tell her
the rest, Doctor.
Mrs Harrison has
improved so remarkably
that she isn't going to
need a nurse any longer.
Really?
And, best of all, I'm going to
get dressed and go out.
Laura, find me
something nice to wear.
Oh, yes!
But don't overdo
yourself, please?
I won't.
I'll say goodbye now.
I hope you keep on
getting better every day.
Thank you, Miss Bailey.
You've been very nice,
and I do appreciate it.
DR GUNTHER: I'll be back
for a check-up next Wednesday.
Now, please be sure
and continue
to take your medicine
regularly.
-Don't worry. I will.
-Good.
-Goodbye.
Well, good afternoon,
Mrs Harrison!
Hello, George.
Mr Harrison's been telling me
how sick you've been.
It's mighty nice
to see you out again.
-Mighty nice to be out.
-Yes, ma'am.
(DOORBELL BUZZING)
George, I guess Mr Harrison
hasn't come back from lunch.
-Will you let me in?
-Oh, I'd be glad to.
-There you are.
-Thank you.
And George, if you happen
to see Mr Harrison,
don't tell him I'm here.
I want to surprise him.
I gotcha.
(DOOR BEING UNLOCKED)
(DOOR OPENING)
Why do you want to
quit modelling for me?
You know why.
All you've been doing
is making sketches of me
in different costumes.
You haven't finished
one of them.
I might as well be
posing for a skywriter.
Well, what difference
does that make?
You're getting paid.
Besides, I like to
have you near me.
I love you more than
anything in the world.
KAY: You have no right
to say such things.
RALPH: Well, you told me
that you cared for me.
Why, you even inferred that,
if I were free,
you'd marry me.
But you're not free.
Well, if you'll only wait
a little while, I will be.
And I'll devote my whole life
to make you happy.
Sorry, Ralph, but you'd
better forget about me.
Oh, don't say that, Kay.
I couldn't go on without you.
Well, I haven't got time
to argue about it now.
Give me a ring
tomorrow or the next day.
Oh, Kay, wait.
Kay, listen.
I gotta talk to you.
Mrs Harrison!
What's the matter?
Miss Vail.
Oh, come to my studio,
and I-I'll call a doctor.
No, no, please.
I'll be all right.
Are you sure?
You're so welcome
to come in and lie down.
No, thank you very much. I'd...
I'd rather go home.
You see, this is my first day out,
and I'm still rather weak.
Well, we'll take you
to your car.
Thank you.
How's Mrs Harrison?
She wants to see you.
(KNOCKING)
Come in.
Darling!
Why, you're actually
up and dressed?
Well, when did this happen?
This morning.
Well, what a pleasant surprise.
Why didn't you tell me?
Well, you don't know
how glad I am.
What's the matter,
darling?
Stop acting, Ralph.
There's nothing quite so
contemptible as a hypocrite.
A hypocrite?
How... How am I going to
defend myself
if I don't know
what you're talking about?
You have no defence
for what you've done to me.
But what have I done?
You destroyed all the love
and respect I ever had for you.
It was such a nice day.
I took a ride this afternoon.
I was so happy
to be out again.
I'd been thinking for days
how glad you'd be
that I was getting well.
I stopped at your studio...
but you were out.
So I had the porter
let me in.
I wanted to surprise you.
But the surprise was on me.
I was there
in the dressing room
when you came in
with her.
Well...
I'm glad you found out
about it, in a way.
I've been wanting to tell you,
but I didn't know how.
I guess it was the worry
about you night and day, and...
the loneliness without you.
I wanted companionship,
and she led me on.
Oh, stop lying, Ralph!
It's perfectly obvious
that I'm standing
in the way of your romance.
That you're even hoping
that I'll die
-so that you'll be free to have her.
-That's not true.
I don't think
you ever loved me.
I've just been a convenience
with a chequebook.
I still love you.
I swear I do.
I despise you
for what you are.
And you shan't have
another penny of my money.
Edith...
Edith,
everyone makes mistakes.
I'll make it up to you
if you'll give me a chance.
You may use the studio
temporarily, until you find another.
Or perhaps
you'd rather go back
to peddling
your silly caricatures?
If you wish to get in touch
with me in the future,
please do so through
Mr Loring, my attorney.
And now, will you go?
(PHONE CLICKING)
This is Edith Harrison. May I
please speak to Mr Loring?
WOMAN: I'm sorry, but Mr Loring
and his wife have gone out,
and I don't expect
them back until late.
Any message?
Yes. Will you ask him
to call me when he comes in?
Please tell him it's urgent.
Yes, ma'am. I'll be glad to.
Goodbye.
Laura!
Laura?
Yes?
Mrs Harrison and I have
had a slight misunderstanding.
I'll stay at my studio
for a few days.
Will you forward
my mail to me there?
Yes, sir.
(ENGINE STARTING)
(DOOR LATCH CLICKING)
(PHONE RINGING)
Harrison residence.
This is Henry Loring.
I'm returning Mrs Harrison's call.
She said it was urgent
and to phone her
as soon as I came home.
Oh, then I'd better
call her, Mr Loring.
Just hold the wire.
Mrs Harrison?
Mrs Harrison! Mrs Harrison!
Mr Loring.
Something terrible's happened.
I found Mrs Harrison
lying on the floor,
and I can't rouse her.
Where's her husband?
I see.
Then you'd better call
her doctor,
and I'll try and locate
Mr Harrison.
Yes, thank you, Mr Loring.
I'll call Dr Gunther
right away.
(GLASS CLINKING)
THE WHISTLER: You're not getting
unnerved, are you, Ralph?
Setting the stage
was comparatively easy.
But what now?
Has your wife taken
the medicine and, er...
did the doctor believe
she died from natural causes?
It's the uncertainty
of not knowing
that's getting you down.
Too bad you can't phone
your home.
No. There's nothing
to do but wait.
A lot of things
could have happened
since you left the house.
Maybe Loring
got in touch with Edith
and she had him
cut you out of her will.
(DOORBELL BUZZING)
Yes? Hello?
(BUZZING)
Who's there?
Henry Loring.
Well, this is
quite a surprise.
I don't think you've
ever been here before.
I just came by
to give you a message,
and I'm afraid
it's not very good news.
What do you mean?
Your wife has had
a relapse.
The housekeeper
found her in a coma
on the floor
of her bedroom.
Well, why didn't Laura
call me?
She was too upset
to even talk coherently,
so I volunteered
to come after you.
Well...
I'm sorry, Mr Harrison,
but you're too late.
Did she suffer any?
She was dead
when I arrived.
I don't understand.
She was doing so nicely.
I thought she was
gonna get well.
In cases like hers,
one never knows when
a relapse can be expected.
I'd like to be alone,
if you don't mind.
I'm sorry.
I understand
how you must feel.
-Good night.
And if I can be
of further service,
have Mr Harrison
get in touch with me.
Yes, Mr Loring.
If Dr Winthrop had continued
treating Edith,
-she'd be alive today.
-How can you say that?
Dr Winthrop admitted he'd
done all he could for her.
He was too ethical
to experiment.
I've a good notion to have
Dr Gunther's medicines analysed.
I've thrown them all out.
What right had you to
touch Edith's medicines?
-I was acting under orders.
-Whose orders?
Dr Gunther's. He told me
to dispose of them.
Oh. So, that's it.
What a clever way to
cover up one's mistakes.
If you feel that way
about it,
why don't you go
to the Zenith Pharmacy?
Every one of his prescriptions
is on file there right now.
Maybe I will.
Before you do,
remember this.
She was doing fine
until she went to your studio
to surprise you.
THE WHISTLER:
Three months have passed
since the mortal remains
of Edith Harrison,
reduced to ashes,
were consigned to a niche
in a cemetery crypt.
Time has stilled Ralph's fears
that the finger of suspicion
will ever be pointed at him.
Home at last, darling.
I was hoping the honeymoon
would never end.
It won't.
We won't let it.
I wish we didn't have to
come back to this house.
While we were away, I had it
refurnished and redecorated.
It's all brand new.
You're such a dear.
Charles, put the car
in the garage
and take the luggage
upstairs.
Yes, Mrs Harrison.
Oh, Laura.
This is Mrs Harrison.
It's nice meeting you,
Laura.
How do you do?
Dinner will be served
whenever you're ready.
Thank you, Laura.
She resents me, Ralph.
Oh, don't pay any
attention to her. (CHUCKLING)
She's a part
of the past, isn't she?
Yes. She worked
for Edith for years.
Why don't you
get rid of her?
Well, I'd like to,
but Edith had it in her will
that she was to have
employment and a home here
as long as she lives.
Oh, don't think about it.
I'll take care of it later.
I want to show you
the house.
Well, what do you think?
Lovely.
It couldn't be more perfect.
I'm so glad you like it.
(KNOCKING)
Come in.
Yes, Laura.
Here's the mail that came
while you were away.
Oh, thanks.
Excuse me, darling.
Anything wrong, dear?
Oh, no, no. It's a bill for
something Edith ordered
that I didn't know
anything about.
Let's go down to
dinner, huh?
All right.
(LIGHT MUSIC PLAYING)
Good day, sir.
Come in, please.
I hope I'm not too late.
Not at all, sir.
-Kay.
-KAY: Hello, Joe.
-Ralph.
-I'm glad you could come.
I'm sorry I'm late, but you know
how it is, working for a newspaper.
You're only one drink behind,
and we'll fix that right up.
Hiya, Linda.
LINDA: Well, what kept you
so late, Mr Conroy? A woman?
Well, it was
a woman at that.
Or perhaps I should say
Exhibit A
in a slight case of murder.
Who got the axe this time?
Mrs Blanche Bennett.
Only it happened to be a .45-calibre slug
that did the business, not an axe.
Mmm.
I thought a burglar shot her.
That's what
the police thought, too,
until a smart cop from
Homicide named Higgins
discovered that Bennett had been
running around for some time
with another woman.
Well, is that sufficient proof
that Bennett killed her?
No, but it's
a darn good motive.
Bennett?
What Bennett is that?
James Bennett,
the hotel man.
Oh.
The story broke while you and
Kay were on your honeymoon.
Anyway, Bennett
was arrested this morning,
and I happen to know the D.A.'s
preparing an indictment
charging him
with premeditated murder.
(GLASS THUDDING)
Oh, I'm terribly sorry.
I hope I haven't
ruined your dress.
LINDA:
Oh, think nothing of it.
I shall just sue you for
damages, Ralph Harrison.
Go ahead.
Everybody sues the rich.
By the way, Ralph.
What did you ever do
with that gravestone?
Gravestone?
Yeah. The one from
the Curtis Monument Company.
Oh, that.
Why, I paid for it,
and told 'em to keep it.
Joe, I'd like you
to meet some people.
Excuse me.
What are you doing
out here, Ralph?
Oh, just having a smoke.
I couldn't sleep.
Anything troubling you?
No, not a thing.
Ralph...
Yes?
What did Joe Conroy mean
when he asked you
about that gravestone?
He was referring
to a monument
that Edith
had ordered for herself.
Then you didn't know
she'd expected to be buried.
We didn't discuss such things.
I didn't know anything
about the monument
till I got a bill for it.
Too bad she never told you
about it, don't you think?
Kay, please.
Let's not discuss it.
I'm sorry.
Didn't you get any
sleep last night, dear?
RALPH: Guess I ate
too much at the party.
Never again.
"Bennett confesses
to murder.
"Breaks down after
hours of questioning.
"After sticking steadfastly
to his plea of innocence,
"Bennett suddenly
broke down
"and confessed to
the murder of his wife
"when confronted with
the damaging evidence
"contained in her diary.
"Entries in Mrs Bennett's
handwriting
"gave new testimony
to the fact
"that he tried to force her
by threats to divorce him
"so he could marry
another woman.
"They also spoke
of her growing fear
"that he was planning
to kill her."
Oh! How awful it must
be for a wife to suspect
that her husband
is planning to kill her.
Mm-hmm.
Why do you hate me,
Laura?
I've never done you
any harm.
Ralph Harrison's
love for you
is what caused
Edith's death.
But why blame me?
I certainly did nothing
to encourage Ralph
while she was still alive.
You didn't waste any time
after she was gone.
Well, why should I?
I was tired
of fighting for a living
and marriage to him
meant security.
You have no right
to ease and luxury
provided by her money.
I have the right
of every wife
to share her husband's
worldly goods.
He only married her
for her money,
and then he waited
for her to die,
so he could get himself a younger
and more attractive woman.
Stop it, Laura!
I won't allow you to say
such things about my husband.
-They're not true.
-You don't have to believe me.
Ask Mr Loring.
He'll tell you that she phoned him
the night she died.
What are you driving at?
She was going to
change her will.
If Loring had been in
that night,
your husband would be
a pauper today.
Why are you
telling me all this?
Everyone thinks she died
of another heart attack.
Well, I'm not so sure.
I won't listen to
another word.
Ralph isn't
that kind of a man.
Besides,
if you had any proof,
you'd tell the district attorney,
not me.
Believe what you like.
You have to live with him.
But the police
were certain, too,
that a burglar
killed Mrs Bennett.
And her husband would
have gotten away with murder
if they hadn't found
her diary.
Edith Harrison
kept a diary, too.
LAURA:
What are you looking for?
KAY:
I don't really know, but...
what you told me
a while ago made me think.
So, you're beginning
to suspect, as I do,
that he killed Edith.
Don't say that.
If I thought he did,
I'd be afraid to stay
with him another day.
Do you think
I've liked staying here,
believing him a murderer?
I only did it in the hope of
finding some way to make him pay
for all the suffering
he caused her.
That sounds too awful
to believe.
Can't you see that he acts like
a man with a guilty conscience?
Well, he has been
acting rather strangely,
now that you mentioned it.
Laura, whatever became
of Mrs Harrison's medicines?
I threw them out.
-All of them?
-Why, of c...
No, come to think of it,
there was one bottle
I couldn't find,
one of those special prescriptions
that you can't have refilled.
I wonder what
happened to it?
Mrs Harrison was supposed
to take another dose at nine o'clock
the night she passed away,
nearly an hour after
Mr Harrison left the house.
No wonder he blamed
Dr Gunther for her death.
What do you mean?
He claimed he wanted to have
all of her medicines analysed.
until I told him
I'd thrown them out.
Don't you see?
He was looking for that bottle.
Then Edith must have
hidden it somewhere.
Yes! Yes, it must be here
amongst all the things
they brought up
from her bedroom.
Well, come in.
What's the matter, Kay?
You look like
you've seen a ghost.
Has Ralph been here today?
No. I haven't seen him
for quite a while.
Please lock the door. I don't
want him to know I'm here.
Now, look. I don't wanna
get mixed up
in any of your domestic troubles.
I've got enough to worry about.
It's nothing like that,
believe me.
I need advice, and you're the
only friend I can turn to.
Okay, but remember,
I'm not pulling any chestnuts
out of the fire for you.
You won't have to.
Jim, I'm frightened.
I think I'm married
to a murderer.
-What?!
-I think Ralph poisoned Edith.
Are you crazy?
You know she died
of a heart attack.
I'm not so sure about that.
He could easily put
something in her medicine.
Well, now,
why would he do that?
She was dying anyway,
wasn't she?
No. She was getting well.
Oh.
Well, you haven't
any proof against him.
Maybe I have.
I found this hidden away in
Edith's knitting bag in the attic,
and I think
there's poison in it.
"Take one teaspoonful
every three hours."
When was it she died?
The twenty-sixth of last May.
And this prescription's
dated May sixteenth.
Hmm. Maybe you've
got something, Kay.
How do I go about
having it analysed?
I didn't know you were
that cold-blooded.
What do you
expect me to do?
Go on living with a murderer
and take a chance on him
killing me, too?
No, I guess not.
I don't want you
to get mixed up in this.
I know the fella to handle it
for you. Joe Conroy.
THE WHISTLER: So your fears
have been revived.
You're wondering why everyone
speaks so pointedly to you
about the Bennett case.
Why Kay was so upset
when she found out
about the monument.
But, above all,
you can't forget that diary.
What if Edith left behind
some entry
that would incriminate you?
Laura?
LAURA:
I'm in the dining room.
Has Mrs Harrison come in
since I've phoned?
No, sir.
I thought it looked phoney
when he had Edith cremated
after she'd ordered
a gravestone for herself.
Yes, and that's what
started me wondering.
Does, er... cremation actually destroy
all evidence of poison?
No, that's a popular fallacy.
Quite a few killers
have been convicted
by a handful of ashes.
Well, it won't take long
to have this analysed.
You'll hear from me, Kay,
probably tonight.
There you are, darling.
Thank you, dear.
I'm glad to see you're
feeling so much better.
I never felt better
in my life.
In fact, I feel
too good to stay home.
Let's go out and have dinner
and do the town.
What do you say?
I wish I felt up to it, but...
I couldn't have any fun
with this splitting headache.
Oh, I'm terribly sorry.
I'd forgotten about that.
I think I'll run upstairs
and take something for it.
Maybe you'll feel
like it later, huh?
Maybe.
(PHONE RINGING)
Hello? Yes, this is Kay.
Is he there?
He's downstairs,
so it's all right to talk.
You were right, Kay.
He poisoned her.
The police are on their way
now to pick him up,
so make sure he doesn't
leave the house.
I'll meet you at the D.A.'s office
when they bring him in.
All right.
(REPLACING RECEIVER)
KAY:
Where are you going, dear?
I thought I'd have
a little fling for myself.
I feel much better since
I took that headache powder.
I'd love to go along
if you still want me to.
Swell. We'll do a round
of the night spots.
Yes, and maybe we'll meet
the milkman on the way home.
Yeah.
I've often wondered
what he looked like.
Who were you talking to
on the phone just now?
Oh, that was Linda.
She wants us to have dinner
tomorrow night.
Well, I'll powder and be ready
in a jiffy, darling.
Wait a minute.
How about a little kiss,
sweetheart?
It's too bad you're
such a liar and a cheat.
I heard you talking
on the phone.
(STRANGLED CRY)
(SIREN BLARING)
(BODY THUDDING)
MAN #1 :
Stop!
He's not seriously hurt,
but call an ambulance anyway.
MAN #2: The woman's dead
from strangulation.
I found this on her.
MAN #1 : This would have
saved Harrison's neck,
but it won't do him
any good now.
(THE WHISTLER
WHISTLING HIS THEME)
SUBTITLES BY POWERHOUSE FILMS LTD