(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(MAN WHISTLING
"THE WHISTLER" THEME)
THE WHISTLER:
I am the Whistler,
and I know many things,
for I walk by night.
I know many strange tales
hidden in the hearts
of men and women
who have
stepped into the shadows.
Yes, I know the nameless terrors
of which they dare not speak.
(BRAKES SQUEALING)
And here tonight,
driving through
this rainswept countryside,
are two young people
about to embark
on the greatest venture
of their lives.
Whether for better or for worse,
only time will tell.
(THUNDERCLAP)
According to that sign,
we should be there any minute.
That's nice, chéri.
But it's also nice
driving in the rain like this.
Cut off from everything...
the past, the future.
Future?
Oh, no, darling, not the future.
-The future is us.
-I didn't mean it that way.
It's the isolation,
the feeling that
you're in a world of your own,
that makes me happy.
But when I'm with you, Ted,
I always feel that way,
rain or shine, day or night.
You're wonderful.
Well, Alice, in a few minutes,
you'll be Mrs Theodore
Anthony Nichols the Second.
-Of New York and Paris!
-(CHUCKLING)
-Are you nervous?
-Yes, but only a little.
-What can I do for you?
-As if you didn't know.
Oh, dear, I'm afraid
you're going to be disappointed.
Oh, but come in
out of the rain anyway.
I'm sorry.
The justice isn't home.
Oh, but I phoned this afternoon
and made an appointment.
-Are you Mr Nichols?
-Yes, that's right.
I remember your call.
I told my husband about it.
He had to go to Gantville this
afternoon on legal business.
Oh, we don't mind
waiting a while.
He won't be back tonight.
He phoned a half-hour ago
and said he wouldn't think
of driving through this rain.
But what will we do?
(THUNDERCLAP)
Now, take my advice and stop
over at the hotel in Marston.
It's just a few miles
down the road.
I'm sure the justice
will be back early tomorrow.
He'd be glad
to accommodate you.
Well, we'll see.
Good night, Mrs Hulskamp.
-Good night.
(ENGINE SPUTTERING)
-Is something wrong?
-I hope not.
Maybe the spark plugs
or something got a little wet.
(BRAKES SQUEALING)
Looks like the end of the line.
This is a pretty lame ending
to a wedding night.
Things could be worse, chéri.
No, but we can't
stay here all night.
I feel very comfortable...
and tired.
Well, we've gotta
get the car fixed
so we can go and be
married tomorrow.
Mm-hmm.
Look, Alice, that's the place.
Come on. You're gonna get
a good night's rest.
I'll get the bags.
Can't do a thing for you, mister.
Oh, have a heart.
You can't brush us off like that.
No use going into a long story.
We're just plumb full-up,
and that's the end of it.
Please, monsieur,
we've driven such a long time.
Too bad, ma'am. We ain't got
space left to board a mouse,
let alone you two.
Er... Well, er, is there another place
you can send us to?
No, it's the only place in town,
so I guess you best
keep moving on.
But we can't.
My car broke down.
Smitty's Garage
is five blocks down the street.
He'll be glad to fix it for ya,
if he ain't asleep
or drunk.
Well, thanks for your trouble,
anyway. Come along, darling.
Oh, just a minute, young fella.
I just recollected.
There is a room.
But it's in bad shape.
Oh, that's okay,
just so long as it's a room.
-Well, that'll be twenty dollars.
-What?
Giving you this room is risky.
Risky for me.
We can dispense with that.
Carry your own bags.
I get little enough thanks
for my job as it is
without having to be a bellhop.
Not exactly my idea
of a bridal suite.
It ain't meant to be.
I'll get you some bedding.
This chair isn't too bad.
I guess sleeping in it
one night won't kill me.
Nothing wrong with the bed.
It's big enough for two.
Oh.
-You two are married, ain't you?
-Well, er, not yet. But we...
-Not yet? Come on, you!
-Oh, no!
If he doesn't stay,
I don't stay.
Oh, suit yourself. I ain't gonna
stick my neck out no further.
Now, it's all right, darling.
I'll get forty winks in the garage
while the mechanic
fixes the car.
That's where we should have stayed.
Together, in the car.
Oh, I thought we'd never
be separated again.
Now, honey,
it's only till tomorrow.
-You're right, chéri.
-That's the spirit.
Well, you might at least turn around
while I kiss my bride-to-be good night.
Well, make it fast.
I've got work to do.
Good night, darling.
Good night, chéri.
Sleep tight.
Foreigner, ain't she?
She's French,
if it's any of your business.
Seems to me
Yankee women is trouble enough
without getting tangled up
with foreigners.
Mind if I leave this here
while I look after my car?
I ain't gonna be responsible.
Better take it along with you.
Um, aren't you forgetting
about the bedding?
Sure enough.
Dang busybody.
Never know what to expect next.
THE WHISTLER:
This isn't just the way
you'd planned your honeymoon,
is it, Ted?
But don't be too unhappy.
It's only a few more hours
till you and Alice will be
united forever.
Wake up, sleepyhead.
It's me, Ted.
Oh, I...
I'm-I'm sorry.
I guess I got the wrong room.
No. No, this is it, all right.
I'm positive.
-Who are you looking for, bud?
-Um, a young lady.
She occupied this room
last night.
Don't know nothin' about that.
Oh, I guess the clerk moved her
to another room.
Thanks, anyway.
Oh, good morning, sir.
Anything I can do for you?
No, I...
I'd like to see the night clerk.
Well, I'm sorry, but Mr Anderson has
gone off duty. I'm afraid he's asleep.
But it's very important.
I'm sure he won't mind.
-What is your name, please?
-Nichols. Ted Nichols.
Oh, Anderson, there's
a Mr Nichols here to see you.
He says it's very important.
Right.
-He says he'll be right down.
-Thanks.
Anderson.
What room
did you move my girl to?
I didn't move her anyplace.
Now, don't you try to get me
mixed up in anything.
Oh, I get it. Well, forget about
the twenty. Where is she?
Well, how do I know
where she went?
I ain't no gypsy mind reader.
You mean she left here?
Well, sure, about a half-hour
after you went away last night.
No, that's impossible.
She wouldn't do that.
Now, listen,
I'm not gonna argue with you.
If you don't mind,
I'd like to get some sleep.
No, you don't. Not till you tell me
what you did with that girl.
I didn't do anything with her.
You're out of your mind!
-Take your hands off of me!
-You're lying!
Why'd you say she ran away, huh?
You're trying to hide something,
and I'm gonna find out what it is!
Er, Mr Hart, there's
a disturbance in the lobby.
You'd better come right out here.
I don't know anything
about where she is!
Why, you..
You leave me alone!
Get him away from me!
He's crazy! He's crazy!
Let go of me.
I'll choke the truth out of him.
What's the trouble?
(EXHALING SHARPLY)
I don't know, Mr Hart.
I rented a room
to his girl last night,
and she checked out
and gave him the slip, and...
-Now he's trying to blame me for it.
-I mean, that's a lie.
-My girl wouldn't do a thing like that.
-I'll handle this.
How could you rent her a room?
We had no vacancies last night.
Well, I felt sorry for the lady.
She looked so tired.
Almost like
she was gonna pass out.
And then I let her have the room
we were gonna paint.
It was strictly against
my orders to rent that room.
And strictly against the law
to pocket the twenty bucks I gave him
and not let her register.
That's why he's lying.
My girl didn't run away.
He's just trying to cover up
for some reason.
Well, he's out of his mind!
After he left, I took the register
down to her room,
and she signed it.
We can check up on that
easy enough.
Sure, and on
the twenty dollars, too.
It's entered in the books
and crossed off.
-Why?
-Oh...
Well, because she came to me
and said she had
to get back to the city.
Wouldn't I let her
have the twenty dollars
as she didn't have money
to pay her fare.
I should've chased them both out
when they came in.
Then I wouldn't be
in this trouble now.
Listen, you're gonna have
nothing but trouble, brother,
if you don't tell me
what you did with her.
Now, just a minute, just a minute.
We'd better let the police settle this.
-Well, that's fine with me.
-Crandall, call Captain Griggs
-and ask him to come over here right away.
-CRANDALL: Yes, sir.
Please step into my office.
And, Anderson,
you bring the register.
(INAUDIBLE)
Well, isn't that
the girl's signature?
Well, the way it's been
scratched out, I can't be sure.
You don't seem to be sure
about a lot of things.
You can't talk me
out of this, Captain.
I'm not trying to,
but Anderson here
explained everything.
But don't you understand?
It couldn't have happened that way.
Alice is a French girl. She...
She's only been
in this country a few weeks.
She wouldn't know where to go.
That still doesn't prove
Anderson's lying. Why should he?
Because he must have had something
to do with her disappearance.
Oh.
Well, if that's the way you feel,
are you prepared to file
a charge against him,
say, for abduction?
It's about the most serious charge
you can make against anyone,
and you might be laying yourself
open for a lot of trouble.
TED: I'm not accusing him of that,
but I've got to find Alice.
Well, you've certainly
gone about it the wrong way.
As a matter of fact,
Anderson has a pretty good case
of assault and battery against you.
I'll hold him if you want to
come down to headquarters
and sign a complaint.
Well, I'd just as soon
forget the whole thing
if he'll promise
to keep away from here.
Anderson's right, Captain.
It would be bad publicity
for the hotel.
They're being very kind
to you, Nichols.
Come on, let's go.
-Have you got a car?
-Yes, but it's being fixed.
-It won't be ready till nine o'clock.
-It's almost that now.
Now, look, I'd advise you not to go
back in there and create a disturbance.
You're getting off
plenty easy as it is.
(ENGINE STARTING)
A fella has to be careful
in some of these small towns.
-A stranger hasn't got a chance.
-Yeah.
Seems to me
you got a pretty rough deal.
How do you know
so much about it?
Well, I was in the lobby.
I heard the whole argument.
Guess this is the
first bit of excitement
they've had around here
for months.
It may seem funny to you,
but it's no joke to me.
Well, I meant no offence.
I'm really very sympathetic.
I only wish there was something
I could do to help ya.
No, thank you. I...
I've got a little time to kill.
I'd just as soon
work this out for myself.
How about a cup of coffee?
I'm sure you could use one.
No, thanks.
I can understand how you let
your emotions run away with you.
It's hard to make a man in love
believe that such a thing
could happen to him.
-What are you, a philosopher?
-(CHUCKLING)
I've been called many things,
but never that.
Well, I don't really care
what you are.
But get this straight.
Alice didn't run out on me.
I... I don't know
what happened to her,
but she certainly didn't leave
of her own accord.
Maybe not,
but I've been called in
on many cases to help find
a missing person
only to discover that he or she
didn't want to be found.
Now I get it.
You're a lawyer.
No, no.
I'm a private detective.
Glad to know you.
But I think
I'll handle this alone.
Now, wait a minute.
I'm not looking for a job.
You're having a pretty rough time.
and I thought you could
use a few friendly tips.
-If that's the way you feel about it...
-Oh, all right... Traynor.
Um... Now tell me, if you were I,
how would you go about it?
Well, first, I'd take
a photograph of Alice
to the
Bureau of Missing Persons.
By the way,
let's see what she looks like.
I... haven't got her picture
with me.
-A fine thing.
-You see, we left in a hurry.
But I know there are
several in my apartment.
-Where's that?
-Back in the city.
I'll get 'em right away.
My car ought to be
ready by now.
Oh, but, er...
Suppose Alice is still
in this town somewhere?
Mmm, never.
Whether she ran away
or whatever happened,
I'm sure you won't find her
around these parts.
Gotta admit,
you're a pretty convincing Joe.
(CHUCKLING)
Well, now, if you want me to help you,
I must know the facts.
Wasn't there anyone in this
country she knew beside you?
Sure, she had some in-laws.
Well, then, she was married?
-Yes, to an American flyer.
-Oh.
Oh, I know what you're thinking,
but you're wrong.
Her husband's dead.
You see, er...
Alice wasn't just
a starry-eyed kid.
Life had kicked her around
quite a bit.
Yeah, stick to the facts, Ted.
Now, who are these in-laws?
Er...
Well, I never asked her
and she never told me.
(GRUNTING)
-When did you meet her?
-About two weeks ago.
-What?!
-Oh, I...
I know that sounds
pretty sudden, but...
sometimes you can live
a lifetime in two weeks.
That's the way
it seemed to me.
Well, after fifteen years
of marriage,
I can understand that.
Now, tell me, how did this
two weeks of a lifetime start?
I was staying for the weekend
at my cabin on Lake Shawnee.
It was Sunday night,
my last night there.
My pipe was drawing well
and I was listening
to the hundred different sounds
you hear in the country
at night, when...
suddenly, I heard someone
walking through the brush.
(SOFT RUSTLING)
Hello! Who's there?
ALICE:
Here! Over here, please!
What happened?
My ankle.
-Let me see.
-Oh!
-You're hurting me.
-Oh, I'm sorry.
But I don't think it's broken.
Probably sprained.
Perhaps I can
try again to stand on it.
No, you'd better not.
Where do you live?
Oh, no, I...
I don't wanna go back there.
Well, you certainly won't
get far on that ankle.
Please, if you could just help me
to the bus station.
-I must get to the city.
-No, you'll never make a bus now.
Besides, that ankle needs attention.
It's starting to swell.
What can I do?
Well, I can take you
to my place. It's close by.
I'll strap up the ankle
so you can walk on it.
Oh, I don't know what to do.
It'll be all right, really.
You take the little bag.
Now, put your arm round
my shoulder. Go ahead.
There we go, up easy.
-(GASPING)
-All right? There.
And from that moment on,
I was sunk.
I couldn't help feeling
there was something
almost symbolic
in the way I found her,
the way she came to me.
The facts, Ted, the facts.
Those are facts,
the way we felt.
You mean the way you felt,
like a kid picking up a stray cat.
Don't you have
any heart at all?
Never mind about me.
What happened next?
When we got to my cabin,
I bandaged her ankle.
I'm so grateful to you...
but now I must be leaving.
Now, stay off that foot!
You wanna start up
that swelling again?
You stay right here,
and I'll fix an ice pack.
ALICE: You're going to
so much trouble, monsieur.
TED: Let's drop the formalities.
The name's Ted. Ted Nichols.
-What's yours?
-Alice.
Aleece? Oh, Alice.
That's a beautiful name.
Alice what?
Alice Dupres.
Here we are.
You're taking
such fine care of me.
You must be a doctor.
No, an engineer.
But I'd certainly enjoy
pinch-hitting for a doctor.
You would make a very good one.
You know something?
-What?
-I feel all better already.
Oh, that's fine. But, er...
considering
the state of your health
and the fact there are
no more buses tonight, I...
Oh, no, I can't stay here.
Oh, now, look,
Miss Dupres, let's be sensible.
There's a beautiful bedroom in there,
and it's all yours.
In the morning,
I'll drive you into the city.
-I'm going in anyway.
-All right, I'll stay.
On one condition.
I sleep right here.
-There.
-But I don't want to put you out.
Please don't be difficult.
I'll get your bag.
Thank you, Ted.
And the way she said my name, I...
knew I wanted to go on
hearing her say it the rest of my life.
You got it bad, son.
The next day,
she felt lots better.
I took her into town with me.
She spent the day
looking for a place to live.
And that night,
she came back to you.
Because there wasn't
a single room to be had
in the entire city.
That's right.
But don't you believe
she told me the truth?
Why should I?
All it actually proves
is that you're a soft touch.
But go on. Let's hear
how she spellbound you
with her domestic skill.
Well, as a matter of fact,
she did cook
-and keep the apartment clean. She...
-(CHUCKLING)
...figured that was
the least she could do.
Mm-hmm, I bet she could whip up
a terrific onion soup.
-Hey, how do know all this?
-It's the pattern, my boy.
Then maybe this
will convince you
that she's not the kind of a girl
you still take her to be.
Is there anything
you can't cook to perfection?
Papa insisted
that I know how to cook.
He used to say that
there was no other pleasure
that lasted a man
from his birth to his death.
Know something, Alice?
You've got
just about everything.
Alice, what's the matter?
Anything I've done?
Yes.
You've been too kind to me,
and I don't deserve it.
Ted, I've made up my mind.
I'm leaving tomorrow.
I'm going back to France.
I'm lost here in this country.
It frightens me.
Now, you listen to me.
Today I had an offer
from a firm in Brazil.
I leave in two weeks.
I'll be gone six months.
Now, tell me,
what's wrong
with you staying here
and taking care of this place
till I come back?
In the meantime, you can look
for work, do anything you wish.
That's the trouble, Ted.
You want to do so much,
and you don't even know
anything about me.
I know everything about you
I want to.
You never even asked me what
I was running away from that night.
Well, I'm sure if you wanted me
to know, you'd have told me.
You have a right to know.
Why?
I was in love once
with an American soldier,
a transport pilot.
He was killed in France
the night we were married.
About six months ago,
my mother passed away.
I was left alone
with nothing but sad memories.
My life became unbearable.
So I decided
to come to America.
My husband had told me
to go to his father
if anything happened to him.
Well, why didn't you go there?
His father had died.
There were other relatives.
An aunt, some cousins.
I never felt at ease with them.
Then, one night,
when I was alone in the house,
one of them came back,
and he...
Oh, I couldn't stand that.
I had to run away.
Oh, I don't even want
to think about it.
It's like a bad dream.
(SOBBING)
Oh, Ted.
Of course you don't have
to think about it, darling.
Although, in a way,
I'm glad it happened.
Otherwise,
I'd never have met you.
Now, speaking of dreams,
don't you think
you'd better get to bed?
Yes, it is getting late.
-Hadn't we better flip?
-Hmm?
-You know, heads and tails.
-Yeah.
-Heads again.
-And you win again.
Well, I win every night.
You have very bad luck.
Good night, Ted.
You know, I think I'm
very fortunate to have met you.
I can't go on like this.
That is why I must leave.
Will you marry me?
Marry you?
But I've only just met you.
You don't know me.
Please, Alice.
You couldn't love me so soon.
You feel sorry for me
because I'm alone.
You pity me.
But pity isn't love.
And she went on that way,
trying to convince me
that I was mistaking
pity for love.
That pity was a terrible thing
because it meant that you...
looked down upon a person
as weaker than yourself.
And when I would finally realise that,
I'd begin to hate her.
-She was right.
-No, she was wrong.
I didn't pity her
in the least.
She was my idea
of an ideal woman.
I'm telling you all of this
only to prove that
marriage was my idea.
I'm the one that insisted.
She fought it
every step of the way.
Does that sound like
the kind of a girl
who was trying to take me?
Mmm, she might be
extremely clever.
Now I give up.
And she never mentioned
the name of her in-laws to you?
Not that I remember.
Doesn't that strike you
as being somewhat strange?
Not particularly.
After the first time, we didn't
talk about them again.
Hmm.
Anything else
you can recall about her?
Oh, wait.
There was one other thing
that happened later that same night.
(SCREAMING)
Alice!
-(SCREAMING)
-Alice, what's wrong?
-What's the matter?
-A man. Through the window.
There's no-one there.
What happened?
But I saw him.
He was going through my things,
and when I screamed,
he went out through the window.
Sure you weren't dreaming?
Oh, but no.
I tell you, I saw him.
Well, if there was a man,
you certainly frightened him away
when you screamed.
Oh, but you're laughing at me.
No, I'm not.
Look, I locked the window.
Try to get some sleep, huh?
Good night, darling.
I still don't know
if that really happened
or if it was only a bad dream.
She just had a nightmare
and too many crêpes Suzettes.
And now, I'm gonna
make you a prediction.
When we reach your apartment,
you'll find a note
and all her things gone.
Well, be that as it may,
I've still got to find her.
-Morning, George.
-Welcome back, Mr Nichols.
-Where's the missus?
-Er... She stayed up at the lodge.
I had to come into town
for a few hours,
take care of some business.
Any mail for me?
Nope. Not a thing, Mr Nichols.
Thanks.
So far, I'm fifty percent wrong.
It'll be an even hundred
before another minute.
-Wanna bet?
-Uh-uh. Now you'd have to give me odds.
Everything just as it was
when Alice and I left here.
-Hmm.
-Come on.
Now who's right?
Okay, okay.
I'll take it all back.
Now, get me her picture
and I'll go to work.
Here, take your choice.
-This her husband with her?
-Yes.
That was taken
the day of their marriage.
Look what I found, Traynor.
Her marriage certificate.
That's her married name, see?
It's Barkley.
And her husband's name
was John.
Barkley.
Barkley. Where have
I heard that name before?
(SNAPPING FINGERS)
I've got it.
Lake Shawnee. It's that
big place near the water.
The Barkley house,
they call it.
Now I'm beginning
to understand a few things.
It must have been the Barkley
house she was running away from.
And that cousin.
Maybe he had something
to do with her disappearance.
Come on, Traynor.
Let's get up there and find out.
Wait a minute, Nichols.
What is it?
THE WHISTLER: You walked
right into that one, didn't you?
But now, at least,
you know just where you stand.
There are others, shall we say,
interested in Alice.
And that marriage certificate
must be of great importance
to someone.
That's why Traynor went
to all this trouble
to get it away from you.
You're on your own now, Ted,
and with no time to spare.
The man I came in with,
did you see him leave?
Why, yes, about ten minutes ago.
Did he say anything to you?
No. He asked, er...
He asked me to call him a cab.
Seemed in a hurry.
Is there anything wrong?
There sure is.
Yes, sir, what is it?
I want to see Mr Barkley,
and don't tell me he isn't home.
Well, now...
What's the meaning of this,
forcing your way
into a strange home?
Never mind. Just tell Barkley
that Ted Nichols is here.
What is it, Mother?
Mother?
This is Mr Nichols, son.
He insists on seeing you.
So you're Barkley.
What did you do with Alice?
Please.
Please, young man.
You don't realise
what you're doing.
This is her husband,
Alice's husband.
Her husband? You?
No, no. No, that can't be.
That's a lie.
Be careful what you say.
But Alice told me
that her husband was dead.
Yes, I know. Killed in France
on her wedding night.
And, after the war, she came here
to live with my father,
but found he had died.
That's what she told you,
isn't it?
Yes, that's just what she said.
I really don't owe you
any explanation,
but, under the circumstances,
I suppose
you have a right to know,
providing you put that gun away.
Mother, I can handle this alone.
-Cigarette?
-No.
I, er, met Alice in Normandy
shortly after the invasion.
I was in the Air Corps,
a transport pilot
for paratroopers.
To make it brief, we fell
in love and were married.
That same night, I left
for a run over Germany
and was knocked over.
There was a false report
of my death.
Under the shock and
the climax of weeks of strain,
Alice's mind snapped.
Oh, yes, she recovered,
except for occasional relapses
when she believes herself to be
a widow and free to marry again.
Yeah, that's what
she gave me to understand.
Oh, no doubt she did.
And made it sound very logical.
The only thing
that makes us realise
she's about to have
one of these spells
are her strange delusions
she's being mistreated at home.
That's exactly
what she told me.
And, er, she usually builds it up
into quite a tale of horror.
In spite of everything,
I don't believe a word of it.
I know you're lying.
Would you like to hear it
from her own lips?
You wouldn't dare.
Mother!
Would you come here
a minute, please?
Yes, John. What is it?
See if Alice is all right.
I wanna take
Mr Nichols up to see her.
Oh, but aren't you afraid
it might excite her too much?
I'm quite sure Mr Nichols
will have sense enough
not to upset her.
Very well.
I've been
thanking my lucky stars
that we found Alice
before it was too late.
It's a good thing that minister
wasn't at home last night.
Yeah. You know
all the details, don't you?
Couldn't be by any chance
you have a fellow called Traynor
-working for ya?
-Indeed I did.
He was the man
who traced Alice.
He checked with
the service station at the lake.
You stopped there for some gas
before driving back to town,
and the attendant knew you.
Then why didn't you
come to my apartment
instead of letting things
go this far?
Mother and I did
the moment Traynor phoned us
and gave us your address.
It had taken him quite a while
to locate you in the city.
We missed you by minutes.
It's a good thing you told the clerk
where you were going.
Still sounds screwy to me.
All right, John,
you may come up now.
Please remember,
you must only stay a minute.
Alice, darling, what's wrong?
What happened?
I'm sorry, Ted.
Please forgive me.
Forgive you?
Well, you don't mean you're
really married to that man?
Yes, I am his wife.
You said wanted to hear it
from her own lips.
Well, you have.
Now, will you be
good enough to leave?
I'll see Mr Nichols
to the door.
Arnold, you may come out now.
You'll forget in time.
Just keep yourself occupied.
Or, better yet,
try to get away for a while.
I'm leaving shortly for South America.
I've got a job down there.
Well, good for you.
I wish I could get away myself.
These past few years with Alice,
ever since we got back from France,
-have been trying.
-I suppose so.
Get up, kid. Show's over.
(SOBBING)
Well, the best of luck to you
and have a good trip.
Oh, thanks.
(BIRDS SINGING)
Well, that takes care
of Mr Nichols.
If you'd stayed away from her
in the first place,
we wouldn't have had
all this trouble.
Let's not go through
all that again.
I told you I was sorry,
but I've made up for it now.
You gotta hand it to Mom
for putting this over.
You realise, of course,
you made a mistake.
-I did?
-Sure. That dope's going to South America.
He naturally would've
taken Alice with him.
If you hadn't insisted
on bringing her back,
all this could've been avoided.
I don't make my plans
with a crystal ball.
When you have a fortune
in the palm of your hand,
you don't take chances.
If it comes right down to it,
she doesn't deserve the estate anyway.
I didn't come here for the estate
in the first place.
I told you,
I knew nothing about it.
You can keep the money
and the house.
All I want is to be with Ted.
Maybe that's the way
you feel right now,
but that boyfriend of yours
is apt to change your mind.
Never.
I swear, neither one of us
will ever bother you.
Please. Please believe me.
Let me go now
or I'll never see him again.
Sorry, kid, you'll have
to do it Mother's way.
Pretty girl like you won't have
any trouble finding another guy.
I hate all of you.
(SOBBING)
Better go downstairs
and see Traynor.
Pay him off
and get rid of him.
What are you going to
do with her now, Mom?
Yeah, you don't suppose
she's gonna stay here quietly
after we clear out, do you?
We'll talk about that later.
Alice might not agree
with what I have in mind.
-Sorry you had to wait so long.
-It's all right, Mr Barkley.
It's not your fault we were
so rudely interrupted by Mr Nichols.
Well, it's a good thing you got here first
and told us what to expect.
How's Mrs Barkley feeling now?
Did it upset her much
to see Nichols again?
No, she took it like a soldier,
but I'm glad it's over.
-Well, let's get down to points.
-Oh, sure.
This is what I got
from his apartment.
Well, she even took
our marriage licence with her.
Yeah, the funny part is, Nichols
didn't know your wife's married name
till he found that certificate
in his desk.
Poor fellow.
He has my sympathy.
Yeah, mine too.
Well, I believe this should
take care of everything.
Thank you.
You've done a good job.
Any time, Mr Barkley,
and I hope you'll call me again,
if I can be of service.
Well, that's not very likely.
You see, we're leaving here.
-Oh?
-We've sold this place
to make Alice forget
about the past.
Mm-hmm.
-Thanks again and goodbye.
-Goodbye to you, sir.
He didn't act suspicious,
did he?
Not in the least.
And look what he brought us.
The only piece of evidence
that would've made it possible
for Alice to prove her claim.
Now we're in the clear.
With that town in France destroyed,
where the marriage took place,
and all its records gone,
she hasn't got a chance.
She could still make a lot of
trouble for us if we let her go.
Wait a minute.
That gives me an idea.
I hope you know
what you're doing.
Spencer 7925.
This is Shawnee 1368.
(DOOR OPENING)
What do you want?
About them trunks, Mrs Barkley.
Well, haven't you
brought them up yet?
Yes, yes, Operator,
I'm holding on.
Well, don't stand there.
Go and bring them
up to my room right away.
Yes, ma'am.
MRS BARKLEY:
Is this Woodland Sanitarium?
I'd like to speak
to Dr Grantland, please.
THE WHISTLER: So Alice actually
came to this country
only about three weeks ago.
She hasn't been here
for several years,
as Barkley wants you
to believe.
That changes everything, Ted,
doesn't it?
Something seems very wrong.
But, after what
Alice just told you,
you still can't go
to the police.
You've got to find out
for yourself,
and there's only one way
to do it.
Go back,
and somehow see her alone.
(INSECTS CHIRRUPING)
(BARKING)
(GROWLING)
SAM: Hold him, Duke, hold him!
Hold him!
Here, boy!
Good boy, Duke. Good boy.
You was here
this afternoon, weren't ya?
Yes, I was.
What are you doin' this late
out here in the garden?
Well, I rang the bell.
No-one answered.
Nobody home. Hold it, Duke.
They tell you where they went?
They left here for good,
bag and baggage.
New owners are coming
next week.
That's why I'm stickin' around,
waitin' for 'em to show.
Well, never mind that.
Did they take Alice with them?
Sure, they took her along, but
she ain't gonna be with 'em.
-What are you talking about?
-Oh, she's been sick,
and they're takin' her
to some rest home.
She's been
carryin' on pretty bad.
Out of her head, I expect.
Did they tell you
the name of the place?
Mmm, no, but I heard
the missus mention it
-when she was telephonin'.
-What was it?
It was, um...
Oh, I clean forgot.
Funny how I've been
getting lately.
-I just can't remember a thing.
-Well, please try to remember!
-(BARKING AND YOWLING)
-SAM: Hold it, Duke.
He don't mean no harm.
Well, it had something to do
with trees.
Elmwood or...
Wildwood...
Pine Crest, er...
(SUCKING TEETH)
Ain't that terrible?
I know the name
of the doctor, though.
I know his name as well
as I know my own, but I...
I sure can't recollect
the name of the place.
-Okay, okay, what's the doctor's name?
-Grantland.
Why didn't you ask me that
in the first place?
Oh, drat that fella.
Now I'll be awake all night
trying to think
of that Woodland place.
Woodland. That's it. Hey!
Oh, nope. Darned if I will.
Yeah, serves him right
for bein' in such a hurry.
Come on, boy.
What took them so long?
Do you want me to tell you
exactly what the photographer said
about making enlargements
at this hour of the night?
Save it.
Ah, just as I thought.
Guess my eyes are
still pretty sharp.
This is a picture of Alice Barkley and
her husband, John, taken in France.
And what's so unusual about that?
Only that the man
who told me he was her husband
and hired me to find her
doesn't look anything like this guy.
It's a fine time to find that out.
Well, I couldn't be sure
from this small picture
I took away from Nichols.
That's why I had it enlarged.
So you've been
on the wrong side of the fence.
I'm afraid so.
I'm sorry, boss.
Anything I can do?
Not at the moment.
Where are you going?
Back to the Barkley house
to ask a few questions.
-(COIN DROPPING)
-(PHONE PINGING)
(PHONE RINGING)
-Hello?
-Woodland Sanitarium?
I'd like to speak
to Dr Grantland, please.
Well, just a moment.
It's for you, Doctor,
on extension one.
Dr Grantland speaking.
Er... This is, um...
My name's Simpson,
Doctor, Howard Simpson.
You've been, er,
highly recommended to me,
and I'd like to
come over and see you.
What seems to be
your trouble, Mr Simpson?
I, er, have these pains
in the back of my head.
Oh, sure. I've had a physical
check-up, X-rays and everything.
Very well, then.
Drop in and see me tomorrow.
I'll put the nurse back on
to give you an appointment.
No, just a minute, Doctor.
Tomorrow might be too late.
Well, you see,
when I have these pains,
I have moments of despondency.
I'm afraid of what I might do.
As a matter of fact, I'm feeling
pretty low right now.
Then maybe you'd better
come over right away.
Well, thank you, Doctor.
Thank you very much.
TRAYNOR:
Come on, talk.
I tell you, I didn't have
anything to do with them people.
I don't know nothin'
about what they was doin'.
You mean you work right here
and don't know what was goin' on?
Nope, I steered clear of 'em.
I didn't like 'em any more
than old Ed Barkley did himself,
after he took 'em in.
-Ed Barkley? Who's he?
-He was John's father.
I'd been with him
since before John was even born.
John's father?
I never heard of him.
Well, you wouldn't,
because he's dead,
same as John,
who was killed in the war.
You say John was lost in the war?
That's right.
Oh. Well, who was the fellow
I talked to this afternoon?
Well, that's Charlie,
John's cousin.
What about the old lady
and the others?
She's Ed Barkley's
sister-in-law,
and them's her children.
They were the closest
livin' relations to the old man,
exceptin' this here
French girl, maybe,
seeing she's John's widow.
Hmm.
Then this place
really belongs to her.
Come to think of it, mister,
you're about right.
Come on, Pop. You've got things
to tell the police.
(DOORBELL BUZZING)
I'm, er, Howard Simpson.
The doctor is expecting me.
Oh, yes. Come in, please.
Right this way.
-This is Mr Simpson, Dr Grantland.
-Oh, yes, Mr Simpson.
-Sit down, won't you?
-Thank you.
I'm rather curious to know
who referred you to me.
Ah... Well, you...
You see, Doctor,
my home's in, er, Albany.
You came here
specially to see me?
No, not exactly.
I'm on my vacation.
See, for the past year,
I've been under the care
of Dr Abner Green.
Abner Green?
Never heard of him.
Well, er, he's heard of you.
He told me that
if I had one of my spells
while I was down here that
I was to contact you at once.
I see.
Very kind of him.
Where do you have those pains?
Right here.
Mm-hmm. Take off your coat.
I'll check up on your heart.
You know,
sometimes these symptoms
are merely indicative
of a nervous condition.
You don't seem like
the nervous type.
Well, looks are
sometimes deceiving, Doctor.
Yeah, I'm constantly
aware of that.
I suppose Dr Green
has those X-rays you spoke of?
-Oh-Oh, yes.
-Good.
See if you can get Dr Green
on the phone for me.
Yes, Doctor.
(DIALLING)
Long distance? Give me
the Albany operator, please.
Hmm, you have
a very erratic heartbeat.
All right, thank you.
All the lines to Albany are busy.
The operator will call us back.
Oh, never mind.
It can wait till morning.
Doctor...
I'll take care of that
while you're staying here.
Oh, don't worry.
I had no intention of using it.
I know, I know. You just
carry it around for self-protection.
Yes, that's right. I travel a great deal,
sometimes late at night.
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
-That must be the new patient, Doctor.
-Excuse me a moment.
I'll be right back.
Sit down, Mr Simpson,
and try to relax.
We don't generally have
this kind of disturbance.
Woman must be pretty sick.
Yes, and just a young girl, too.
Very sad case.
Total loss of memory.
Even insists she isn't married
to the man
we know is her husband.
I'm sorry, Mr Simpson. Maybe
I shouldn't have said anything.
Oh, that's all right.
Dr Grantland has
handled many cases like hers
and always with great success.
And I'm sure he'll take
good care of you too.
You'd better get to bed,
Mr Simpson.
I'll give you a complete
examination in the morning.
Is Mr Simpson's room ready?
Yes, I'm putting him in 207.
Good. Did you bring
some things with you?
Well, no. You see, I didn't
expect I'd have to stay.
Oh, that's all right.
We'll give you what you need.
This way, please.
ALICE:
No, no! They're lying!
Now, please don't worry.
The doctor will quiet her
very soon.
Er, this is Mr Simpson.
Will you get him
some sleeping garments?
-He didn't come prepared to stay.
-Certainly.
He'll be in 207.
This way, please.
Better get ready for bed.
The doctor will be in to see you
once more, before you go to sleep.
No, no! Let me go!
This is terrible, son.
Poor dear, she must be suffering so.
I can't bear to watch.
I know it's awful, Mother, but
we're doing the best we can for her.
-What's the matter now?
-We can't get her to quiet down.
She falls asleep for a few minutes,
then starts all over again.
I don't like to do this, but I guess
we'll have to use the jacket.
No, no, no!
No!
-(GASPING)
-Ssh!
No. Quiet, darling.
I'll get you out of here.
Now, please step
in here a moment
so we can complete
the financial arrangements.
Oh, dearest,
don't ever leave me again.
But, darling, I didn't run away.
I know. I was too trusting.
But they came to me
to the hotel,
and begged me
to forget what happened,
said they would
take me to you.
We'd go home,
have a big wedding.
That hotel clerk.
They must've given him plenty
to make up that phoney story
about you running out on me.
But never mind that now, darling.
Where are your clothes?
In there.
-Hurry up.
-Yes.
I guess we've seen
the last of her.
Mmm. We've just about time
to make the plane.
Sybil and Arnold
will be worried.
(ENGINE STARTING)
Well, what are you
stopping for?
Wait a minute.
That looks to me like Nichols' car.
It's impossible.
It couldn't be.
But if I hadn't told you
I was his wife,
they would have killed
both of us.
I know. I understand.
Don't talk about it now.
Please hurry.
I'm ready, dear.
Wait a minute, wait a minute!
He's a paranoiac.
Put him in a straitjacket.
Not so fast, mister.
You're holding the wrong man.
That's the one we want.
I don't know what your game is,
but I owe something to you, too.
Just a minute.
He doesn't deserve that.
You'd be in a fine fix
if it wasn't for him.
Well, I still don't know
whose side you're on.
I can't blame you, Nichols.
I admit I made a mistake.
-They certainly had me fooled.
-Okay, forget it.
But that doesn't go
for that phoney doctor.
I demand his arrest for keeping
Alice here against her will.
This institution is
of high professional standing.
When Mr Barkley
brought this lady here,
he proved to me
that he was her husband.
He had every legal right
to put her under my care.
But I told you he was lying.
And, in spite of that,
you didn't bother to find out
whether he was actually the man whose
name appeared on the marriage licence.
All right, cut out the arguing.
You're all going to the D.A.'s office.
and you can
explain everything to him.
Well, what about Mrs Barkley
and her other son and daughter?
They'll be there
waiting for us. Come on.
Oh, er, I almost forgot.
There's a man locked up
in the closet of my room.
You'd better let him out
before he suffocates,
and I'm accused of murder.
All right, let him out.
Come on, Doc, you too.
Pardon me, sweetheart,
if I've asked you this before.
-Are you nervous?
-Not this time, darling.
(CHUCKLING)
THE WHISTLER:
You certainly were lucky, Ted.
It might have
ended differently,
with you and Alice
worlds apart.
But fate, this time,
was on your side.
(THE WHISTLER
WHISTLING HIS THEME)
SUBTITLES BY POWERHOUSE FILMS LTD