(MAN WHISTLING
"THE WHISTLER" THEME)
THE WHISTLER:
I am the Whistler.
I know many things,
for I walk by night.
I know many strange tales,
many secrets hidden in
the hearts of men and women
who have stepped
into the shadows.
Yes, I know the nameless terrors
of which they dare not speak.
The man sitting alone
is a stranger here.
He has means and
a responsible position in society.
He's a man who is more at home
in a fashionable club
than in a waterfront bar.
But, tonight,
he is turned from
the comfort and security
of his own world
to meet a man
whose business is death.
-You are Lefty Vigran?
-Mm-hmm.
Oh, you can talk.
There's nothing to be afraid of.
I've got a job for you.
Well, just what is it
you want done, Mister...?
Do you have to know my name?
No.
I want to have a man...
removed.
Oh.
Well, um...
What does this fella do?
Would that make any difference?
Yes, it makes a lot of difference.
You see, if he's important,
I won't touch it.
He's just a small manufacturer.
Oh, legitimate businessman, huh?
You see...
murder of a chap like that
will get a lot of publicity.
Well, if it's the money
you're thinking about,
I'm prepared to pay you well.
Take ten thousand to handle it.
You see, I have to split
with the gentleman
who actually does the work.
Of course, he'll never know
who's putting up the money.
And I don't want to know
who he is.
(CHUCKLING)
You won't.
What's the name and address
of the party?
Bring the money?
-Oh, you...
-You see, I'm not the type
to take payment for a job
and not deliver.
And that goes
for those who work for me.
Well, that's what I've been told.
What are you worrying about?
The time.
Must be done between
now and next Friday.
It will be.
Hey, I think the fella
back there wants you.
-Say, I think the fella...
-He doesn't understand
a word you're saying, mister.
He's a deaf mute.
Oh.
Deliver this.
You know where.
Right away.
You understand?
And don't lose it.
(DISTANT FOGHORN)
(PHONE RINGING)
Deal's all set.
I'm sending some details
over to you.
How many details?
Five.
I'll give you a fancy job
for that.
Never mind anything fancy.
Just play it safe.
Has to be done
by next Friday night.
Okay.
(REPLACING RECEIVER)
(QUIET CHATTERING)
You expecting to meet
anybody outside?
No.
I'm afraid you will
if you leave by the front door.
Oh, yeah?
Thanks, Gus.
Hello, Gorss.
Gorss? (CHUCKLING)
My name's Lefty Vigran.
Maybe so,
but your name was Gorss
when you killed a cop
in St Louis three years ago.
Get 'em up.
-Drop it.
-What...?
(TWO GUNSHOTS)
(DISTANT FOGHORN)
(KNOCKING)
(COCKING GUN)
(DOOR CHIMING)
Good evening, sir.
Hello, Jennings.
If I may say so, sir,
you're looking very much better.
Come into the study for
a minute, will you, Jennings?
Very well, sir.
Sit down, Jennings.
Is anything wrong, sir?
Of course not.
Sit down.
Pour us each a brandy, Jennings.
Very well, sir.
Why is it you've never married?
Well, sir,
one set of family responsibilities
at a time is sufficient.
Oh, come now. I haven't been
as difficult as all that.
Your very good health,
Mr Conrad.
May it continue to improve, sir.
Thanks.
Er...
I've been awfully worried lately, sir.
I thought, perhaps, that you...
You mean you thought
I've been...
-cracking up?
-In a way, sir.
Well, you can put
your mind at rest.
Everything's going
to be all right now.
Well, I'm awfully glad
to hear it, sir.
By the way, where was it you
wanted to own an orange grove?
(CHUCKLING)
At Riverside, sir.
Jennings, you're fired.
I want you to leave
for Riverside in the morning.
Here's your severance pay.
But I really don't care
for oranges, sir.
(CHUCKLING) Except for a slice
in an old fashioned.
Well, you wanted an orange grove.
Now you're stuck with one.
But how about you
and the house, sir?
You always said you wouldn't have
anything changed from the way that...
Mrs Conrad left it.
And that includes me, sir.
I'm giving up the house,
Jennings.
And, where I'm going,
quarters would be a little
cramped for both of us.
Good morning, Miss Foster.
Oh!
Oh, good morning, Mr Conrad.
Hello. Hello, Myrtle?
Tell Mr McNear
that Mr Conrad is in today.
He looks fine.
Like a different person.
-Good morning, Alice.
-Earl!
I'm certainly glad
you came in today.
Now, don't you start on me.
Come inside, will you, please?
Much work piled up?
I was able to handle
most of it.
Has Mr McNear been worried
about my absences?
After all, he is your partner.
Something's happened
to you, Earl. You're...
You're different.
If I seem less upset,
it's because I've become
reconciled to Clare's death.
You're wise to try and forget. I...
I think it's best that way.
Not much chance
of my forgetting.
My friends have taken care of that.
You dropped all your friends.
They'd changed.
They weren't the same
any longer.
Oh, you imagine that, Earl.
The trip was my idea.
It took a lot of persuading
to get Clare to go.
You see, something had happened
to our marriage.
We'd drifted apart,
even thought of separating.
-Why, I always thought...
-Yes, I know.
I didn't mention it
to you or McNear
because I didn't want to bring
my domestic troubles into the office.
I talked Clare
into making the trip.
I'd even hoped that it might
bring us together again.
Most of our friends knew
that we were having trouble.
You'd imagine how they reacted
when I came back alone.
No.
She was in my arms
in the water.
I let go of her to reach for
a raft that was floating past.
When I looked back,
she was gone.
But you helped
other people onto the raft.
Well, that's exactly the point.
Our friends have been
wondering why I was unable
to get my wife on the raft
when I was able to help others.
Do you mean anyone
has suggested you...
you deliberately let Clare drown?
Oh, no. No-one has been
as crude as that.
But I've felt the accusation
in their eyes.
Oh, you're mistaken, Earl.
You must be mistaken.
No.
No, you sense a thing
like that even more strongly
than if it were put in words.
Oh, come in, Charlie.
Hello, Earl. Er...
Miss Walker,
I'll see anybody today.
(DOOR CLOSING)
Look here, Earl.
You're not being fair to me.
I think we'd better come
to an understanding.
About what?
For months now,
you've been coming to the office
only once or twice a week,
and then for only
a couple of hours.
Well, I haven't been myself, Charlie.
Everything's gonna be all right now.
I know, Earl, I know, but...
you know I wouldn't have
invested my money
in a business
I know nothing about,
if you hadn't assured me
you were going to give it
all your attention.
Well, what would you do
if I had an accident?
-Well, I... I...
-I'll tell you what you'd do.
Absolutely nothing.
I've taught Miss Walker all there is
to know about this business.
And I'm leaving her
my share of the firm,
so she'll never run out on you.
You can just relax
and enjoy yourself.
How do you do?
I'd like to speak to Mr Conrad.
My name is Smith.
Mr Conrad is busy just now.
-Well, I'll wait.
-(DOOR OPENING AND CLOSING)
-You may go in now, Mr Smith.
-Thank you.
Well, good morning, Mr Conrad.
My, you have lovely offices.
My name is Smith.
Oh, it's a pleasure to meet
a successful businessman like you.
One that's successful
and also accessible.
Willing to sit down,
talk business,
doesn't have those "keep out"
signs on the door.
What can I do for you?
These are specimen policies, Mr Conrad.
I came to talk to you
about life insurance.
Oh, a little warm, isn't it?
I'm with the Atlantic Mutual,
and my company has developed
a very special type of policy
for a man in your position.
You can forget all the drivel.
Hurry up and get it over with.
Well, now, don't rush me,
Mr Conrad.
I'll get it over with.
I don't need any life insurance.
Oh, I think you do.
As a matter of fact, I cancelled
all my policies yesterday.
Oh! Well, now,
is that fair to your partner?
Maybe the business
would require additional capital
if something unexpected
ever happened to you.
Nothing unexpected
is going to happen to me.
Oh, I wouldn't be too sure
about that, Mr Conrad.
Life is so uncertain, you know.
One moment you're alive,
and the next you're dead.
Nobody knows what's waiting
around the corner.
Now, take your own case,
for example.
You live alone,
that is, except for your butler.
Did you ever think of this?
A short circuit at night,
a fire...
Why, you could be suffocated
to death without ever waking up.
As a matter of fact,
my company just paid
one of these
partnership claims.
One partner
wanted to go hunting.
He took the shotgun
out of the case to look at it.
First thing he knew,
he'd blown his head off.
Now, what makes you so sure
that nothing unexpected
is going to happen to you?
Well, I'm sure that I don't
need any life insurance.
Well... Well, maybe you want
to get married again.
Oh, you'd better take out
a policy now, Mr Conrad,
while you can still pass
the physical examination.
-Get out.
-But, Mr Conrad, I...
-Well, all right.
But thanks so much
for the interview.
I'll see you again sometime.
(DOOR OPENING)
(DOOR CLOSING)
Who's in here?
-(GASPING)
-Mr Conrad?
Yes.
I understand your phone's
out of order.
They sent you
this time of night?
Well, you're lucky to get
service at any time these days.
You want to come inside?
Roughly, that's the idea.
Unless you keep your phone
out here on the porch.
Have you ever heard the theory
that it's impossible
for anyone to go into a room
without leaving behind
some trace of their presence?
Now look, do you want me
to fix your phone or don't you?
There's nothing wrong
with my phone.
Well, somebody reported it
out of order.
Come in and look for yourself.
Now, I'm all alone, so...
you can forget
the pretence of the phone
and get it over with.
Get what over with?
I know why you came here.
It's all right.
Go ahead and do it.
See? It's dead.
(REPLACING RECEIVER)
Wire's been cut.
Soon as I get this fixed,
you better call the police.
Yes, I will.
It's okay.
Your line's in.
You can call the police now,
or you can ride downtown with me
if you want to.
No, I'll be all right now,
thanks.
REPAIRMAN:
Well, good night.
EARL:
Good night. Much obliged.
(DOORBELL CHIMING)
Oh! It's pretty late for you
to be out, isn't it, Alice?
Well, I... I tried to phone you,
but your line is out of order.
Yes, I know.
Come into the study.
Earl...
Jennings came to see me tonight.
We both thought it strange
that you'd given him five thousand
dollars in cash as a gift, and...
and were in such a hurry
to get him out of the house.
Why, I let Jennings go
because I'm giving up the house.
I wish I could believe that.
It's the truth.
I feel as if you're going through
some sort of crisis, Earl.
(COCKING GUN)
(INAUDIBLE)
You've been perfectly swell.
But there isn't anything more
that you can do for me.
I wish there was something
I could do
that would really help you.
Perhaps I'd better go.
Would you mind
seeing me home?
(MAN WHISTLING
"THE WHISTLER" THEME)
Did you hear someone whistling?
I didn't notice.
(FOOTSTEPS)
(LAUGHING)
Well, I hope my being here
hasn't upset you.
I persuaded your landlady
to let me in.
What'd you do?
Tell her I was your son?
Heaven forbid.
Get your belongings together,
will ya?
I want you to take a trip
south with me.
I'm all tied up.
I got a job I inherited
from Lefty Vigran.
When will you
be ready to leave?
Well, I expected to be through
tonight, but I was interrupted.
Oh, that's what made you
so jumpy, huh?
Yeah. Had a feelin'
I was bein' watched.
Then I thought I heard
somebody whistlin'.
Still got time
to make the train tonight.
I've been paid.
I gotta deliver.
Well, that's highly ethical.
Well, now, don't be funny.
Look, why don't you go away
with me for a couple of days.
Then you can come back
when ya like.
Naturally,
the town's hot right now
after Vigran tried
to shoot it out with the police.
Yeah, but I gotta finish
this job by Friday.
Well, I'll tell ya.
I'll be at the Majestic Hotel
over the next couple of days.
If you change your mind,
look me up there.
(LAUGHING)
Studies of Necrophobia,
Exaggerated Fear of Death.
(LAUGHING)
I like it.
Why don't you try
raising orchids for a hobby?
Let stuff like that alone.
It's liable to awaken
your imagination.
A fellow like you's
better off without it.
Hey, wait a minute.
Thanks for reminding me
of this book.
You've given me an idea.
Yeah.
Maybe I can knock this guy off
without killin' him myself.
What's that?
Do you know that some people
actually die of fright?
See you at the hotel.
(DOOR OPENING)
(DOOR CLOSING)
I've been trying
to get you on the phone.
I've got wonderful news
for you.
Oh, come inside, Alice.
What's the wonderful news?
It's about Clare.
She's alive, Earl.
I can hardly believe it.
Do you think there could
possibly be some mistake?
Oh, of course not.
What she must have been through
these last two years.
Yes, I know, but...
the joy of coming home
will compensate even for that.
Thanks, Alice.
Not only is Clare released, but...
I can go on living again.
Do you realise what that means?
I can look at my friends without
seeing "murderer" in their eyes.
I...
-I...
-What's the matter, Earl?
Oh, nothing. Nothing serious.
I-I've got a...
a call to make.
I'll be back in a little while.
(DOOR OPENING)
(DOOR CLOSING)
Mr Conrad nearly ran me down
in the corridor.
Where's he going?
Well, I don't know,
but he'll be back soon.
I came to congratulate him
on his good news,
but he couldn't even wait
to hear me.
I'm surprised to see you
looking so cheerful.
Why shouldn't I be?
Well, his wife's popping up alive
must have upset your plans.
Now, don't be angry.
Everybody but Conrad knows
you're in love with him.
And I was hoping you'd win.
You might have
straightened him out.
Has, er...
Mr Tomley come in yet?
Yeah, he got in
a few minutes ago.
Oh, I guess it's all right for you
to go right on in, Mr Conrad.
Thank you.
Hello, Tomley.
I've been in and out of here
all day trying to see you.
I want to get in touch
with Lefty Vigran right away.
Tell him I want to see him
as soon as possible, will you?
Of course, you don't know
Lefty Vigran is dead.
No, I didn't.
When'd it happen?
I suppose it's a great
surprise to you,
but he was killed by detectives
as he left that barroom
just after your meeting
with him.
Well, this is a surprise. I...
I haven't been reading
the papers as much as usual, but...
Look, if Vigran's dead,
I'll have to get in touch with
the man that works with him.
I don't know anything
about his friends.
Well, you knew a lot
about Vigran
the first time I came here.
I didn't ask what
you wanted him for then,
and I don't want
to discuss it now.
Well, what's the matter,
Tomley?
You know who I am.
Do you think
I betrayed Vigran?
I wouldn't know.
Well, I'm not an informer.
All I want is to call off
the deal I made.
Whoever's got the money's
welcome to it.
Vigran was a close-lipped man.
Too bad,
but I can't help ya.
(DOOR OPENING)
(DOOR CLOSING)
(CHATTERING)
I'd like to speak to you
for a moment.
Weren't you in here
the other night
when I was talking to Lefty Vigran?
You know, Lefty...
GUS: He don't understand
a word you're saying, mister.
He's a deaf mute.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Well, maybe you
can help me.
Yeah?
Remember I was in here
the other night?
In that booth over there
with Lefty Vigran.
Oh, yeah, I remember.
What'll you have?
A bourbon.
Do, er... any of
Lefty's friends come in?
They'd better not.
I didn't know the guy you were
with was Vigran
until after he was shot
out in the alley.
You know, I'd give a lot to know
some of Lefty's friends.
Yeah, there were a couple
of fellas in here yesterday,
said the same thing.
They were detectives.
Yes, miss?
Sherry.
I'll have another.
Sorry, when you get time.
Er...
Do you remember exactly
what Vigran did after I left?
-Same?
-Yes, please.
He made a phone call,
I think.
Yes, I remember now.
He made a phone call,
and then he sat at the table
at that booth over there.
Then he called
to a friend of his
who was over here
at the counter
and handed him an envelope,
and the guy beat it.
Who was he?
You'll have to ask Lefty
about that, mister.
You're lying.
You know who he is.
-I know you know who he is.
-Take it easy!
I'm sorry.
(SIGHING)
Finding this friend of Vigran's
is a matter of life
and death to me.
Here's my card.
If he comes in again,
will you ask him to wait here
and phone me?
Okay, I'll ask him.
Bartender.
The back kitchen, I think.
Thank you. I want some change.
I'd like to play a record.
He was lying to you.
Let's see what they have
on the machine, shall we?
Did you know any
of Vigran's friends?
Yes.
The man who runs this place
owns a roadhouse
on Mountain View Drive.
I used to sing out there.
Lefty hung around there
all the time.
-What's the name of...?
-I, er, hope you like music
that's sweet and soft.
That's the mood I'm in.
What's the name
of the roadhouse?
The High Hat.
I'll show you where it is,
if you want to go out there.
Shall we start now?
All right.
I should have phoned
for a cab.
I left my car
in a parking lot uptown.
Oh, that's all right.
Mine's right here.
Oh.
(DISTANT SHIP'S HORN)
Do I make you nervous
driving around these curves?
No.
I thought you said this place
was just out of town.
It isn't much farther.
Don't you think we should
introduce ourselves?
Oh, I'm sorry.
I'm Earl Conrad.
My name is Vigran.
Antoinette Vigran.
You can call me Toni.
You mean that you're
Lefty Vigran's wife?
Yes.
Is it possible that you were
Lefty's partner?
-I was his wife.
-I know.
Did you work with him?
-Were you actually...
-Actually what?
I made a deal with Lefty.
I paid him to have
something done.
Oh, yes, I heard a little
about that.
You heard all about it.
You were the one
he told to do it.
But everything's changed now.
I don't want it done.
Don't you see?
I've got everything
in the world to live...
(TYRES SCREECHING)
(SIREN BLARING)
I hired Lefty
to have someone kill me
because I thought
my wife was dead.
Now I know she's alive.
So don't you see?
I don't want to die.
You had a wife
and you loved her,
and you didn't want to
live without her, is that it?
-Yes, and I...
-I had a husband.
I loved him.
I don't want to live
without him.
But Lefty was a murderer.
I don't know anything
about that.
All I know is you set him up
to be killed.
(SIREN BLARING)
Don't worry about them.
They can't take these curves
any faster than I can.
(TYRES SCREECHING)
What a mess.
Yeah, sure is.
That's all for her.
Yeah.
Wonder where her boyfriend is.
You better go up to the car
and report her.
-Right.
-I'm gonna take a look around for him.
THE WHISTLER:
It wasn't Earl Conrad's destiny
to go to his death
with Antoinette Vigran.
I know you're in here.
I want you to listen to me
for a minute,
then you can do
whatever you like.
I know you're in here.
ALICE:
Earl.
Earl, you've been
in an accident.
-Are you hurt?
-I'm all right.
Oh, I've been so worried all day.
When you left the office,
I thought you'd be back soon.
Why did you turn out
the lights in the study?
Well, I-I heard someone
outside the house,
but I didn't know
it was you.
By the way, who did you think
you were talking to
when you came
into the house?
Well, I didn't know.
I saw the lights go out
and knew someone was inside.
What did you mean
when you said,
"Listen to me for a minute,
then do what you like"?
You're afraid of someone, Earl.
Someone you believe
is going to kill you.
Isn't that true?
Now, you run on home, Alice.
I'll handle my own affairs.
-(DOORBELL CHIMING)
-Shall I answer it?
(WHISPERING)
No, I will.
Don't you come out in the hall,
no matter what happens.
Who's there?
Mr Conrad?
Yes, what is it?
We're from
the detective bureau.
Just a minute
till I answer the phone.
MAN:
Never mind, just open the door.
(WHISPERING)
I don't believe they're detectives.
I'm going to get out,
and you'd better come with me.
-Got a bed?
-Yeah, twenty-five cents.
You can take bed eleven,
second row.
And pay now.
-Hmm?
-Pay now.
Oh.
Wait a minute.
There ya are, nine seventy-five.
Name?
"John Smith."
(GRUNTING)
(SNORING)
(BEDSPRINGS CREAKING)
(SIGHING)
KILLER: Now, ya see,
in my business, er...
you have to be careful
of your reputation.
I'm in demand because people
know I always go through
with anything I start.
That reputation is just
as valuable to me
as yours is to...
As yours is to you.
(LAUGHING)
I think you're making
a fool of yourself.
You've been paid.
Vigran's gone.
His wife's gone.
Who's there to know whether
or not you go through with it?
The guy that paid Lefty'll know.
He doesn't know you.
Anyway, I'm havin' too good a time
to leave town now.
Too good a time?
Yeah.
My psychological experiment's
going great.
(CHUCKLING)
What are you talking about?
I'm rough-shadowing this guy.
-"Rough-shadowing"?
-Yeah.
That's what detectives call it
when they want a guy
they're shadowing to see them.
You know...
Familiar face bobbing up
here, there, everyplace.
They tell me that's hard
on the nerves.
(CHUCKLING)
There you are. That's what comes
of a fella like you
when he reads a book.
(LAUGHING)
The guy I've got marked
knows he's gonna get it.
All his actions prove that.
But he doesn't know when,
where or how,
because I don't know that
myself yet.
Well...
How'd you like to be
in his spot, Gorman?
(CHUCKLING)
I could have knocked him off
long ago,
only he's so scared, I...
I believe I can
scare him to death.
Thought you were kidding
about that.
I never kid.
At the right moment
I'll just show him a gun,
and he'll die of heart failure.
Yeah.
Maybe I'm on the track
of something big.
Something new
in the art of murder.
No fuss.
No muss.
Yeah.
Suppose he doesn't drop dead?
My gun won't be empty.
Well, I guess I'll get back
to my little playmate now,
in case he kicks his covers off.
Why...
Why don't you come
with me?
What I want you to do
is safe and easy.
Friday.
Then I'm your man.
Give me a fleabag.
This place is fumigated
every day.
Smells like it.
You can take any bed
that's vacant.
What's your name?
Any name.
"John Smith."
(SNORING)
(QUIETLY) I want Sergeant Klein,
Detective Bureau.
-What?!
-Ssh.
I was just trying
to wake ya.
(WHISPERING) Did you
come in here to ditch the cops?
Huh?
You must have flashed a roll
in front of that
stool-pigeon clerk.
He's back there telephonin'
the cops to come and get ya.
Ssh. Take your coat.
I'll show you a way
to get outta here.
Like I was telling you, huh?
This place is all right.
Ain't nobody gonna know
where you are, huh?
Here we are.
This is a cosy, quiet little place.
Sometimes I sleep here myself
when I can't dig up
a quarter for a bed.
There you are, mister.
Now, what do you say,
I give you a boost, huh?
Up you go.
(GRUNTING)
(WHISPERING)
Here we are, huh?
I always keep a candle
here somewhere.
Rats in this place
as big as beavers.
They won't hurt ya,
but you're liable to trip
over 'em in the dark.
Now...
There you are, mister.
Between them cases.
That's my bedroom.
Flop right down on 'em.
(SIGHING)
Nothin' like newspapers
to keep you warm.
You look very tired.
Yes.
(GUNSHOT)
(CLATTERING)
(QUIET CHATTERING)
Would you like to discuss
some life insurance with me?
You're not selling insurance.
You're the man Lefty Vigran
hired to kill me.
Why don't you stop clownin'?
You better take out some more
insurance today, because...
tomorrow may be too late.
Something I want to explain to you.
I'm the man who paid
Lefty Vigran.
So I'm the man
you're actually working for.
Yeah?
Now I've changed my mind.
I want to call
the whole deal off.
Oh, you can keep the money.
I don't care about that.
What money?
The five thousand that
Vigran gave you for killing me.
Yeah?
Now, this is somethin' new.
You mean, you paid a guy
to have yourself knocked off?
That's the truth.
Whaddaya know about that?
Huh.
That makes you a bad risk.
I don't think we can do
any more business.
Oh, it's understood, is it?
And you agree not to do
anything more about it?
Maybe.
Now, wait a minute.
You seem to forget that I saw
you kill a man in the warehouse.
What?
Oh, you know a lot about me,
don't you?
Maybe too much.
(LOUD CLATTERING)
MAN:
Had a drop too much, mate?
Come on.
Come on, try to get up.
That's it.
There.
Why, you ain't drunk.
Come on, pull yourself together
and I'll take ya inside.
Steady, now.
That's it.
There you are.
I'll get you a cup of coffee.
Now, you drink that,
and you'll find it'll warm you up.
Oh, and help yourself
to the sugar there.
I'll be back in just a minute.
(DISTANT SHIP'S HORN)
(DISTANT CHUGGING)
I don't think there's much use
waiting any longer.
Better go home
and get some rest.
Oh, I'll stay for a while. He...
He can't keep out of
everybody's sight indefinitely.
If there's anything I can do,
call me at home.
Thank you. Good night.
-This is for Mr Conrad.
-Thank you.
Sign here, please.
(SWITCHBOARD BUZZING)
Hello?
This Excelsior 41352?
Yes.
Who's speaking, please?
Well, I'll leave immediately.
The corner of First and Harbor.
Thank you.
(DISTANT FOGHORN)
(DOOR OPENING)
(DOOR CLOSING)
Well, do you feel better?
(CHUCKLING)
Hey, you're not
a talkative man, are you, hey?
I, er...
Oh, come on.
What seems to be the trouble?
Are you...
Are you sick?
Just tired, that's all.
Well, you can stay here
for a while
and rest yourself up.
Thanks.
You a seafaring man?
I was.
I just watch the dock now.
You see, it isn't
being used much and...
Well, I've got an easy enough job.
When is the ship
at the next pier sailing?
The Soddenhahn?
Say, you're not thinking of
shipping out on her, are you?
(CHUCKLING)
Why, that's the
Swedish Exchange ship.
She's chartered
by the Red Cross.
When's it sailing?
You know, I wouldn't
be a bit surprised
if she pulled out of here tonight.
But you've got to be either
a Swede sailor or a Jap prisoner
to get aboard her.
I was just curious,
that's all.
Well, I've got to go
on my rounds now.
So you, er...
You just stay here
and rest for a while.
And don't you worry if I'm not
back for, oh, say an hour or so.
Just...
you know, take it easy.
(DOOR CLOSING)
(BOLTING DOOR)
(DISTANT FOGHORN)
(WATER LAPPING)
(INSECTS CHIRRUPING)
Perhaps I'd better go in alone.
Watchman?
Yes.
Ah. You know, I was afraid
he might wander away
while I was meeting you.
He seemed very much interested
in that Red Cross ship
at the next pier.
Oh.
I'd like to go over there.
Do you mind going with me?
Why, I'd be glad to, ma'am.
MAN:
Watch that load there.
Wait a minute.
Hey, Mac, is this one
of your men?
No.
What are you trying
to do on this ship?
You're Conrad.
He's the amnesia case.
His picture
was in today's paper.
Oh, yes, I read about him
myself, Sergeant.
Remember who you are?
Of course.
You look pretty sick.
Come on down to the office.
I guess you can handle it
without me now, Miss Walker.
I can only thank you now,
but I wish you'd come
to the office tomorrow.
That's all right, ma'am.
But, Mr Conrad,
there's one thing
I'd like to know.
Exactly why did you try
to get onboard the ship?
Just a minute.
I think I can explain that.
You see...
(INAUDIBLE)
THE WHISTLER:
The police have Conrad now.
They'll make him talk.
He'll give them
your description
and he'll tell them about
the murder in the warehouse.
(THE WHISTLER
WHISTLING HIS THEME)
If they pick you up,
Conrad will identify you.
There may come a day
when he'll stand up in court
and give testimony
that will hang you.
You hadn't thought of that,
had you?
It was this man's destiny
to die tonight.
Earl Conrad lives,
because man cannot
change his destiny.
And, after this dark night,
he will recover
from his mental illness,
and there will come a new
chapter in his life
which will bring
happiness to him.
I know, because...
I am the Whistler.
(WHISTLING HIS THEME)
SUBTITLES BY POWERHOUSE FILMS LTD