(MAN WHISTLING
"THE WHISTLER" THEME)
THE WHISTLER:
I am the Whistler,
and I know many things,
for I walk by night.
I know many strange tales
hidden in the hearts
of men and women
who have stepped
into the shadows.
Yes, I know the nameless terrors
of which they dare not speak.
And one of the greatest
of these terrors
is loneliness.
In my wanderings,
I have seen
the lonely people of the Earth.
I have seen their drawn
and haunted faces
in a city of teeming millions.
And I have seen them,
too, in places
that have been long
deserted and forgotten.
Gull Point Lighthouse was
abandoned many years ago.
But, today, a woman
lives here all alone.
She never leaves her
forlorn and isolated home.
Hers is a strange story
for she loved the bustling cities,
the gay crowds,
the laughter of pleasant company.
Why, then, has she shut
herself away in this desolation,
where no-one ever
comes to visit her?
Hers is a story
of loneliness and greed.
It began years ago in a big city,
when the great industrialist
John Sinclair
was rising from obscurity.
(PROJECTOR WHIRRING)
(BRASS BAND PLAYING)
NARRATOR: The soldiers returning
from the First World War
found a changed America.
Mass production was
born out of the war,
bringing with it a new
school of industrialists.
John Sinclair was
the foremost of these.
The Gibson Motor Car Company
was a pioneer in its field,
a conservative company
with limited production,
until John Sinclair
bought the company
and adopted the slogan,
"A Car Within Every Man's Reach."
The year 1929 brought the greatest
financial disaster in history.
Millions were swept away
in the stock market crash.
Throughout the country,
hundreds of banks
closed their doors,
but the House of Sinclair
never failed
to meet its obligations.
Not a single depositor
lost any of his savings.
And John Sinclair paid
four percent interest
on every dollar
invested with him.
By 1931 , John Sinclair's qualities
of leadership, initiative,
and enterprise
won recognition
from the youth of America,
and he was awarded
an honorary life membership
in the Boy Scouts of America.
And here,
drawing to its conclusion,
we see the famous trial
of Sinclair and Associates
against the Turner Company
for infringement of patents.
(CHATTERING)
Very good.
Very good indeed.
MAN #1 : Yes, I thought it was
an excellent tribute.
MAN #2:
I enjoyed it very much.
Wake up.
Show's over.
How did you like the picture, John?
Satisfactory.
We thought it would
be a good idea
if you said a few words tonight
when we show it
at the banquet.
Stallings of Public Relations
has written a speech for you.
I won't be at the banquet.
But you're the guest of honour.
It's our testimonial to you.
After all, we are celebrating
the court decision
whereby Turner and Company
have to pay us twenty-two million
for infringement of
the Sinclair patents.
I see no cause
for celebration.
I knew how it'd turn out.
Planned the whole thing.
You handled the case
very well, Paul.
Thanks. I had to win
or you'd have fired me.
Probably.
Very likely would have.
We do wish you'd come
to the banquet, John.
Yes. It's a special occasion.
Then you can celebrate for me.
In future, I want one thing
clearly understood.
From now on, I want nothing,
absolutely nothing,
to interfere with my personal life.
What personal life?
THE WHISTLER: Suspicion and distrust
in his fellow man
have driven John Sinclair
to solitude.
There has been no time
for love or companionship
in his ruthless drive
for power and riches.
Even over his chess game,
he cannot relax,
for it is through the medium
of these ivory pawns
that he plans the strategy
to expand his enormous holdings.
But, without realising it,
he has already strained
body and mind beyond endurance.
I've been telling him
for a long time to take it easy.
Now he's gone the limit.
Another of these attacks
may be fatal.
I want him to go away
for a long rest,
forget about business,
and loaf.
He should go where he can't
be reached by telephone.
A boat trip on the Great Lakes
would be excellent.
I'll see that he goes.
And remember, no last day
to clean up the work at the office.
I want him to leave town
in the morning.
All right, Doctor.
I'll see you to your car.
Thank you.
(DOOR CLOSING)
I know Sinclair isn't married.
Has he any close relatives?
So far as I know,
he hasn't a relative in the world.
Well, he shouldn't go away alone.
Why not?
Well, another of these attacks
may be the last.
That's why somebody
should go with him.
A friend, if he has no relatives.
There isn't anyone in the world
he could call a friend.
Too bad. Well, good night.
Good night.
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
(KNOCKING)
Come in.
Telegram, Mr Sinclair.
I won't accept it.
It's for you, sir.
I don't care.
I won't take it.
I'm on a vacation.
STEWARD:
Last call for dinner!
Well, what shall
I do with it, sir?
Do anything you want to
with it. Tear it up.
I won't be bothered
with business.
Tell that dining car steward
I want my dinner
served in the room.
Very well, sir.
And another thing...
I'm not to be disturbed
till we get to Chicago.
Very well, sir.
(SIGHING)
(KNOCKING)
We're coming in to Chicago, sir.
Mr Sinclair?
Mr Sinclair...
Are you sick, sir?
Oh, I'm all right.
Is this Chicago?
Yes, sir, and you've got to
get across town to catch your boat.
Don't worry about
your baggage, sir.
The transfer company
will take care of that.
(CHATTERING)
Taxi, guv'nor?
What is it, guv'nor?
Are you all right?
Steady, guv'nor.
Put your arm
around my shoulder.
I'll help you to the cab.
Easy does it.
I'd better get you
to the doctor's.
I'll be all right.
I've had these attacks before.
Just as you say, guv'nor.
Where shall I drop you?
Dock 23. I'm taking
a steamer to Duluth.
Right you are, guv'nor.
(GENTLE SNORING)
(YELLING)
Here, here.
Take it easy.
You're with friends.
You became unconscious-like
before we ever reached the dock,
so I brought you up here.
This room's right next
to the one I live in.
How long have I been
like this?
All day. It's eight o'clock now.
I must have been
a lot of bother.
No bother at all, guv'nor.
Glad to do it.
I knew you was alone.
I'm used to being alone.
-(GROANING)
-Yes, I know.
I was in the same boat once.
You try and get some sleep.
I'll sit by in case
you want anything.
(CHAIR CREAKING)
So you're John Carter
of New York.
And you're Ernie Sparrow.
Lightweight champion of
England from 1919 to 1925.
Yes, I've had my moment
of glory, as you might say.
-Louis, how's tricks?
-Fine, Ernie, fine.
You know, they still talk about you
in the athletic clubs.
It was a long moment, too.
Morning, Mrs Smith.
MRS SMITH: Good morning,
Mr Sparrow.
I had all the money I wanted.
Boxed before the King and Queen.
I had the whole of England
in the palm of me glove.
-Cootchie-coo. How's the baby?
-She's fine, Ernie.
Yet, er, something
was missing, huh?
Yes, there was. Catch?
You were lonely.
How did you know?
Well, you said that
you were like me,
you didn't trust anyone.
Oh.
I was always training hard.
Never had time to make
many friends then.
Always liked people,
but never got to know them.
It was always
"hello" and "goodbye".
-TONY: Hello, Sparrow!
-How are ya, Tony?
How's the wife and kids?
And how's the business?
-Everything fine.
-Good.
-For you.
-Thanks.
That's for driving
the wife and kids to church.
That was nothing.
I was on me way home.
One for your friend.
Thank you.
And one for me, too.
Eat it.
It won't hurt you.
-Bye, Tony.
-Come back soon.
SPARROW:
I will.
I see what you mean
about making friends.
-What was I saying?
-Er...
Oh, yes.
Then, when I got the title,
it was worse than ever.
I had time to make friends then,
but I never knew who
my friends really where.
People always slapped
me on the back.
"How are you, Sparrow?"
"Have a drink, Sparrow."
That was it, guv'nor.
I had too many drinks.
Good morning, Ernie.
Hello, Mike.
I brought home a sack of
charcoal for you last night.
It's down at my place
when you need it.
Thank you.
Much obliged, Ernie.
You were saying something?
I was saying, so you
ran away from it all, huh?
You're right there
again, guv'nor.
-Hi, Al.
-Hiya, Sparrow.
-How's business?
-AL: Fine.
But I'm not sorry.
I'm happier in this country.
Here I'm just plain
Ernie Sparrow.
And I have real friends for
the first time in me life.
Here's one of them now.
Violets! Violets!
Buy your violets.
Got you, Ferdinand!
Hi, Sparrow.
Mr Carter, this is
Hammerlock Ferdinand.
He used to be a wrestler
and a very good one.
Now he's doing what
he wants to do,
growing his own flowers.
Hmm.
Glad to know you, Mr Carter.
Remember Ferdinand
the Bull?
He liked to smell
flowers, too.
I'll take that
sprig of violets.
Handle them gently,
now, Sparrow.
Don't crush 'em.
Remember, they're delicate things.
Righto, Ferdinand.
-Goodbye.
So, tell me, Sparrow,
how does a person go
about making friends?
You don't.
People make friends
with you,
if you give them
half a chance.
Well, here we are.
A clinic.
If anybody in the world
can help you, they can.
Last time I was sick,
I was given up for lost,
but, somehow,
they pulled me through.
Well, I'm sorry,
Sparrow, but I...
If you're gonna
trust people, Mr Carter,
you'd better start right now.
We all have to learn to
do that sooner or later.
I did.
Go on in.
Er, wait a minute.
Yes?
Do me a favour, will you?
Er, these violets.
There's a pretty
young girl in there.
Her name is Miss Joan Martin.
Give them to her, will you?
CHILDREN:
Choo, choo, choo, choo, choo...
(WOMAN LAUGHING)
WOMAN:
Oh, choo-choo yourself.
GIRL:
Choo, choo, choo, choo...
Goodbye, choo-choo.
Hello.
They're pretty. Can I smell?
Smells pretty.
For your girl?
No.
Can I be your girl?
My name's Bobbie.
Everyone says
that's a boy's name,
but it isn't.
What's your name?
John.
Well, this is a nice
state of affairs.
The minute I turn my back,
you're untrue to me.
All you women are alike.
I can't help it
if I'm popular.
(LAUGHING) They certainly learn
young nowadays, don't they?
Well, beautiful, if your
gentleman friend doesn't mind,
I must borrow you for a moment.
Goodbye.
Bye.
Hello, Bobbie.
How's our favourite patient?
Just fine, thanks.
Don't be nice to her, Joan.
She's been two-timing me.
-(CHUCKLING)
-No, I haven't.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Will you come in, please?
Just wait in here, please.
Thank you.
Good morning.
Your name, please?
John Carter.
Oh, I was told to take
very good care of you.
You're a very privileged man.
I don't understand.
You happen to have pull
with a certain young lady
by the name of Bobbie.
Oh.
Is your name, by any chance
Miss Joan Martin?
Why, yes.
These are for you.
(GASPING) Well, this is
sort of sudden, isn't it?
What'll Bobbie think?
Well, you don't understand.
Sparrow asked me
to give you those.
Oh, isn't that nice!
How thoughtful of Sparrow.
He's always doing things
for other people.
You've no idea how
he makes friends.
You be sure to thank him for me
when you see him, will you?
I certainly will.
Did you wish to see
Dr Rose, Mr Carter?
I hoped I might.
Let's see, um...
"Name, John Carter."
Address?
Er, 238 Gordon Street.
(MUMBLING)
No wife, no family, no relatives.
And should I add, er...
no friends?
Have you finished
your examination?
There's more
to an examination
than a physical check-up
and a few tests.
If I'm going to help you, you must
be perfectly honest with me.
Well, it's no use, really.
I... I've been to too many doctors.
I'm sorry if I've wasted
any of your time.
Well, of course we can't afford
to waste any time here.
There are too many people
who really need us.
And we don't care
who the patient is
or where he comes from, but
we do expect him to help us.
Think it over.
My office is open
to anyone at any time.
All finished?
Oh, yes.
Yes, thanks very much.
Well, goodbye, Miss Martin.
Well, when are
you coming back?
I don't know.
(DOOR CLOSING)
There you are.
You don't often see
a man of his type.
I wonder what his story is.
Hello.
Why, hello, Sparrow.
How's Florence Nightingale?
It was sweet of you
to send those flowers.
By the way,
how's your friend, Mr Carter?
I want to talk about him.
Why hasn't he come
back to the clinic?
I'm sure Dr Rose
could help him.
So am I.
You know, I think he'd come
back if you was to ask him.
Me?
Why, Sparrow,
I've only seen him once.
But you made a rare
impression on him.
He's staying at my place.
Would you ask him
as a favour to me?
-All right.
-Ha!
(ENGINE STARTING)
(KNOCKING)
JOHN:
Come in.
Someone to see you, John.
Well, this is
a pleasant surprise.
Mr Carter, I...
I hope you won't think
it presuming of me,
but I wondered
why you didn't come
back to the clinic.
Well, whatever the reason,
it is nice of you to come.
Er, why-why should you
concern yourself about me?
I-I don't know.
Dr Rose send you?
Oh, no.
I know it may sound
very strange to you, but...
Well, when you
didn't come back,
I began to worry about you.
You worried about me,
a total stranger?
Some people are never
strangers, Mr Carter.
Won't you come back
to the clinic
and see Dr Rose again?
I know he can help you,
i-if you'll only let him.
Will you?
Mm-hmm.
I have the laboratory
reports, Mr Carter.
They are not favourable.
Well, I didn't expect they would be.
Well, of course, I only know
what your body tells me.
But there are things
about a man
that the body has
nothing to do with.
What you're trying to say is,
if there's any help for me,
it hasn't anything to do
with medical science.
Well, something like that.
Well, I was planning
a trip on the Great Lakes.
Well, that's the worst thing
you could possibly do.
Why?
For a man without friends,
there are few places so lonely
as a crowded steamship.
And you'll find the sea coast
much more relaxing
than the Midwest.
Well, go up to the coast
of Maine somewhere.
Get good sea air into your lungs
and wholesome thoughts
into your mind.
Get a job.
And, above everything,
try to make friends.
And never forget, Mr Carter,
that loneliness is a disease
that can destroy a man's mind.
Could a man's mind give way
from lack of companionship?
Could a man actually die
for want of a friend?
You are the answer to
your own questions, Mr Carter.
Well, goodbye, Dr Rose.
Thank you.
Oh, Mr Carter.
Mr Carter!
What's the matter?
Nothing.
I know.
I feel sorry for him, too.
But for your own
peace of mind, Joan,
you can't allow yourself
to become interested
in a patient's troubles.
I guess I'll never get used to
working around here.
FRED:
Busy for a minute, dear?
No.
I want to talk about us.
Of course, Fred.
You know, between
the night work here
and my lectures
with Dr Farnum,
we hardly see each other
except when we're working.
You're right.
I'm really the world's
most neglected fiancée.
(CHUCKLING)
But you're the one
who wanted to wait.
You didn't want to get married
until I'd established my own practice.
And you agreed with me.
I've changed my mind.
I think we should
get married right away.
No.
After all, darling, it'll
only be another six months
until you've finished your work
with Dr Farnum. Then...
Then I still won't
have enough money
to start on my own anyway.
Oh, come on, Joan, say you'll settle
for a weekend honeymoon.
I can't, Fred.
I want a home and security.
I want our children
to see the sun
without having to go
to a public park.
And I want you to come home
from your office with pride,
not tortured
and frightened by debt.
You don't show
much faith in me.
Oh, I do have faith
in you, darling.
Everything in me
wants to say yes.
But I won't chain
your life and mine
to an environment like this.
FRED: I wish I could
believe you're right.
I am.
(BOTH CHUCKLING)
(QUIET CHATTERING)
What you gonna do?
I was asking,
what you gonna do?
I'm gonna take Dr Rose's advice.
I know you can get a refund
on your boat ticket,
but will that leave you
with enough to go to Maine?
Look here.
This is no time for silly pride.
I've got enough put by
to tide you over for a while.
We'll go to the bank
first thing in the morning,
and you can be on your way.
Well, you hardly know me.
It ain't time that makes
a man trustworthy.
I'm bettin' on you
all the way.
Well, this is the first
time in my life
that anything like this
has ever happened to me.
I don't know what to say.
Just say "yes", and we don't
need to say no more about it.
But I don't need money.
I have more than enough.
I don't understand.
Sparrow, I've found something here
that money can't buy.
Something that I
didn't know existed.
Come to think of it,
a six months' vacation
wouldn't do you any harm.
Why don't you put that
cab of yours in storage
and come along as my guest?
I couldn't think of it.
Well...
If you put it that way,
I can't refuse.
-(CHUCKLING) It's a deal.
-Fine.
-Let's go.
-Right.
-Hello, Joan!
-Good evening.
Hello.
Is Fred working again tonight?
I'm afraid I was
rude this afternoon.
Oh, I understood.
I'm putting the old bus
in storage tomorrow.
Mr Carter and me's off to Maine
for health and happiness.
I see you're finished
with your dinner.
Why don't you join us
for a last spin in the park?
Wish you would.
I'd love to.
Okay, let's go.
There were times when we didn't
have enough food in the house
or money for medicine,
when I was a child.
Maybe that's the reason
I went to work for Dr Rose.
Do you intend to devote
your entire life
to working with these people?
No. So long as I work,
I'll remain with them.
But when I get married,
I intend to leave it forever.
Oh, it's not that my
husband has to be rich,
but he can't be poor, either.
I don't want my children to have
a childhood like I did.
Or the youngsters in the clinic.
Well, that's very understandable.
Of course, you do get
away on your vacation.
You don't take vacations
when you work for Dr Rose.
You sure need one, Joan.
Why don't you come along
with me and Mr Carter?
I guess our housekeeping
could stand a feminine touch.
Fred would love that.
Is Fred the young man
who doesn't have to be rich
but doesn't dare to be poor?
Oh, I'm sorry.
He's going to be a great specialist
one of these days.
You mark my words.
He's studying with
the lung specialist, Dr Farnum.
All the evenings he can
get away from the clinic.
How long have you been engaged?
Four years.
Sparrow, it's been a lovely drive,
but I think we
should go home now.
Right you are, Joan.
-Hey, have you packed yet?
-Yes, sir.
-Well, I'd like to pack.
And another thing, let's get started on
a man-to-man basis.
No more of that "sir" stuff, huh?
Righto, guv'nor.
-Say, have you stored your car yet?
-Not yet.
How'd we get to the station
if I put the old bus away?
Well, we could take a cab.
There ain't no profit in that.
(CHUCKLING) Well, you get rid of
that hack of yours.
I'll take care of the tickets.
Yes, sir.
I mean, um...
guv'nor.
(DOOR CLOSING)
Oh, hello, Mr Carter.
Hello, Ferdinand.
-Flowers today, sir?
-Yes.
Well, we have
some roses, asters...
These two I can't pronounce.
-Carnations...
-I'll take all of 'em.
-Violets... All of 'em?
-Yes, all of 'em.
Youse going into business?
No, I want some flowers,
a lot of flowers.
Want to impress a girl.
Oh. Some impress.
Well, these are two-and-a-half.
I'll give 'em for two bucks.
A dollar and a quarter,
for a dollar.
These I'll throw in.
A dollar seventy-five,
eighty cents...
Er, thirty-seven fifty?
-Delivered?
-Delivered.
You take this end.
I'll take your end. Come on.
This is the place.
-What now?
-Wait right here.
Why, look, Georgie,
I don't know when I've seen
such nice, fresh flowers.
Yes, very pretty.
Er, how much are
your carnations?
-Two dollars a dozen.
-Why, that's outrageous!
Did you ever hear of
such a thing, Georgie?
What have you got
that's within reason?
Marigolds.
Two bits a bunch.
I don't like marigolds.
They smell up the whole house.
So do roses.
It's all a matter of money.
If you got four dollars
and want to smell up the house,
you buy roses.
If you got two bits,
buy marigolds.
How much are your violets?
Twenty cents a bunch,
three for a half.
Well, that's more like it.
Wrap them up.
They're not for sale.
Didn't you just say they were
three bunches for fifty cents?
That's right, but only
when they're for sale.
Georgie, this man is trying
to make a fool out of me.
That's a wonderful idea.
Yes, it certainly...
What did you say?
-Hmm?
-Why, the very idea
of you siding in with him
and insulting me...
(LAUGHING)
Don't you ever say that
to me again. Don't you dare!
It certainly was nice of you
to drop by and say goodbye.
Well, I wanted to bring you
a few flowers before I leave.
How thoughtful.
Hello, Ferdinand.
Hello, Joan.
Look, Mr Carter bought 'em all.
-(LAUGHING)
-All?!
Er, Ferdinand, maybe you better
take 'em in the clinic.
Yeah, maybe I better.
(CHUCKLING)
That was an awfully
nice thing for you to do.
Will you have lunch with me now?
Well, I don't have very long.
Oh, we'll just go down the street.
All right.
(CHATTERING)
You know, there's so much
I have to say to you
and so little time
in which to say it
that I hardly
know where to begin.
Will there be anything else?
No, that's all. Thank you.
What's bothering you?
Sparrow said something
last night, jokingly,
and I've been thinking
about it ever since.
What was that?
About you coming
along with us.
-Oh, you can't be serious.
-I am.
Of course, I realise
that we have
only the most casual
interest in each other.
So I'll put my proposal
on a business basis.
"Proposal"?
Yes.
I'm asking you to marry me.
What?
But...
I'm not in love with you.
Oh, I know that.
When two people go
into a business deal,
there has to be something
in it for each one.
Now, what you have to offer
is my chance to live a lifetime
within a few months.
In return for those few months,
you'll be able to have
everything you ever wanted.
Does the name Sinclair
mean anything to you?
Sinclair...
John Sinclair?
Yes.
I took the name of Carter
because I'm sick and tired
of the dishonesty
surrounding Sinclair.
I wanted to be another man
for the time being.
Any man.
Oh, I see.
Oh, you don't have
to decide now.
Think it over, carefully.
And remember,
my entire fortune
for a few months of your life.
(INSECTS CHIRRUPING)
You're late.
Sorry. I was held up
at the last moment.
Did you get it?
Easy, dear.
What's all this mystery about
Carter being John Sinclair?
You certainly were
excited over the phone.
Now, suppose you tell me
what it's all about.
I will.
I will in just a minute.
You know it's not right
going through the files
and taking out cards.
Are you sure
this report's correct?
I don't know why
you're so worried about it.
Answer my question.
Yes, I'm positive it's correct.
I made that report myself,
and Dr Rose agreed with it.
Look, darling,
let's find a bench
and talk about ourselves, huh?
Come on.
Oh, it's good.
Good to have a night off.
I hardly ever see you anymore
except at the clinic.
Well, it can't last forever.
Just a little while longer
and I'll be able
to have my own practice.
(CHUCKLING)
Business will probably be so bad
you'll complain about my being
around the house too much.
Oh, Fred, I do love you.
You must believe me.
Oh, Fred...
it's so wrong living the kind of life
we have to live.
Struggling, never being able
to have the things people should have.
You've been very patient
to stick it out.
But you won't be sorry.
Just wait and see.
Fred...
I'm going to marry
John Sinclair tomorrow.
What did you say?
Oh, I know
it sounds ridiculous,
but it's our chance to get
everything we've ever wished for.
You mean, you've wished for.
It's just an arrangement
for a short time.
He knows he's going to die.
Oh, Fred, try to understand.
It's for us.
It's not wrong.
Tell me it's not wrong.
Tell you what?
You say you're in love with me
and yet you could even think of
doing something like that?
Oh, I do love you.
Oh, that's great. Yeah.
(CHUCKLING)
You're so much in love with me
that you can't wait
to marry somebody else.
Oh, don't lie, Joan.
Why don't you tell the truth?
You never even thought of me.
You're doing it
because you're selfish.
Because you're not satisfied
to wait and work hard
like any normal,
decent woman would do.
No, I don't think you're
being dishonest...
I think you're rotten!
Why shouldn't I have
my chance?
For four years now,
I've waited for you.
Do you think it's been fun
being alone night after night?
Being in love with
someone you never see?
I'm human!
Oh, Fred, I do love you.
I always will.
I've given you the
chance to get ahead,
and you've failed.
Now I'm gonna do it my way.
I've waited for you
because I believed in you.
But you're soft.
You've been afraid.
You're always letting other people
push you down.
Oh, Fred...
Try to understand.
Yeah.
Thanks.
Thanks for everything...
Mrs Sinclair.
Fred. Fred!
THE WHISTLER: John Sinclair
converted this abandoned lighthouse
into a beach home.
Here, he learned to relax.
The simple wholesome life
and Joan's care
brought an astonishing
change in him.
But, as the months passed,
the strange bargain
between Sinclair and his wife
took an ironic twist.
You're a real outdoor man now.
You can do a day's work
with the best of them.
Ain't this the life?
Yeah, it's the life.
There's something
bothering me, Sparrow.
I'd like your advice.
Right, Cap'n.
I think I know what
you're going to say.
Yeah?
You're not the first bloke
what's fall in love
with his nurse, right?
Right.
I am in love with Joan.
That's what comes from
getting your health back.
Have you mentioned the
matter to the lady yet?
Well, that's rather difficult.
You see, our marriage
is based entirely on
a business proposition.
What are you going to do?
Eat your heart out in silence?
Well, I don't know.
Trouble is, I've always had my
own way about everything, except...
The most important thing, guv'nor.
I'd have talked to her long ago
if I was in your place.
Have it out with her tonight.
What shall I say?
First of all, I'd apologise to her
for being alive.
You were supposed to die
in six months, remember?
That was part of
your marriage contract,
so, don't you
owe her an apology
for breaking your agreement?
I'd tell her it was her fault
for taking such good care of you.
Maybe you got something there.
Hello, Joan.
How's the water?
Don't you think it's dangerous,
swimming out so far?
I'm perfectly able to
take care of myself, John.
Won't you change your mind
and come with us tomorrow?
You know I don't
like boat trips.
Well, wait just a minute, and
I'll walk up to the house with you.
No, thanks.
It's chilly.
I'm going back now.
Cap'n, maybe my
advice wasn't so good.
Why don't you
wait a little while
before you talk to her?
I'll have to work this out
my own way.
I hopes you know
what you're doing.
Oh, Sparrow, I don't feel
like playing tonight.
That suits me fine.
You must be tired. Why don't you
get a good night's rest?
You know, we've got a big day
ahead of us tomorrow.
I feel fresh as a daisy.
Sparrow...
Oh, yes, come to think of it,
I am a bit tired.
-Good night.
Joan, let's take a little walk
down the beach.
I want to talk to you.
We can talk here.
Oh, but you don't
understand, Joan. I...
I understand only
one thing, John.
I'm leaving you.
Leaving me? Why?
Ever since we've been here,
I've been completely alone,
except for Sparrow and you.
Nobody ever comes near this place.
You even do all your
business by telephone.
I thought you were happy here.
I hate it here!
We never go anywhere.
We never see anybody.
You never invite anyone to visit us.
I can't stand it here any longer!
Joan, we made a bargain and...
That's just it. I've kept my
part of the bargain, you haven't.
Oh, it... It isn't being married
to you, John, that I mind. It's...
It's this place!
Are you sure it isn't
your young doctor that you miss?
At first, I thought
that was the reason, but...
Oh, well, that's all over now.
I gave Fred up
when I came here.
Oh...
Oh, John,
let's call off our bargain.
You don't need me anymore.
You're all right now.
Oh, but I do need you.
I've been so busy getting well
that I didn't realise
how lonely you've been until now.
If we were to leave here,
it'd make a difference,
wouldn't it, Joan?
Oh, maybe, I...
I don't know.
Well, we'll leave here.
We'll travel, Joan.
We'll visit all the places
you've ever wanted to go to.
We'll do all the things that
you've ever wanted to do.
I promise you
you'll never be lonely again.
I'll be able to straighten
out my affairs in a few days
and I'll make
all the arrangements.
I love you, Joan.
You've got to stay with me.
Sparrow!
Hey, Sparrow!
Well, I'll be. Doc!
How are you?
What a surprise.
Where'd you come from?
How did you get here?
How long are you gonna stay?
Not so fast, Sparrow.
I'm tired enough as it is.
I've been walking for miles.
How anyone could find
this place is beyond me.
Exclusive, that's what we is.
Exclusive!
Wait till Joan sees you.
Will she be surprised!
You stay here.
Just wait till Joan sees you.
Joan! Oh, Joan!
JOAN: Yes, Sparrow?
What is it?
SPARROW:
Guess who's here?
Hello, Joan.
Fred!
Oh, Fred!
Where'd you come from?
How'd you get here?
How long are you gonna stay?
Oh, you're as bad as Sparrow.
Give me a chance
to catch my breath.
(CHUCKLING)
I'll give you just two minutes,
and then I'm gonna fire
question after question at you.
Oh, Fred,
it's so good to see you.
I'll see you later, Doc.
Come on up.
Clever idea, turning a lighthouse
into a beach home.
An expensive idea.
Is it much further?
What's the matter?
Can't you take it?
This is good exercise.
-Yeah.
-Come on.
Oh, at last.
It's lovely, isn't it?
Yeah. Yes, it is.
Not me, silly, the view.
Oh, sure.
That's all right, too.
This is our solarium.
On a clear day...
BOTH: You can see for miles out to sea.
(LAUGHING)
Oh, Fred, it's so wonderful
to see you again.
Did you miss me?
Of course I did.
You must have been lonely.
A little.
Who's the chess player?
John. He's a master at it.
He's been teaching me to play.
How is he?
Much better than when
you last saw him.
He's gone to the city
for a few days.
Joan, when you
play chess with him,
don't you get a feeling
you're being trapped?
What do you mean?
Oh, looking for a way out
and not finding any.
What makes you say that?
I don't know. It...
It's just a feeling I have
that you're not
really happy here.
Joan, you know
it's still not too late.
I tried staying angry
with you, but I couldn't.
Why don't you admit
you made a mistake?
Tell Sinclair you're
coming back with me.
Maybe I'm still selfish, Fred.
But, Joan, I...
I left the clinic.
I have my own practice now.
We can have all the things
we've always wanted.
Why didn't you
tell me this before?
Because of pride, I guess, and...
then I realised I needed you
more than anything else.
That's funny.
If you'd told me this and asked me
just a few days ago,
I would have said yes.
Then why not now?
Because John has fallen
in love with me.
I see.
He made the same mistake I did.
Now we're both in love with you.
FRED: I guess the plans
we made together
don't mean anything
more to you now.
JOAN: Oh, Fred,
of course they do.
Just... Just give me
a little more time.
All right, Joan.
It's gonna be interesting
to see what happens.
But, somehow or other, I'll
make you see things my way.
JOHN: Hello, Joan.
You up there?
Well, hello, Fred!
Well, this is a grand surprise!
What's, er...
What's the matter with you two?
Fred, this is terrific!
It's grand to see you.
Oh, I forgot,
I'm sore at you.
This is the first time you've shown up
since we've been here.
How do you think I look?
Wonderful, John.
You don't look so well, Fred.
Does he, dear?
Well, we'll have to fix that.
You're gonna stay
right here with us
until we close this place
and move back to New York.
Isn't he, darling?
You promised to make up
your mind today.
I have.
Well?
I've been here now
for six months,
shut away from the world,
away from life.
And now I'm going to collect
for every minute of that time.
But we'll still be able
to see a lot of each other.
It'll work out.
Just you wait and see.
How nice.
I'll just stick around
and every time Sinclair
goes out the front,
I'll sneak in
through the back door.
Stop it, Fred.
You must try to understand.
Nothing could ever
possibly come between us.
You know that.
I do, Joan.
We only disagree on
one little thing.
The only way I'll ever come in
is through the front door.
Remember that.
Couldn't you wait just
a little while longer?
No.
You see, I've changed.
You once said I was soft.
I-I let people
push me around.
And you were right.
But not anymore.
I've tried to
get you out of my mind.
I know it's wrong
to keep on loving you,
but I can't help it.
There's nothing
I can do about it.
But you're not
going to ruin my life.
You've had your chance.
Now, I'm going to
do things my way.
I'm afraid we're not
being very good hosts.
Joan has a bad headache
and I'm tired.
Please don't apologise.
After all,
I barged in on you.
Here's one of Sparrow's mystery books.
How about that?
Some people find them relaxing.
Thanks.
I'll be ready for bed myself,
in an hour or so.
You know,
most people like those,
but, personally, I can't
get interested in them.
You always know the murderer's
gonna get caught.
Oh, of course.
Murder's one thing
nobody can get away with.
Oh, I don't know about that.
In real life, there are
some unsolved murders.
All it takes is the intelligence
to work out a plan
and then the nerve
to carry it through.
-You think so?
-Oh, certainly.
It's like a game of chess.
Come over here.
Now, supposing
I had some good reason
for wanting you
out of the way.
Here's how I'd go about
murdering you.
(LAUGHING) Don't...
Don't look alarmed.
Look at the board.
(CHUCKLES)
Now, move number one,
witnesses.
I'd establish my alibi.
-How?
-Simple.
I'd let it be known
that you'd been
walking in your sleep.
I'd tell Sparrow.
It'd get around the village.
I'd say that
I caught you halfway
out of one of these
solarium windows.
Why not the bedroom window?
Too narrow.
A man couldn't get through it.
Then I'd tell Sparrow...
I'd throw your body
through this window.
At four a.m., the tide
would carry your body out to sea.
And, as far as the police
were concerned,
an unfortunate sleepwalker
had met an accidental death.
In chess,
that's known as checkmate.
You missed your calling.
You'd make a master criminal.
Well, it's a pretty good murder,
if I do say so myself.
Pretty good?
It's clever!
Ah, but there's
something wrong with it.
There's one thing missing.
What's that?
I have no motive whatever
for murdering you.
(BOTH CHUCKLING)
You going downstairs?
Oh, don't forget your book.
Er, no, no, I, er...
I think I'll sit up here
for a while and read.
THE WHISTLER: What did he mean
by that game of chess?
Is he planning to kill you?
Or only trying to frighten you?
Better leave here
before it's too late.
You've lost Joan,
haven't you?
Or is there something
you can do about it?
(WAVES CRASHING)
Evening, Fred!
Oh, hello, Sparrow.
Where are you off to?
Oh, I'm gonna do
a bit of surf fishing.
Nice night for it.
Do you want to come along?
No, thanks.
Oh, Sparrow, er,
will you do me a favour?
-Anything you say.
-Thanks.
Look, when you go down
to the village tomorrow,
will you, er, stop in
the marine hardware store
and buy some locks?
Tomorrow is Sunday, Doc.
Sunday?
Oh, yes, I'd forgotten.
Well, you can get them
first thing on Monday.
All right. Er...
What kind do you want?
Let's see, um...
Just locks for windows.
How many you need?
Mmm, there's ten windows.
I'll need ten locks.
What you need all those for?
Nobody can get in through
a lighthouse window.
It's a steep drop.
I'm not worried about
anybody getting in.
I'm worried about
somebody falling out.
Falling out?
What do you mean?
I don't want to alarm
you or Joan, Sparrow,
but last night I caught John
walking in his sleep.
Walking in his sleep?
Yeah, I heard someone
moving around,
so I got up to investigate.
The noise seemed to come
from the solarium.
When I reached there,
I saw him climbing out
through one of the windows.
I pulled him back just in time,
or he would have fallen
and killed himself.
Over-exercise,
that's what it is.
He's been taking things
too strenuous.
I'll get the locks
as quickly as possible.
Oh, Sparrow,
don't mention this to Joan.
She doesn't know
anything about it,
and there's no need
to worry her.
Mum's the word.
And whatever you do,
don't say anything to John either.
He doesn't realise
what danger he was in.
He didn't wake up
till it was all over.
No, I won't tell him.
Funny I never knew.
Good night, Doc.
Good night, Sparrow.
-Good morning.
-How do you do?
Will you please fill this
prescription for a sedative?
It's for Mr Sinclair.
He's not sleeping well.
You want it in tablets?
No, I'd like to have it in
powder form,
if you have it.
Mr Sinclair can't swallow pills.
Here you are.
Better tell him to be careful
not to take an overdose.
This is powerful stuff.
FRED:
I know. I'm a doctor.
THE WHISTLER: Everything's
working perfectly, isn't it?
Wasn't it thoughtful
of Sinclair to tell you
exactly how to murder him?
You know John will sleep soundly
when he drinks this.
Coffee, John?
Black, please.
Thanks.
Sorry you had
to change your plans
about leaving tomorrow.
Er, yes, I-I would have
preferred staying
until you closed the house
and gone back
with you and Joan.
Well, maybe you won't go.
Maybe you'll feel differently
about it tomorrow.
Couldn't you possibly stay
a little longer, Fred?
No, er...
No, my work's piling up.
I've... I've gotta get back.
It's been wonderful,
your being with us.
Yes. Yes, it has.
Well, I think I'll take my coffee
into the solarium.
I'd like a farewell
look at the view.
Coming, John?
I'll be with you in a minute.
(DOOR CLOSING)
One grand fella, Fred.
You're gonna miss him,
aren't you, darling?
Coffee cold?
Well, here, take mine.
Mine's warmer.
I... I guess I'll
turn in now, dear.
I-I'm really exhausted.
I'll have my coffee
before I go to bed.
-Good night.
-Good night, darling.
(DOOR OPENING)
(DOOR CLOSING)
(CLATTERING)
Where are you?
I know you're
in the room.
I know you're in here!
Where are you?
I know you're here!
I know you're in here.
Please... Please!
I wasn't gonna...
Sinclair... Sinclair, don't!
Don't!
(HYPERVENTILATING)
THE WHISTLER: You told Fred
every step in your scheme
and he helped you
carry it out.
Who would suspect
that a murdered man
would collaborate in his
murderer's alibi?
Hurry, John, hurry.
The coroner may be
able to determine
that Fred was dead before
his body struck the rocks.
No, the windows won't open.
This calls for a quick
change of plans, doesn't it?
Carry the body
downstairs, quickly,
and lay it on the rocks.
Then you'll have time
to come up later
and open one of the windows.
It's riskier than your first plan,
but when you tell the police
about walking in your sleep
and finding that Fred had fallen out
while trying to save you,
maybe they won't examine
the body too closely.
(CLATTERING)
(CRYING OUT)
Sparrow,
what are you doing here
this time of night?
I often go walking
in the early morning.
You know that.
Something terrible has happened.
-Fred is...
-The doctor?
Yes.
I must have been
walking in my sleep.
I woke up halfway out of
one of the solarium windows.
Fred must have fallen out
trying to pull me back.
I saw him hit the rocks.
It was horrible.
You say he fell out of
one of the windows
in the solarium?
Yes.
That's impossible.
Impossible?
What do you mean?
I couldn't buy locks
on Sunday, John,
so I nailed all the
solarium windows shut today.
All right, Sparrow.
It didn't happen
just the way I said.
But it was an accident.
Fred tried to kill me tonight,
so that Joan would be
free to marry him.
-I can prove it.
-How?
I suspected him,
and I rigged up a dummy
and I put it in the bed.
I can show you where he
tried to kill me in my sleep.
Show me, John.
And if it's the truth...
I'll stand by ya.
I'll show you.
There's been a terrible accident.
Fred fell from a window
in the solarium.
That's a lie.
He didn't fall.
I saw you carry his body
down the stairs.
You murdered him.
But you don't understand.
Fred tried to kill me.
No, he didn't.
You murdered him because
you knew I loved him.
Joan, let me explain.
It won't do you any good.
I've called the police.
It's too late now, John.
I guess you'll have to face it.
THE WHISTLER: Sparrow did
what he could for his friend,
but the jury didn't believe
John Sinclair's story,
and he paid the extreme penalty
for the murder of Fred Graham.
Joan inherited the Sinclair millions,
and went away
to the life of luxury
she had always craved.
But constantly haunting her
was the tragedy that cost the lives
of the man she loved
and the man she married.
She travelled from city to city,
seeking forgetfulness.
But there was no
escape from the past.
She came back, at last,
to live out a life of torment
in the solitude and
desolation of the lighthouse.
I know, because
I am the Whistler.
(WHISTLING HIS THEME)
SUBTITLES BY POWERHOUSE FILMS LTD