(dramatic music)
♪ We're on safari, beat that drum ♪
♪ Go on safari to kingdom come ♪
(men sing chorus in foreign language)
♪ I want a ticket to be free ♪
♪ Give me the pass to liberty ♪
(men sing chorus in foreign language)
(drum beating)
(drum beating continues)
(dramatic music)
(dramatic music continues)
(music fades)
(drums beating in distance)
♪ We're on safari, hit that drum ♪
♪ Go on safari to kingdom come ♪
(men sing chorus in foreign language)
♪ I want a ticket to be free ♪
♪ Give me the pass to liberty ♪
(men sing chorus in foreign language)
Daddy! Daddy!
Hiya, boy!
Buddy! Buddy! (chuckles)
Did you bring me a present?
Ah! I completely forgot.
Ah, you always say
that but you never do!
Aw, I know.
[Both] An apple a day
keeps the doctor away.
(Ken laughs)
-Jerusalem!
-Bwana?
[Ken] Shove off!
Jerusalem, shove off!
(men laughing)
-Okay, little bwana!
This is my son, Kenny,
Mr. George Jason, Mr. Evans.
Hello, sir. How do you do, sir?
Hey, it's a tank. I
wonder who this tank is for?
A tank!
-Does it fire?
-Of course it does.
(engine turns over)
Daddy, will you take me with you?
When you grow up.
I grew two whole inches last year.
But you haven't grown enough.
Jeroge?
-Yes, bwana?
Be sure and take care
of the little wimp here,
and his Aunty May.
Yes, sir, bwana.
Bye, Kenny!
Bye!
(men shouting)
Bye.
Golly!
(elephant grunting)
(birds chirping)
(elephant trumpets)
(trumpeting continues)
You have first go.
(elephant trumpeting)
(dramatic music)
Don't move.
(elephant trumpets)
(dramatic music continues)
(gunshot bangs)
I'm sorry, that was a near one.
Forget it. It happens to all of us.
(horn honking in distance)
It's a DC's car. He's way off his beat.
What does that mean?
It can only mean one thing, trouble.
They are waiting, bwana, waiting.
Calling Roy Shaw. Come
in, Roy, this is Duffield.
The DC told me to call
you. What's the problem?
Hello, Ken.
There's big trouble near Rumuruti.
White settler killed.
They've never struck in that area before.
It's getting near your house,
and I thought you ought to know.
(frantic music)
(disquieting music)
(tank whirring)
Come along, Kenny! Time for bed.
Oh, no, Aunt May, five more minutes?
You heard.
Batten the window catches, Jeroge.
Wambui, you bolt the door.
(ominous music)
(victim yells)
(suspenseful music)
(dramatic music)
(Mau Mau shouting)
(frantic music)
Mau Mau!
(Mau Mau shouting)
Kenny, get out the back and hide!
-No, no, I'll take...
-Go on, get out!
Get out and hide!
(glass shattering)
(dramatic music)
(gunfire blasting)
(men groaning)
Here, memsahib.
(gunfire blasting)
Kenny, I'm going around to the back!
Get some ammunition,
Jeroge! Don't stand there!
(glass shattering)
(dramatic music)
(gunfire blasts)
Go around to the back, Kenny!
Why?
(gunfire blasting)
Open the other box!
(blade thudding)
(dramatic music)
(gunfire blasting)
(Mau Mau shouting)
I'll go around to the back, bwana!
Right!
(gunfire blasting)
(terrifying music)
Jeroge! No, Jeroge!
(gunfire blasting)
(gunshot bangs)
(dramatic music)
(fire roaring)
(vultures squawking)
(grim music)
(grim music continues)
(disconcerting music)
(dramatic music)
(officer speaks foreign language)
(dramatic music continues)
(mournful music)
I wouldn't go inside if I were you.
(heavy-hearted music)
(heavy-hearted music continues)
Ken, one of your own men
was responsible for this,
a houseboy, Jeroge.
Jeroge?
We got it out of those
wounded men down there, Ken.
Jeroge was one of their generals.
Jeroge?
Ken, we'll clear up here.
You go back to Nairobi.
And don't get any wrong ideas.
Finding Jeroge is our job.
It was your job last night.
We'll get Jeroge, Ken.
You have my word for it.
Where's my key?
One of my boys will drive
you back to Nairobi, Ken.
Inspector!
-Sir?
You mustn't go taking the
law into your own hands.
I'm afraid you can't
come back into the district
until we've got Jeroge under lock and key.
(dramatic music)
Inspector, we'd better arrange
to have his hunter's licence revoked.
That'll keep him in Nairobi
until further notice.
(dramatic music)
That's the plane, all right.
We've still got time for another drink.
Good, I'm going to need it.
I'm not looking forward to this much.
Oh, it's not your fault
that Duffield isn't available.
Sir Vincent must realise that.
I'm afraid Sir Vincent
will only realise one thing,
that I was sent out here in advance
to get him what he wanted,
and I've lost his white hunter.
Ah, Brian!
Hello, Vincent. Hi, Linda.
Hello, Brian.
This is Roy Shaw, of
the African Hunters.
Nice of you to come and meet us.
-My fiancee, Miss Latham.
-How do you do?
Come on, the boys will
take care of the customs.
Just one more question...
Did you have a nice trip?
I guess so, no clouds,
no bumps, no sleep.
(both chuckle)
No comment. I told you I'm on holiday.
By the way, isn't it usual
for my hunter to come and meet me?
How's Duffield?
Well, I'm afraid Duffield's
out of the game for a bit.
I've got another man for you.
Oh, what's this?
Brian, I thought you cabled me
that Duffield was contracted.
Well, it's not his fault.
Anyway, the substitute is just as good.
-Hmm, I don't accept substitutes.
-The fact is, Vincent...
The facts are perfectly plain, Brian.
You have, in common parlance,
mucked things up again.
You know, I'm getting a little
tired of you as a lame dog.
The time is rapidly approaching
when I'll have to throw you to the wolves.
Oh, don't be so rough on Brian, Vincent.
What difference does it make?
I'm sure the other hunter is just as good.
Nobody is "just as good," Linda,
when I choose a hunter or a wife.
You should realise that.
You say the nicest and the
nastiest things, Vincent,
I get so confused.
Well, we don't want to hang about here.
Brian, find this man Duffield
and bring him to the hotel
at 8:00 this evening.
[Linda] See you later.
I told you before, I'm not interested.
I've got some unfinished
business to take care of.
Ken, leave it alone,
you can't spend your whole
life chasin' after Jeroge.
It's more than a one-man job.
You're wasting your time, Roy.
I've made my last safari.
I was out in the bush
lookin' after your client
when I should've been back
home lookin' after my kid.
Ken? Ken!
Your gun-bearer's outside,
says he's got a message.
(pleasant lounge music plays)
What did you find out?
Jeroge in country near Isiola.
How do you know this?
My own brother saw him.
He said plenty of police
hunt Jeroge all the time.
You get Jerusalem and O'Keefe.
Tell them to be ready,
we're gonna leave any time.
-But, bwana...
-What's the matter with you?
I thought you hated the Mau Mau?
Makora not scared, bwana.
But district commissioner
won't let bwana into Isiola.
You get the boys I'll take
care of the commissioner.
Yes, bwana.
300 rounds of .375,
which should be sufficient.
That'll do to get on with.
We can always send you over
some more if you need it.
I'll call you up on the
shortwave if I need it.
Charley?
I want to go north with you
tomorrow on your safari.
Don't be funny,
you know that country's
out-of-bounds to you.
I also know the police
won't search your lorry.
You can have me and my boys
under the tarp in the back.
Well, Ken, I mustn't get...
You can't get Charley mixed up in this,
he's got a wife and kids.
I had a family once, remember?
Oh, if it'd help, it'd
be different, but it won't.
Leave it to the police, Ken.
All you'll do is get yourself killed.
Maybe you'd be satisfied with that
if you killed Jeroge at the same time.
-There's Roy Shaw.
-Huh? Oh.
-Mr. Vincent, good evening.
-Hello.
Well, as Duffield
didn't come to the hotel,
I thought I'd come and look for him.
Is he here?
-Yes, he's at the bar.
Hey, Ken? Ken?
Sir Vincent Brampton, Ken Duffield.
How are you? My fiancee, Miss Latham.
-Hello.
-Sinden.
Ken Duffield.
Well, excuse me.
Duffield, you can spare a minute?
After all, I've travelled
4,000 miles for this safari.
Everyone in Kenya's
travelled 4,000 miles,
it's the only way to get here.
Some people had to travel 10.
Ah, Miss Latham's a fellow
countrywoman of yours.
Yes, I figured that out myself.
What do you drink, Sir Vincent?
Oh, no, don't. Brian,
you get the drinks.
-Let's sit down now.
-What'll you have, Mr. Duffield?
-Nothing, thanks.
-Duffield...
I came down here after a lion.
You got the wrong boy.
I'm out of circulation.
-Roy should have told you.
-That he did, but I need you.
All you need is a licence
and that'll cost you 10 quid.
But I'm after a particular lion, Hatari.
Where'd you hear about him?
Everywhere I've hunted,
I've heard about Hatari.
You know that you're
taking on the champ?
Even his name, Hatari, means danger.
He's the most vicious
killer in this jungle.
(moans) That's enough
for me. I'm going home.
You staying, Vincent?
Yes.
Because I want him.
You think that's all it takes, hmm?
Didn't you know, when
Vincent wants anything,
he always gets it?
That's right, Brian.
Do you know where to find this lion?
Yes.
The trouble is,
he was last seen in Mau
Mau country, near Isiola.
I'm not interested in local problems.
I'm ready to go, Mr. Duffield, are you?
I'm ready.
But there's one minor
problem, the licence.
I've got one.
I haven't. It's been revoked.
Of course, if anyone had
any influence of any kind...
Brian, go to the Governor and tell him
I accept full responsibility
for Mr. Duffield.
The safari will be in my charge
and he will answer to me.
You can check rifles and
equipment in the morning,
we'll leave at dawn the following day.
We'll check the rifles
and equipment tonight
and we'll leave tomorrow.
Goodnight, gentlemen.
-Goodnight.
Roy, I want to tell you something.
If I may make so bold,
who manipulated whom?
(people chattering indistinctly)
(both chuckle)
So my bush baby's made
another friend, huh?
Ooh, I'm not so sure.
(Roy chuckling)
-Did he bite you?
-Mm-hmm.
I'd like you to meet your gun-bearers,
Nkola, O'Keefe, and Jackson the tent-boy.
-Hello.
-Hey, what are you doin' there?
Bwana Duffield tell
me take rubber dinghy.
All right.
And this villain is Jerusalem,
camp cook and head boy.
When he grows up, he's
gonna be a band leader.
Glad to have you know me, ma'am!
-Hello, Jerusalem.
-Do you like music?
(hems and haws) Not too loud.
Oh, I make it good and loud, real bebop.
I'm some cat.
"By Jupiter."
(trumpet toots)
Jerusalem...
Come on, Jerusalem. Tribe?
-Luo.
-Date of birth?
19... 1940 maybe?
Number of wives, 4.
Now 5, bwana!
I've been in Nairobi 2 days.
He'll be smokin' next.
200 shillings a month
and a shilling a day posho
money when travelling.
Uh, make a mark there, please.
Bwana, Jerusalem can write.
Next, please.
Tribe?
Kikuyu. Makora knows me, he's my friend.
He's a good man, bwana,
I know him a long time.
Sorry, only take men we know. Move on.
Why so fussy?
Mau Mau's a disease
and they come in all sizes from 8 to 80.
Makora, tribe Akamba.
One of these days I'm gonna
put a mouse-trap in my pocket.
(laughs) Bwana, this time you take me?
I just see how you go out on safari again.
Try me out, eh, bwana?
I said come back in 10 years.
Come along when you're bigger.
Last year you said,
pretty soon I'll be big boy.
But you're not big
enough, next year maybe.
You really want to go, don't you?
Oh, yes, very bad me
follow bwana any place.
I'll fix it!
Mr. Duffield?
-Yes?
Uh, Mr. Duffield, couldn't we take
little, uh, what's-his-name with us?
We don't need him.
What's the matter with
you, don't you like kids?
Please, bwana, please!
Oh, please, bwana!
Odongo, hop in the truck!
(Odongo laughing)
Thank you!
Thanks, Ken, I'd have lost
that contract if you hadn't...
Save it, Roy.
You know the only reason I took this job.
Oh, forget Jeroge, can't you?
Could you?
All set?
Ready and waiting.
What sort of animals
do we shoot with this?
You can never tell
what kind of animals you might run into.
Good luck, boys!
Goodbye, Sir Vincent, and good luck.
(jaunty music)
♪ We're on safari, blow that horn ♪
♪ And keep alert from dusk till dawn ♪
(men sing chorus in foreign language)
♪ Through the bush, across the plain ♪
♪ We'll soon be there and back again ♪
(men sing chorus in foreign language)
♪ I saw a lion three mile long ♪
♪ He rolled his eyes when I tried to run ♪
(men sing chorus in foreign language)
♪ Three mile lion after me ♪
♪ But I rode home on a chimpanzee ♪
♪ That big giraffe-ah, he had a laugh-ah ♪
(men sing chorus in foreign language)
♪ We met a pretty gay gazelle ♪
♪ Who said her name was Lulu-belle ♪
(men sing chorus in foreign language)
♪ Lulu-belle, she said that she ♪
♪ I want a trip to gay Paris ♪
♪ In an ostrich feather
for sunny weather ♪
(men sing chorus in foreign language)
♪ We saw a big grey crocodile ♪
♪ Who met us with a juicy smile ♪
(men sing chorus in foreign language)
♪ His pal the hippopotamus ♪
♪ Said he couldn't stand the fuss ♪
♪ The elephant, he finds it handy ♪
♪ To take his trunk on safari ♪
What are they?
[Ken] Flamingos.
You're not going to shoot them?
You watch them.
(gunshot bangs)
(flock fluttering)
♪ Go blow that horn, we're on safari ♪
♪ Blow it loud, never mind the key ♪
(men sing chorus in foreign language)
♪ If you're not awake, my friend ♪
♪ Then it will soon be journey's end ♪
(men sing chorus in foreign language)
(ominous music)
What brought you out here, Mr. Duffield,
an American in Kenya?
World War II, a leftover.
In other words, mind your own business.
I suppose it was a woman.
Ah, welcome to Africa,
famed for its warm hospitality
and healthy climate.
I don't think the climate's
too healthy, not now, anyway.
Oh, I have nothing to worry about.
In addition to you and Vincent,
I have a BWH to look after me.
Big white hunter.
Yeah, I almost figured that out myself.
Were you born friendly?
Or do we all get like you
after a while out here?
You can never tell.
They say that Africa does
strange things to people.
(gunfire blasting)
(gunfire continues)
Mau Mau?
Yes, gang of 30 up there.
(Mau Mau shouting in foreign language)
Ken, you know you're not allowed up here
without your hunter's licence.
I got my licence back.
That man over there can vouch for me.
He's got my papers.
(dramatic music)
I know you.
You used to work on my
farm at harvest time.
You're a friend of Jeroge's.
(dramatic music)
Duffield? Duffield!
You knew that was a Mau
Mau battle we heard.
That's right.
And you deliberately drove into it,
endangering the lives of all of us.
Vincent, after what the
Inspector just told me...
Linda, I'll handle this.
I'm sorry about your misfortune,
but I can't concern myself
with your personal feuds.
I appreciate your sympathy, Brampton.
But I haven't finished.
I engaged you as a hunter, nothing more.
When you've finished the job,
you can chase Jeroge or anything you like.
But until then, your one
concern is to lead me to Hatari.
Is that clear?
Very clear.
Because if it isn't
clear and acceptable,
you can leave for Nairobi
with this officer now.
Come on, Ken, why don't you give it up?
Give it up?
You must be crazy.
Sir Vincent, from now on in,
you've got yourself a hired hand.
Let's go!
(whistle tooting)
(drums beating)
(both greet in foreign language)
(drums continue beating)
Duffield?
(Ken speaks foreign language)
What goes on here?
Ceremonial dance.
One of the villagers
was killed last night.
The villager was killed by a lion!
What lion? Hatari?
I don't know whether
it was Hatari or not,
but it was a big one, a man-eater!
(Jerusalem playing jazzy trumpet)
(Jerusalem continues playing trumpet)
Jerusalem!
-Yes, bwana?
-Do you want me to lose all my clients?
Oh, no, bwana.
Better stop playing that horn.
Makora?
Go tell the Massai
chief I want to see him.
He hates the Mau Mau as much as we do.
Yes, bwana.
(precarious music)
(gunshot bangs)
What's happening?
[Brian] I've just had a
snake shot from over my head.
Snake?
(Linda groans)
If you have to sleep in the afternoon,
it might be safer to
do it inside your tent.
[Vincent] Duffield,
it's your job, isn't it,
to take care of your clients?
You know as well as I do,
you couldn't catch a cold from that snake.
Memsahib, you want something to eat?
Oh, Odongo, you take
very good care of me.
Bwana say, I don't look after
white lady, he have my ears!
Oh, did he?
Well, that was nice of him.
Oh, yes, bwana say
all white ladies little silly in the head!
Oh, did he?
Well, maybe so. Go on.
(Odongo laughing)
Can write my name too,
and sing "God Save Queen," want to hear?
Not right now. Where'd
you learn all these things?
Bloody missionary school.
Did they teach you that there too?
Oh, yes, good people.
Here you go wash your tongue with soap.
-Me?
-Yeah, you!
[Linda] Don't they
supply soap in this hotel?
Huh?
Did you hear me properly,
Mr. big white hunter?
-Thanks!
-(chuckles) You're welcome.
Give me a hand.
(Odongo laughs)
Here, wash your ears!
-Me?
-Yeah, you!
(Odongo laughing)
That scar above your...
On your back, who did that?
A lioness?
Yes.
Whatever happened to her?
She's dead.
Ooh.
Well, that washes up that
topic of conversation.
My ears are clean now, bwana.
Back to camp. Clean pants, clean shirt.
All right, bwana, all right!
White hunter, here's your soap.
Don't you want it?
Just drop it.
Mm, you're just full of
conversation, aren't you?
(chuckles) I'm not
paid for conversation.
Look, why don't you take
that chip off your shoulder?
I came here to apologise.
I'll remember that "don't
you like kids" crack
till the day I die.
It was a terrible thing to say.
There was no way for you to know.
I should have known.
No man hates another
man, as you hate Jeroge,
without a reason.
You don't like us, do you?
I'm not paid to like you.
If it wasn't for the
money, you wouldn't be here?
Let's put it this way,
I'm not here because of
your beautiful blue eyes.
Look, I'm not making a pass at you,
(chuckles) though I can
see how you might think so.
Ex-chorus girl engaged to rich
man meets Big White Hunter,
how could you miss?
But as hard as it may
be for you to believe,
I like Vincent,
and I enjoy being the
future Lady Brampton.
Who are you kidding?
Outside of money, what's he got?
The best of everything.
The finest jade, beautiful tapestries,
and a wonderful collection of paintings.
Has he told you which wall
he's going to hang you on yet?
Linda?
It's time you came back
and dressed for dinner.
It's nice of Duffield
to look after Linda like that, isn't it?
(relaxing music)
(Jerusalem clears throat)
Dinner on the beam, bwana?
[Brian] We just wanted
to say what to say
what a very good dinner it was.
-Good, good.
-[Linda] It was lovely.
-It was cool.
-Thank you, thank you.
In fact, it was real gone.
You think so?
Bwana, maybe you think dinner so good,
you give permission for a small practise?
A few hot licks, yeah? (laughs)
Maybe tomorrow, when
we're far away from camp.
Thank you, bwana. Thank you. (laughing)
(hyena chattering)
(Ken laughs)
You'll get used to the
hyenas in the jungle.
(chuckles) I did, years ago.
That's all over.
By the way, I don't
think I told you, Linda,
how pretty you look in that dress.
Thank you.
Even if it is a little
out of place here.
I think I catch on.
My first safari, you know.
Bwana! Buzz buzz, 9:00!
He means they're calling me on the air.
See you later.
(call signal beeping)
Can I come in and sit down?
There's only the bed.
Look, junior, I didn't say lie down.
Calling Nairobi. Hello, Nairobi.
Calling Roy Shaw.
Come in, Roy. This is Ken Duffield.
[Roy] Hello, Ken. Hello, Ken.
Now this is important, make
sure you're on your own.
Make sure there's no one listening. Over.
-Okay, Roy, shoot.
-Hello, Ken, there's been a roundup
of Mau Mau in Nairobi today.
Hundreds of them have been questioned
and they found out something.
One of your safari boys has
taken the Mau Mau oath. Over.
That's impossible, Roy.
These boys have been with me for years.
Hello, Ken, we don't know which it is,
so don't trust anyone.
Be on your guard. Out.
How will you find out who it is?
It's extremely important
that no one else hears about this.
Do you understand?
I understand.
(Linda gasps and screams)
Mau Mau! Do something!
Mau Mau!
Stop screaming.
You might frighten them.
-Jambo!
-Jambo, bwana.
Relax, everyone. They're
our friends, can't you see?
-Who are they?
-They're Massai.
(groans) First time
I was ever frightened
out of a full bottle.
-Makora?
-Bwana?
See that everyone sleeps
with their rifles tonight,
you understand?
-Yes, bwana.
What's this, more Mau Mau scourge?
You know as well as I do,
they're not interested in strangers,
it's only settlers they attack.
Maybe so.
But you're gonna get
a rifle just the same.
I'd suggest that you sleep
with them under your mattress.
If you lose them, it's 250 pounds fine
plus 6 months in jail.
And that goes for little girls, too.
Don't worry about me.
I'll just throw my bottle.
(Ken and Brian chuckle)
[Ken] What'd you find out?
Chief says Jeroge came
near here three nights back.
Police had a big fight,
took plenty of prisoners.
But not Jeroge, bwana.
-Jeroge get away.
-Where is he?
No one knows, but he cannot be very far.
Jeroge won't get away from me this time.
Have the chief send out trackers
right away to look for him.
But, bwana, how will
you explain to the others
why we stay here?
Bwana Vincent is in a big hurry
to move on and find Hatari.
Tell the chief to put on a
lion hunt tomorrow morning.
That should keep them quiet for a day.
(local speaks foreign language)
Makora...
Bwana?
One of our boys is a Mau Mau.
Do you know who it is?
I thought I could trust every one of them.
You can trust me, bwana.
I know that, Makora.
Thank you, bwana.
I'll keep my eyes open.
(drums beating)
(dramatic music)
(drumbeat continues)
(dramatic music continues)
I say, it's remarkable,
nothing but spears!
Part of the ritual.
Until a Massai's killed a lion that way,
he hasn't proved he's a man.
I can think of better ways.
Go and see if the chief
has found out anything.
Yes, bwana.
(lion growling)
(drumbeat continues)
(dramatic music continues)
(lion growling)
(drumbeat continues)
(dramatic music continues)
(lion roars)
(men shouting)
(dramatic music intensifies)
(men cheering)
Let's go.
-Why now?
-The show's over.
(hunters sing and chant)
Bwana!
What'd you find out?
Massai chief say he found out
Jeroge now hiding on Makoma Rock.
That's about an hour from here.
Yes, bwana.
If we leave now, we can
get back before they miss us.
(duplicitous music)
Bwana, fresh tracks.
Makora, he's probably
in those rocks up there.
Get behind me and cover me.
Yes, bwana.
(Jackson mimicking bird call in distance)
(intriguing music)
(Mau Mau speaking foreign language)
(Jackson speaks foreign language)
(Jeroge speaks foreign language)
(dramatic music)
(suspenseful music)
(suspenseful music continues)
Wait, don't fire!
(Ken grunts)
Get him!
(dramatic music)
(gunshot bangs)
(gunfire blasting)
(gunfire continues)
(dramatic music continues)
You get back to camp. We go north.
He got away this time, but
I'll get that filthy scum
if it's the last thing I ever do.
Duffield! Duffield!
Where have you been?
I was looking for Hatari.
I don't believe you.
This is your last safari, Duffield.
A hunter that leaves his camp unprotected
from Mau Mau men...
Unprotected?
You were here, weren't you?
Besides, I thought you weren't
concerned with local problems.
I am concerned with you
doing what I tell you.
You're under my orders.
Stop your squawking.
You want Hatari, that's what you'll get.
Ken? Mr. Duffield?
Yeah?
Could I speak to you for a moment?
What's your beef?
I'm dreadfully sorry, but I...
Well, go on!
I've lost my rifle.
-You what?
-Well, I left it on my bed.
The whole country sweats its guts out
to keep arms from the Mau Mau
and you come along and give
it to them on a platter.
You miserable incompetent!
Why didn't you tell me?
I don't mind your making
a fool of yourself,
that's your function in life,
but now you're making a fool of me.
(scoffs) Get back into
your tent and stay there.
I'm sick to death of the sight of you!
Why don't you kick his
teeth down his throat?
It's not as simple as
that. Vincent's a killer.
Oh, no, nothing violent. He's
much more subtle than that.
He finds out your weaknesses
and he plays on them.
Have you got any weaknesses, Duffield?
I'm loaded with them.
Not gambling, I hope?
Vincent loves gamblers.
He loves to help them,
help them dig a hole for themselves.
And then when they're in so
deep and there's no way out,
no honest way, that is, he saves them,
on certain conditions.
Anyway, I am sorry about that rifle.
Forget it.
Probably one of my own boys took it.
Good night.
Why don't you have one for the road?
(glass shatters)
You'd never get a job with the Dodgers.
Bwana want anything?
No thanks.
Say, Odongo, did you fix this for me?
No, memsahib, she fix.
She think maybe bwana be hungry.
Well, that was very
nice of her, wasn't it?
Bwana treat memsahib very bad,
she fix nice drink for bwana.
(Odongo scoffs)
I get it. Bwana stick
big foot in big mouth, huh?
That's right, bwana big chump!
You (laughs) fresh kid!
(both laugh)
(cautious music)
Can I have another one?
The one you threw me is a little muddy!
Okay.
You'll have to help yourself, though,
I wasn't expecting company.
(warm music)
Did you get him?
No.
He got away.
I'm sorry.
(book thuds)
(warm music continues)
Did you ever play football?
No.
I... I thought not.
Your book.
Good night.
(ominous music)
(men snoring)
(alarming music)
Bwana, bwana! I can't
find Jackson in camp.
He must have stolen the rifle.
He must be the Mau Mau.
First it's Jeroge, now it's Jackson!
All right, Makora,
tell everybody to sleep
with their clothes on.
Yes, bwana.
Memsahib?
What is it?
Bwana says everybody better get dressed.
Why, what's the trouble?
No trouble, memsahib,
but bwana wants everybody keep eyes open.
All right, Makora, thank you.
(sneaky music)
(dramatic music)
(Jackson grunts)
(campers chattering)
Jackson?
He came back. (breathing heavily)
I tried to hold him, but he got away.
I hurt him real bad, bwana.
I'm sorry.
What the devil was that?
Jackson's escaped. He's a Mau Mau.
We've got to go on after him.
-What is it?
-I don't know. It's...
What's the matter?
What's the matter, bwana?
Look, hot licks, you and
Odongo stay here in camp
and take care of Miss Linda.
Here.
(suspenseful music)
(suspenseful music continues)
[Newscaster] Tomorrow's
weather will be fine.
Good hunting, everybody, and good night.
(wistful music)
(suspenseful music)
(owl screeching)
(suspenseful music continues)
(wistful music)
(ominous music)
(intriguing music)
(Linda screaming)
(dramatic music)
(Linda groans)
(Linda groaning)
(pan thuds)
(Linda grunts)
By golly, by golly.
Does it hurt?
(Linda groaning)
Memsahib!
Don't worry. Don't worry,
you'll be all right.
(disconcerting music)
(gunshot bangs)
(Linda whimpering)
-Linda! Linda!
Are you all right?
Don't pretend to
start worrying about me.
Can't blame me if
Duffield lets a Mau Mau...
For heavens' sake, Vincent,
this is no time to start...
Oh, why don't you shut up?
Stop it! Don't you see she's hysterical?
(Linda whimpers)
Thought you'd gone off with the others.
No, Ken and Vincent agreed
that I should stay here
and act as camp policeman.
Oh, well, at least they're
on the same side for once.
Though, I think for
rather different reasons.
Sir Vincent wanted me
to keep an eye on you.
Exactly what did you mean by that crack?
I think it's all this subversive talk
about the things Africa does to people.
Perhaps Vincent's worried
that you're beginning
to see things straight for the first time.
I know I am.
Have you ever tried saying what you mean
without using double-talk?
All right.
Linda, you're a nice person, very nice,
you ought to stay that way.
But you won't unless you get
away from Vincent, and now.
Brian, I want to marry Vincent.
Let's leave it like that.
All right.
Now why don't you go
get me another drink?
Oh, Linda.
Why not? You said I could
handle my liquor well.
Oh. All right.
(birds fluttering)
You're wasting your time
putting out bait for Hatari.
Only scavengers eat dead meat.
Bwana! Come, quick!
Look!
That's a big lion.
Big enough to be Hatari?
Let's go see.
Memsahib! Memsahib!
Well, Odongo, what have you
got to be so excited about?
I catch big fish for memsahib!
Really? Let me see!
Come here, I'll help you.
Hmm, let me look.
How nice! I think I'll try my hand at it.
Bwana said no go on the river, please!
No, no, no, memsahib!
Memsahib! Memsahib!
Memsahib! No, no, memsahib!
Memsahib!
Memsahib! Memsahib!
Bwana!
Bwana! Bwana!
Bwana! Memsahib go fishing in the river!
Gone fishing?
(panicked music)
Linda, come back, you fool!
Come back!
(carefree music)
(elephant trumpeting)
(imposing music)
(lion growls)
You haven't got a
prayer at this distance.
I ought to know, Duffield.
I make these things.
That's what the telescopic sight's for.
I know, but if you miss,
I've got to go in that bush and get him.
Don't worry, Duffield,
I've come a long way for
that lion, I won't miss.
(gunshot bangs)
You brute.
Uh, I'm sorry, Duffield.
That's great, lover boy.
(birds chirping)
(foliage rustling)
(lion roars)
(lion panting)
Ken!
-Bwana!
It's Linda!
She's drifted down the
river in the dinghy, alone.
-What?
-My wounded lion's in there.
Linda can take care of herself.
(carefree music)
(elephants trumpeting)
(distressing music)
(hippos snorting)
(panicked music)
(fearsome music)
(fearsome music continues)
(panicked music)
(rapids rumbling)
(panicked music continues)
[Linda] Help!
Oh, hurry! Help!
(tense music)
Help! Help!
(waterfall rumbling)
(tense music continues)
(gunfire blasting)
(gunshot bangs)
(gentle music)
Was that the big white hunter?
Haven't you been in enough water,
for the last couple of days?
This is a bath!
You sent for me?
Yeah, two things.
I wanted to thank you for today.
Part of my job.
And I wanted to ask
you, could we go back?
Brampton gives the orders
around here, you know that.
It's him I'm worried about.
(sighs) This mania about killing a lion,
maybe it's because he's sick.
He's always been sick.
Only out here, you can
see it much plainer.
Look, all I wanted to know
was whether we could go back?
Go back to what?
-Good morning.
-What are you going to do?
I suppose you'll have to
go after that lion again.
I have to, it's wounded.
What would happen if a hunter didn't
follow up a wounded animal?
He'd lose his licence.
Are you feeling all right?
I'm perfectly all right.
These are just a precaution.
Are you sure you don't want to go back?
I'll say when I want to go back.
Okay, it's your funeral.
Well, I have a feeling that
you're not going to shoot
that lion after all.
What are you talking about?
Well, you heard what
Ken said, didn't you?
Now it's wounded, it's his job.
He said that, did he?
Yes.
Did he?
(ominous music)
-Makora?
-Yes, bwana?
Tell bwana Duffield
that I'm ready to go.
Yes, bwana.
(ominous music)
Okay, let's go!
Haven't you messed
things up enough already?
I can take care of the kill.
No, Duffield, I'll
take care of the kill.
(engine turns over)
(ominous music)
(lion roars)
(dramatic music)
Bwana! Bwana! (speaks foreign language)
(gun clicks)
(rhino grunting)
(gunshot bangs)
(rhino squealing)
(Makora screaming)
(gunshot bangs)
(sombre music)
(disconcerting music)
(Jerusalem speaks in foreign language)
(mournful music)
("Swing Low, Sweet Chariot)
Duffield, tell him to stop
that blasted trumpeting!
Sorry, but I want my men to forget
what happened to Makora.
Any objections?
No, give the boy's family
whatever you think's right.
It's more than you've
got or ever will have.
It was my fault that Makora was killed.
It wasn't because my magazine was empty.
I knew from the first day I met you all,
you'd be nothing but trouble.
Well, I've had all I'm gonna take.
You're leaving tomorrow
morning for Nairobi. Got that?
Listen, Duffield, I've had
enough of your insubordination.
This safari ends when I finish
off Hatari, and not before.
But tomorrow morning at daybreak,
you're heading south
for Nairobi, non-stop!
And how about you, our big white hunter,
risking our necks so he
can get his own revenge,
-what's he going to do?
-I'm going to stay here
and clean up the mess your
lover boy left behind.
(metal clanging)
Hot Licks!
Oh, it's you, bwana.
How do you like my new hat?
Who sent you that, Hedda Hopper?
(Jerusalem laughs)
Shh. Keep your eyes open.
Okay, bwana.
One for the road, Duffield?
(soft music)
Why don't you get some sleep?
Um... Not yet, not plastered enough.
Such stuff as dreams are made on.
Try a dream, Duffield. No extra charge.
No thanks.
Good for you, Mr. BWH.
I loathe people who don't
know when they've had enough.
Hate to see me do this, don't you? Why?
That's your problem.
But I asked you.
Well, from where I stand,
it don't exactly help the picture.
Funny, from where I drink,
it's always made the
picture look much better.
Ken, sit down, please?
This is the last time we'll
ever see each other alone.
I wanted you to know something.
This is the last drink I'll ever take.
I need it now so I can blame
it for what I'm going to say.
I love you, Ken, I always will.
No need for you to say anything,
because this is all there is to it.
(sighs) I've said it,
and I feel great for it.
I hope some day you'll get
that hate out of your heart,
so you can say it to someone.
(hopeful music)
I need some sleep.
(pensive music)
Bwana! Bwana!
Buzz buzz!
Calling Roy Shaw!
Come in, Roy, this is Duffield.
District commissioner's orders.
You've got to move camp.
200 Mau Mau broke jail this afternoon,
20 miles south of you at Isiola,
and they're heading towards your area,
probably to join up with Jeroge.
Now, Ken, I know how
you feel about Jeroge,
and why you're staying in that area.
But my feeling is that
you should move north
as soon as you can.
-Hot Licks!
-Bwana?
Load the trucks we're
leaving right away.
Okay, bwana!
Okay, come on, trucks!
(engine turns over)
[Brian] Say, Ken, what's happened?
I thought you said we weren't leaving
until tomorrow morning.
I've changed my mind. We're leaving now.
Get your gear.
-Why?
Duffield, I'm not leaving
here till we finish off Hatari.
Look, there's 200 Mau Mau
around here somewhere on the loose.
I'm takin' this safari outta here.
If you want to stay, stay!
Odongo! Odongo...
You there, unload that truck!
I say when this safari
leaves, not Duffield.
Sorry, bwana, can't do it.
Why aren't you dressed?
Why is everything changed?
Why are we heading north?
200 reasons, all of them Mau Mau.
But the Mau Mau and Jeroge
are what you're after,
and you're giving it all up, why?
Because you're my
favourite football player.
Now get dressed.
I won't be 5 minutes!
(men chattering outside)
(fabric ripping)
Bwana, come quick!
What's your problem?
Look! Look!
Unpack my big Express
and 900-grain bullets.
Hey, hot Licks? Hatchets and ropes!
Vincent's gone?
The stupid fool's
out there in the jungle
in the middle of the night.
-He must be raving.
-Shall I come with you?
-No, you stay here.
And keep your rifle in your hand.
Don't leave no matter what happens.
Thanks.
(dramatic music)
If you want to stay alive, keep behind me.
(lion roars in distance)
(gunshot bangs)
Brampton! Brampton!
(dramatic music)
Stay where you are, Duffield!
Stay where you are, or I'll shoot.
Take cover, he's crazy with fever.
Don't be a fool, Brampton.
Stay where you are, I say!
The lion's mine!
(gunshot bangs)
(bullet ricochets)
(gun cocks)
Now do you believe that I mean what I say?
Nobody wants to stop you
from killing that lion.
I only want to stop you from
getting yourself killed.
Look.
(gunshot bangs)
(bullet ricochets)
(gun cocks)
(dramatic music)
Don't move, Brampton.
Do what I tell you.
What do you think you're trying now?
Brampton, there's a lion over your head.
It's less than 20 feet away.
You can't fool me with that old trick.
When I give you the word, turn and fire.
(tense music)
Shoot!
(lion roaring)
(gunshot bangs)
(gunshots bang)
(dramatic music)
Did I get him?
Did I get Hatari?
You got him.
Jerusalem!
-Bwana?
-Stretcher.
O'Keefe, stretcher!
I hope that's enough
morphine to keep him out.
Will he live?
All depends on how fast we get there.
That means going south.
You understand what that means, don't you?
I understand.
Ken, if there's no other way
but to go through Mau Mau country,
hadn't we better stay here?
Sorry, old man, but we
gotta take that chance.
Jerusalem! Let's go!
(Jerusalem speaks foreign language)
(onerous music)
-What is it?
-I don't know.
Looks like the police.
We've been lookin' for Mau Mau.
Can you take us to the
police station, please?
Hop in and tell the
others to get in the truck.
(officer speaks foreign language)
(onerous music)
(ominous music)
(gunshot bangs)
(bullet ricochets)
(explosion booms)
(Jeroge shouting in foreign language)
(Mau Mau clamouring)
(gunshot bangs)
(dramatic music)
(Mau Mau clamouring)
(heart-pumping music)
Hurry, Jerusalem, bring that ammunition!
Re-load this!
Keep your heads down!
(Mau Mau clamouring)
(automatic gunfire blasting)
(gunfire blasting)
(Mau Mau shouting)
(gunfire continues blasting)
(shouting continues)
(gunfire pauses)
Fire!
(gunshot bangs)
(bullet ricochets)
(uneasy music)
(birds squawking)
What are they waiting for, Ken?
Darkness.
It won't be long.
How many casualties?
One boy killed, two very
badly hurt, one askari dead.
Well, it could have been worse.
What about Nairobi, Ken, the radio?
Closed circuit.
They don't open that
unit till 9:00 tonight.
We'll tell 'em we're
here if we're still here.
Bwana? (speaks foreign language)
(Ken speaks foreign language)
(officer repeats Ken's response)
He's trying to through for help.
(ominous music)
(gunshot bangs)
(dramatic music)
(gunfire blasting)
(Mau Mau groans)
(dramatic music)
Where's Odongo?
Isn't he with Jerusalem?
Haven't seen him anywhere.
-Jerusalem!
-Could that kid be a Mau Mau after all?
Of course not, not possibly.
You don't think so?
I'll bet he thought the same about Jeroge.
(dramatic music)
Jerusalem, get that tyre fixed!
I could probably get you
all out of here on the truck
before they close in.
Brian, you drive. Jerusalem
and O'Keefe will be with you.
Where will you be?
When you get in, you send help back.
That your best idea?
-That's it.
-You'll have to do better.
Because if it's the end of the road,
so it's the end of the road.
(dramatic music)
Bwana! Bwana!
Bwana!
(horn honking)
Bwana! Bwana! (speaks foreign language)
(tooting whistle)
(heroic music)
(officer speaks foreign language)
(heroic music continues)
(Odongo speaks foreign language)
(brooding music)
Don't waste any ammunition!
How is he?
-Get me out!
-Vincent, lie down!
Do-do-do you hear me? Get me out!
Don't worry I'll get you out of here.
If you don't get me out
of here, I'm finished.
(ominous music)
They are coming!
Get the car started, Brian.
(suspenseful music)
(gunshot bangs)
-Please lie down, please?
-Ken!
No, I'm not going!
Ken, I'm not going! Ken!
(Ken mutters)
(dramatic music)
(gunfire blasting)
(Mau Mau shouting)
(wood cracking)
(Linda yelps)
Get out! Run for it!
(tense music)
(gunfire blasting)
That was close!
There's one more chance,
the truck's up there.
-No, Ken, I won't go!
-Go ahead, Linda,
don't argue!
-No! Ken!
(gunfire blasting)
(dramatic music)
(explosion booms)
Fall back!
(gunfire blasting)
(Mau Mau groans)
(Mau Mau shouting)
(Mau Mau groaning)
(gunfire blasting)
(dramatic music)
(gunfire continues)
(Mau Mau groaning)
(Mau Mau yells)
Get back!
(gunfire continues)
(dramatic music continues)
(Mau Mau groaning)
(heroic music)
(disconcerting music)
(gunshot bangs)
(Ken groans)
(gunfire continues blasting)
(combatants clamouring)
(Jeroge shouting in foreign language)
(officers clamouring)
(gunfire blasting)
(dramatic music)
(weapons clashing)
Bwana! Bwana!
(dramatic music)
(gunshot bangs)
(heroic music)
Well! And where have you been?
I thought we lost you.
Bwana no lose Odongo!
Odongo save Bwana's life!
I come every safari.
Well, what about me?
I thought you were going
to always take care of me.
Bwana, he look after memsahib.
Bwana no more big chump.
(epic music)
(Odongo laughing)
♪ We're on safari, beat that drum ♪
♪ Go on safari to kingdom come ♪
(men sing chorus in foreign language)
♪ If you're not awake, my friend ♪
♪ Then it will soon be journey's end ♪
(men singing chorus in foreign language)