[dramatic blues music plays, then stops]
[metal clanking and thudding]
-[electricity humming]
-[tools whirring and grinding]
[buckets clanking]
[men yelling indistinctly]
[dramatic blues music plays, then stops]
-[clanking continues]
-[whirring and grinding continue]
[jackhammer clacking]
[dramatic blues music playing]
-[music stops]
-[whirring and grinding continue]
[man] What about the Angels, Nick?
You like the Angels?
-Nick.
-Huh?
What?
The Angels?
I hate the fucking Angels.
Every time I think they'll do something,
they do the exact opposite.
An inconsistent group of people.
The Padres, I got in my pocket.
They're always the same.
They suck.
[Nick] You got anything, Yoyo?
But to what degree do they suck?
I mean, there are many different levels.
Have you got anything
for my fucking head, Yoyo?
Anything of a pharmaceutical nature?
I'm not carrying
that sort of item anymore, Nicky.
Talk to Stavros.
If I buy from Stavros,
then I bet with Stavros.
Hey, look.
I don't expect you guys to work,
but could you park your butts
somewheres out of the way?
Got equipment moving through here.
Know what my head feels like today, Riggs?
Oh, you want to take a sick day, Nicky?
Be my guest.
If you don't want me here,
why don't you just fire me?
Because I can't fire you.
You mean
you don't have the balls to fire me.
It's out of respect for your father.
Who you don't have the balls
to stand up to.
Fucking Riggs, I swear.
You won't fire me?
I quit.
Don't put it that way, Nicky.
-As your union representative, I...
-That's it, I fucking quit.
I'm out of here.
You're not really gonna bet
with Stavros, are you, Nick?
The guy's a fucking pirate.
He'll throw those
Greek odds at you, Nicky.
Look, I'm sure you got some people
who can handle the job.
But my hands are tied.
I deal with the union.
You go find Yoyo.
He's the shop steward on this job.
I already talked to the man over him.
-What, Belcher at the Local?
-Yeah.
-What did he say?
-He said, talk to you.
If you made a stand,
then maybe his membership would accept.
Right.
What that means is,
his guys walk for two weeks
till I kiss their ass
and hand them all kinds of concessions.
Then maybe, maybe
they'll take in a handful of your people.
On top of them,
which I already got on the job.
Which includes four, five guys
who only sit and read the paper all day.
Hey, I made a bid on this job.
You're saying no.
Maybe some other job, all right?
Something for the city.
But not on this one.
I'm out on a limb on this one.
There's no way I can bring your people on
and still make my bid.
What the hell? What's he doing? Oh! Nicky?
We're good enough to rent
these apartments, but not to build them?
No. Excuse me.
-Riggs.
-[Riggs] Yo.
-Where the hell's Nicky going?
-[Riggs] He says he's quitting.
That...
Stavros.
Late breakfast?
I need some crank.
What, am I a drugstore?
Stavros, look,
you are a fucking drugstore.
I need enough for a day or two.
Did you have anything to eat today?
I got juices. I got papaya drink. Yoo-hoo.
Coke, Stavros.
Papaya drink is good.
It's 1 0-percent real.
Just give me the fucking drugs, will you?
Yo, Nicky, you having breakfast
or scoring coke?
Hey.
Tell the whole world, why don't you?
You better be buying drugs.
Breakfast here will kill you. [laughs]
-[man] You want a beer, Nick?
-Sounds good.
-What, are you playing hooky?
-I quit.
-All right.
-[Bobby whoops]
-Hey, Nick, you owe me.
-Put it on my tab.
-You don't have a tab.
-Start one.
[engine sputtering]
[engine starts]
[Bobby whoops]
Later.
-["Yvonne" playing over stereo]
-[tools clanking and whirring]
You know who that is?
She is married to the assistant
to the District Attorney.
Little shit name of Zimmer.
-They got a beautiful car.
-I used to fuck her.
-[Bobby] Really?
-Yeah, really.
In high school.
Yvonne Plasky.
Bet she shit a brick
when she saw where the hook brung her car.
She's gonna turn this way.
When she turns, I'll point at her.
You laugh like I'm telling you
something really hot about her.
-["Yvonne" continues]
-[inaudible laughter]
All right.
Vinnie, go sit in the front seat
and, uh, eat your breakfast.
But, Carl, I'm all dirty.
That's the point, dipshit. Move it.
If she wants to know is her car done,
tell her you gotta ask me.
Only you're on your break now. Go.
[man laughs]
What are you laughing at, Turkey?
Get back on that Buick.
Yo, Turk, steal any good cars lately?
All right, you two. Business.
Tonight's the night.
Just need the wheels, Carl.
They still available?
Is that asshole in on it?
Not so far.
You got a problem with Nick?
I got a problem with his whole family.
What's he doing out of work?
He's the only fuck I know
stupid enough to quit a no-show job.
All right, you keep this one on a leash.
Vinnie's got the keys. Yo, Vinnie.
We're on the job, we're cold, man.
We are like ice water.
We're pros, dude.
If you two fuck this thing up
and my name gets into it,
I'll have you converted
into building materials, you understand?
Vinnie, you fat fucking hemorrhoid,
get in here.
Professionals.
["Peace of Mind" playing on stereo nearby]
♪ Gotta have peace of mind... ♪
Hey, hey there, big and beautiful.
-Don't start up with me, Levonne.
-You know I finish what I start now.
You best reel that thing of yours back in
before somebody out here step on it.
[laughing] Go ahead.
Levonne?
Oh, look who done come down off the hill
to mingle with us common folk.
Professor Oreo.
Yo, Malik, we got us a royal visit here.
You on an errand for city hall?
Could you help me get some people
down to the council meeting tonight?
-There's a bond issue for the school.
-The white man's school.
Our kids go to them.
You got no kids, Wynn.
Black people's children
go to those schools.
Now we talking about Black people?
See, now you got to get that shit clear.
You playing the white man's game.
Don't come here looking for support.
There's not enough of us in the city
to fight amongst ourselves.
-I have a little power on the council.
-You believe that?
-You got shit, Wynn.
-You got crumbs off the white man's table.
-Look.
-[car horn honks]
I gotta run.
You don't have to back me or what I say.
Just come tonight, bring some people,
so they know we're still alive.
[Levonne] Nice of you to stop by, Wynn.
Don't be no stranger now.
Any luck?
Not with those two.
[engine starts]
[sighs] I'll hit the projects next.
-Wynn...
-Mm-hm?
Have you thought any more about Franklin?
What can I do for Franklin?
Well, you talk to people all day.
Business people, shop owners...
You expect me to ask them for a job
for my brother-in-law? How will that look?
They do it all the time.
They are nepotistic sleazebags, remember?
[sighs]
Wynn, he's a Black man.
He lives in your district.
He's had some bad breaks...
Grand theft is not a bad break.
Drop me off here.
Look, I promise that
if something comes up for him,
I'll do the best I can, okay?
-That's all I'm asking.
-Okay.
Hang tough.
-Yeah, you too, baby.
-[laughs]
[sighs]
[man] "Mad Anthony again,
the lowest man in town.
This time I've really
gone off the deep end.
Everything, and I mean everything
on our shelves
has been marked down
to rock-bottom prices.
All your electronic
and computer-age needs under one roof..."
We're here every day.
We see what happens here.
It's the Spanish.
It hasn't been the same
since they showed up.
They make this noise with their teeth,
this sucking noise.
I was raised on this block.
Now I wouldn't walk here alone.
I'm a married woman with children.
Means nothing to them.
And these people out on the street.
You walk out your door,
it's a friggin' lunatic asylum.
Needles in the sandboxes in the park.
These crack vials.
No respect. No sense of responsibility.
It's the welfare. Why work?
The government takes care of you.
I used to feel bad for the kids,
but they're the worst.
Thirteen years old
with a baby on their hip.
-Do you ladies have a complaint?
-Complaint? Have you been listening?
A specific complaint.
A criminal charge.
See, Connie? They don't care.
They don't care.
You gotta be gang-raped
and roasted at the stake
before they'll lift a finger.
If it was your kids
out here on this street,
you wouldn't be sitting on your ass,
doing nothing.
[Joann] Look at this.
There's your tax money, right there.
[Connie] Why do we bother?
Jesus fucking Christ.
In stereo.
The skinny one's like my mother's cousin.
A bitch on wheels.
They got a point maybe,
but it ain't our fault.
I'm gonna drive by DeLillo's.
-Will you quit with that? It's over.
-Never.
I'm not giving up on it, all right?
Just what I need. O'Brien.
Morning, fellas.
Bill.
You going to the mayor's dinner
on Friday night?
What, a hundred bucks a pop? Forget it.
But I'll see you there, won't I, Mike? Ah.
Now, take these, push them around
to people on your beat.
You make that kid Ramirez,
you run him in.
We ran him in yesterday.
-Bring him in again.
-What for?
Suspicion of being on my shit list.
Make it a priority, Tommy.
Oh, have a good one.
-What's your problem with O'Brien?
-He's an asswipe.
So?
So he ain't a detective.
He's a fucking politician.
Everybody's a politician.
Yeah? I'm not.
Why do you think
I'm still in uniform at my age?
Because you're stupid.
Right. Because I don't kick back
to the pols every time I turn around.
A hundred bucks a pop. Christ.
Wonder if she's working today.
Hey, forget about her, kid. She's history.
[Bobby]
Maybe you should start small, Nick.
Open up a lunch wagon next to Stavros.
Yeah, Nicky's Food-O-Rama. [snickers]
Restaurant's gotta have personality.
And very hot waitresses.
Yeah, that can be part of it.
I'm sorry I'm late. I had a class.
You got Tables 6 and 9.
-I started them for you.
-All right.
Good seeing you folks again.
I'm sure Larry can iron out
all the details with you.
-Take it easy, Alex.
-Take care.
-I'll send your waitress right over.
-[Zimmer] Thanks, doll.
So, what are these details?
He talked about racquetball.
The district attorney
would be happy to have your backing,
but we need to get more specific
about the parameters.
We're discussing certain properties
on L Street.
I recall the previous conversation.
L Street has to come down
for Galaxy Towers to go up.
If those buildings aren't clear in a week,
the New York money walks,
the Japanese walk,
the whole thing falls apart.
If we get past that,
we'll need major juice
on the development package
when it comes up at council.
He's the district attorney, fellas.
This stuff's all municipal.
Who's municipal?
This comes down from Baci.
The second-most indictable mayor
in the state.
You must have a file like a phone book
on the guy.
The district attorney is very concerned
about municipal corruption,
but to take on a machine like Baci's...
I'm just not sure
what the incentive would be.
If your man tries
for the Senate next year,
he'll need a lot of resources.
Any effort on his part
to improve the climate in this city...
We're moving mountains here, fellas,
and you give me a week.
But we're always interested
in support from the business sector.
I think you can count on us.
Ah!
[Angela] Hi.
I'm Angela.
You gentlemen know what you want?
Everything, and l mean
everything on our shelves,
has been marked down
to rock-bottom prices...
You want me to give your program
free computers,
you understand l don't get them free
from the manufacturer.
The program isn't funded
to make purchases more than--
If these are people without money,
they're not likely to be my customers.
Look, you're a member of the community.
You do business here.
You hire local people.
[laughs] I wish I could hire local people.
I haven't had a night watchman
for two weeks.
You advertise for minimum wage,
you know who shows up?
Deviants show up.
Mentally disturbed people, blind people.
You need a security guard?
-You got someone?
-I might.
-This is a friend of yours?
-My wife's brother.
[laughs] Getting the old freeze-out, huh?
No tickee, no nookie.
Sure, tell him to come on over.
He's got a record.
-[video game weapons firing]
-This one's the ultimate, man.
This one makes Nintendo look pathetic.
I've never played Nintendo.
Where you been raised, boy?
You got a TV, don't you?
We got a TV.
And a VCR, right?
No.
Well, shit, man,
don't be inviting me over to your house,
watching some old
Mister Rogers network dog dookie.
Something else you need?
Stereo, VCR, CD player? A dehumidifier?
Thank you, no.
About Franklin, you don't have to...
Hey, look, he paid his debt, right?
Look, you're my representative
on the council.
Someday l got a matter
that needs representing, quid pro quo.
Am l right?
Bullshit. You haven't got a thing.
We've got the dumpster contract thing.
We've got the kickbacks
on the elderly lunch program.
We've got eight major no-show jobholders
donating a full quarter
of their generous salaries
to your political action fund.
-He's just blowing smoke, mayor.
-This just fell into our laps.
I hate to think what
a serious investigation would turn up.
Your guys want to bust my balls?
Hi, Phil, how you doing?
Not at all, Mr. Mayor.
The district attorney is well aware
that in municipal government
there are many gray areas.
Mrs. Spivak, say hello
to your mother for me.
-God bless you.
What does he want?
The apartment buildings
we discussed before, on L Street.
He's your brother, Pauly. What's up?
He's putting the usual pressure on,
but won't go along with the other thing.
He won't? He's a virgin all of a sudden?
-He forgets how he owns these buildings.
-[Zimmer] Gentlemen.
This is a conversation
I should not be hearing.
All you need to understand is that
the success of the development package
that's been proposed by certain
very good friends of the district attorney
has become essential
to your political future.
We're down to the wire on this, fellas.
We need results.
I'll leave the details
in your capable hands.
-[Bill] Larry.
-[Zimmer] Hey, Bill.
Is this a social visit
or are we under arrest?
[both laugh]
I hear your man's making a run
for the Senate.
Only a rumor, Bill. Only a rumor.
-If you need any help...
-[Zimmer] I'll keep that in mind.
I pay you 45 grand a year,
you can't deliver your own brother?
I talked to him.
-Lean on him, Pauly.
-With what?
Joey's hooked up with Kerrigan.
He's got his own thing going.
Gus, what'd they do?
Close down the dog track?
No, they made a mistake on my check.
They left off the overtime.
If you don't put in time, Gus,
how can you put in overtime?
I'd like to condemn your fucking house.
Have a good one, pal.
No, man, it's more than a guitar.
It's a pre-CBS Strat with a Kahler whammy,
single stack coil,
full MIDI rack kit,
MESA/Boogie amps that are fucking cherry.
Never been over 30 dBs.
Guy played folk music on it or something.
Yo, this thing has no fingerprints.
-Man, you're sucking it down today.
-[rock music playing over radio]
Nutrition.
Man cannot live by narcotics alone.
You should take it easy.
I'm a free man today, Bobby.
Shit is gonna happen.
Important stuff.
I can feel it.
-Right.
-[car horn honks]
Hey, it's Mr. Goodwrench
and his faithful companion, Jim.
What happened to the face, Jimmy?
Fucking boogs got him
last night down on M Street by the tracks.
For a small fee,
I'll hook you up with some steroids.
Two weeks,
you'll be beefed up for a rematch.
Fuck that. We're going down there,
kick some ass tonight.
You guys want a piece or what?
Haven't l seen this on WrestleMania?
Chickenshits.
-We'd love to help, but we got a gig.
-This Bud's for you.
What a dick, huh?
What, is he 1 9?
Eighteen. He dropped out this year.
That's how old
my brother was when he died.
Hey, uh, did he tell you
about the demo we're doing?
Top-of-the-line production, man, 24-track.
Yeah, right. On whose nickel?
Well, that was something
we wanted to talk to you about, Nicky.
Carl is bigtime now, Nick.
The guy is connected.
You know that warehouse fire,
took down half the waterfront,
but no one got a scratch?
That was Carl.
He's not just a loan shark anymore.
We done a couple of things with him,
turned out real good.
This is very serious money.
You know, with this one,
we retire, go back to the music full-time.
We figured since you're our friend
and you're not on the tit anymore,
if you want in...
It's a declaration of independence.
You know, think of it as "fuck you" money.
Isn't there anybody
you want to say "fuck you" to?
-I'll be right out. Ten minutes max.
-Yo.
["Oh Marie" playing over speakers inside]
-♪ Oh, baby ♪
-♪ Tell me you love me ♪
♪ Kiss me once
While the stars shine above me ♪
♪ Shine above me ♪
-♪ Hey, Marie ♪
-♪ Hey, Marie... ♪
[laughter and indistinct chatter]
-Hey, Nicky, how's it going?
-Just fine. Good to see you.
-You're in big trouble, pal.
-Where's the old man?
He's in there with Uncle Pauly.
You really quit this time?
Yeah. Where's Mom?
She's in the kitchen,
supervising the galley slaves.
Are you on something?
-We gotta talk.
-Nicky.
You ditch me now, l tell Mom
you spent the weekend with a married man.
That was over a year ago.
If you don't come through,
the whole thing comes down on my head.
I raised the rent to the legal ceiling.
I had the heat off
for three weeks in March.
The buildings stink
from garbage I don't pick up.
Pauly, these people are not leaving.
They have nowhere to go.
You know what you can do.
No fucking way.
Don't mention that again, understand me?
Look, have something to drink, will you?
I gotta find my kid.
[man] Hey, Joey, you're getting skinny.
Yeah, right.
I'm on a steady diet of agita. [laughs]
[Laurie] Where did you learn
how to make Italian food?
Italian food, Jewish food,
Chinese food, yuppie food.
-[Joey] Laurie.
-Hm?
Where is he?
-Nick?
-Yeah.
Um, he went out with Mom.
I think they went out back.
The only kind of food
I don't make is Japanese food.
Those people eat some strange things.
[woman] Nick, l will never say no to you,
but I'm not going behind
your father's back.
You go to him, have it out, whatever,
then come to me.
Okay, okay, I'll talk to him.
First. You talk to him first,
then you come to me for money.
Are you getting enough sleep, Nicky?
You look drawn.
-He's on drugs, Mom.
-[Nick] Hey, shut up, Laurie.
I have guests.
I'll send your father out.
Try to be nice.
So, what happened to last week's paycheck?
[Nick] The Angels took it.
The Angels? What, this is football?
Football? The Angels, baseball.
-So I'm a cultural illiterate, I'm sorry.
-[sighs]
What, this is money you owe, I take it?
For $2000, I'm a free man.
["Buona Sera" playing over speakers]
I got maybe 50.
It's in my bag in the TV room.
Help yourself.
-I'm naming my first kid after you.
-Mm.
Boy or girl. It's like fake alligator?
Dark brown?
You bet this on sports, you die.
No way, no way.
-You're my hero.
-Mm-hm.
♪ It is time to say goodnight to Napoli ♪
♪ Though it's hard for us to whisper
Buona sera ♪
♪ With that old moon
Above the Mediterranean sea ♪
♪ In the morning... ♪
-I'm an idiot, right?
-[chuckles]
My son does the same thing to me.
-He's family.
-Mm-hm.
["Buona Sera" continues muffled]
[door opens]
♪ Buona sera, signorina, buona sera... ♪
What's the story?
No story. I just quit.
Oh.
You got another job?
No.
Then how can you quit
a good setup like you got?
I'm bored out of my skull over there.
Sitting around...
Who says you gotta sit around?
Hey, if it's more responsibility you want,
I can set it up.
No, I don't want you
setting shit up for me.
I don't want any part of it anymore.
Part of what?
Hey, Nick, I'm a builder.
I make things
where there was nothing before.
What, is there something wrong with that?
You kiss up to Baci
and every other scumbag downtown
with a nickel in their pocket.
The outfit tells you,
put three guys on the payroll
that you never even seen, you do it.
If they told you to roll over and die,
you'd do it.
Think I like
to take that shit off of them?
What do you think
puts the food on the table?
Nick, I always try to do right by you,
by your mother, Laurie, and Tony.
Yeah.
You did a job on him, all right.
Your brother died in the war.
What could I do about that?
What could you do?
You could've stood up for him
instead of throwing him in like you did.
I would've killed for that kid.
Don't do me any favors
like you did for Tony.
[door opens]
[Mad Anthony] Joe.
What is this? An antique?
What do you get on this thing?
Milton Berle? Sid Caesar?
I gotta fix you up
with some new equipment.
Introduce you to the state of the art.
What do you say, Nick?
[car engine starts]
I'm in.
Let's fucking do it.
-We went through a lot of trouble for you.
-They give me a gun from Toys "R" Us.
-Well, what do you expect?
-Look at this outfit.
Oh, you look handsome in a uniform.
Please. Anybody l know see me in this,
I'm moving to Canada.
Oh, Franklin, it's just a start.
Might as well have a sign on my back say,
"l make chump change."
Uh-uh.
It'll keep the parole off your back.
It don't even fit, Reesha.
My prison clothes looked better than this.
-[Reesha] Would you just stick with it?
-Not bad.
Too old, but not bad.
Her boyfriend thinks it's Halloween.
[both laugh]
Yo, bird legs, come back here, darling.
I got something for you.
Stuck-up bitch.
Look at that one.
Them ain't real, Desmond.
Woman over 30 carry her tits up there?
That's plastic, man.
-Miracle of science. Foam rubber.
-[officer] Hit the bricks, fellas.
-Come on.
-Hands at your sides. Let's go.
-What'd we do?
-That's for us to figure out. Spread them.
-Wide.
-[Fuentes] Empty your pockets.
How can l hold the wall
and empty my pockets?
Did we ask for your opinion, punk?
Keep your yap shut.
-Where'd you hide it?
-Hide what?
You know. Don't get smart with me.
What are you two faggots doing down here?
This is a free fucking country.
[laughs] Where'd you hear that one?
You keep your shit down south
of L Street from now on, hear?
And I'm gonna point you
in the right direction.
Now move it.
-Go on, beat it.
-Faster.
-I don't think those were the ones, Paddy.
-They were up to something down here.
Didn't have a nickel between them.
[Fuentes] You think we stepped on them
a little too hard?
[Paddy] They're probably up there
laughing at us right now.
If you can't get respect,
you settle for fear.
[Fuentes] I think the ones
we want are a little older.
[Paddy] I've seen that kid l had before.
He's headed for the dirt farm.
-Oh, God, look at that. [laughs]
-Wow. She's beautiful.
-[Paddy] Oh!
-She must be 1 5 or 16.
[Paddy] They keep making new ones
every year, don't they?
American cars went to shit
after the Mustang in '65.
But fine-looking snatch,
they keep stamping it out.
-[Fuentes laughs]
-Regular production line.
[Fuentes]
Oh, lookie here. Look who we got there.
[Paddy] El Señor Ramirez,
a credit to his race.
[Fuentes] Fuck you, man.
[band playing "As One" in bar]
♪ On and on
Hand in hand... ♪
My fucking luck. We finally get a girl
in the band, she's a lesbian.
No, she's not.
I just asked her out, she said, "No way."
This town's full of chicks
who won't go out with you.
-Yeah, lesbians, all of them.
-Pfft!
It's the fluoride
in the fucking water supply or something.
Who is that? l know that girl.
[Zip] Just some lesbian, Nicky.
I want to know that girl.
[Zip] Yo, l got business.
We're up in five, Zip.
[Zip] And I'll be there, Bobby.
He's like a mother to me.
Qué pasa, Chato? What's in the pantry?
Blow. Extra strong.
Yeah? Could be shit,
could be stairway to heaven.
What do you say
we step into my office and find out?
-[song ends and crowd applauds]
-[singer] Thank you.
Yo, you got a son, l heard.
That's all right, another little Ramirez
running around in the world.
Hey, Nicky.
[Nick] Hey, Riggs.
I want you to know
there's no hard feelings.
Sure.
Your father's been so square with me,
I feel a certain amount of loyalty.
Right.
He's like your brother was.
You need him, he's right there for you.
I'm the only washout in the family, right?
No, I didn't mean it that way.
Hey, look, I'm not in the mood
to hear war stories about my brother.
-All right, yeah, yeah.
-Okay?
Thanks for quitting.
Takes a big load off my back.
Anytime.
[man] Hey, Nick, I hear you quit your job.
So, what's it to you?
Uh, this looks like the vig
for maybe one month here.
You're into me for 2 grand.
You lose your job,
I got a reason to be concerned.
Where'd you get this from, your mommy?
I hope you die.
[guitar and drums playing]
[Bobby over PA]
Check, one, two, one, two, three, four.
[Zip speaking in Spanish]
Yo, Pancho,
you too fucked up to play or what?
No, way, jefe, l am el numéro uno.
That thing the right key?
[Zip] We'll find out.
Let's boogie.
Uno, dos, three, four.
[playing "I Want It Back"]
♪ Mama, tell me no lies ♪
♪ l don't need misery ♪
♪ Keep those old alibis ♪
♪ Just come crawling to me ♪
♪ 'Cause l will admit
l want you back ♪
♪ Back in my arms ♪
♪ And I wanna take
And I want you right ♪
♪ Right back in my arms... ♪
[inaudible dialogue]
This used to be a city where the children
would inherit their parents' houses.
You got married, you lived upstairs.
It wasn't easy,
but you shut up, and you did it.
Couple years later,
God willing, there's children.
And you took over the payments.
You know how much our bills went up...?
-I talked to him again.
-And?
He jumped down my throat.
It's not gonna happen.
Hm. That's what he thinks.
I think that's very unfair
to our teachers.
You'll have your turn to speak, Nidia.
All I'm saying is that
this bond issue is an insult
to the working people who built this city.
Thank you.
Any other comments
before we hear from the council?
Uh, Mrs. Gianfreddo.
I'd like to comment on this issue
of quality in our schools.
My husband and l send our children
to St. Agnes',
and it costs an arm and a leg,
not to mention ironing
the damn uniforms every night.
But l wouldn't have them
in these public schools.
I was born and bred in this town,
and when I went to J Street,
teachers got a fraction
of what they get today,
with none of this psychological counseling
and computer technology nonsense...
Not much of a turnout for our side.
Just the death-to-taxes posse.
Listen, guys,
I've gotta break rank on this one.
-Why?
-What?
I got Crespi breathing
down my neck in November.
I don't want him to beat me
with this tax thing.
-Peter...
-So we lose 7-to-2.
Instead of 6-to-3, like we always do.
There's a principle involved.
Well, I don't have your ethnic thing going
in my district.
I can't afford to go down with the ship.
-I'm sorry.
-I mean, English as a second language?
Now, maybe l missed something,
but where l went to school,
English was the first language.
And has reading changed
that much in 25 years?
[band continues playing "I Want It Back"]
I like you.
What?
I don't really know you,
but I'm positive that l like you.
-Oh.
-I recognize you.
-You were a senior when l was in ninth.
-[song ends]
-You remember?
-[crowd applauding]
-[Bobby] Thank you very much.
-Yeah.
You had a brother who played basketball.
Right? He was ahead of me.
-[Bobby] Thanks for coming]
-Yeah.
-Tony.
-Tony Rinaldi.
He was a major heartthrob.
Yeah, he went over there, and...
Yeah.
Yeah, that was, um...
That was sad.
You went out with that, uh-- That creep.
That whosits, Michael Rizzo, right?
We got married.
Oh.
Really?
I walked right into that, huh?
Was he a creep in high school already?
I don't remember.
You're not with him anymore?
Free woman.
Well, listen, I'm Nick, and l like you.
But l gotta go. l gotta drive my friends
to pick up some equipment.
I'm like their designated driver,
you know what l mean?
But I'd like to see you again.
You didn't see me this time.
Huh?
It's nice to meet you.
I like you.
You said that. You don't know me.
Yeah, l do. You're something great.
I'm glad you think so.
[Bobby] Yo, Nicky, game time.
I will see you again. Believe this.
Hm.
Who's that?
Some drunk.
Cute drunk.
Very cute drunk.
White faggot-ass motherfuckers.
If they don't got a gun,
I'd fuck them up good.
Fuckers.
[Tito] We didn't do shit, man,
and they treat us like that.
Cracker-ass bastards.
Bastards.
We gonna do the time,
we might as well do the crime.
Dickless cocksuckers.
Yeah, we fuck them up good.
Look at this faggot-ass motherfucker.
-Hey.
-[Tito] Fuck, man, what you...?
Where you running, white boy?
Cut that out. Help.
Hey, hey. [grunting and gasping]
Shut the fuck up, faggot.
Cut-- [yells] Hey.
Cut it out.
Help.
[Tito] Grab him, Desmond.
[Les] Help, help.
-[Tito] Come back here, faggot.
-[Les] Help!
[grunts]
[tires screech]
[Paddy] Jesus, what happened to you?
All the other problems
we're hearing about tonight,
the unemployment,
the drugs, the street crimes,
those will always be the highest
where the people have the least education.
So you can pay now, or you can pay later.
If you had a brain tumor, you wouldn't
shop around for the cheapest surgeon,
you'd look for the best.
And that's what we're voting on tonight,
the best for our children.
Or do we sell out their futures
for a few tax dollars?
Thank you.
I think we're ready
for the vote now, folks.
All in favor of the motion
to implement Bond Issue C
as a method of raising additional revenues
for the city schools,
raise your hands.
All opposed?
The motion fails, seven votes to two.
[attendees applauding]
Quit kidding yourself, tough guy.
You're going one place. Get in here.
I mean, we can't go out on the street
and sell them ourselves.
Straight ahead up here.
Carl is giving us
45-percent wholesale value.
-The guy is slime.
-Yeah, but you owe him money, right?
So split this score,
and he'll be off your back.
Pull up to the loading dock.
We'll go around.
The key only works in the front.
You got a key?
I told you, it's simple. Like jerking off.
-What's jerking off?
-Come on, Moe.
Nyah! Nyah!
Oh, Christ.
You dead, sucker.
[lock clicks]
[Zip] "We'll beat the best price in town,
or else you get the shit for free.
Mad Anthony is the lowest."
We want the Mitsubishi, JVC, Panasonic,
top-dollar stuff only.
And nothing bulky.
-[Franklin] Freeze!
-Oh, shit.
Oh, shit. Oh, shit.
-What are you doing here?
-What the fuck you mean?
Hold it, fucker. What you trying?
I'm getting down on the floor.
I told you to freeze.
-Is this Simon Says?
-Shut up. Get on the ground.
-That's what I was doing.
-You too.
Just relax. Don't shoot that thing, huh?
We haven't stolen nothing.
Maybe we could work a deal, huh?
How about 1 00 bucks?
-You ain't got 1 00 bucks.
-Shut up. We'll give you whatever we got.
If you don't shut up,
I'm gonna shoot your dick off.
I don't think this deal thing
is gonna work, Bob.
Zip, you stupid sack of shit.
You told me nobody was gonna be here.
Goddamn, you're the worst thieves
I ever seen.
I got to go call the cops now, all right?
Should we have our hands on the back
of our necks or something?
Do me a favor, will you?
Shoot his dick off.
I'll vouch for you in court.
[engine revving]
[tires screech]
[engine rumbling]
-[man 1] Fuck you, motherfuckers!
-[man 2] All right, fuck you!
[man 1] Stupid.
-[tires screeching]
-[men whooping]
The light's better, you've calmed down.
We need to be positive.
I was in the car when they caught them.
One more time now.
These the boys?
Yes, that's them. I'm positive.
Okay, I'll take you to Detective Riley.
He'll record your statement.
-Faggot.
-Man, what'd you have to hit him for?
Because he's a white motherfucking faggot.
How'd you know that?
Look, if they ask us,
we say he wanted to suck our dicks,
and we tried to get away.
What's that gonna do?
They drop the case.
Being a faggot's against the law,
so we walk.
-Say he put his hands on you.
-No, man.
Fuck, say he put them on you.
Didn't nobody touch me.
Whoa, no skin off my butt.
[Bobby] This is a gross
misfeasance of justice here.
When we walked by, the door was wide open.
What would you have done? We assumed
there was a 24-hour sale going on.
We stick our nose
in the door 2 fucking centimeters,
and fucking Rambo over here
comes down on us,
yelling out racial epitaphs,
waving his piece around.
This man is dangerous, officers.
He almost blew
my friend's private organs off.
The gun's got no bullets in it, sucker.
-No bullets?
-It's plastic.
-Know how embarrassing this is?
-Oh, shit.
-[Zip] You hear what he's saying, Bob?
-[Malik] Brother Franklin.
[Franklin] Hey, Tyrone.
Malik.
Nah, nah, Tyrone.
-Malik.
-Yeah, look at you.
Yeah, look at you, brother.
Oh, yeah, I was recently incarcerated.
Pretty sorry, huh?
So, what happened to you?
I've surrendered myself
to the will of Allah.
-[Levonne] I knew you'd pull this shit.
-Knowledge is power.
-Got a plate glass window, no witnesses...
-I spread it. What about you?
Well, I surrendered myself
to the will of Mad Anthony.
Toshiba, Yoshida, Hitachi, Horita!
Toshiba, Yoshida, Hitachi, Horita...
Yo, the dude was a faggot.
He got what he deserved.
Even if that was the case,
which I doubt,
it's not against the law
to be a homosexual.
Yes, it is.
You approach this guy...
The fucker approached us.
Hey, what's the story here?
They saying assault.
This faggot come up to us in the park.
This isn't any of your business, Levonne.
I'm making it my business.
He put his hands on Desmond.
-That true?
-[detective] Levonne.
Is that true?
He tried to... You know.
Yeah, but l popped him one.
So he'd run on away from us. Self-defense.
You boys don't say anything until
I get you some legal aid down here.
-Understand?
-Yes, sir.
Levonne, this isn't a murder case.
Hey, Jeanette, you okay?
They got my boy here.
Is he one of those?
Oh, Lord.
-Did he do bad?
-[scoffs]
Just keep them quiet
till l can get them a lawyer, okay?
Go on, keep them quiet.
Uh... Hey, brother.
[laughs] Don't forget your weapon.
[officers laughing]
It's a jungle out there.
[Nick] Hi.
Hi.
Your friends in the band
never came back, huh?
Yeah, they got tied up.
Motor problems?
-It's like totally dead.
-Hm.
You know much about cars?
Not a thing. Do you?
No.
Then what are you doing
looking under the hood?
That's what people do, right?
You shouldn't be walking around here
alone at night.
I'll walk you home.
It's all right, I can manage.
I'm serious, it's dangerous around here.
Wait, look.
I'll walk on the other side of the street,
all right?
Don't be dramatic.
I'm on Lincoln, just between J and K.
Okay.
So are you happy?
What? What kind of question is that?
It's an important question.
You mean, am l happy right now?
With your life.
Are you happy with your life?
I'm not gonna tell you that.
What about you?
Me? No, I'm not happy.
Maybe if l had someone like you
to be with, l could be.
Are you always like this?
No, I'm usually, you know,
asking the regular bullshit.
Like, "What do you do?
What does your apartment rent for?"
I don't have time for that shit right now.
-You're on a deadline or something, huh?
-[exhales]
-You ever been in a car accident?
-Yeah.
Things, like, slow down,
they become real clear?
Important shit is going down in my life
right now all at once.
Like l saw you tonight.
Hey-- [chuckles] --I'm not that great.
Yeah, you are.
Well, tell me
the worst thing about yourself.
The worst.
I've put up with jerks in my life
for too long.
What, is that me? I'm a jerk?
I didn't say that.
Oh, thank you.
The jury's still out.
Do l turn your stomach
to look at or something?
No.
Well, am I neutral? Attractive?
You're a good-looking guy,
and you know it too. Big deal.
Well, I think you look fantastic.
Hm.
And if you're not married
or involved with anybody right now,
it's because nobody's figured out
what you're worth.
Hey.
Hey, what's the matter?
You can't say things like that.
Why not?
Because you don't know me. That's why not.
It's funny, I was married
for eight fucking years,
and my husband never said
one thing that nice to me.
Anyway, I don't know you,
so it's just words.
I'm sorry.
You were married eight years
to Michael Rizzo?
Who the fuck did you go out with
in high school?
Mary Ellen Battaglia.
-Mary Ellen Battaglia?
-Yeah.
Mary Ellen Battaglia
needed an instruction manual to chew gum.
She had other things, you know.
Yeah, she had tits in the third grade.
Her major fucking accomplishment in life.
Yeah, well, l didn't live with her
for eight years, you know?
Well, it was like l was with the Moonies
or something, you know?
It was my life.
Couldn't imagine anything else.
Did you have any kids?
I have a son.
Yeah?
That's cool.
Little guy, huh?
My mother takes him part of the time.
I'm going back to school
and I got a job at a restaurant.
DeLillo's.
Have you been following me?
No, I saw you in there once.
It's a public place, you know.
Jesse, uh-- That's my little boy.
--he, uh...
He has this disease.
Congenital. It makes him, like, spastic.
They call it "severely involved" now.
What do you do to have fun?
Fun?
I tell you, Nick,
it's like you asked me am I happy.
It's not something
I can think a whole lot about right now.
You said my name.
-What?
-Nick. You said, Nick.
I love that, you saying my name.
You are a strange fucker.
I think maybe you should
walk on the other side of the street,
like you said.
Listen, l could get my sister to babysit.
She owes me.
She's always borrowing money from me.
Then we could go out.
Hey, hey.
Slow down. Cool your jets.
I want you to take me seriously.
I don't think
you take yourself seriously, Nick.
I mean, those friends of yours, come on.
Yeah, l know, I know, but...
They're really not bad guys.
I mean, they're loyal.
Dogs are loyal.
Well, uh, this is my place.
You know when you're a kid,
a teenager, right?
And it's Saturday night, and you go out,
and every place you walk into,
you think, you know, this is it, you know?
There's gonna be somebody terrific
in here, I'll meet her,
and my life's gonna be
completely different after tonight.
Today has been a wild day for me.
I mean, unbelievable shit has gone down.
But I've had that feeling right here.
I haven't had it in such a long time,
because it never happens.
You never meet that girl,
or she's not the right one.
And then I see you.
You're gonna make me cry again.
Damn it, I'm just...
I'm kind of tired.
Angela Sabino.
Angela.
That's what it sounds like.
So, uh-- So, what if l call you up?
Worse things could happen.
Good night, Angela.
Good night, Nick.
[blues music playing]
[music fades]
You did it, didn't you?
[Nick] What?
Don't bullshit me, Rinaldi. You did it.
I did what?
Don't hand me that.
What if I did?
You're fucking with me now.
Don't fuck with me.
You did it, didn't you, you fuck?
I saw you with her.
You don't own her, Rizzo.
And if you ever did,
then you don't anymore.
You stay away from her.
No, you stay away from me.
You got your uniform,
your fucking badge, you're a big man, huh?
This uniform is the only thing
that stands between you
and a fucking trip
to the hospital right now, pal.
If I was off-duty, I'd bury you.
Yeah? What time you get off?
You're history, Rinaldi.
You're dead.
You're out of line, Mike.
It's none of your business.
You ride with me,
that makes it my business.
You settle your personal shit
on your own time.
Fine. Just butt out, okay?
No problem.
You're gonna get yourself in trouble.
Just shut the fuck up about it, huh?
They popped the window
out of here last night.
Gonna be all over us in the papers.
This is all a part
of a systematic campaign
to undermine Black manhood
in this country.
You stand up for yourself,
the white boy cuts you down.
These young brothers are being sacrificed
into the jaws of the racist conspiracy.
That's three pages.
I'll have to do some editing.
We had Dwight Rollins, unarmed,
shot to death by racist police this April.
Hollis Washington beaten to death
while in custody.
Why don't you ask the Great White Hope
what he thinks about it?
Somebody busted your window?
Morning, Wynn. What do you plan
to do about this park thing?
-Park thing?
-[Levonne] Yeah.
Two young Black men approached in a park
by a white homosexual.
They give him what for,
next thing you know,
they're run in by the cops for assault.
Last night?
What are you gonna do about it?
-Call the police...
-Go straight to the enemy.
Man got nothing to say
for the African-American community.
Man just a stooge in the system.
Half of everything you say is true, Malik.
The other half is pure shit.
-That's off the record, Kyle.
-Fucking politicians.
Off the fucking record, Wynn.
What do you plan to do
for the young brothers?
First I'll investigate the charges.
You saying the brothers are lying?
Is that what?
Councilman Himes promised a thorough
investigation of the incident. Period.
Excuse me.
Fucking politicians.
I'm not gonna tell you
what to do about this, Les.
I just want you to understand
the kind of pressure we are under here.
First thing this morning, l get a call
from the P Street Community Center.
I'm not backing down.
Those kids are dangerous.
I understand that,
but the homosexual thing complicates it.
We have a very tenuous relationship
with the people in this city.
What homosexual thing?
They didn't tell you?
The boys said you made advances to them.
Goddamn it.
There was a follow-up call
from the police department.
-Hi, Les.
-In light of the circumstances...
-That's a lie.
-Oh, God, what happened to him?
I saw an article
in the paper this morning.
He was mugged in the park
by some kids last night.
Oh, God. Did they say what race?
-What?
-The race of the kids, Black or white?
-Black.
-Oh, great.
That doesn't have anything to do with you.
-Suzanne, you know better than that.
-[Angela] He's younger, but not that much.
I was a senior when he was in ninth grade.
By now that's not such a big deal, right?
And he's good-looking and everything,
so I don't think much about it.
I get out to my car, it's dead.
Turn the key, not a sound.
That piece of shit that Michael left me,
I hate to even look at the thing.
And then he shows up, this guy, Nick,
and he's, like, lost or something.
[laughs]
Listen to me talk about this stuff.
-Am l stupid or what?
-They beat me up.
They say l came on to them?
I'm sorry, but to me that's a big deal.
-It is.
-There's a principle involved.
A very important principle.
Of course there is, Les, if you say so.
I'm not a homosexual.
I understand that,
but we have a public profile.
And if l was, so what?
What does this school stand for?
Let's do this inside, okay?
We have your prints all over the van.
Outstanding.
An ever-tightening net
of circumstantial evidence.
Who was the third guy?
You got the prints. You tell us.
You give me a name,
I'll put a word in with the court.
You guys hang around
with Nick Rinaldi, don't you?
Nick who?
Forget it, Bob.
He's too fucking smart for us.
Look, we give up.
It was him.
[Bobby] Yo, Asteroid.
-Say, "I did it."
-[Asteroid] l did it.
-[Bobby] No, l did it. No, I did it.
-[Asteroid] No, l did it. No, I did it.
-[Zip laughing]
-I did it. No, l did it. l did it.
No, I did it.
-No, I did it. l did it. l did it.
-[Zip and Bobby laughing]
I did it. l did it. No, no, I...
No, I did it.
[car engine revving]
[tires screech]
-Hey, O'B.
-[engine stops]
Long time no see.
Engine problems?
You're the one with the problem, Carl.
Get in.
[pneumatic wrench whirring]
Nice rig you got here, O'Brien.
You're doing all right for yourself.
-I can always be doing better.
-Aw.
I hate to see a man unsatisfied
with his station in life.
What's the beef?
Mad Anthony's? Last night?
Can't help you. How much did they clear?
Nada, your little friends Bobby and Zip
tripped over their dicks.
You should know better.
-Got nothing to do with me.
-They talked.
I don't fall for that shit, O'Brien.
You should know better.
I got Leo Snider at Rahway
coming up for review.
He says if l help him,
he'll put your ass away for me.
The vending machine hijack?
Lehman's furs?
The fire on the waterfront.
Why not throw
in the Kennedy assassination?
I hate to be the one to break this to you,
but a lot of people don't like you, Carl.
What do you want?
Suspect number three.
Somebody left a hot van
outside of Anthony's.
The security guy says
he saw the third outside,
but he couldn't make him.
I figure that somebody
on the inside gave you the key.
That's all?
And a player to be named at a future date.
Nick Rinaldi.
Oh, that's very good news.
You know, we should have a talk
like this more often.
You tell Snider to eat shit and die.
You sound bitter, Carl.
I hate to see a man unhappy
with his station in life.
[engine starts]
Hey, Carl.
Somebody pulled the distributor head
off this thing.
There's nothing to it.
Whose car is it?
I don't know. Some girl.
Hook brung it in.
Uh...
Tell her we're gonna replace
the ignition system.
Hey, Carl.
When are you gonna give me something?
You tell your boyfriend Ramirez
he can come in by himself
or we can bring him in.
The second way is not gonna be any fun.
This is a condemned building, miss.
I give you two days.
Two days, l come back here,
you better be gone, comprende?
[Tommy] Let's go, Mike.
Jesus, what a pit.
That baby is gonna get sick.
I used to come in here
and shoot pigeons up on the 4th floor.
Hundreds of them.
They come in through the broken windows.
It's good for the reflexes.
Yeah, you should slow
those reflexes down a little bit.
Can you imagine living
in a place like this?
My father lived here when he was a kid.
A different building on the same spot.
Probably the same kind of dump.
But he got himself out, right?
He ran numbers
till his cousin got him on a job.
Then you guineas moved in,
the place went to hell.
[Mike] Oh, funny guy.
[Tommy]
So, what do you wanna do for lunch?
Let's cook up some pigeons, huh?
[Tommy] Nah, I'm sick of Italian food.
["Body Language" playing over stereo]
♪ l read you loud and clear ♪
♪ Nobody to meet
When you feel that heat ♪
♪ Eye to eye
As it starts... ♪
Um, excuse me.
Do you know a boy named Desmond Price,
lives in this building?
He's already talked to the police,
the social worker...
I'm your councilman in this district.
♪ Your body language
You can have your say... ♪
I seen your picture.
I'm Desmond's mother.
Great. Um...
Could I talk with him?
-You think my boy lie?
-No.
But l would like
to ask him a few questions.
You think he lying.
I don't know. I wasn't there.
Sometimes, under pressure from the police,
kids can say a lot of things
to keep themselves out of trouble.
Get out here, Desmond.
[stereo turns off]
My son doesn't lie.
I want to be able to help
to clear this thing up.
Sit.
Talk to the man.
Um... Hi, Desmond.
I'm, uh, Wynston Himes.
I'm your councilman in this district.
I seen your picture.
Right. Um...
Can you tell me what happened that night?
Go on. Tell the man what you told me.
[sighs]
Me and my friend Tito was hanging out
at the park.
Not doing nothing.
Sitting on this bench.
And this dude in sweats sit by us,
and start talking that
he give us money if we let him...
You know.
What words did he say?
Suck us off.
Then he reached for me,
but he didn't touch me.
See, don't nobody touch me.
But he was gonna.
That's when Tito went off on the man,
pops him in the face,
one, two, three, and we run off.
And that's it?
Then the cops catch us and run us in.
That's the truth? Not just saying this
to stay out of trouble?
My son doesn't lie, mister.
And he ain't going to no family court.
Well, I'll try and make sure
that doesn't happen.
Thank you for talking to me.
Oh, and if any newspaper people
come by, try not to--
We already talked with a man
from Black Courierthis morning.
Uh-huh.
Them faggots always after you
up to the park.
Be happening all the time, mister.
Get back in your room, Desmond.
Thank you.
His son was third party
in a robbery attempt last night.
The other two got caught, he got away.
We haven't ID'd him yet.
Hard evidence?
I can nail his ass to the wall.
Look at that.
My heart rate.
Yeah.
I croak on this damn thing,
they'll be able to make a printout of it.
Anyway, I thought you'd be interested.
I appreciate it, Bill.
If things turn out right,
we won't forget you.
We could do it through our own office.
I can handle it.
We've got a timetable on this, mayor.
The Japanese want it cleared
by the weekend.
If the Japanese pull their money out,
we got a real...
I can handle it.
Right, it's your turf.
Rinaldi's practically your brother.
All you goombahs
are practically brothers, right?
We just need those buildings cleared.
-I don't want to hear Parks Department.
-Ben Ianucci, that mamaluke.
Do you people ever go in that park?
There are no street lights.
It's like the Dark Ages, medieval times.
-A professor got mugged there last night.
-A supposedly intelligent person.
I wouldn't go out in that park
in a Sherman tank after dark.
-Pauly, come inside.
-Like a Charles Bronson movie.
-Excuse me, ladies.
-There's animals out there.
Now. Pauly.
Fiscal crisis. Excuse me.
-They don't listen.
-They never listen.
[indistinct chatter]
Yo, Gus. [whistles]
So, what's the fucking story here?
You're shut down, Joe.
For what?
You got a septic clearance
that isn't up to spec.
I got a green light on that months ago.
Yeah, but not on paper.
You know where it came from.
I know. Then I suggest you go back
to where it came from, and talk to them.
What the fuck you think I'm out here for?
Septic clearance, my ass.
Still on the clock, Joe.
You call Belcher and get off the clock.
This could take a week.
Belcher says no breaks from the Local.
Contract stands.
What the fuck is that?
Your juice has been cut off, Joe.
Whatever problems you got downtown,
you clean them up,
we can cut you some slack.
Come on. Don't take it personal.
Yo, Tommy.
-Joe...
-[Yoyo] Tommy, wait up.
Man, I'm sorry.
Did, uh, Nicky come back today?
No.
[Pauly] Hey, Joe.
Joe, we gotta talk. We got problems.
That two-bit crook you work for
has got problems, starting right now.
We got a situation here, Joey.
Get in. Gotta stop by the apartments
on the way downtown.
Fucking Gus shut me down.
It's Baci, right?
It's this fucking L Street deal.
We got worse problems than that, Joe.
Nicky's in trouble.
What trouble?
He and Bobby Krausse and that kid Zip,
they tried to do
Anthony's warehouse last night.
What, is he in jail?
No, he got away,
but they know he was in on it.
It doesn't make sense.
Why would Nicky need to do a robbery?
[scoffs]
-Was anybody hurt?
-No, no guns.
But the thing about it is,
the DA's office is butting into it.
The guy's bucking for Senate, right.
They figure they go after Nicky,
respectable family,
juice with the people downtown,
shows he's impartial, right?
Incorruptible, all that shit.
They're trying to bury him, Joe.
They got a stolen van,
Anthony's place, no mercy.
I asked the mayor as a personal favor
to hold them off.
He's made an effort.
But l gotta tell you,
I don't think his heart is in it.
And what would it take
to put his heart back into it?
What we talked about
with L Street. Tonight.
This is my kid.
You're using my kid against me like this?
Your nephew?
It's grand larceny, Joe.
And Nicky put us here, not me.
Look at this place, Joe. It's a dump.
It wouldn't be
if your outfit didn't have my hands tied.
It's coming down anyway, sooner or later.
They're not asking you
to do the thing itself.
They just need to be sure once it's done,
you don't go fixing the place back up.
Where's Nicky?
He's okay. They haven't found him yet.
I put the word out, kid gloves.
I'm gonna have to go to Kerrigan on this.
What the fuck?
Yo.
Gus.
Hello, Joe, what do you know?
What's this?
You got six or seven violations here.
I haven't even been to the basement yet.
Oh, you.
You're gonna pay some fines, Joe.
Oh, you fuck.
And just yesterday it was all up to code.
Things fall apart quick, don't they?
[diners chattering]
-Hi.
I'm Nick. I was...
Yeah, I'll go get her. She's in the annex.
Thanks.
Yo, Nicky, you a busboy here or what?
-[Nick] What are you guys doing out?
-City shut us down.
[Nick] What for?
What do you care? You quit.
Nicky, come over here.
I wanna talk to you.
Nicky, the cops come by
just after your old man left the site.
-You in trouble?
-[sighs]
I might be.
-You need a few bills to see you through?
-No, no, no.
They had a real hard-on for you, Nicky.
If I were you, I wouldn't go back
to your place for a while.
Take it light, huh?
Thanks.
[Wynn] All l see right now
is that you and your people are
selling off my district, piece by piece.
What brings revenue to the city,
what brings life to the city,
is good for everybody.
Right, the trickle-down theory.
But things only seem
to trickle down so far.
Can't expect the developer to build
if he can't make a profit.
You don't expect people
to watch their neighborhood be plowed
without lifting a finger.
The development creates jobs.
With jobs, people can afford higher rents.
And those jobs are gonna go
to the people on L Street?
Tell me another one.
[laughs]
I was hoping that
we could cut some kind of a deal here.
You mean a personal deal?
I hear that you got your brother-in-law
on Mad Anthony's payroll.
What does that mean?
I understand what it's like.
New guy on the council.
The last man at the banquet.
People expect you to deliver.
Okay, I got housing inspectors,
I got teacher's aides.
You keep pushing Galaxy Towers
the way it's set up now,
we'll fight you
on blighting classification, on evictions,
on construction and demolition,
every little step of the way.
We'll make the L Street apartments
a symbol
for everything
that's fucked up in this city.
They can't be a symbol
if they aren't there.
Sounds like they got you
by the short one, Joey.
I was wondering, uh,
since your people fronted me
the money on this thing...
[laughs]
You want me to get Baci off your back?
Well, he's hurting your investment.
We invested in you, Joe.
This creep,
he's using my family against me.
You think he didn't check with us
before he made a move?
And if l blow my bid
on the apartment building?
If I can't make the payments?
What would a regular bank do?
You're not a regular bank.
I'm carrying your people on my payroll.
Look, Joe.
We appreciate that.
We really do.
You'd still get to put up buildings,
you just wouldn't be your own boss.
Maybe you never were, really.
I borrowed from you
to get something for myself.
Without Baci, without my brother.
That's not the way our society works, Joe.
You got something good, first everybody
on top of you gets a taste,
then you share what's left
with everybody below you.
We're social animals,
human beings, not dogs.
Come on, Joe. You'll do what you have to.
And the people who know,
the people that count,
they'll understand, Joe.
They'll respect you for it.
Thanks.
Shit.
[Roger] Les?
Preparing a lecture?
Right.
Listen, we heard about you getting mugged.
I was really sad to hear that.
Thanks.
And we heard the rest,
the rumor, about the countercharges.
I wanted to say that we're really glad
you're gonna fight this out.
Who's "we"?
"We" us.
You know, those of us
who are gay on the faculty,
our friends in the community.
How could everybody
have heard of it so soon?
Anyhow, we... l think it's great
that you're taking a stand.
Who says I'm taking a stand?
I'm not gay, Roger.
We know that.
What if I stonewall,
and the police and the press
and everybody believe the boys?
What if it backfires? What...?
What if it plays right into the hands
of the racists and the fag-bashers?
Homophobics.
Sorry. But what if that happens?
If you just roll over for them,
they'll never change.
Hi.
Oh, um, l heard about Les.
That's so awful.
Yeah.
Take care.
Yeah, you too.
[sighs]
-Hi, baby.
-Hi.
How'd it go today?
Les Pullman was mugged last night.
I know.
It's gonna get worse too.
How could it get worse?
The two kids who beat him up
say he was coming on to them.
Les isn't gay.
How do we know that?
Because he isn't.
Levonne Willis is stirring the pot.
Worked up a meeting tomorrow
at the community center.
The whole point is
to nail me to the wall in public.
Don't be paranoid.
Do you know who these boys are?
I talked to one of them.
Do you think he was telling the truth?
Levonne will have me up in front
of every heavy hitter in the community.
The Black press, everyone.
He'll ask that same question.
How do you think I'd better answer?
Do you think they were telling the truth?
Politically speaking, it doesn't matter.
It matters to me.
[Angela]
You like that. You like that, don't you?
Yes, you like that. You like that so much.
I'm 1 0 years older than my brother was
when he was killed.
Okay, let's go for a walk, okay?
He was just a kid.
My big famous brother.
-I've been thinking...
-Good boy.
What have l done with my life
in those last 1 0 years?
I mean, what have l got
to show for all that time?
What do you think you should've done?
I don't know.
Have a family?
No, not a family.
Do something heroic?
Maybe. Not...
You know, not in the Army, though.
-What is that? What is that?
-Nothing like that.
Something big.
I want to be my own boss.
What, like your father?
No.
Not like him.
Not anything like him.
[melancholy, pensive music playing]
[music fades]
So it's you.
Yeah.
I guess l shouldn't be surprised.
People do favors for me,
I do favors for them.
You know how it works, Joe.
Why does it have to be tonight?
Look, the fire is very minor.
We gut two or three floors
on the abandoned side,
other side of the firewall.
After I get my kid in there,
make a few adjustments
to the sprinkler system, we get a flood.
Water damage.
Nobody gets hurt,
nobody moves back in either.
I don't like it.
You're not supposed to like it, Joe.
You're supposed to bend over,
spread your cheeks, take it like a man.
Not too fucking thrilled about it myself.
Don't organize any block parties
down there tonight.
It's life, Joe. What are you gonna do?
[melancholy, pensive music resumes]
You don't have to do this, you know.
I'm not gonna let them run my life.
If I back down now, they win.
Who's keeping score?
I'll see you in a bit.
I have to be careful when he's got a cold.
He's always had a hard time breathing.
Hey, you shaved.
Yeah, there was a razor in there.
Ooh.
I use that for my legs.
You're lucky you got skin left.
Yeah, well, l haven't been
to my place all day.
You break up with your girlfriend?
Oh, I haven't been with anybody
for a while now.
Why not?
Whenever l need somebody,
it's like, zap,
all the women in the world disappear.
I swear they smell me coming
from a block away and they hide somewhere.
It's the same with guys
when they find out I got a kid.
They figure all l got on my mind
is roping them into getting married.
Well, what is it you got on your mind?
Usually something about
how much sleep I can get,
and still go to school, and go to work,
and do Jesse's therapy every night.
It's very romantic.
I guess you can get used to anything.
I don't wanna get used to it. It sucks.
You, uh-- You can't be a creep, okay?
I mean, you start any bullshit,
I just don't have the energy.
I'll do my best.
I'm kind of defensive, huh?
You're like a surgeon general's warning
with legs.
I'm sorry.
I mean it though, huh?
Don't worry about it.
Do you have anything?
Aren't you on anything?
No, I have something.
You got quite a supply there.
A girl can dream, can't she?
You want?
Yeah, when we get to that point.
[Jesse coughing]
Wait.
What?
What is it?
It's all right.
You still up for this?
I could be persuaded.
[moaning]
[both chuckle]
-[sighs]
-You okay?
Yeah. [laughs]
When I started to go off,
I caught a cramp in my foot.
A foot cramp.
[both laughing]
-Mmm. You know what?
-What?
-It went away though.
-Oh, yeah? Hm.
"Dear Dr. Ruth,
Lately my wife's been
having orgasms in her toes."
[both laugh]
Come here, my baby.
-Oh.
-"ls this normal?"
Bring me a towel, baby.
Don't stand in front of the window.
Poor Mrs. Hurley is gonna have a stroke,
she sees your pretty behind
mooning out at her.
[both moaning]
Did l make you forget?
Forget about what?
All your problems.
Sugar, l forgot my name.
[ominous blues music playing]
Joe, how long have you been here?
I don't know.
Not long.
Are you hungry?
Mrs. Ramirez made a casserole.
No.
I'm not hungry.
Joe?
Something the matter?
[sighs] Nicky's in trouble.
He's wanted for a robbery.
-Is he all right?
-I don't know, Pina.
They haven't found him yet.
He didn't do it.
Yes, he did.
-I'll get Bart on the phone...
-No, it'll take more than a lawyer.
I've already put things in motion.
What does that mean?
What did you do?
[ominous blues music playing]
Help, help. We need help.
We need help clearing our warehouse
of these bargains. We've got great deals.
Psychoses, neuroses, dementia, amnesia,
schizoid, paranoid, psychotropic seizure,
hebephrenic, melancholic,
agoraphobic, alcoholic,
manic, manic depressive,
genetically regressive,
rabies, scabies, char-babies.
Help, help.
We need help clearing our warehouse
of fantastic bargains.
We've got great deals.
Psychoses, neuroses...
Maybe we could plea bargain.
No, we have to have
something that they want, Bobby.
Besides Nick.
-That's out.
-Gonna do time, then.
-Right.
[Asteroid babbling]
Maybe this is hell.
No, if this was hell,
my mother would be here,
reading from USA Today
about which foods are the most
mucus-producing when you have a cold.
Compared to my house, this is Disneyland.
Bring on the night, shut out the light.
Shut out the light. Shut out the light.
[Zip] Oh, shit.
[Bobby] What'd he have to do that for?
[siren wailing]
[horn blaring]
[siren continues wailing]
[Nick] Damn.
Hey, if you want to sneak off,
you can go out the front door.
[Nick] Half the fire engines
in the world are down on L Street.
I think it might be
one of my father's buildings.
[horn blaring]
You father owns a slum?
Back it up. Come on, people.
Come on, we don't want any injuries here.
-Back it up. Let's go. Let's go.
-[crowd chattering]
[man] Give me more slack here.
Move on back. See if the windows...
-[Joe] Kevin?
-[siren wailing]
Kevin, you got it under control?
The floors are starting to fall though.
It won't spread next door,
but you got a flood in this one.
Your water main went
with your sprinkler system.
And nobody hurt though?
We may have some people on the 4th here.
But that side's abandoned.
[Mrs. Ramirez screaming
and yelling in Spanish]
[firefighters yelling indistinctly]
[paramedic] Get the oxygen on her.
[Mrs. Ramirez continues screaming]
[firefighter 1] Any more up there?
[firefighter 2] Nothing we could see.
The 4th floor's too secluded.
[firefighter 1] Where were they?
[Mrs. Ramirez continues screaming]
-Nick.
-[Fuentes] Move it back, let's go.
-Nick, Nick.
-[Paddy] Back it up, folks.
[Joe] Hey, where you going?
[Paddy] Yo, folks.
-Nick.
-Hey, what'd I tell you?
Yo, back it up, let's go.
Hey, Paddy.
Have we still got a want on that kid?
It's that Ramirez.
[firefighter speaking indistinctly]
-After the funeral.
-[siren wailing]
All right, come on...
[blues music playing]
Help, help.
Help, we need help. Help.
Any messages for me?
We got bargains. We got deals.
All your electronics needs.
We got deals.
Under one roof. Under one roof.
Help, help. We need help.
Man, who the fuck are you?
I am the lowest. Who the fuck are you?
Look... Hey, Levonne.
Levonne, you working here?
No, I just came by to check out the show.
I ain't seen so much paper in all my life.
All of them ask the same damn questions.
You see, it helps them
to stall while they try to figure out...
Why settle for less
when you can have it all?
Money talks, nobody walks.
Money talks, nobody walks...
[speaking in Spanish]
-[in English] Hi, Wynn.
-Uh...
Hi. How many people was it?
Uh, 1 3 families, a couple of singles.
Only a few have family they can stay with.
How long till they rehab the side
that didn't burn?
Rinaldi says it's totaled.
He's gonna knock it down
and sell the land.
The development package.
Not very subtle, are they?
[speaks in Spanish]
-[in English] I'll see you later.
-Yeah.
Levonne.
What's this, Wynn?
Photo opportunity?
And what would you be saying
if l didn't come?
-Hi.
Whose is this?
-Mine. Hold her for a minute?
-Yeah?
-Yeah. Felice had to work today.
-Hey, there.
What's your name?
[laughs] She looks just like you.
Yeah, maybe.
Can l talk to you?
I wish you'd reconsider this meeting.
If you have to kiss the man's ass,
that's your problem.
That's off the point. This here,
this is what's worth fighting for.
-We have to choose where we make a stand.
-What "we"?
Okay, it's your ass.
They probably started it themselves.
They had no power in there.
They used candles and shit.
Probably knocked something over.
Arson.
Huh?
Arson. It was a torch job. Professional.
How do you know that?
Because l lived here 40 years, that's how.
Listen to me, I want you
to be calm about this, all right?
The guy you went off on yesterday
made the charts.
Nick Rinaldi?
What'd he do?
Robbery suspect.
Suspect, right?
No guns involved. No priors.
No reason to believe
he's armed or dangerous.
We see him, you stay in the car,
I make the collar, right?
-Right?
-Right.
Just let me at him in the fucking car.
You're a mess, kid.
Where you turning?
The site up here. He was working that job.
Ferraro checked it out yesterday. He quit.
Fucking deadbeat.
She takes up
with a fucking deadbeat thief.
What's it to you anymore?
Hey, Tom, it reflects on me, all right?
She's my ex-wife, the mother of my child.
Child?
You never told me you had a kid.
Boy or girl?
Boy.
How old?
He's 2.
Huh. Two-year-old son, huh?
I never knew you had a kid.
Well, I do.
[man speaking indistinctly]
If you like that one, I'll be glad
to make the estimate for you.
Hector.
Whatever she wants,
you cut your price in half.
I'll pay the difference.
And don't let her know.
-[man 1] Hey, Errol.
-[man 2] Hey, Errol.
Morning, fellas.
It was a lot more fun playing here
when they were afraid of me.
-I took them to court.
-This was restricted?
Yeah, no Blacks, no Jews,
no undesirable elements.
I'd hang out at the 1 8th green
by the clubhouse, and just smile,
and make the old bastards
1 2-putt the final hole.
Took two years before anybody said hello.
Must've been tough
to concentrate on your game.
I never played better.
So you've got yourself
a nice little mess, Wynn.
Makes me glad I'm retired.
You were operating on a bigger scale.
Scale doesn't matter.
You always try to gain some ground,
no matter what the situation is,
and make some good come out of it.
I don't see how this is good for anybody.
You think those boys are lying, don't you?
-Well...
-You wouldn't be here otherwise.
I think it's too big
for them to go back on their story now.
[laughs]
I didn't use enough club.
I hate it when I do that.
I nibble my way up to the green.
It's a failure of nerve.
Why l have to take a stance
on this at all...
-You're not a policeman.
-Right.
-Nor a judge.
Right.
But the moment will come
when Levonne will put it to me
in front of the whole community,
"Do you think our boys are lying?"
Wedge?
[sighs] What?
Do you think l could use a wedge
from this far out?
[sighs] l don't play.
-Tennis? Racquetball?
-I don't play anything.
You do have a problem.
You, um...
You could say you believe them.
If we're gonna take power,
we have to take responsibility too.
You're absolutely right, professor.
How are you, darling?
It's good to see you up and around again.
You got your color back. That's marvelous.
Oh, you should've been there last night.
We had a big one.
The equipment our boys have now.
Not like in your day,
a bucket and a ladder.
How's your fingers, huh? Make a fist.
Beautiful, beautiful.
Did you come for the lasagna, Joe,
or is this official business?
Two people are dead because of you and me.
They were trespassing. Those are the kind
of people accidents happen to.
You suck.
Joe, things change fast.
People get hurt. I'm sorry about that.
It was an accident.
Now if everybody stands up
like a good soldier,
we can stay on top of it.
Joe, in the next couple of years,
this town is gonna be one big yard sale.
And anyone with a half a brain
will make tracks,
let the Blacks and the Spanish
duke it out over whatever's left.
I want you off of my kid.
I'll call Walsh.
We'll take his name out of the computer.
It never happened.
And the other two?
Anthony is good people.
He'll drop the charges if l tell him to.
Tell him to.
[all] Surprise.
Mrs. Donnelly, 90 years old.
Joe, 90 years ago,
the Irish ran this town.
There were horses shitting
on Jefferson Street.
My grandfather got here off the boat.
They gave him a scoop and a shovel.
Now l run the place.
America, huh?
♪ America, America ♪
♪ God shed his grace on thee ♪
♪ And crown thy good ♪
♪ With brotherhood ♪
♪ From sea to shining sea ♪
-Let's try it one more time.
-[knocks on door]
I'm gonna step out for a second.
If I'm not back,
do The Star-Spangled Banner, okay??
I wanna be able
to hear your voice, Warren.
Where the hell have you been?
I've been calling your apartment.
There were police.
-They came here?
-Oh, yeah. Big show.
Kids treated me like a TV star.
I got some problems.
Being late with the rent
is having some problems, Nick.
Cops after you for robbery
is being seriously fucked up.
-Listen.
-No, you listen.
You know where Mom was this morning?
In church, praying for you.
You turn her into a religious fanatic,
Nicky, so help me...
Laurie, l need you to do something for me.
We had a deal.
You remember?
After Tony died?
You and me against the world.
How come I'm always helping you out
and I never get anything back?
I helped you with that marriage deal.
You fucked up my engagement.
He was an asshole.
He was my asshole.
Hey, listen, listen, listen.
I'm gonna turn myself in, okay?
I just need
to straighten some things out first.
I think Dad might be in trouble.
Yeah, one of his apartment buildings
burned down last night.
People were killed.
Yeah, I'd say he's got trouble.
I think it might be worse than that,
all right?
Now...
Now call him up, be nice to him.
You know, I don't know, talk or something.
-Why can't you do that?
-I can't.
Why not?
I can't.
Doesn't work that way between us.
Please, don't get hurt, Nick.
I was one of the first Black mayors
of a major city in this county.
Lot of media pressure, millions of people
affected by my decisions.
But there was no way l could turn my back
on the people who put me in.
So I brought some of them along with me.
Some of them messed up.
Well, they're only people. They're human.
I let it go at first
because l didn't believe it,
and then because
I didn't want to believe it,
and finally because
we would lose more ground
by cleaning house in public
than by sweeping it under the carpet.
Took 1 2 years
for all that to catch up to me.
That's a pretty nice run,
the way things go these days.
You decided not to run again?
There were three grand jury indictments
hanging over my head.
If I'd stood for another term,
a lot of people would've gone down,
and I would've gone down with them.
So I should lie,
and hope for 1 2 good years?
This isn't the Old Testament, Wynn.
People didn't vote you in
so you can test your moral fiber.
If you're going to be a leader, lead.
Take it to the man every chance you get.
-It's not about a fight with white people.
-It's always about that, Wynn.
If it isn't,
you're just another ward heeler.
You don't defend anything.
You attack what's wrong.
That's what a leader is.
I worked so hard to get on the council,
I never thought about...
Can't know how you'll play the green
while you're still back at the tee, Wynn.
You just figure it out when you get there.
[Riggs] Hey, Nick?
Figured you might be here.
This was always your favorite hiding spot.
What do you want?
To see if you needed help.
What do you wanna help me for?
Your brother must have saved my ass
a half-dozen times over there.
And then your father.
When I got back, l was pretty messed up.
This job has been...
-Look, you don't owe me nothing.
-All right.
The offer stands though.
You need money?
A go-between?
-After your friends thrown you in...
-Who said that?
The guard saw me.
What are you talking about?
The cop that came by here just said,
"His pal threw him in."
Carl.
Fucking Carl.
-What are you gonna do, Nicky?
-I gotta find something out.
Hey, thanks, man. l owe you one.
Right.
Fucking kid.
[Wynn] How are your, uh...?
How are your classes this year?
They're fine.
Sometimes I, uh, really miss it.
The classroom, the faculty politics.
Well, it's...
It's all a bit tame now, isn't it?
I know why you're here, Wynn.
Let's get on with it.
I understand why you want
to hold your ground on this thing.
Oh?
Why is that?
Because you're telling the truth.
But you're not gonna
go to bat for me, are you?
This is not about what l think is right.
I have to represent the people in my ward.
If I was Black and they were white,
would that stop you?
There are two possibilities
as to what will happen.
Number one, if you drop the charges,
a few of the people at school,
not the ones that you respect the most,
will whisper.
"Where there's smoke, there's fire."
That you're gay.
That you must have
made a move on those boys.
Number two, if you push this thing,
those same accusations
come out in the press, in a court of law.
You're labeled a homosexual
and a racist.
Finally it comes down
to your word against theirs,
and it doesn't matter what the verdict is.
Those same people
will still think you're guilty.
Now...
I can't stop any of that.
At all.
But if you do drop the charges,
I will do everything I can
to make it a clean break.
This stinks.
To high heaven.
["All For Nothing, Our Balls to the Wall"
playing on stereo]
♪ Balls to the wall
Balls to the wall ♪
♪ All for nothing
Our balls to the wall ♪
Balls to the wall... ♪
Hey, it's the fugitive.
You got a problem?
Yeah, you.
You fucking rolled over on me.
That's not a very nice thing to say, Nick.
The way l see it, you stuck your nose
where it wasn't invited.
Then your two little friends fucked up,
and even the dumbshit cops in this town
were smart enough to run you down for it.
Nah, you rolled over on me.
They didn't have to whack you
with phone books, step on your fingers.
They walked in the fucking door,
and you were ready to spill.
You rolled over on me,
just like you did on Tony.
Don't talk to me about that old shit.
Your best fucking friend,
and you threw him in.
You think he was a fucking hero,
don't you?
Tony.
He was a punk.
Who do you think
was driving the fucking car that night?
Who was driving shitfaced,
went up on the curb, and hit that woman?
Who ran away,
ran his little all-state ass away,
and left me there
with my leg all fucked up
and that woman lying on the ground?
That's bullshit.
Ask your daddy, Nick.
Ask him what went down.
And get out of my way. I'm closing up.
-That fire last night.
-What about the fucking fire?
It was you, wasn't it? You did it.
Like l said before, Nick,
ask your daddy.
You fucking liar.
-[Carl] You fuck.
-[gun cocks]
You finished, Nick?
Because if you're not,
I'll blow your fucking brains out.
[officers humming "Highway Patrol"]
[Mike]
If ever the laws of any state are broken,
a duly authorized organization
springs into action.
We may be called the state police,
the state troopers,
the militia, the rangers,
or the highway patrol. [laughs]
These are the stories of the brave men
whose training, skill, and courage
have preserved and enforced...
Have enforced
and preserved our state laws.
[officers applauding and whistling]
Thank you.
Gentlemen, brothers of the shield,
I salute you.
And I bid you farewell.
[officers applauding]
You can't walk, kid.
Who needs a wife when you got
this fucking guy on your case?
Ten-four, brothers.
Take care.
-I'll see you tomorrow.
-[Mike] Yeah, yeah.
-[Paddy] Early.
-[Mike] All right.
-[O'Brien] Hey, Mikey.
-Hey.
Jerry, stand them up. A round of drinks
for all these lousy beat walkers here.
[officers cheer]
You hit the lottery, O'Brien?
I'm moving up to the DA's office.
Special investigator.
That's great to hear.
All those years sucking up to the pols.
I'd hate to think there's no payoff.
Everybody drinks but him.
I don't see why
I gotta say all that again.
People have to hear it
with their own ears.
I don't like saying it.
You ain't got nothing
to be ashamed of, do you?
Part about him trying to touch me.
-Did he touch you?
-No.
You know, you can tell me.
It don't mean a thing about you if he did.
No.
But he did try to?
No. I...
I mean, yes.
Desmond, what's the one thing
I tell you the most?
The one thing.
Be a man.
What?
And how you do that?
-Stand up for yourself.
-No.
You stand up for what is right.
I'd dive down into hell to keep you safe,
but you gotta be straight with me.
Now I'm gonna ask you one last time, okay?
[indistinct chatter]
Wynn.
Excuse me.
-Hi.
-You talk to him?
-Uh-huh.
Did you believe him?
Yes.
What are you gonna do?
All right, if everybody would please
just grab a chair and sit down.
We're just waiting on Jeanette Price
and her son.
[chatter continues]
We can get started now.
It's nice to see all
of you concerned people here tonight.
-I appreciate your support.
-[chatter stops]
We have a lot to talk about tonight.
Desmond Price. Tito Rollins.
Two of our young men
have been accused of a serious crime.
I've had all the charges dropped.
Their names will not appear
on any criminal record.
The root of the problem was
another overreaction by the police force.
At the next council meeting,
I will present a demand
for a Civilian Review Board to investigate
the death of Hollis Washington,
and several other incidents
in the past year.
But more importantly,
more importantly,
we had a fire last night.
Thirteen of our families
were left homeless,
and resulted in the death
of a young woman and her 3-month-old baby.
-[indistinct chatter]
-The city's response to this was pitiful.
Instead of finding temporary shelters
and rehabilitating those apartments,
the city is pushing through a deal
to knock them down and replace them
with a high-income condominium
and a shopping mall.
[groaning]
When they needed our rent,
they jammed us in there,
they didn't turn the heat on,
they didn't collect the garbage,
they didn't provide street lights,
or police protection,
or any of the other services
we should've expected
as residents of this city.
But now, now,
now that they can smell a profit,
they want to burn us out
and plow us under.
[crowd groaning]
They want to drive a wedge
through this community,
cut us up to pieces,
until we dry up and blow away.
See, l know what they're thinking.
I know what they're thinking.
They're thinking that
we are just a bunch of poor people,
a bunch of Black people
and Hispanic people,
people who just got off the boat
and can't get it together down here.
People who don't even know
how to work together.
People who don't care,
people who don't count,
and people who don't even vote.
So I'm gonna ask you right now,
are we gonna prove them right?
No.
Are we gonna lie down and take this?
Are we gonna allow them to push us around,
shut us down, and burn us out?
No.
Well, you know,
just three blocks from here, up the hill,
the mayor and four councilmen
are attending a dinner
to raise funds
for next November's campaign.
[dismayed chatter]
Now, we were not invited.
Now, l think we ought to go up there,
and let the mayor know
just how left out we feel.
-Don't you?
-Yeah.
I think we ought to go up there
and tell the mayor
that if he don't get
his act together real fast,
he's the one who's gonna be left out
of the city hall next election.
-[man 1] All right.
-Let's do it.
-[man 2] Yes, sir.
-[man 3] Right on.
[excited chatter]
-Is everybody behind me?
-They're coming, baby. All of them.
-I hope I've got the address right.
-What are we going to do?
We'll figure that out when we get there.
-[woman] Come on.
-[man] Yeah.
-[rock music playing in bar]
-[crowd clamoring]
I have fought at the municipal level
to provide corporate tax incentives
to lure industry back to our city.
I have fought at the state
and federal levels for funding
to rebuild our roads,
to light our streets,
to keep the police
and firefighting forces up to strength.
But more importantly,
and this I take particular pride in,
I have fought against
the environmental alarmists
and the special interest groups
that would block important developments,
like the Galaxy Tower complex,
which promise to revitalize our economy
and put our city back on the map.
And I intend to keep up this fight.
And with your help,
we will once more
be a city with a future,
a city on the move.
Truly, a city of hope.
[guests applauding]
[indistinct chatter]
I've brought some concerned citizens.
[cheering and whooping]
-They've been looking for you, Mr. Mayor.
-[woman] Yeah, mayor.
You got a minute?
[basketball bouncing]
[Franklin] Little help?
Thanks.
[Nick] Just getting out of work?
No, just going in.
-It's a tough gig, the night shift.
-Yeah.
Ugh! Your hand's messed up.
My life is messed up. This is nothing.
-You play?
-Nah, I suck.
My brother used to try to teach me.
He was the real thing.
All-State guard. Big deal.
Play around here?
Sacred Heart.
Tony Rinaldi.
Oh, snap. Tony the Tiger. Yeah.
I played against that dude.
Sucker was bad.
Fire up those Cazzie Russell jumpers,
no arc, bam, bam, bam.
Kill you with that jump shot.
Where'd he play in college?
Marines got him.
Yeah? He go over?
Uh-huh.
[sighs] l did that.
Infantry.
He make it back okay?
Nah.
Nice ball-handler too.
He was fast for a white guy.
Not fast enough.
Hey, look, l, uh...
I gotta run.
-Take it easy.
-Yeah, you too.
Tony the Tiger.
What a waste.
Why settle for less
when you can have it all?
when you can have it all? Why?
Why settle for less
when you can have it all?
You can have it... Why?
Why? Why settle for less
when you can have it all?
Angela Sabino.
Why settle for less
when you can have it all? You can have it.
Yeah, but she might be out front.
Well, just tell her that I got hung up,
but I'm on my way, all right?
Thanks.
Rinaldi. l got a want on you, punk.
Yeah, stick it up your ass.
-I'm not playing around, asshole.
-Hey!
You don't have your little cop suit on.
[car tires screech]
[tires screech]
[Fuentes] Freeze. Lay it down, pal.
It's me, you fucks. Mike Rizzo.
You're letting that cocksucker get away.
It's all right. He's one of ours.
What's the fireworks for?
Had a suspect try to take my head off.
-Armed?
-He hit me with a fucking garbage pail.
Assault with a deadly trash receptacle.
-[laughing]
-Yeah, fuck you.
Come on, let's get him.
It's that punk, Nick Rinaldi.
We're supposed to pick him up.
-They called the dogs off on that guy.
-What?
He got a clean bill this afternoon.
Where were you?
That piece of yours,
is it private, or on loan from the job?
It's mine.
-You been drinking, Mike?
-What the fuck?
-You didn't hit him, did you?
-He resisted arrest.
He wasn't wanted.
Did you read him the book first?
He's a piece of shit.
-[Paddy] Did you hit him?
-I don't know.
[Paddy sighs]
We could say we were there in time to see,
and then he went after you...
Hey, Paddy, I'm not going for this.
-If this happened to you...
-I'd deserve to get kicked off the force.
Accidents happen, kid.
We gotta close ranks here.
I'm not going for it, period.
You're not gonna back me up?
He's my partner.
What am I gonna do, shoot him?
Paddy, you know me.
You better hand your piece up here, Mike.
Oh, I don't believe this.
I don't believe you fucking guys.
What happens if he dies?
What happens to me?
Mike,
do you believe in a supreme being?
How'd you find me here?
I saw your address in the police report.
What do you want?
I want to talk.
Forget it.
Come on, man.
What?
You won.
Great. You wanna rub it in?
I'm sorry we fucked you up.
Little late for sorry.
I know you're not a faggot.
[sighs]
We got a long way to go, don't we?
Look, l gotta run.
You mind if I hang with you a minute?
It's a free country.
-Where'd you hear that one?
-[laughs]
-You're a teacher, huh?
-Yeah.
What do you teach?
Urban relations.
Yeah? What's that?
[blues music playing]
[music fades]
[clattering]
Who's that?
Nick?
Are you up there?
Riggs told me l might find you here.
I needed a place to rest.
I've been worried about you.
[laughs]
Worried?
Worried about what,
that the cops would pick me up?
Make you look bad in the papers?
I don't know.
You rob a place
that belongs to a family friend.
I mean, what is that?
What, you need money?
You need money, you come to me.
And how do you make your money?
I don't steal it.
No?
I swore this wasn't gonna happen to you.
Not after Tony.
I was gonna look after you.
How?
By chasing me into the Marines,
like you did with him?
They were drunk and they stole a car.
And they hit somebody,
and they left them in the street.
He wasn't a hero, Nick.
He ran away from it.
And he came to me,
and he wanted me to cover for him.
I took him to the station.
Yeah, down to all your pals.
Nick, they would've found out.
They had the woman in the hospital
with a broken back.
And his pal, Carl, in the hospital,
ready to spill his guts.
I did the best l could.
I got Tony a choice.
The service or jail.
Some fucking choice.
You think you get through this life
without making choices like that?
You told him to go.
[sighs]
All my life,
I thought that l was the one in control.
I made sure l had the juice.
I had all the angles.
Jesus.
I'm not in control of a damn thing.
Did you come here to turn me in?
Nobody's after you, Nick.
I took care of that. [chuckles]
How?
I talked to some people and...
You did a favor.
Yeah.
I did a favor.
You had Carl burn down L Street.
Nicky, they were coming after you.
They weren't gonna give you any choices.
Daddy.
Those people, they burned up in there.
I saw when they brought them out,
a girl and a little baby.
I let them do it.
Oh, Jesus Christ.
[Nick groans]
Daddy?
I'm fucked up over here.
-Nick, you're bleeding.
-Daddy.
My life is such a fucking mess.
Hold on, I'll get help.
No, no, no.
Stay with me, please? Stay with me.
Please? Don't leave me here alone.
Okay. All right.
-I'm scared.
-All right.
-Oh, God.
Nick.
Oh, Jesus, it's bad.
No, wait.
Where you going? Where you going?
I'm not going anywhere.
Just breathe easy, okay?
Okay.
-Take it easy.
-Okay.
-Be right back.
-All right.
-Stay here.
[Joe] Help!
Help!
Over here!
Come on, we need help!
Over here, in the building!
Hey, we need help over here!
Hey. Hey, you.
You. Help. Up here.
Up here in the building.
-We need help.
-[Joe] Yeah, help.
-Yeah, help.
Over here. Help. Help.
-We need help over here.
-Help.
-[Joe] Help.
-[Joe] Over here.
-Over here.
-[Joe] In the building.
-In the building.
-[Joe] Help.
-Help.
Help. Over here.
Over here in the building.
Help, help. Help, we need help.
Help, help.
Help, we need help over here.
Over here, over here in the building.
Help, we need help.
Help. Help, we need help.
We need help over here.
Help, we need help over here.
Help in the building. In the building.
Help. We need help.
We need help. We need help.
Help, help.
Help, we need help. Help, we need help.
Help, we need help. Up here.
We need help. Help.
Help, we need help. Help.
Help, we need help.
Up here in the building.
Help. Help, we need help.
Help, help.
Help, help, help.
Help.
Help, help...
["Fearless" playing]
♪ l took a walk along the sea ♪
♪ Lost in thoughts of you and me ♪
♪ Just like the moon ♪
♪ Turning the tide ♪
♪ l feel a pull ♪
♪ From so deep inside ♪
♪ So many questions haunting us ♪
♪ So many doubts attacked our love ♪
♪ Dangerous thoughts ♪
♪ Of what could go wrong ♪
♪ Against the odds we must carry on ♪
♪ Must be strong and fearless ♪
♪ We must be fearless ♪
♪ Oh, counting on help from above ♪
♪ Trusting the power of love ♪
♪ We must be fearless ♪
♪ Fearless, fearless ♪
♪ For so long l was afraid ♪
♪ To step from the shadow of my mistakes ♪
♪ Your love has given me ♪
♪ The courage l need ♪
♪ Together I know
Nothing can stop you and me ♪
♪ If we are fearless ♪
♪ We must be fearless ♪
♪ Oh, counting on help from above ♪
♪ Trusting the power of love ♪
♪ We must be fearless ♪
♪ We must stand in the light
Willing to fight ♪
♪ Whatever may come between us ♪
♪ And be fearless ♪
♪ We must be fearless ♪
♪ Oh, counting on help from above ♪
♪ Trusting the power of love ♪
♪ We must be fearless ♪
♪ Fearless ♪
[song fades]