(dramatic string music)
(seductive saxophone music)
(seductive saxophone music continues)
(truck revs)
- Good morning.
- [All] Good morning.
- Has the director told you anything yet?
- No.
- I didn't think so.
Well, here's the deal.
We've got just enough cash to
get us through the production.
I think.
Uh, the studio's allowing
us to shoot here,
so long as we don't get anyone's way.
All we have to do is pay our
electricity bill every week.
- You mean to tell us we don't get paid?
- You'll get to star in
a major motion picture!
Maybe.
(footsteps pattering)
- Farris. ..
I must see their shoulders!
- Shoulders?
- Exactly.
- Well. ..
Pinky Malloy!
Are you primarily an actor or a boxer?
- Uh, basically a boxer.
- That's great.
Because the character
that you would be playing
is the part of a boxer,
who falls in love with a dance hall girl.
Now, the important thing about this boxer
is that he must personify the meanings
of the words jealousy, of
passion, of love, of tender.. .
- Forget it.
- Well, I really haven't
done anything before.
I’m just looking to break in.
- I can be a 23-year-old actor.
Just this.. don't let this face fool you.
I've done some boxing too.
I didn't get it from
selling Good Humor ice cream
on the street corner.
- Sure, I could play Italian.
- [Farris] Are you Italian in any way?
I mean, do you like pasta?
- Oh, I love pasta.
- Yeah, I never lost a fight, man.
Never lost a fight.
- [Farris] Did you ever win a fight?
- Yeah, I won a. . .
What do you mean? Of course I won a fight.
- [Stanley] So, you think
you can be an actor?
- I can do just about
anything if I want to.
- [Farris] What kind
of theater? What roles?
- Uh, high school.
- What's going. ..
Hey, what are you doing?
- [Stanley] I'm consulting
with my producer.
- Well, if I'm gonna be a part
of this movie, what the hell?
Why don't you talk to me too?
- Thank you very much.
- He's an actor and he's a boxer.
- Farris, get him the fuck outta here
or I'll break your neck.
(Farris laughs)
- My name's Tony.
Look, let me help you guys out, all right?
Listen, I know you've
been sittin' here all day,
you've been looking at all
these other rummies around here.
You want me to help you?
Look, I'm a professional actor,
and I'm also a good fighter.
- Yeah, I have worked
in a couple of movies.
No big named people, mostly college stuff.
You know, they like
people that look like me.
- Farris, why is he
wearing a goddamn shirt?
- Stanley, for God's sake,
this is Esteban Molinas.
- I've seen you fight.
You were good.
- For a couple of years,
I was really good.
14 and 1 .
But it wasn't in my heart.
I did it for the money.
- There's no money in this.
- You know, I grew up in the streets.
I learned to fight 'cause
I had to defend myself.
Once you live like that,
you have to live inside yourself.
You have to have so much control.
In acting, you can be anything you want,
you can feel anything you want,
you could express yourself.
Yeah. Acting makes me happy.
- Are you available tomorrow?
- Tomorrow? Uh.. what's tomorrow?
- [Farris] Thursday.
- Come back.
I think I may have something for you.
- Stevie Blake.
- Do you have an appointment?
- Give me a break, huh?
- Mhm.
- What have you done?
- What have I done?
What have I done? Are you kidding me?
Don't you know who I am?
- No.
- Well, it's who you can be that counts.
And I can be anything you want.
Anything.
- Ask him if he can be a boxer.
- Could YOU be a boxer?
- I could've been a contender.
I could've been a contender.
- This guy doesn't look like a boxer.
He doesn't even look like an actor.
- Precisely, Farris.
Ask him where he's from.
- Where are you from?
- New York.
Where do you think, Paris?
Farris?
- Ask him what he thinks of blondes.
- What do you?
- You know what they say. ..
- No.
- If you've got one life to
live, live it with a blonde.
- Nooo!
It's "If you've got one
life to live, live it-"
- Is she on the set?
- Should be.
(mellow seductive jazzy music)
(mellow seductive jazzy music continues)
- Carol Redding, Steven Blake.
Carol is playing Betty.
(soft string music)
- [Stevie] Hi, gorgeous.
- He's been watching her through
the window for two years.
He's been watching her dress,
he's been watching her undress.
He knows her apartment
like he knows his own.
He even knows where she puts her lipstick.
But he's never spoken to her.
One night, he's lying in bed.
He's tossing, he's
turning, he can't sleep.
Suddenly, from across the courtyard. ..
(Stanley screams)
Who is it?
It's the girl from across the courtyard.
- The one he's been
watching for two years.
Carol's role.
- Cut to the young boxer.
He looks across, there's a man in a room.
He runs to the door, down
the hall, the man hides.
- Ms. Stein?
- [Stein] Yes, Mr. Silva?
- [Frank] You get it?
- [Stein] Yes, Mr. Silva.
- Bring it in.
- He gets to her door. ..
(phone rings)
- Yeah.
If you're nervous, you
shouldn't borrow money.
Forget it.
(phone thuds)
No second chances.
- He gets to her door, the
door behind which lives. ..
Betty.
Carol, right?
He kicks it in!
(door thuds)
The girl is by the window, about to faint.
He catches her as she falls,
and he lays her on a small, iron bed.
He brushes a strand of blonde
hair away from one eye.
She's woken up.
She's looking at him as
if from a long way off.
"What's the matter?"
This will kill you.
She looks at him. Trying to focus, huh?
And she says one word to him.
What does she say?
Jealousy.
- Jealousy!
- Okay, fellas. ls that it?
I got work to do here.
- Is that it?
Jesus Christ, it's just the beginning.
They've only just met.
- Do you want a receipt?
- Send it.
We'll do this week by week.
Listen, she's been very depressed.
Make her happy.
That's all I want, you understand?
- Believe me, we'll take care of that.
Big talent, and a nice person too.
Don't you worry about a thing.
(door thuds)
(Frank laughs)
- Do I look like the worrying type?
- We got it, we got it!
- Yeah, week by week, that asshole.
(soft string music)
- [Farris] He changed his mind again.
He said to put a dressing
room on the stage.
- [Stanley] We don't have enough money
for him to change his mind.
- [Farris] You wanna tell him that?
(soft dramatic music)
(soft dramatic music continues)
(people chattering)
(people laughing)
Redding and Blake!
On stage immediately.
(soft dramatic music continues)
(Farris claps)
Okay, everybody.
It's our first day, everybody's nervous,
but we're all professionals.
So.. .
Let's go.
- Last night, you heard her scream,
and you ran over, and you calmed her down.
You took care of her.
She was like a child.
This morning, she's grateful.
She's an adult, meaning cynical.
(people laughing)
Farris, can we have
quiet on the set, please?
- Quiet, please!
Quiet on the set.
- Well, and then I came to New York.
I was lonely and...
Well, you know.
- A long pause here.
- I took a job in a dance hall.
I like to dance.
- Play with the glass, on the table.
- And then of course, I met Mr. Scandelli,
who owns the dance hall.
- Is that the guy from last night?
- I-
- You give him a look, and then look away.
- At first, he was so nice.
So kind.
But then he. ..
- Don't overdo it.
- Then he wanted more than
I was willing to give.
- Good, Blake.
- What's your story?
- Well, I kinda don't have one.
I was a boxer, until yesterday.
Now.. .
Now I’m thinkin'...
Maybe I'll go back to Iowa.
- Don't indicate.
- Now I’m thinking, maybe
I’ll go back to Iowa.
- Good.
- D-d-depends.
(Carol laughs)
- Ms. Redding!
- Iowa?
Depends on what?
- Okay.
Let's do it again.
Only this time, let's talk to each other.
All right?
Farris, get the lights set, please.
- Gentlemen, ladies, get moving.
- Well, and then I came to New York.
I was lonely and...
Well, you know.
I took a job in a dance hall.
- Mmh.
- I like to dance.
And then of course, I met Mr. Scandelli,
who owns the dance hall.
- Is that the guy from last night?
- At first he was so nice, so kind.
But then he-
- Lean closer, Blake!
- It's okay.
- Oh, you touched her hand.
That's good.. .
Uh, keep that.
You need to let more happen to you.
- At first, he was so nice, so kind.
But then he. ..
Then he wanted more than
I was willing to give.
What's your story?
(soft sentimental score begins)
- I kinda don't have one.
I was a boxer.
You know, 'til the other day.
Now?
Now I'm thinking. ..
Maybe I'll go back to Iowa.
Depends.
- Iowa?
- Yeah.
- Depends on what?
- Okay, let's go for a take.
(sensual saxophone music)
- Well, and then I came to New York.
I was lonely and...
Well, you know.
I took a job in a dance hall.
I like to dance.
And then of course, I met Mr. Scandelli,
who owns the dance hall.
- Is that the guy from last night?
- At first he was so nice, so kind.
But then he. ..
Then he wanted more than
I was willing to give.
(soft saxophone music continues)
What's your story?
- I kinda don't have one.
I was a boxer, until yesterday.
Now.. .
I’m thinking of going back to lowa.
Depends.
- Iowa?
Depends on what?
(soft saxophone music continues)
(saxophone music fading)
- Cut!
Ms. Redding, you're not the director
of this motion picture, I am.
And your job is to stay in character
until you hear me, and only me, say "Cut".
ls that understood?
- Hey, there you are.
- Yes, here I am.
- Hey, listen.
Could happen to anybody.
It's not a big deal.
- Thanks, but no thanks.
I loused up.
- Well, you know what they say.
- Who?
I'm sorry. What do they say?
- That it's lucky to have a bad first day.
- Do they really say that?
- Sure.
'Cause it can only get better.
Let's go for a walk around
the lot, do something.
It's beautiful out, c'mon.
- You're crazy. I'm going
home and get some sleep.
I'm beat.
- Hey.
You were good.
- Was I?
- Better than good.
- Good night.
(soft music)
- [Stanley] Nice girl.
- Could be.
- Don't be too cautious.
Emotionally she's a child,
on the verge of becoming a woman.
- When she does, she's
gonna be a great actress.
Great.
(Stanley sighs)
She may need a little help.
(soft music continues)
(car engine revs)
- Frank!
I think I was good. I
really think I was good!
- Really?
- Yeah!
- Yeah.
- You're very late.
- Oh, what time is it?
- It's nine o'clock.
- Nine o'clock?
- Shoot!
I better get to bed. I
got a six o'clock call.
- In the morning?
- That's show business.
(soft music continues)
- Show business.
- I gotta talk to you, Billy.
Do it.
Do it, do what he says.
I gotta talk to you, Billy.
Do it, do it.
Do what he says.
Gotta do it.
Do what he says-
- Hey, what are you doin'?
- Learning my lines.
- Oh.
Well then, there's two things you gotta do
before you go to bed each night.
You gotta go through
your lines five times.
By the morning. ..
(Stevie snaps)
You'll know 'em like your own.
- And the second thing?
- You have to think about me.
(Carol chuckles)
Come on, let's go.
(people faintly shouting)
(bag thuds)
- Okay, come on.
Let's go.
That's it.
There.
Keep your hands up.
(bag thuds)
Hey, come on.
Let's go.
Stick the left hand.
(bag thuds)
Good.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
(glove thuds)
Okay, okay.
Good.
How you feelin'?
- I feel all right.
- Okay.
Just keep the elbows in.
- Yeah. Give it to me.
- Forget it. Don't drop
the left hand, huh?
- I won't drop the left hand. It'll be up.
- Okay, now remember, this
guy's got a glass jaw.
One pop on the chin, and
we go home early, huh?
- I'm gonna uppercut him to death.
Don't worry.
- Yeah.
- I gotta talk to you, Billy. I gotta.
Do it, do it.
You gotta do it. Do what he says.
- I know why he wants
me to throw the fight.
It's 'cause of you.
But you're more important
to me than he is.
- Cut.
Farris, didn't it ever occur to you
that the manager wouldn't be here?
- I didn't write the script,
you wanted him there.
- Esteban.
Ven aqui.
We'll take it from where
you enter, Ms. Redding.
Blake, you're alone now.
It's five minutes to fight time.
First positions!
- Roll sound.
- We have speed.
- Roll camera.
- Rolling.
Scene 8, take 2.
Marker.
(marker claps)
(water splashes)
- How is it?
- A little chilly.
- No, the movie. How's the movie?
- You get there in the morning,
and next thing you know,
it's time to go home.
So exciting.
And you do a scene good,
and everything seems right.
(Frank chuckles)
- And the director, how's he doing?
- Well, we have to work on Saturday.
We're a day behind.
But he's clever, I think.
- He better be clever.
I gave him a lot of my money.
- I do know.
And I do appreciate it.
- And the kid.
What about the kid?
- What about him?
(soft string music)
(Carol groans)
Frank!
Let go.
(soft string music continues)
- [Frank] Get out.
(water splashes)
- I just hate to leave this place.
Every night, it's like saying
goodnight to a sweetheart.
- Yeah.
Hey.
- It's only me.
- [Guard] I want you to
meet a friend of mine.
- Hi. How's the coffee biz?
- Okay.
- Oh, I gotta go.
See ya later, man.
Goodnight, Shirley.
- Goodnight.
- Goodnight, kid.
Nice boy.
Actor.
Mm.
(faint upbeat radio music)
Good guy for you to know.
- I never know what to say.
- You know, Shirley...
People have time for people like you,
if you want them to.
Don't be so. .. so bashful.
Don't hide it.
I got nothing to hide.
- Oh, Shirley!
(Carol laughs)
("Sh-Boom" by The Chords)
(Shirley laughs)
♪ Oh, life could be a dream ♪
♪ Sh-boom, if I could take
you to a paradise up above ♪
♪ Sh-boom, tell me darling ♪
♪ I'm the only one that you love ♪
♪ Life could be a dream ♪
♪ Sweetheart, hello, hello again ♪
♪ Sh-boom and hopin' we'll meet again ♪
♪ Oh, life could be a dream ♪
♪ Life could be a dream ♪
♪ Do-roo-do-do, sh-boom ♪
- Liverwurst on Wonder Bread, please.
- Everybody's done something
they're ashamed of.
Everybody's got a past.
- I know.
But it's hard for a girl
to get her pride back out.
- It's not what you've
done, or what you've been,
it's what you can become, aah, Betty.
Believe in us.
- I do. I do.
- We're back on stage in half an hour.
Half an hour, 30 minutes.
- 1 800 seconds.
- That's exactly 1 800
seconds, Ms. Redding.
And not a second more.
(people laughing)
(footsteps tapping)
- [Stanley] I've got it, Farris.
It's been bothering me all week.
The dance hall owner.
- Something's been bothering me too-
- Wait!
The dance hall owner.
When he asked the boxer
to throw the fight, huh?
The symbolic fight,
which he is not going to throw after all,
because he loves the girl.
- Does Blake know where we
got the cash for this film?
Does he know about Carol and Silva?
- Heat.
Heat!
There must be heat between them.
If they're hot, the audience is hot.
If the audience is hot,
finally we make some money, huh?
Please, don't tell tales outta school.
I want an alley for a scene
between the dance hall
owner and the boxer.
And then afterwards, we
can use it for the capture.
- What? I don't understand.
- An alley, a small alley.
It's simple.
- Where is this alley?
- Build one!
- My dear Stanley, alleys are expensive.
- Sit down, Farris.
We're working very hard, huh?
And we finished one week's
filming, and we have more.
Now, I hope that the money is in order.
- I called yesterday,
and he said he'd bring it here
Monday morning first thing.
- Good.
You are doing your job.
Except for one thing.
- What's that?
- Under no circumstances
do I ever eat liverwurst.
(Stanley spits)
- Hi, Big Louie.
(mellow jazzy music)
Hey, Mark.
Hi, Jeff.
You owe me a week's
pay, and I want it now.
- Where are you gonna go?
What are you gonna do?
- I'm going to Iowa.
The air is better up there.
- Betty, you and me.
We had a plan, we-
- You and me? Hah!
You're an old man, your hair is greasy,
you've got a hunchback and you smell.
- Get outta here!
Get outta here, before I. . .
Get outta my sight!
Get out! Get out!
- Nothing would make me
happier, but I ain't go nowhere
till you give me the money you owe me!
- Betty, don't say anything.
I'm begging you not.
Please, I always hurt the ones I love.
Please don't let it happen again.
Please!
(Scandelli sobs)
(mellow jazzy music continues)
- I'd rather be poor.
- I'm gonna kill you!
I'm gonna kill you!
(mellow jazzy music continues)
- You get the money?
You didn't get the money?
- He's crazy.
- Is in there?
Is he still in there?
- He's crazy.
- I’m gonna go and get it myself.
Is he still in there?
- You can't go in there, he's-
- What are we gonna do?
- I don't know.
- Do you have any money?
I don't have any money.
- Oh, Billy.
- Betty.
- Cut!
Thank you very much, ladies and gentlemen.
Not bad.
Now tomorrow we're going
to go back and do the scene
where you go in there after your money.
He's a sadist.
Remember that.
He's already hit you in the mouth once.
But he's got your money, and
you think that you can get it,
because you have such a
strong sexual hold over him.
You think that sex is a more
powerful force than pride.
Good night.
- Uh, Stanley.
Um, don't you think that
Scandelli's acting was a bit,
you know, excessive?
- No.
(Farris sighs)
- It's a wrap.
(Farris claps)
- So why did you give it up for?
- I just got tired of beating heads in
for a living, you know?
People watching and
screaming night after night.
I hated it.
- Sure. I can understand.
God. . .
She is so beautiful.
- Hey, stay cool, huh?
- Yeah, I'm cool, but.. .
She's just so beautiful.
- Hey, listen.
Don't sleep where you eat, kid.
(apple crunches)
(projector clicking)
- [Stanley] "Strange and Dangerous".
Scene 826, take two.
Marker.
(clapperboard clacks)
Action!
- Everybody's got a past.
Everybody's got something
they're ashamed of.
- I know.
But it's hard for a girl to
get her pride back after,
You know?
- It's not what you've done.
It's not who you've been.
It's what you can become.
Oh, Betty...
(projector clicks)
Believe in us.
Hey, I've been lookin' for you.
I just couldn't let you
leave without telling ya. ..
You were really beautiful
in that dance hall sequence tonight.
- Well, I don't know about that, but. ..
When I came out, and you
were among the dancers,
that look you gave me was such a help.
It's very difficult because. . .
I don't know if my
character is supposed to be
good or bad or what.
- Yeah, but I like that.
- Well, so do I.
I think she's both.
I think she does love you,
but her shame holds her back.
- Yeah.
- When she sees you, she loves you though.
And that's why that look
you gave me was such a help.
- Well, with you, it's easy.
(Stevie chuckles)
- Hold this for a sec, will you?
- I’ve been admiring your car here.
I’ve never even driven in a car like this.
- No?
- [Stevie] Well, where ya goin'?
(engine revs)
- Home. I'm beat.
- I guess that's it.
- Good night.
(engine sputters)
- Hey, Carol!
You forgot your script!
Shit.
- Mm. Very good.
(mellow music)
Did you put something in it?
- Vodka.
- Did you?
- Yeah.
- I hate it.
(Carol laughs)
(Frank laughing)
(soft jazz music)
- What do you think?
What do you guys think?
Should I call her?
Pretty flimsy excuse, huh?
She might need it.
(siren faintly blares)
Yeah, I guess you're right.
I'll give it a shot.
(mellow piano music)
(phone rings)
- Who is that?
(phone continues ringing)
- Hello?
(phone clicks)
(mellow piano music continues)
If a man answers, hang up.
Right?
(change clatters)
Did I tell you about a new building today?
- No.
- Duplex.
(phone rings)
On Willowby.
Mm.
(phone continues ringing)
- Hello?
(mellow piano music continues)
Hello?
(phone clicks)
(phone clacks)
(mellow piano music continues)
Two units.
Two bedrooms upstairs.
(phone rings)
(phone continues ringing)
(soft dramatic music)
(chairs clattering)
(dramatic music)
(intense piercing music swells)
- Hey, gorgeous.
- Hey.
- Sleep well?
- Okay. You?
- Nah, I counted sheep all night. Here.
- Thanks.
- I tried to call you last night, but-
- So it was you.
- I'm sorry, but I thought
you might need your script.
- That's a private number!
- Go ahead, baby. Get outta here.
I'll keep him busy for a while.
Don't worry about me.
- I can't. I can't.
I won't.
- How did I ever fall for a dame like you?
- Cut!
Jesus Christ.
How much do you two really
know about each other, hm?
How much?
- What do you mean?
- I mean that this scene requires love.
You give me love!
You do it again, and you do it right!
Right away.
Right away!
Go, go.
- [Speaker] Rolling.
- [Stanley] Action.
(door clatters)
- Go ahead, baby.
Get outta here. Get outta here!
I'll keep him busy for a while.
Don't worry about me. Go!
- I can't. I can't.
I won't!
- How did I ever fall for a dame like you?
- Cut.
Okay.
Ms. Redding, I want a word with you.
Farris, prepare the boxing sequence.
I want the low angles.
- My left is so solid.
But my right is, I don't know.
- Listen, you gotta feel it.
Power is in the heart.
- Yeah, I know, but how
do I get it in the arm?
(bag thuds)
- Put it in the ring.
Ready to shoot in, uh.. .
One minute.
- [Stanley] Okay, Esteban.
Show me what you've done.
- [Esteban] Okay.
The first one looks like
he's gonna lose, right?
- [Stanley] Yeah.
- It looks like he's allowing
himself to be hit on purpose.
Okay.
Well, here's the sequence.
You lead off, right?
Remember.
Okay, let's do it.
One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven.
- [Stanley] Okay, fine, fine.
Now do it again.
Wait a minute.
Okay, do it again.
Action.
- One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven.
(Stevie grunts)
- Okay.
All right.
Let's go for one now, all right?
For real.
I want some good, hard blows.
You understand?
Hard, hard.
Do not hurt his face.
Got it?
- Yeah, I got it.
- Stevie, give it to him with some power.
One more thing.
Try not to step on my face.
All right?
And action!
Oh, cut.
Cut.
What is it with you, Blake?
I want you to be tender,
you look like a killer.
I want you to be a boxer,
you look like a baby.
Do it again.
Right away, please.
- Rolling!
- And. ..
Action!
(gloves thudding)
Cut!
Reload.
- [Farris] Reload.
- Thanks a lot, Blake.
Thank you.
(soft string music)
- How's it going?
- Badly.
You can go home, Ms. Redding.
- Mind if I stay?
- Suit yourself.
(soft string music continues)
- All right.
Right away, please.
Here we go.
Action.
(gloves thudding)
Oh, cut!
You guys, back to your corners.
Esteban, come here.
Esteban, you're not doing your job.
This is not what I call fighting, hm?
I hired you as the fight arranger,
I gave you a part in my movie.
No fight.
Broken promises.
I’m very unhappy.
- Want them fired up, huh?
- Quite so.
- So why do they call you Tony "The Rose"?
'Cause after every fight, I
still smell sweet, you know?
- Like her?
- Like that.
- Looks like you got some competition.
- Okay. Right away, please.
Quiet on the set.
- [Farris] Rolling!
- And action!
Oh, that's great.
Great!
(gloves thudding)
Are you writing scripts or what?
In my script, he knocks you out!
- This picture could be so good.
We could become like Bogart and Bacall,
like Tracy and Hepburn.
- Well, who knows?
Who knows?
It's a lovely thought, anyhow.
- Well, anything's possible.
- Sure.
You should've seen his face.
- Whose?
- Our director's when
you decked the other guy.
- That was nothing.
- What's the matter?
- Nothin'.
- Yes, there is. I can tell.
- You can?
- Yes, I can.
- Hey, well, that's the way
it should be between us.
- What do you mean?
- That's the way it should be.
I mean, for the work.
We should have some kind of understanding.
You know, rapport.
- What's rapport?
- That's something without words.
That's the way I see Billy and Betty.
That's why they fall in love so quickly.
Haven't you ever had that?
- I don't know.
- Well, I had it once.
I met this girl.
That night, she was living with me.
She stayed two years.
And then...
(Stevie snaps)
She was gone.
Never even said goodbye.
What's the matter?
- Nothin'.
- Yes, there is. I can tell.
- There is nothing the matter.
Do you know how I can tell?
You and me.
We have rapport.
(soft saxophone music)
- I know.
You put the idea in my head!
He doesn't mean anything to me!
He's a nobody! I love you!
You know what I want, I want you.
(Scandelli grunts)
I want you, and kids, and a family. ..
- What you taking me for, Betty?
A 14 carat idiot, or what?
- She's so good at fear, so bad at love.
(Scandelli yells)
- [Carol] He doesn't mean anything to me!
- What am I gonna do about that?
(Scandelli grunts)
- What are you taking me for?
What are you taking me for? An idiot?
(dramatic string music)
Or what?
- Hey, I really miss ya.
Carol?
I never see you.
Goddamn it, I'm talking to you!
(Carol sighs)
Are you behaving yourself?
- Oh, Frank, please
don't start that again.
(door slams)
- [Reporter] Good morning.
This is Dick Whittingham
with our daily story record.
After this, we give all
kinds of prizes away,
with a chance to win. . .
- Why are you always depressed these days?
How do you think it makes me feel?
(chair clatters)
- Here.
Maybe this will make you feel better.
(cash clatters)
(mellow music)
(mellow music continues)
- [Woman] Oh, please don't!
No, don't throw us out!
No, no, no!
- [Frank] Come on!
(woman shrieks)
(Frank grunts)
(mellow music)
- Hi.
- Hi!
- How about a kiss, baby?
(mellow music continues)
- All right, now this is THE kiss.
Up until now, you've
resisted the attraction.
But now all pretense, all
resistance has evaporated.
You are fleshy magnets.
And make me believe it.
Make us believe it.
Make Scandelli believe it.
All right?
Action.
(sensual saxophone music)
Blake, where's your shirt?
Blake, cut.
Blake.
Blake!
Where is your shirt?
- Excuse me?
- Where is your shirt?
- Oh, oh.
(Carol laughs)
I'm sorry, I forgot.
- Get a shirt, please.
- Don't you like my pecs?
- Get a shirt!
Raise the camera higher, would you?
All right, action.
No, cut.
Haven't you ever been in love?
Try it again.
Please.
Action.
No, no, no.
(Carol laughs)
Cut.
Hold her face gently.
(Carol laughs)
Tenderly, you imbecile!
- You can't get to me by
calling me an imbecile.
- Right. Thank you.
Action.
- Can I ask you one question?
Should I use my tongue?
- [Stanley] Ask her that.
- No, I don't wanna do anything with-
- [Stanley] Don't use your
tongue, we can't see it.
- I never thought of that.
- And we don't know where it's been.
So if you'll please just.. .
(person laughs)
(Stevie chuckles)
Now reverse sides, change sides.
Thank you.
Action.
Let her...
Okay.
Other way with the nose.
I realize there's a lot of it.
- Other way with the nose?
- [Stanley] Yes, on her left
cheek, as opposed to obscuring-
- Like this?
- [Stanley] Mr. Blake, it
is funny, we're all tired,
but you're hiding her face.
Carol, don't let him hide your face.
- I got it.
So you want my nose on this side,
so I don't block with my nose.
Like this.
- Farris. Where's Farris?
Okay, stop.
Okay. Change frame.
- Like this?
- Right. Better.
- [Stanley] Okay, change
your heads around,
so your head is toward camera.
- Hm?
- [Stanley] No, no, no!
Turn your lips to the other side.
(Stanley laughs)
- I'm sorry, but-
- Come on, face 90 degrees to the camera.
- Can I. ..
Okay.
- [Stanley] Can you kiss
turning your head the other way?
The other way.
Right.
No, no, other way, sorry.
You're blocking her from the camera.
Could I touch her breasts?
(crew laughing)
- [Stanley] No, you can't.
Please, Blake.
(crew laughing)
Quiet, everybody.
- Hey, would you look at that?
Real life.
(dog barks)
- I can't stand him.
- [Stevie] Who?
- Our director is so manipulative.
- I wish you'd stay with me tonight.
- Oh, Stevie.
- Somebody else?
- Maybe.
- Guy who answered the phone?
- Don't wanna talk about it.
- Maybe I wanna talk about it.
- Dunno what to say.
I wish this picture would never end.
- $2,271 and 52 cents.
$2,299 and 99 cents.
$3,324 and 31 cents.
$3,999 and 44 cents.
- Is she married?
- Wait.
- $2,271 and 52 cents.
$2,299 and 99 cents.
$3,324 and 31 cents.
4,000...
ls who married, Blake?
- Carol.
Is she married?
- I don't think that's
any of your business.
- [Stanley] Goddamn it!
Damn it! Damn it!
I cannot understand why you can't get
anything done in this country.
- [Farris] What's the problem this time?
- [Stanley] Catholics!
Monday is some goddamn Catholic holiday!
So they can print our stuff tonight,
but they can't release it until Tuesday.
Which means that we-
- So do it on Tuesday.
- Farris, I've had a brilliant idea.
I'll view it on Tuesday.
Blake, what are you doing here?
- Asking questions about Carol.
- Excellent.
Good.
Blake, go home and get some rest.
Tomorrow we're gonna do the chase sequence
with you and Scandelli.
No Carol.
(soft string music)
(dramatic string music)
(birds faintly chirping)
(dramatic string music continues)
(speed bag clatters)
- No money, no light.
That's the rule.
(speed bag clatters)
- Blake!
Stop it!
(speed bag clatters)
(tense music)
Go talk to him.
(footsteps pattering)
(tense music continues)
- Does Stevie know what's going on?
- Certainly not.
- Good.
It will come.
It's just-
- Sure.
(tense music fades)
(straps clacking)
(bell jingles)
(phone rings)
- Hello?
Yes, we'll have someone right away.
The money's here! It's at the gate!
- All right!
(Stanley claps)
Back to work, everybody.
Blake!
Get down here instantly.
Farris, call Ms. Redding!
I'd like to do a walk by.
I'd like this to be a
first date improvisation.
Thank you.
Eventually Scandelli and his
folks are gonna be in this car.
Ms. Redding?
Ms. Redding, you don't
wanna look in the car.
- Hello?
- [Frank] Hello.
- Can I help you?
- [Frank] May I speak
with Ms. Redding, please?
- Hold on.
- Now you're coming down the street. ..
No, no, no.
You and Carol are on your first date.
And you're just gonna
be walking by the car.
- There's someone on the
phone for Ms. Redding.
- She's busy.
Could you take a message?
- Okay.
- Save it for the reel.
You guys are just overjoyed
to be out with each other.
Something. . .
Okay?
You're not gonna see that.
You're not.
(Stevie and Stanley chattering)
- Hello?
- [Frank] Carol?
- No, it's me again. She's busy.
Give me a number and I'll-
- [Frank] Who are you?
- Nobody.
- [Frank] Well, listen
to me, I'm Frank Silva.
I put up the money for this show.
(soft saxophone music)
(Stanley chattering)
- It's Frank Silva.
He says he wants-
- Wait.
Just wait.
Stanley.
It's Silva on the phone for Carol.
Uh, the waitress heard.
- She heard?
- Yeah, she picked up the phone.
(Stanley clears throat)
- Okay.
Get Carol to take the call,
and I'll talk to the girl.
Hello.
- Hello.
I'm Stanley. I’m the director.
- Hi, Stanley.
- What's your name?
- Shirley.
- [Stanley] Shirley, you're very lovely.
- [Shirley] Thank you.
- Hello.
- Carol?
- Yes.
(Frank sighs)
- I'm sorry.
- You should be. You just
stopped the whole show.
- About this morning.
- Give me some air, Frank.
Let me breathe.
I gotta get back to work.
They're all looking at me.
- You're interested in films?
- Mm.
Mhm.
- Hm.
Did it ever occur to you
that you could be in films?
- Well, I always kind of wanted to.
- Did you?
- I dunno if I can.
- You can.
- We're very busy, Frank.
(Frank sighs)
- Well. ..
- Goodbye.
- Bye.
(phone clatters)
(soft music)
- [Carol] I thought it went well tonight.
- [Stevie] For you.
(Carol chuckles)
- You're always saying that, "For me."
What about you?
- Eh, you know.
I'll say it for you, you say it for me.
(Carol chuckles)
- Mm, fresh air.
Ah.
You know, every evening
I stay in costume longer.
(soft music continues)
- It's almost over, kid.
- Let's go and sit over there.
(soft music continues)
- [Stanley] Cut.
Start it over, please.
You were fine, Ms. Redding.
- [Carol] I wonder why
he always wears black.
- [Stevie] Mourning for his life.
- [Carol] Huh?
- That's a Chekhov play, "The Seagull".
You read that?
- [Carol] You're smart.
Read things, and people like
you, and you make 'em laugh.
- [Stevie] Well, I'm an actor.
I'm a faker, you know.
- [Carol] Yeah, but I can't do that.
- [Stevie] People know who I am.
They know where I come from.
Nobody knows anything about you,
so it's kinda hard for
them to be friendly.
- [Carol] Mm.
- [Stevie] Same with the director.
I mean, I don't know
anything about him either.
- Do you think he lives with Farris?
(Carol chuckles)
- I don't think he lives
any place but here.
I think when he's gone
from here, he's, um...
.. .he's like a wino without his wine.
He has to drink us to feel good.
- [Carol] ls it always like this?
I mean, every time you make a movie?
- [Stevie] Movies are like dreams.
There's no rules.
- [Carol] And when it's over?
- [Stevie] Sometimes
you don't wanna wake up,
and see yourself as you really are.
I guess it depends who you're playing,
who's playing your role.
Anyway, I'll tell you something.
It's been fun working with
you, getting to know you.
- [Carol] Yeah.
- And I'll be damned if. . .
I'm gonna let some fun in my life end,
just 'cause the movie's gonna end.
(soft music continues)
- Yeah.
- Carol?
- Who's that?
Kiss her properly, we can't fake this!
Okay, now the other way.
Try again.
Blake, cut, Blake!
- You want me to get started,
then you want me to stop.
When I’m kissing her, it's hard to stop.
- [Stanley] I understand.
- Okay. I’m just apologizing.
Okay.
(soft music continues)
- Who is it?
Carol, don't.. .
You're not being raped, darling.
Return the attention.
Damn.
- Thank God we're almost finished.
(flowers thudding)
(soft music continues)
(phone rings)
(papers thwacking)
- Yes.
Oh, hello, Mr. Silva.
How are you?
But of cour.. .
Certainly, that's no problem.
Unfortunately, he's not
here right now, but...
Oh, I can come over right away.
No problem, Mr. Silva.
- I'm worried.
- [Farris] Oh?
- I'm worried about my investment.
- Well, really, there
is no need for concern.
(phone faintly rings)
- That's all.
By the way...
My cousin Jimmy wanted to know,
could he come down and maybe
watch a couple days filming?
- I gotta talk to you. This is serious.
- I cut it this way, I cut it that way,
it doesn't work, the alley is shit.
- I just spoke to Silva, he's crazy.
You better go talk to your boxer.
- See, he uses her for bait.
They don't get caught together.
The boxer follows her down
here to the warehouse.
- [Farris] He's a very dangerous man.
- That's right. He's a very dangerous man.
- Jesus Christ, Stanley!
This is life I'm talkin' about!
He's putting one of his
goddamn goons on the set!
- And I'm trying to make a movie
about a man and a woman
in love, and I want heat!
- And you don't care
how you do it, do you?
- Jesus Christ! I’m trying to work!
- Oh, Sidney, I'm sorry.
(dramatic string music)
- No, you're not.
(dramatic string music continues)
- We're almost at the
end of your relationship.
After this, it's all chase and violence.
You've decided to leave New York together.
You're meeting to discuss the last details
in the courtyard of the tenement.
Carol, you are afraid.
You are very afraid.
You know Scandelli.
And as you talk, and as
you kiss before you part,
you are aware.
You are very aware.
Maybe he's watching you.
Maybe he's up there,
spying on the two of you.
Carol, are you listening to me?
- Yeah.
(soft saxophone music)
- First positions.
Roll it.
- [Crew] We have speed.
- [Crew] "Strange and
Dangerous", scene 67, take one.
Mark.
(clapperboard clacks)
- Action.
- Meet me at the station.
- Five o'clock, I'll be there.
I love you.
- Don't go, not yet.
- I love you, but we must hurry.
- Cut.
Very good, Carol.
Very good.
We're done with you two for today.
Everyone else take 1 0.
- You ever notice how he
never mentions me anymore?
I mean, it's always...
"Very good, Carol.
Excellent, Carol."
Then. ..
"Oh, thank you Stevie. Goodnight."
(Carol chuckles)
- He knows you've got more
confidence, that's all.
- Oh, it goes quick, you know.
Everything goes quick.
Let's get a drink. Come on.
- Maybe tomorrow.
- Why maybe?
- Good night, Stevie.
- Oh, Shirley.
I'd really like to speak to
you for one second. Could I?
Just for one second.
Come over here.
Look, I know you know, and
obviously I need to know.
So, where does she go at nights?
- Home, I expect.
- Well then, who called
her up the other day?
- I've been told not to tell you anything.
- Who told you?
- Director.
- Why?
- I don't know.
- Well, if you don't know,
obviously it doesn't
make any sense to you.
So why don't you just tell me?
- He told me not to.
- So what?
- Well, I gave him my word.
- What's it to you, Shirley?
What, he promise you a big part
in his next movie or something?
- Uh huh.
Said I was a natural.
- Probably are.
- I'm sorry.
- I think you got it wrong, boss.
I don't think nothing's happening at all.
Actors, the whole crowd.
They're too fuckin' busy
with the junk they're making
to have time for anything else.
And if the boy is having
an affair with anyone,
my money's on a waitress down there.
- Stay with it.
- Do I have to?
- I wanna know.
(insects faintly chirping)
- You're late.
- I'm late?
- Have you eaten?
- Yeah.
- In case you're interested,
I'm doing my last scenes tomorrow.
- Tomorrow?
- Tomorrow night.
- Why?
- I don't know.
Suddenly decided he had
enough to make a movie.
(chair clatters)
- Hi.
Listen, when the movie ends...
Do we end?
Please, Carol.
- [Crew] Redding and Blake!
Redding and Blake.
On stage immediately.
- After work.
- You wanna come back to my place?
- No, let's talk here.
- [Stevie] Here on the set?
- Well, somewhere.
- Your place or mine?
- Mine, okay?
- Okay.
(soft dramatic music)
(change clatters)
(rotary clicks)
- "For six months, she
was petted and spoiled.
For the rest of the year, she
was thwarted and neglected.
With such discrepancy
determined, inevitably,
her whole outlook upon life.
The conditions of her own home,
refined and comfortable though it was,
became repugnant to her.
It was only the other life.
The gay, sunny, butterfly
life that was tolerable."
What do you think?
- [Stevie] I don't understand
- What's to understand?
I was reading last night, and
I got an idea about Betty.
- Oh.
Oh, Scandelli.
The dance hall.
It's the last day, I'm forgetting.
Plus, I can't concentrate.
This guy's always. ..
Farris.
- Farris.
Poor, maligned Farris.
You are appreciated, Farris.
And action!
(soft music)
All right, focus.
Second bar, come into it.
Cutting right to the end.. .
Leaving. . .
Blake, long look.
Stay put.
And out the door, catch
her, and out, and cut.
(soft music continues)
Cut, print it.
That's a wrap.
(crew clapping)
- [Farris] Ta-dah!
- [Stanley] What's this? Hey hey!
- [Crew] Thank you very much.
(cork pops)
♪ Nobody ♪
♪ Loves me with you ♪
♪ You may not know ♪
- What I wanted to tell you is. ..
It's not easy. I'm not
a very strong person.
(soft soul music)
- You wanted to know.
(Jimmy sighs)
Hell of a target.
♪ You may not know ♪
- Get me home.
- [Jimmy] Home?
- I wanna go home.
- [Jimmy] Ain't you gonna. ..
- I'm going home.
(glass clatters)
(Frank grunts)
(bottle shatters)
(Frank sighs)
(Frank grunts)
(Frank exhales)
(Frank coughs)
(soft music)
- I can't end five years in five minutes.
- Call me later.
- Tomorrow.
- I'll come with you.
- I'll call you tomorrow.
I promise.
- What are you afraid of?
(soft music continues)
(engine rumbles)
(tense string music)
(tense string music continues)
- [Frank] Finished?
- Yes.
- Congratulations.
(glasses clinking)
- I-
- There.. .
(Frank sighs)
There's something very
important I want to say to you.
Please sit down.
You know. ..
When you and me first.. .
I picked you up.
I knew I was a convenience for you.
I gave you a place to
stay, took care of ya.
You were a convenience for me.
But in the past few weeks, I realized. ..
It wasn't like that anymore.
At least, not for me.
(soft dramatic music)
I'm gonna take you back to New York.
(soft dramatic music continues)
I want you to marry me.
What do you say?
(soft dramatic music fades)
(change clatters)
(rotary clacking)
(phone rings)
- Where is she?
- Where's who?
- Carol.
- She's in here, Stevie. In here.
- Just finished cutting it.
- You and Carol, good or bad,
pinned down forever on celluloid,
where you'll never grow old.
- I wanna know where she's gone.
I wanna know where she is now.
I've tried her at home. I've-
- Stevie, forget about her and move on.
There's a wrap on that.
You're a good actor.
- Movies.
Haven't you got anything
else in your life?
- Would you like to come to the viewing
and see if it was all worth it?
- No.
Thanks.
- Better hurry, Stanley.
He's very keen on punctuality.
- See you around, Blake.
- Wait a minute.
You got what you wanted.
I gotta know where she is.
I know about the money,
I know about Silva,
I know everything!
We had plans.
- She's gone, Stevie.
I've tried reaching her too.
She's just gone.
I wish I could help.
(soft dramatic string music)
- [Stevie] Well, I can hardly believe it,
but I’m leaving New York.
Giving up boxing.
Had to, under the circumstances.
Betty.. .
I guess she never really
loved me after all.
I ain't seen her since that night.
I wonder if she holds it
against me 'cause of Scandelli.
I was just trying to take the danger away.
I guess it just goes to show you,
you can't do a woman's thinking for her.
It just comes back to get you every time.
It's just like boxing, being in love.
Sometimes you get knocked down by it,
and you get right up.
Sometimes you get knocked out.
And you lie there, and it
just goes right over you.
Damn.
I'll miss that girl.
(dramatic saxophone music)
- Billy, Billy!
- Betty, Betty!
(dramatic saxophone music continues)
- Wow.
Now that's a movie.
You should be damned proud of yourself!
- I am.
And if you think that's
good, listen to this.
Vegas.
You like Vegas?
Six desperate men, two beautiful women.
One good, one evil.
$2 million.
A split second meticulously planned heist.
- At a casino.
- Time.
Put your watch to your ear.
That noise you hear is time running out.
Do you know why time is running out?
Because tomorrow, at 12 noon, MG and M,
That is Metro and Goldwyn and Mayer,
is closing this deal!
- I'm surprised you
didn't come to me first.
- Farris, speak to this man!
Speak to him!
There may still be time.
Speak to him.
- Here's the deal.
(soft saxophone music)
(soft saxophone music continues)
(soft saxophone music fades)