(dramatic music)
(dramatic music continues)
(gentle music)
(gentle music continues)
(pensive orchestral music)
(pensive orchestral music continues)
(chalk clanking)
(hammer thudding)
- What's all that hammering?
- Jake the hangman.
(George laughing)
- Greasing up his
gallows for us, lads. (laughs)
- T'ain't funny, George.
T'ain't funny at all.
- There, that'll help a bit.
- Aye, that it does, Doctor,
though it's a little late
to be worrying about my neck now.
- You never can tell.
- Yeah, I hope you're right.
- [Captain] By your leave,
gentlemen, by your leave.
- [Prisoner] Well, if
ain't the governor himself.
- [Prisoner] And his Lord Chamberlain,
the keeper of the keys.
- Come to join us in a
dish of tea, no doubt.
(prisoner laughing)
- Quiet, boys, can't you see
he's posting a royal proclamation?
- You have an hour to get ready, one hour.
- Outta the way.
- Yes.
- Hark to this.
(dramatic music)
Having weighed the evidence
in connection with the crimes
upon which you have been tried,
convicted, and condemned to death,
his Majesty's Privy Council
is graciously pleased
to commute the aforesaid
sentences to transportation
to New, New South Wales for life,
Ned Inching, pickpocket,
the Reverend Mortimer Thynne, traitor,
Thomas Oakly, highwayman,
Hugh Tallant, highwayman.
- [Prisoner] How about us?
- [Prisoner] Some blokes has all the luck.
- [Prisoner] Give you a
quid for your place, Parson.
- Too bad there's no longer
transportation to America, Hugh.
Then, you'd have a free trip home.
- I'll take New South Wales.
- Where would New South Wales be?
- Who cares?
- The important thing is
we've only got another hour
in this filthy hole.
- I doubt the governor will
know when the hour's up.
- Why not?
- Seems he forgot his watch.
(Tom laughing)
(water sloshing)
(gentle music)
(boat creaking)
- [Prisoner] New South Wales, Botany Bay.
It's all one to me.
- Where is Botany Bay, sir?
- The other side of the world, young man,
even further than Mr. Tallant's America.
- [Nat] Will there be savages, sir?
- He said the land's full
of wild men nine feet tall.
- (laughs) That sounds fascinating.
- Is it so, Reverend, sir?
- I don't think they're as tall as that.
- Don't be afraid, son.
Nine foot tall or 29 foot,
I'll look out for you.
- I wonder who'll look out for me, Parson.
- That's easily answered.
At your service, ma'am.
- Ahoy, the shore.
Ground ahoy.
- [Sailor] Seven
prisoners for the shuttle.
- [Sailor] Come on side. Get them on.
- [Sailor] Cast your grab line.
- [Sailor] Watch your instruments.
They're coming up for the gear.
- [Sailor] Yeah, boat is
fast. I call you on nines.
Oakly, get a move on.
Step lively.
- Yeah, all right.
- Inching.
- That's me.
- Thynne, Nellie Garth, Nat Garth.
- Be careful, Nat, boy.
- [Sailor] Mind ye foot there, lads,
Sally Munroe, Hugh Tallant, come on.
Get up the ladder.
- I'm not sure I want to risk
my life on a tub like this.
- Better do as you're told.
- What business is it of yours?
- Stop your jawing and get up the ladder.
- Suppose I don't.
- We got ways of taking
care of people like you.
Brown, put her aboard.
- [Sally] I'd like to see you try.
- Come on, my pretty.
Come with us.
- Let go.
Let go.
- Come with us.
(dramatic music)
- Let me outta here.
(dramatic music continues)
(rope creaking)
Get me outta this thing.
Get outta here.
(sailors laughing)
- Would you look what
flew up outta of the sea?
A blooming mermaid. (laughs)
- Will you get me outta this thing?
- With pleasure, your ladyship.
- Watch it now, Hurst.
- Did you hurt yourself, me lady?
- Keep your flippers off that one, matey.
I seen her first.
- Yes, he did.
- [Hurst] In a well spot, he did.
- All right.
(dramatic music)
Get your knife out, matey.
I'll slice enough salt also
off your gut to feed a ship.
(hand smacking)
(body thudding)
(item clanking)
(suspenseful music)
(chains clanging)
- Bo's'n.
- Aye, aye, sir.
(imperious music)
- Who has the watch?
- Mr. Spencer, sir.
- Where is he?
- Below deck, sir,
inspecting the prisoners.
- [Captain] What have we here?
- [Bo's'n] More prisoners, sir.
- So I see.
So I see.
And some men begging
for a touch of the cat?
- Ah, they was only having
a bit of a lark, sir.
- Put those knives away and go below.
- Aye, aye, sir.
- Mr. Spencer.
Mr. Spencer.
- Coming sir, coming.
(boat creaking)
- Are you or are you not the
mate of the watch, Mr. Spencer?
- I am, sir, but I was tween decks-
- I want this understood
once and for all.
I'm a peaceful man, and
I have a great liking
for a peaceful ship.
- [Spencer] Yes, sir.
- You must be the Reverend Dr. Thynne.
- Yes, Captain.
- Bo's'n.
- Sir.
(chains clanging)
- Escort this gentleman to my quarters
and strike off his fetters at once.
- Aye, sir.
(chains clanging)
- As to the other prisoners...
- Sir, I'd like to thank you.
- For what?
- Why, for saving me from those men.
- What is your name?
- Sally Munroe, my lord.
- Perhaps a lord someday
should a relative or two die,
but at the moment, Captain Paul Gilbert,
mate of His Majesty's Navy
and owner of this vessel.
Are you with this man?
- No, sir, I never saw
him before in my life.
- Have the prisoners taken below.
- Yes, sir.
- Sentry.
- Take the women to their quarters first.
- [Sentry] All right, you
two, come along with me.
- Boy, you're to go with the men.
- I don't want to leave
my mother's side.
- Do as you're told.
It'll be all right, lad.
- Come along.
- [Captain] Mr. Spencer.
- Yes, sir.
- Those men you permitted
to brawl on deck.
- Yes, sir.
- They'll be brought before
me for punishment tomorrow.
- Very well.
- And to their names, kindly add your own.
(boat creaking)
- [Sentry] Stand by
below, female prisoners.
- This way, over there.
(Mrs. Garth screaming)
(foot thudding)
(mouse squeaking)
- Welcome to Hampton Court, ladies.
(prisoners laughing)
- Welcome yourself.
- [Jenkins] Come on, you.
(gate clanging and squeaking)
Get in there. Come on.
(prisoners laughing)
- Oh, stow it.
(prisoner laughing)
- You and your fine feathers,
someone'll have 'em off your
back before all night's out.
(prisoners laughing)
- I don't think so.
- Hmm, we'll see.
(footsteps plodding)
- They bring the male prisoners down yet?
- They're inside.
- Then let me through.
- Why should I do that?
- I have a message for
two of 'em from Nick Sabb.
- And who might Nick Sabb be?
- Well, you're new aboard, ain't ya?
The richest fence in London,
he was, before they caught him
and still rich enough to buy
a little favour now and then.
Am I making myself clear?
- You are.
(bolt clanging)
- [Prisoner] Oh, I don't who he was.
(prisoners chattering indistinctly)
(gate clattering)
- [Prisoner] Something besides slop.
- Pipe down, pipe down.
Which of you is Oakly and Inching?
- That's us.
- Well, get up.
Come this way with me.
(chains clanging)
Not you.
- But where are we going to sleep here?
- Anywhere you like, my bully boy,
and keep your mouth shut
unless anybody speaks to ya.
(hand knocking)
- [Nick] What is it?
- Oakly and Inching, Mr. Sabb.
(doorknob clattering)
- Well, bless me soul. (laughs)
I'd almost given ya up
for lost, gentlemen.
- Sabb, fat old lip.
(Nick laughing)
- All the comforts of home and taverns,
the finest Stinger and plenty more
in the barrel where this came from.
- Anything else, Mr. Sabb?
- Bring the rest of their belongings.
- Then we're to live here?
- Where else?
- How did you know we'd
be be on the Charlotte?
- (laughs) I arranged it with the aid
of a few well-placed tokens,
uh, but don't thank me.
I imagine there'll be openings
at Botany Bay for the firm
of Oakly, Inching, and Sabb.
- Throats cut while you wait.
- If you're agreed, that is.
- I'm for it.
- And you, Tom?
- Aye, if you can find room for one other.
- Who?
- My charge, Hugh Tallant.
- What's he doing aboard?
- The same as the rest of us.
- Odd, very odd indeed.
Fetch him, will you, Ned?
(chains clanging)
Can't be my sources of
information were wrong.
Bring me that strong box, Tom.
- Aye.
(chains clanging)
This one?
- Yes.
(box thudding)
(paper rustling)
(chains clanging)
Now.
Oh, here it is, the
latest London broadsheet.
- Hugh, this is Nick Sabb.
- Who's the boy?
- My name's Nat Garth, sir.
- He's with us.
- Oh.
His Majesty's Privy Council
yesterday reconsidered
the conviction of Hugh Tallant, American,
for armed robbery on the highway.
Documents newly arrived
from Maryland prove
the money stolen was part
of a 20,000-pound legacy
from Ezra Tallant, great
uncle of Baltimore.
It is reported a royal
pardon has been authorised.
- Your freedom and a fortune.
- That calls for a round in celebration.
- Not so fast, me laddie box.
The Charlotte sails at daybreak.
It's near midnight now.
The king's messenger,
even if he's on his way,
is snoring peacefully in some cosy inn.
Course, you could speak to the captain.
- I have to.
- It can be arranged
if you have the money.
- I have no money.
- That's a pity.
- Don't be a fool, Nick.
Didn't you just read he was a rich man?
- Lad, go tell the guard
Nick Sabb wishes to see him.
- Yes, Mr. Sabb.
(chains clanging)
- I imagine, since you're a
friend of Governor Philip,
he told you the Charlotte is destined
to travel in solitary splendour.
We'll not overhaul the
fleet short of Botany Bay.
- How long will the voyage take?
- Eight months with
luck, it's 16,000 miles.
(hand knocking)
Excuse me.
(glass thudding)
- You wanted to see me, sir?
- Enter please.
It's all right, Bo's'n.
- [Spencer] Captain.
- What is it?
- This man, sir, says he has to see you
about a matter of life and death.
- It's not that bad,
sir, but it is important.
- What's your name?
- Tallant, Hugh Tallant.
- Wait here. I'll attend
to you in a moment.
You're listed as an actress.
- Yes, sir, the Theatre Royal Drury Lane.
(pages rustling)
- Five years transportation,
theft of a necklace from
a certain gentlemen.
- I prefer to call it a slight argument
over who owned the necklace.
- Having heard of the
gentleman, I can understand.
- [Sally] Then you don't
think me a dangerous criminal?
- No more criminal than
this gentleman here,
who along with a good many
others dislikes a German king
on the English throne, but
you are dangerous, ma'am,
a veritable spark in a powder keg.
There are 148 men aboard the Charlotte.
- And some 30-odd women.
- Slatterns and chained below.
- I'm in chains, too,
or hadn't you noticed?
(chains clanging)
- If you are forward,
I shall keep you in
your present condition.
However, I was thinking of
giving you separate quarters
and a certain measure of freedom.
In return, I must ask you
to hold yourself aloof.
A journey as long and
tedious as this affords
many opportunities for mischief.
- I'm sure that you and the, uh,
Reverend Gentleman here can
keep me out of mischief.
Don't you think so, Parson?
- [Reverend] We can try.
- Mr. Spencer.
(keys jangling)
See to the lady's shackles.
- Yes.
- Now, this matter of life and death,
what was your crime?
- Armed robbery on the
King's Highway, sir.
- Innocent, I suppose.
- No, sir.
- That at least is a novelty,
the one guilty man aboard.
- But the one man aboard that I know
of who has a pardon on the way.
I've just learned
that the Privy Council
has reconsidered my case.
If you read this, sir,
you'll see that the money
I was charged with stealing was my own,
part of a 20,000-pound inheritance.
- [Captain] Imposing sum,
but how exactly does one set
about stealing one's own money?
- (laughs) Oh, for one thing
you need a dishonest London agent.
- Mm-hmm, go on.
- And an uncle in Maryland.
You see, he was sending me money
so I could finish my apprenticeship
at Cauldwell Hospital,
but the money never came, and
I had to give up my studies.
Then, I learned from a
bookkeeper in the agent's office
the money had come.
I accused the agent of pocketing it,
but, well, sir, I had no proof,
and the bookkeeper was afraid to speak.
So one night when I learned
that the agents went
on the Liverpool stage,
I, I and a friend of mine
arranged to have it stopped.
I only took what was mine, sir.
My friend was wounded,
and, well, we were caught.
- Most unfortunate for both of you,
what would you have me do about it?
- Could you delay sailing
for a few hours until the pardon arrives?
- My instructions are to
leave with the morning tide.
Should I miss it and the weather change?
I might be here for days.
The authorities will be angry,
and there will be the additional expense
of feeding some 200 souls.
- Maybe you could put
me ashore under guard.
One man more or less
at Botany Bay can't make much difference.
- You're an American, aren't you?
- Yes, sir.
- And a medical student.
You could be quite useful aboard ship
since we've no surgeon.
And as to New South Wales,
the wilds of a new country,
it should hold no terrors
for a man of your birthplace.
- I see.
I'm wasting your time as well as mine.
- Mr. Spencer, take the man below
and see that he stays there.
- Very well, sir.
(pensive music)
Come on.
(chains clanging)
(pipe thudding)
- Struggling medical
student, money from America,
dishonest agent,
armed robbery in the middle of the night,
it would do well for the plot of one
of your Drury Lane
concoctions, wouldn't it?
- Except there's no part in it for me.
- Perhaps it's just as well.
(chains clanging)
(pensive music continues)
- Brown.
Take this man to the tween decks
and see that his leg
irons are well secured.
- Aye, aye, sir.
(dramatic music)
(body thudding)
(chains clanging)
(water splashing)
- [Sailor] Man overboard.
- [Sailor] Have you got him?
- [Sailor] He went over the
side like a vanishing bird.
- [Spencer] Do you see anything?
- [Sailor] Not a sign.
- No, nor will there be,
not with him carrying the
weight of those leg irons.
- [Sailor] Perhaps he's lucky at that.
(footsteps plodding)
- Bo's'n.
- Aye, sir.
- [Spencer] Notify the
captain and be quick about it.
- Aye, aye, sir.
(pensive music)
(water sloshing)
- [Sailor] Charlotte, ahoy.
- [Sailor] Aye, who goes there?
- [Sailor] Shore boat coming alongside.
Stand by for me bell line.
- [Sailor] Aye, aye.
- There's someone in the water, sir.
- Stand by to pull him in.
(pensive music continues)
- I've got him, sir.
- Grab him.
Pull him in.
- [Sailor] In with ya, me boy.
(water splashing)
Come on.
Hold him down.
Pin his legs.
Trying to escape, are ya?
(whip snapping)
(tense music)
(clothes rustling)
- I don't want any danger of infection.
Have you the salt ready for his wounds?
- [Bo's'n] Yes, sir.
- Then you may proceed with the punishment
as soon as you're ready.
The sentence is 50 lashes,
each stroke to be counted clearly.
- [Bo's'n] Aye, aye, sir.
- I've had the cat meself, matey.
No matter how bad it hurts,
keep the weight on your feet,
and don't put the strain on your arms.
- Thanks.
- Stand by.
- It's regrettable that
this has to happen,
but this is a merchant
ship with only a file
of Marines to maintain order.
We have a long voyage ahead of us
and a ship filled with criminals.
(whip snapping)
(dramatic music)
- [Sailor] One.
- You might think these
proceedings to be unduly harsh,
but I assure you it is necessary.
(whip snapping)
- [Sailor] Two.
- Shipboard, as in all accepted
forms of civilised society,
authority has to be enforced.
(whip snapping)
- [Sailor] Three.
- Commands have to be obeyed
with celerity and without question.
(whip snapping)
- [Sailor] Four.
- It's an unpleasant sight.
Perhaps you'd be well
advised to follow her.
(whip snapping)
- [Sailor] Five.
Six.
(whip snapping)
Seven.
Eight.
- Next time, I'll have a plan.
- [Tom] You intend to try again?
- If I can get help.
- [Tom] You can count on me.
- Me too.
- But not me.
I'm too fond of me hide for that.
- There'll be 1,000
pounds waiting in London
for every man who helps me get free.
- 1,000 pounds?
(brooding music)
That's a great deal of money.
(bottle clanking)
(liquid sloshing)
(majestic music)
We're 800 miles off the
coast of South America.
Making good headway we are.
- I'd best be getting up
on deck now, Mr. Tallant.
The captain will be
wanting his dinner soon.
- Don't forget now. Keep your ears open.
We wanna know what's going on.
- Yes, sir.
- And your mouth shut.
- Yes, Mr. Sabb.
- We should reach Rio
by the end of the month.
- If the wind holds.
- We all ready?
- We will be, Hugh.
I told you the day we sight
the coast, boat in provisions.
- Why aren't the provisions ready now?
- Well, it's a delicate matter,
what with the guard's watching,
and tales of informers
among the prisoners, and the
Captain thirsting for blood.
We're risking our necks every minute.
If I hadn't-
(hand knocking)
- [Ned] Sir.
- [Nick] What now?
- Another knock of the
dark for the ladies.
(Nick laughing)
- They've swilled enough
rum already to float a ship.
- Here's a broach.
- Was a day I wouldn't bother
with a trifle like this,
but business is business.
(door clanking)
(liquid sloshing)
Make sure they don't
filch the muck. (laughs)
20 pounds I've netted, and
there's half an hogshead left.
- A long way from 1,000 pounds.
- You're right, me boy,
but don't you worry.
Nick Sabb's not one to
let 1,000 pounds pass.
Now for me weekly shave.
I pays high to get the water.
As long as I have it,
I'll share it with you.
We gents need to keep up appearances.
(hand knocking)
(door squeaking)
- Tallant, work party, report on deck.
Hurry up.
(chains clanging)
- [Sailor] Sailmaker,
raise up the foreyard.
- [Sailor] Aye, sir,
hands to the foreracers.
- [Sailor] Aye, aye.
- [Sailor] Cure the balsa
with the holy stone.
(stones rasping)
- Look at them, chained and
prodded about like animals,
worst possible way to reform them.
- Most of them look past all reformation.
- I disagree, young lady.
Most of them, in fact,
are not even criminals.
- Well, what are they then?
- Unfortunate souls fallen foul of harsh
and unjust laws with no more
against them than the theft
of a few potatoes or half
a loaf of stale bread.
You'll find Governor Philip agrees with me
when we reach Botany Bay.
- What do you think
will happen to me there?
- Well, you'll be given
a wonderful chance.
You'll be taught cooking, baking,
washing clothes, weaving, sewing.
You might find it a
little difficult at first.
- Yes, I might.
- Of course, if you found a husband...
- What then?
- The governor plans to
give married couples land,
land and the freedom to work it.
- That sounds a little better.
Now, which one shall I marry, Parson?
(stones rasping)
- The sea evidently agrees
with you, Mistress Sally.
You look very well.
- Thank you, sir.
(footsteps plodding)
- [Captain] Stand by for time sites.
- Parson, didn't you tell me yesterday
the captain had a wealthy wife?
- Yes, I did.
She's a very great heiress,
the Earl of Selingham's daughter.
- I think I have heard of
her brother, Lord Cannon.
- Yes, you've heard of him.
He's reputed to be the
worst rake in London,
but I don't quite understand you.
- You will later on.
Now, about the prisoners,
I think you're right.
In fact, I think you
should ask the captain
to give them more freedom.
We might even suggest the young
doctor be made ship surgeon.
- You're embarking on a
dangerous game, young lady.
- I've always been clever at games,
and you did say you were in favour
of reforming our fellow
prisoners, didn't you?
- Yes, I did.
(stones rasping)
(waves lapping)
Captain, I should like to speak
to you about the prisoners.
For one thing, it seems inhuman
to keep them fettered
while exercising on deck,
and I hear there is much sickness, so-
- I shall be glad to hear
what you've heard, Parson,
after I've established my noon position.
Watch the helm.
- Aye, sir.
- Time.
- Make eight bells.
- Eight bells it is, sir.
(bell ringing)
- I have 68 degrees, 34 minutes,
and two tenths, Mr. Green?
- Five tenths more, sir.
- Mr. Spencer?
- I'm two degrees off your reading, sir.
- Not once on this voyage
have your readings tallied
with mine and Mr. Green's.
Now, with Mr. Green's help,
do you think you can plot our position?
- Yes, sir.
- Then do so.
Now, Parson, I'm all attention.
- Well, I, I wanted to
speak to you about the-
- Watch out. You're too close.
- Aye, sir.
(majestic music)
- Open up.
Is the prisoner Tallant ready?
On deck, follow me.
(chains clanging)
- Sergeant.
- Yes.
- I see your arm's no better.
- No.
- Mind if I look at it?
- I told you it wouldn't be right
for a ship's officer to be
treated by one of the prisoners.
- Who's to know?
- I won't discuss it.
Come on.
(footsteps plodding)
(chains clanging)
- Mr. Spencer.
- Yes.
- May I speak to the ship's surgeon?
- Who would that be?
- Why, Mr. Tallant, of course.
I happen to know the captain's going
to offer you the position.
- But I'm no surgeon.
- You studied medicine, and as surgeon,
you're going to have freedom of the ship.
Of course, you'd have to give
your pledge not to escape.
I promised the captain you'd do that.
- What else did you promise him?
I'm to be indebted to his lady.
I'd like to know how deeply.
(dramatic music)
(hand smacking)
- You're a fool, Tallant.
- [Prisoner] How's it
feel with that iron still?
- [Prisoner] Light as a
feather, that's how I feel.
- Here comes the queen.
(prisoners laughing)
- And all dressed up in her Sunday best.
- Uh, tell me, fancy piece, too good
for us common folk, ain't ya?
- Rip off her finery, Moll.
- Leave her alone, Moll.
She's doing you no harm.
- Mind your own business, ya fat sow.
(fist thudding)
- Fat sow, ya slag.
(dramatic music)
(prisoners screaming)
(water splashing)
(prisoners yelling indistinctly)
(body thudding)
- [Sailor] Hey there, stop it.
Do you hear me? Stop it.
(water splashing)
- Hey, stop it. Do you hear me?
Stop it.
- Try to, try to kick him.
(dramatic music continues)
- [Sailor] Stop those wenches fighting.
They're outta hand there.
(prisoners yelling indistinctly)
(water splashing)
(gunshot blasting)
(prisoners whimpering)
(footsteps plodding)
- Reload, sentry.
If there's any further disturbance,
I shall order the deck
swept with musket fire.
Remove the net, onto
your feet, all of you.
Against my better
judgement, I was persuaded
by Dr. Thynne to exercise
a certain clemency.
I ordered you relieved of your fetters
and allowed you privileges on
deck, and now this exhibition.
What have you to say for yourselves?
- Well, you see it was like this, Captain.
We was dancing a-
- Silence.
Insurrection and impertinence,
what have you to suggest now, Parson?
You shall have 20 lashes.
As for the others, Mr. Green,
restore their leg irons,
and by way of an example,
select three of them
to have their heads shaved.
- Aye, aye, sir.
- Guard, escort Mistress
Munroe to my cabin.
(waves lapping)
(prisoner whimpering)
(clothes rustling)
(prisoner screaming)
(shears rasping)
(whip snapping)
(prisoner screaming)
Mr. Spencer.
- All right,
get fired, all of ya.
- For failure to preserve order,
you are again admonished,
the fact again to be entered in the log.
- I did what I could,
sir, but with this arm.
- Is it my fault that, in
addition to being incompetent,
you are a cripple?
Well, sir, will you answer me?
- It is not your fault, sir.
- You change your mind
about your arm, Mr. Spencer,
just give me the word.
(footsteps plodding)
(boat creaking)
- Wait outside.
(door clattering)
(pensive music)
The women seem to have taken
a dislike to you, my dear.
I trust you're unharmed.
- More or less.
- I see on your shoulder a scratch.
Perhaps we should send
for the new surgeon.
- He refused the position.
- You talked with him?
- Only a few words.
- Pity on a skin so smooth.
- And ruined the only decent dress I have.
- There's thread and
needle in the ship's store,
and I'm sure material of
some kind can be found.
- Don't I owe you too much already?
- Yes, and I think it's
time we talked of payment.
You're not gonna be alarmed, are you?
Violence is foreign to my nature,
but you have enjoyed a
favourite position onboard ship,
private cabin, special
privileges, special food.
Either these pleasant conditions continue,
or you return below with the other women,
and I hesitate to think what'll happen
to you, feeling as they do.
- You leave me little choice.
- You're very wise and very lovely,
and I think you'll find
me not unappreciative.
- I'm sure, but in a way, this is a pity.
- How?
- I shall have to destroy
those letters I intended
to send from Rio and write
others in their place.
- Letters to whom?
(footsteps plodding)
- Lord Cannon.
- Selingham's son?
- I thought I'd told you.
Jack and I were friends in London.
- He has the reputation of a rake.
- I found him quite constant.
I'd written such glowing accounts
of your kindness and chivalry.
- Why change them?
- Jack made me promise to tell him
exactly what went on aboard the Charlotte.
I suppose it was because of
his sister, your wife, Helen.
(dramatic music)
(footsteps plodding)
Now, with your permission,
sir, I'll leave.
(door clattering)
(pensive music)
- Escape's getting closer every day.
Look what Tom lifted for the longboat,
ship's lantern, rope for rigging sails,
canvas, and a file to
cut off your shackles.
- It's good for a start.
But how do we get the
longboat over the side?
- I'll think of a way
if I have to sink the Charlotte to do it.
(hand knocking)
All right, Tom.
(chains clanging)
(hand knocking)
- That you, Ned?
- Aye.
(door clattering)
Gents, look at what Ned Inching run onto.
- What is it?
- Token of esteem from the
tenants of the Earl of Selingham
to Captain Paul Gilbert on the occasion
of his marriage to Lady Helen Cannon.
(lid clanking)
- His boat compass.
- Fancy made and fancy mounted
and a mighty handy thing for Hugh to have.
- Handy?
Handy enough to get us all
hanged from the yard arm.
- But I thought-
- Who told you to get it?
- Well, nobody.
- You take it back.
- How can I?
Might be days before I got
a sure chance again.
(hand knocking)
- [Jenkins] Mr. Sabb.
(boat creaking)
(doorknob clattering)
- What do you want?
- The mate wants Tallant in his cabin.
- Be right there.
Find a chance to get it back in quick.
You understand?
- [Ned] Yes, Hugh.
(chains clanging)
(door clattering)
It'll be 50 lashes at least if I'm caught.
- Worse, if I know the captain.
- Let me take it, Ned.
I'm in and out of his cabin day and night.
Would be easy for me.
- Give us your hand, boy.
You're a perishing genius. That's what.
- There's no doubt about it, Mr. Spencer.
The arm has been set improperly.
- You sure you can remedy it?
- Yes, but I'll have to re-break it,
and, well, it'll hurt.
- I'd put it in fire if I thought
it would make it right again.
- Then I'm to go ahead?
- Whenever you're ready.
There's just one thing that
bothers me, though, the fee.
I have a little money in my
sea chest but not very much.
- I wasn't thinking of money, Mr. Spencer.
When we provision at Rio,
the supply barges come
alongside, don't they?
- No, Tallant, I have no
cause to like this ship
or its master, but I know my duty.
- All you have to do is turn your back
for a minute, Mr. Spencer.
I think it's a small fee for a mended arm.
- It's a fee I'll not pay.
- All right, we'll forget the fee.
- I don't know that I like any of this.
By rights, I should inform
the captain immediately.
(fist thudding)
(dramatic music)
(pensive music)
(ropes creaking)
- [Sailor] Light it along current.
Light along current for the sail locker.
- [Sailor] Get a move on,
or you'll get a taste of a rope's end.
Bear a hand.
Get that sail along to the sail locker.
- [Nat] Let me go, sir.
I wasn't doing anything.
- [Mr. Green] Not much you weren't.
- What is it, Mr. Green?
- I caught him outside your cabin
with your boat compass, sir.
Lucky I happened to be passing by.
- Very lucky.
What have you to say for yourself?
- Nothing, sir.
- You did intend to steal my compass?
Speak up.
- [Nat] Yes, sir, I did.
- The sentence for theft
is 100 lashes well applied
and solitary confinement
on bread and water
until such time as I
see fit to release you.
However, in view of your age,
I will suspend the flogging.
Take him below.
And Mr. Green, return that to my cabin.
- [Mr. Green] Aye, aye, sir.
(pensive music continues)
(footsteps plodding)
- Couldn't I speak to
my mother first, sir?
- I'm afraid not, son.
(coins clanking)
- Present from Nick Sabb.
- What's it for?
- Little talk with the boy.
- But you make it short.
I'm only relieving Sim while
he goes to get the food.
Over to you.
(boat creaking)
(keys jangling)
- [Hugh] Nat.
- Mr. Tallant.
- That was a very brave
thing you did today.
- I couldn't very well
tell on Mr. Inching.
- I know, Ned, not and be a man.
We'll see you don't suffer
for too much, though.
- I'm all right, but it's
awful dark down here.
(door clattering and creaking)
(footsteps plodding)
- Yeah, what's going on?
- Business, business
that we've been paid for.
Come on.
We'll feed Connors his ration.
Tallant, I'll give you one minute more.
- Will you tell my mother you saw me?
- [Hugh] I'll do that right away, Nat.
- [Jenkins] Blast me guts.
Gone and died on us.
- He's stiff as a bowling pin.
- [Jenkins] That ain't
natural, not so quick.
- No, it ain't.
Did you see his skin?
He's all covered with black spots.
- Plague, that's what it is.
(brooding music)
And you touched him,
plague, plague, plague.
- [Sailor] We want the
captain, and we want him quick.
- [Sailor] Let us pass,
or we take to the boats.
- [Sailor] No cause to die like this.
- Be all very well free to
shout silence, Mr. Spencer.
We going up whether he like it or not.
(dramatic music)
- Back, or there'll be violence.
- Hold it.
- [Sailor] The surgeon.
- You'll all get yourself in
trouble for no cause at all.
- Plague no cause?
- Not the plague, it's scurvy.
I'll give you my word.
- [Sailor] Scurvy?
- You know what scurvy is.
I examined him, and there's
not a trace of plague.
All he needed was a decent meal.
Better go below before
the captain sees ya.
- After this, you keep your mouth shut.
(hand thudding)
(dramatic music)
- [Spencer] Come on all of
you, back to your quarters.
- I wonder what Captain
Gilbert would've thought
if they'd gone pouring into his cabin.
- They would never have reached my cabin,
at least not alive.
Come here, both of you.
(chains clanging)
Mr. Spencer, it is now quite obvious
you are a hopelessly incompetent officer.
I will enter that in the log
as well as the fact you
are permanently relieved
as second mate on this date.
Stand still while I'm talking to you.
The bo's'n will take
over your former duties.
Move your gear forward
to the folks at once.
You may resume your duties.
How is it, Tallant, you were
so sure it wasn't plague?
- My father and mother died
of the plague in Baltimore.
- Hmm.
For leaving your quarters
without permission,
I should punish you.
But that might be ungrateful.
I shall content myself
with cautioning you against
such liberties in the future.
(dramatic music)
(chains clanging)
- Mr. Tallant.
May I ask you something?
Why did you refuse to be ship surgeon
when you're doing all the work anyway?
Was it because you'd have to
give your word not to escape?
- Would you?
- Yes, if it meant I'd do
better here and at Botany Bay.
- I don't want any favours from anywhere.
- What do you want?
- I wanna do what I set
out to do, be a doctor.
- Tell me the real reason,
or don't you even know it?
- Maybe I don't like leg irons.
- It's time you decided
to make the best of them.
- [Hugh] Why?
- Because the odds
against escape are 1,000
to, a million to one.
Even if you do get away,
you'll probably have to
run the rest of your life.
- I'd rather be a free man running
than the most comfortable
slave in the world.
- The world's taught me we're
all slaves one way or another.
That's life, Mr. Tallant.
You might as well accept life.
- Like you did with the captain.
- At least I wasn't nearly
drowned, and flogged,
and put to scrubbing decks.
- Supposing you attend to your business,
and I'll attend to mine.
(dramatic music)
(chains clanging)
(pensive music)
(Nick laughing)
- So you'll slip over the side at Rio.
Sounds simple, like
stepping into the next room
till you remember there's
guards to be greased,
locks to be picked, boltmen to be hired.
My way of thinking, you'd have done better
to stick with my scheme.
- I might have, Nick,
if you'd have found out
how to launch the boat.
Think the new plan's safer, though,
and you get your thousand
pounds regardless.
- Sure you can trust the outside man?
- Who said there was an outside man?
- There has to be.
- I can trust him.
- Maybe you'd like my opinion.
- I promise I'd tell
nobody's name, not even Tom.
- Must be someone important.
(hand knocking)
(chains clanging)
(door clattering)
- Knock it. The mate's coming.
- Yeah, it's the glib.
(suspenseful music)
(door squeaking)
- Tallant.
- Yes.
- You're to come with
us, Captain's orders.
(chains clanging)
(pensive music)
- It's a pleasant evening.
(hand knocking)
Oh, it's you, Tallant.
Come here and stand beside Spencer.
Mr. Green, you can wait outside.
- [Mr. Green] Aye, aye, sir.
(waves lapping)
- I don't want to keep you
from your dinner, Parson.
Perhaps you'd like to say grace.
- I've already said my
devotions privately.
- Very well, I'll say grace
for myself and Mistress Munroe.
Oh, God, give us
thankfulness, and humility,
and thankfulness for
your bounty and humility
before our fellow man.
(lid clanking)
(glass thudding)
(boat creaking)
(waves lapping)
Tompkins, you may serve the soup.
(bottle clanking)
This is a matter of discipline.
It'll only take a moment.
Before I pass sentence on you, Tallant,
justice requires me to ask
if you have anything to say for yourself.
- About what?
- [Captain] You're charged
with plotting an escape with Spencer.
Do you admit the charge?
- No, sir.
- Do you recognise these keys?
(keys jangling)
- Ship's keys I suppose.
- And the master key to
the prisoners' shackles.
- I told you I meant to use
them for my own purposes.
- They were found on Spencer,
who I believe is deeply indebted to you
for having repaired his arm.
I have a witness who saw you treating him
not more than an hour ago.
- I see no witnesses.
- Be quiet, sir.
(hand thudding)
You've not only done yourself a disservice
but also your fellow convicts.
Since it is possible there
are others in your plot,
I shall not put in it Rio
but proceed to Cape Town
where the authorities will
provide me with extra guards.
This will mean shorter
rations for the entire ship.
As for the witness, I shall
produce him when you're brought
before Governor Philip at Botany Bay.
In the meantime, you'll both
be held in solitary confinement
for the remainder of the voyage.
(dramatic music)
(thunder clapping)
(waves roaring)
(water splashing)
- [Sailor] We're taking water below.
We're taking in water.
(water splashing)
(Nat whimpering)
(boat creaking)
- Oh, Mother.
Oh, Mother, Mother.
- Nat.
- Mother.
I want my mother.
I'm so cold. (sobbing)
- Keep out of the water
as much as you can, Nat.
- I cold, so cold.
- Think there's any chance
of our escaping earlier?
- You know better than that, Hugh.
It'll be at least a week
before we're close enough
to the coast of Africa to
have any chance at all.
(Nat sobbing)
(thunder clapping)
- Mother. (sobbing)
- We gotta get him outta here.
- Perhaps his mother could
reason with the captain.
- Better still, somebody get
word to the captain's lady.
(thunder clapping)
(water splashing)
(dramatic music)
(sailors yelling indistinctly)
- [Mrs. Garth] If you have
one drop compassion left
in your blood, Captain,
you'll do what I ask.
- If you persist in badgering me,
I shall have you in chains.
- But he's only a child.
- Get below, both of you.
Get below, I said.
(wind howling)
(dramatic music continues)
(thunder clapping)
(water splashing)
(wind howling)
(boat creaking)
(water sloshing)
- Nat, Nat, Spencer.
- [Spencer] Yes.
- Can you see him, Spencer?
- No.
- Jenkins, Jenkins.
- Pipe down, pipe down.
(keys jangling)
What is it?
- Take a look at the boy.
- Seems to be asleep.
- Put something under him.
- What me?
If I was as much as to touch him,
the captain would've
me hung up by my heels.
(boat creaking)
Now, this is strange.
Who gave you permission to come down here?
- What do you care, long
as Nick Sabb's paying ya?
Give me your keys.
- He's not paying me to hand
over no keys, not to nobody.
(hand thudding)
(Jenkins groans)
(water sloshing)
- [Mrs. Garth] Nat, Nat, Nat.
- Bring him outside, Tom,
where I can take a look at him.
(metal clanging)
- Nat.
(melancholic music)
(chains clanging)
Nat.
What have they done to you, Nat?
My boy, it's your mother.
Speak to your mother.
(water sloshing)
- Afraid he can't, Mrs. Garth.
(boat creaking)
(water sloshing)
- No.
No.
Nat, Nat.
My son, my only son. (sobbing)
(boat creaking)
(water sloshing)
(bell ringing)
(body thudding)
- Gangway, gangway there, gangway.
- Uncover.
"I am the resurrection and
the life," said the Lord.
"He that believeth in
me, though he were dead,
yet shall he live, and whosoever liveth
and believeth in me shall never die."
I know that my redeemer
liveth and that he shall stand
at the latter day upon the earth,
and thereafter my skin,
worms destroy this body,
yet in my flesh shall I see God,
whom I shall see for myself,
and mine eyes shall behold not another.
Thou knoweth, Lord, the
secrets of our hearts.
Shut not thy merciful ears to our prayers,
but spare us, Lord most
holy, oh, God most mighty,
oh, holy and merciful saviour,
our most worthy judge
eternal, suffer us not
at our last hour for any pains
of death to fall from thee.
And to almighty God we commend
the soul of Nat Garth departed
and commit his body to the deep.
(Mrs. Garth sobbing)
(body rasping)
(water splashing)
Assurance that and hope
of the resurrection
unto eternal life through
our Lord Jesus Christ
who's coming in glorious
majesty to judge the world.
The sea shall give up her dead,
and the corruptible bodies of those
who sleep in him shall be changed
and made like unto his glorious body
according to the mighty
working whereby he's able
to subdue all things unto himself.
Dismissed, gangway.
- Aye, sir.
- [Sailor] Gangway there,
gangway for the captain.
- [Sailor] Prisoners below.
- Mr. Green, the mizz
and the gallant are not braced properly.
(chains clanging)
(brooding music)
(door creaking and slamming)
(paper rustling)
(candle holder thudding)
(brooding music continues)
(knife rasping)
(dramatic music)
Mr. Green.
(revolver clattering)
(gunshot blasting)
- Are you hurt, sir?
- Leave me be.
Get her on her feet.
If nothing else, I shall have the pleasure
of seeing you hanged tomorrow morning.
Take her away.
Get my medicine box.
(pensive music)
(boat creaking)
- This is an awful sudden decision, Hugh.
- Would you have Mrs.
Garth hanged at the atoll?
- No, but I've had no
chance to bribe anyone,
save the guards below deck.
- We'll handle the rest.
- Where is Mrs. Garth?
- She should be here now.
Inching's fetching her.
- How about the men?
- They're rigging the tackles.
- The boat?
- Water breaker grub
ready to go.
(door squeaking)
- Here they are now.
- You ready, Mrs. Garth?
- Just a minute please.
- What's the matter?
- She claims nothing.
- I'm all right, just...
(dramatic music)
- Blood, she's been wounded.
- Bad?
- No, it's just a flesh wound.
Rest and care, she'll feel fine.
- She'll not get either in an open boat.
- No, she won't.
- But we can't leave her here.
- Perhaps we can.
Nick, where were you
hiding those big barrels
of rum you were selling?
- Forward of the cable
tier, it's all gone.
- I know that.
How big a place was it?
- Big enough for two of her.
- That's no good.
They'll search till they find her.
- No, they won't.
They'll think she went with us.
Nick can hide her until
they get to Botany Bay
and then put her to shore.
I understand Governor
Phillip is a very fair man.
It's our only chance, Tom.
- And I'll be staying,
too, and look after her.
- Good luck.
(gentle music)
(suspenseful music)
(footsteps plodding)
- Mr. Green, smoke coming
from the fore peak.
(footsteps plodding)
- You men, below to the fore peak.
- What's the matter?
- Hey, what's this?
- Where's everybody going?
- Yeah, where?
(prisoners chattering indistinctly)
(suspenseful music continues)
- [Prisoner] There must
be something up, eh?
(footsteps plodding)
(door clattering)
(club thudding)
(body thudding)
- [Sailor] Ah, sulphur and old rags,
something odd about this.
- [Sailor] Stuff it out, Parsons.
The rest ya, deck side, double.
(rope creaking)
- [Prisoner] No hope to get out of here?
No hope?
Hey, hey.
(rope creaking)
(suspenseful music continues)
(hand thudding)
(sailor grunts)
- [Sailor] It's battened down.
Let's try the fore hatch.
(rope creaking)
(suspenseful music continues)
(water splashing)
(hand thudding)
- [Sailor] Deck, ahoy.
On, deck, sir, on deck.
On deck, sir.
- Aye.
- [Sailor] On deck, open up.
Unbatten.
(hand thudding)
(gentle music)
(water sloshing)
- A long way to go.
- But don't you think we
ought to come about now?
(oar creaking)
- Look.
(dramatic music)
(suspenseful music)
Gilbert's alive.
- [Tom] What makes you so sure?
- Nobody else would've
searched in this direction.
- Unless someone informed on us.
- [Captain] I trust you enjoyed
your excursion, gentlemen.
- While it lasted, we did.
- You wouldn't have liked
the coast of Africa,
fever, hostile natives, dangerous animals.
Shouldn't there be three of you?
- Mrs. Garth is dead.
- Oh, how did that happen?
- She drowned herself when
the Charlotte came in sight.
- And neither of you tried to save her?
- So you could hang her?
- I shall be lenient.
You chose to escape by the sea,
and you shall be punished by the sea.
Mr. Green, you'll make preparations
for keelhauling the prisoners.
- Captain Gilbert, no
man has been keelhauled
on an English ship for 50 years.
- [Captain] Oh, I don't
think it's been that long.
- Why don't you hang us
and have done with it?
- I've seen hangings
but never a keelhauling.
Do your duty, Mr. Green.
- [Mr. Green] Aye, aye, sir.
Get a move on.
(footsteps plodding)
- Make sure that block's well greased.
- Bo's'n.
- What is it, Reverend?
- I have, of course read of keelhauling,
but I'm not quite clear
as to how it's done.
- Maybe it best remain that way.
- Only one in 50's ever lived through it.
- It's nothing really, Parson,
if you can do without breathing.
- The punishment, as
the name says, consists
of dragging a man down
and under the keel by means of two lines.
One's attached to his
feet to drag him around
and the other to his neck
to make sure the journey's not too quick.
- And how many times is he pulled across?
- Generally, once is enough.
(drum rumbling)
- Mr. Green.
- Aye, aye, sir.
- Commence punishment.
- [Mr. Green] Aye, aye, sir.
Hoist away.
(pulleys clanking)
(drum rumbling)
High enough.
Lower away.
(pulleys clanking)
(drum rumbling)
(water sloshing)
(metal clanging)
(pulleys clanking)
(drum rumbling)
18 on the landboard side.
- All the way on the key lines.
Keep 'em taut.
- Stay where you are.
- They're coming up, sir.
(water sloshing)
(drum rumbling)
- Are they alive?
- I think so, sir.
Fast heaving.
Shall I haul 'em aboard?
- No, take them under the keel
again to the starboard side.
- Slag away.
- [Sailor] Haul in on the starboard side.
(drum rumbling)
- Pay off.
(pulleys clanking)
(drum rumbling)
(water sloshing)
- Never live.
- Not so fast, put a
strain on those lines.
(pulleys clanking)
(drum rumbling)
- [Sailor] The line's twisted.
- Captain Gilbert.
- There seems to be
some trouble, Mr. Green.
What is it?
- One of the lines has bowed, sir.
- [Captain] Well, clear it.
- Aye, aye, sir.
- You've got to bring them aboard.
- Are you sure you mean them?
- Doesn't matter what I mean.
You've got to bring them aboard.
- [Mr. Green] Clear for
hauling 'em in, sir.
- Haul them onto the deck.
Let's have a look at them.
- This is the most barbarous
proceeding I've ever witnessed.
- You think so, Reverend?
(chains clanging)
(drum rumbling)
(pulleys clanking)
(footsteps plodding)
(boat creaking)
(water sloshing)
- Is he alive?
- Mr. Green.
Their condition?
- Tallant's alive, sir.
- And Spencer?
- Dead, sir.
- Clear the decks.
- Aye, aye, sir.
- Captain Gilbert.
You now have three deaths to answer for,
Spencer, Mrs. Garth, and her son,
and no doubt there will be more,
but you may be sure, if I survive,
I shall make a full
report to Governor Philip
when we reach Botany Bay.
- I'm sure he'll find
that most interesting.
(footsteps plodding)
(majestic music)
(majestic music continues)
- [Sailor] Land, ho.
Land, ho.
- Where are we?
- [Sailor] Two points on landboard bow.
- Our destination, Mr. Green.
237 days, fine passage, I
shall make an entry in the log.
- Let go of the starboard anchor.
(water splashing)
- Get up forward.
- Pull upside with the boat.
(pulleys clanking)
(boat clattering)
- [Sailor] Stay with
the boat (indistinct).
(chains clanging)
- Mr. Tallant.
- Sentry, escort the Reverend
Thynne and this woman
to the boat at the gangway at once.
Where's the other prisoner?
- The other?
There was only Mr. Tallant, sir.
- Perhaps I forgot to tell you.
We've had another prisoner for some time,
a certain Mrs. Garth
whose friends elected to confine her
forward of the cable tier,
a most unhealthy spot.
However, she survived.
When you take this man
ashore, hand him over
to the guards in charge
of the Encouragement.
- Aye, aye, sir.
Come on.
(majestic music)
- [Sailor] Come on now.
Get ashore and take
your belongings with ya.
- [Prisoner] Only too happy to oblige.
(footsteps plodding)
(prisoners chattering indistinctly)
(Moll gasps)
- [Sailor] They're is harmless
as foul in a barnyard.
- Aye, but do they know that?
- [Sailor] Keep walking.
(majestic music)
- Welcome to New South Wales, Captain.
- Thank you.
- The governor is waiting for you.
(monkeys howling)
(birds chirping)
- I've heard your
evidence, Captain Gilbert,
and the testimony of the Reverend
Thynne and the two persons
against whom you have
brought these charges.
- Surely, there can be no question
of their guilt, Governor Philip.
- No, there is no question as to that.
- And no doubt they'll hang.
- There are two purposes
behind transportation,
Captain Gilbert, the one to
give people a chance to reform,
and the other to open up a new world.
Neither is accomplished with corpses.
Now, as to the disposition
of the prisoners,
there are certain
mitigating circumstances,
your natural resentment
over the fate of your son
and your conviction that you
have been treated unjustly.
However, the removal of
the colony from Botany Bay
to this port has seriously
disrupted our programme,
and I, I'm not prepared to
wait upon the bickerings
that attend upon a protracted trial,
but when the case is reopened,
the mitigating circumstances will have
the fullest consideration.
- [Captain] Why not free them
now and have done with it?
- [Governor] Put this man for
the time being at hard labour.
- Go on, up the hill.
(hammers thudding)
Take it up.
(birds squawking)
- What's a word from Sabb?
- He's got the chart, Hugh,
a copy of Captain Cook's.
- Does it show the Dutch Islands?
- Aye, both Java and Timor.
We can't figure out how we get there.
- We'll get there. We have to swim soon.
(saw rasping)
- Not hungry?
(monkeys howling)
(birds chirping)
You hungry?
(Sally laughs)
(birds chirping)
(prisoners chattering indistinctly)
(water sloshing)
- Saw the American this morning.
- How was he?
- Seems to be holding up.
- Mm.
- And should be
with you smuggling him food each day.
This is probably his washing, too.
- And if it is, what of that?
- Well, nothing.
So why, that he'll settle down long enough
for you to halter him?
- He won't the way things
are now, but I have a plan.
- Hmm, that's always
useful if it's a good one.
- It's a good one, all right.
The parson has promised
me to ask Governor Philip
to make him a doctor, and
when he has something useful
to do, and he feels people trust him-
- Mistress Sally.
May I have a word with you?
(birds chirping)
- What do you want?
- You've been much in my mind of late
since I had business to show
up with Governor Philip,
I thought I should
satisfy myself about you.
- That's very kind of you.
- How do you like your new occupation?
- It's not half as bad
as I thought it would be.
- Good, but the smoke from open fires
and the vapours from boiling soap,
not the best thing for the complexion.
- By the time I leave here,
my complexion won't matter.
- My vessel leaves for
home in a week or two.
It shall be a very pleasant voyage,
no troublesome cargo, ample quarters,
the best of food and wine,
interesting excursions ashore
to Cape Town and Tenerife.
- What happens when we get to England?
- A word in the right quarter,
and a pardon is not beyond
the realm of possibility.
- I have a feeling I'm gonna like it here.
- Hmm.
I'm afraid you're allowing
sentiment to cloud your judgement.
- Yes, that's right, I am.
- The man's a thief, convicted
and sentenced for life,
and destined, I'm sure, to hang someday.
- He's not a thief, and he'll not hang.
(birds chirping)
- We shall see.
(water sloshing)
(birds squawking)
- At the suggestion of
the reverend Dr. Thynne,
I've been going over your record.
I note that your medical
studies in London were centred
on fever and plague.
- [Hugh] That's right.
- I'm disturbed over a
second unexplained death
in the new settlement at Norfolk Island.
- What is that to do with me?
- If it should be fever or
plague, I would like your help.
- Do you trust a convict to be a doctor?
- If your story is true,
you're not a convict.
And even if you were,
New South Wales and I
would still want your aid.
This can be a great land,
given the same chances
that your own America has had,
a soil by the millions of
acres waiting for the touch
of the plough, pastures
bigger than all of England
waiting for sheep and cattle,
harbours waiting for cities.
And with England already overpopulated,
this could easily realise
the dreams of a new world.
I'd like to persuade you, if I can,
to remain here for the rest of your life.
We need men like you.
Failing that, I'd like to
make a bargain with you.
- What kind of a bargain?
- If you'll assist our doctors
until your pardon arrives,
I will drop the charges brought
against you by Captain Gilbert.
- May I think it over?
- By all means.
- Thank you, sir.
(pensive music)
(footsteps plodding)
- Somehow, I feel you've
bungled things, the way you did
the night he and Spencer got
free in the ship's boat.
You're positive he doesn't suspect you?
- Yes.
- And equally positive
he no longer intends to escape?
- [Conspirator] I'm no
perishing mind reader, but...
(dramatic music)
- But?
- He no longer talks about it.
Oakly's come to an
understanding with Nellie Garth,
and Tallant's near one
with Mistress Munroe
if I'm any judge.
He's taken to his medical
work like a duck to water.
- No escape, I should have to do something
about that when I return
from Norfolk Island.
- Norfolk Island?
Isn't there supposed to be plague there?
- Nonsense, two deaths from malnutrition.
I have the glimmering of an
idea, Sabb, a very neat idea
that will finish him
no matter what he does.
Make certain no one sees
you as you go ashore.
- Not the easiest thing for
a man of my girth. (laughs)
(birds squawking)
(regal music)
- Stand there.
- Tallant, Captain Gilbert
has come here by boat
from Botany Bay to discuss
his, uh, charges against you.
- During my stay at Norfolk
Island and yesterday
at Botany Bay, I had the
opportunity to review
my admiralty law, especially those parts
concerning mutiny and
insurrection upon the high seas.
I found it is my duty to present the facts
before the correct authority,
which in this case
appears to be in London.
It is also my duty to
present the defendant
at the same time.
- You mean to take me back to England?
- I have no choice in the matter.
The Charlotte sails in three days.
- I'm afraid there's
nothing I can do, Tallant.
- Why do you tell me this now?
- I felt it was only fair
to give you the opportunity
to prepare for your voyage
and make such farewells as you care to.
Good day, sir.
(footsteps plodding)
- Even if I survive the
voyage, which I won't,
I'll be hanged when I get to England.
- You have no choice but to escape.
- What I wouldn't give for a
chance at Gilbert's gullet.
- You're not in this, Tom.
- Do you think I'd desert you now?
- [Ned] Count me in, too,
whenever you're ready to go.
- And me.
- We'll need supplies and ammunition.
- Too bad we can't make
use of Gilbert's hunting.
- Hunting, where?
- Stillwater Cove.
He's taking the ship boat
with a couple of men.
He's gonna camp there while
the Charlotte's at Botany Bay.
- Where's Stillwater Cove?
- About 10 miles short of there.
- That's it, Gilbert,
and escape in one bundle.
- That don't sound half bad.
- Ammunition, supplies,
and a good, stout boat,
we're practically in Java already.
- [Ned] And we can use
Gilbert's hide for a sail.
(gentle music)
- What is it, Parson?
- I've been given permission
to speak to you, Hugh, over here.
(birds chirping)
Sally.
I'll wait, Sally.
- Mrs. Garth just told me
what you're going to do.
You must be out of your mind.
You'll all be caught and hanged.
- [Hugh] How long do you think
Gilbert would let me
live on the Charlotte?
- Well, couldn't you just hide
in the back country till he's gone?
- Ship back to England on the next boat?
- The parson's sure he can persuade
Governor Phillip into sheltering you.
- Philip wouldn't dare.
Even if he did, I'm
tired of being a convict.
- What about the others?
Do you care about them?
No, I suppose you don't.
You're blind to everyone but yourself,
blind to what you've already done
to Mr. Spencer and the Garth boy,
blind to what you're doing
to Nellie and to Tom Oakly,
to me.
(gentle music continues)
- Sorry.
(birds squawking)
(gun clanking)
(pensive music)
Sure about the sentry?
- Sure as I am there's beer in England.
- All clear.
(birds squawking)
(suspenseful music)
(monkeys barking)
(birds chirping)
(footsteps plodding)
(suspenseful music)
Did you see the black man back there?
- There's been a dozen or so
following us for the past hour.
- Well, what's to be done?
- If they're anything
like the Indians at home, if we...
don't bother them,
they won't bother us.
Come on.
(waves lapping)
(leaves rustling)
(waves continue lapping)
(wood clattering)
(fire crackling)
(wings fluttering)
- Here, did you hear something?
- No.
- Stay where you are.
Inching, can take that musket.
Where's Gilbert?
- He's in the tent.
- Keep 'em covered.
(canvas rustling)
- Ah, Mr. Tallant.
- [Hugh] Get out of there.
- Welcome to Stillwater Cove.
- I don't think we'd
be so welcome, Captain,
if you knew what we intended.
- Oh, but I do.
You intend to steal my
boats and such provisions
as we have here and then proceed to Java,
having presumably wreaked some sort
of vengeance upon my person.
- You seem pretty sure of our plans.
- I am, and also of mine.
Now, if you'll be good
enough to look behind you.
(dramatic music)
- Down with those muskets.
Down with them, I said.
Line them up by the boat
and put them in irons.
- Very well, sir.
All right, line 'em up over there.
- I was afraid I might
have to wait some time
before seeing you hanged,
gentlemen, but now.
Sabb.
- Yes, sir?
- Put this is my tent. Fetch my pistol.
- Yes, Captain, that I will.
(dramatic music continues)
- Your unsavoury friend
has been most useful to me.
Without his loyalty and resourcefulness,
this scheme would never have evolved.
Fetter them securely, Sergeant.
The Charlotte won't be here
until sometime tomorrow.
- Aye, aye, sir.
- I suppose you realise, Tallant,
I never had the slightest intention
of taking you back to London.
- I do now.
As long as I'm gonna hang...
(fist thudding)
(dramatic music)
- Your pistol, sir.
(gun clanking)
- I'm not gonna kill you now,
'cause that would deprive me
of the very great pleasure
of watching Mistress Sally's face
when you dance at the rope's end.
- Sir, there are some natives watching
from the brush over there.
It looks as if they mean to attack.
- [Captain] A shot or
two will discourage that.
Discharge a few rounds at them.
- Very well, sir.
- [Hugh] Better leave them alone
if you don't want trouble.
- Nonsense, take cover.
(suspenseful music)
Fire at will.
(gunshots blasting)
(spear thudding)
- [Soldier] There are
some more over there.
Don't let them get into the clearing.
(Captain Gilbert grunts)
(gunshots blasting)
- [Soldier] I can't see them, sir.
- [Soldier] Shoot higher.
(gunshots blasting)
(dramatic music)
- I say.
- Reload as fast as you can.
Tread carefully.
- Pull it out.
- Do no good.
- Blasted, you pull it out.
- You'll bleed to death.
- You're lying.
(gunshots blasting)
(dramatic music continues)
Perhaps I shan't see you hang after all.
(gunshots blasting)
(dramatic music continues)
- Too exposed, should
get behind the ridge.
All right, controlled volleys.
- [Soldier] Take Aim.
Fire.
(gunshots blasting)
Load.
- [Soldier] I'll load for ya.
- Take aim.
Fire.
(gunshots blasting)
(dramatic music continues)
Aim.
Fire.
(gunshots blasting)
Aim.
Fire.
(gunshots blasting)
- Not a sign of them anymore.
- We got them.
- And we've got you.
(waves lapping)
Now, your arm's good as new.
- What do you intend to do now?
- Take the boat.
- I meant about us.
- You can send one of your men
back to the settlement for help.
- I found Sabb, Hugh, what was left of him
after the black men got through.
- Four dead, two wounded.
- Three wounded, I've
got a scratch on my arm.
- Take off your shirt, and
I'll have a look at it.
Tom, load the boat.
- All right.
- Sit down.
- All right, you men, lend a hand here.
Get that gear into the boat.
- It's deep, but the bone's unhurt.
Couple of weeks, you'll never know.
How long have you had
that lump on the arm?
- Mm, two or three days, I think.
- Headaches and chills?
- Yes, yes, how did you know?
- Anybody else got any swelling like that?
- Uh, yes, uh, Malfi over there for one
and one or two others aboard ship.
- Who's Malfi?
- That'd be me.
- Hugh, Hugh.
The Charlotte coming into shore.
(majestic music)
- We'll never get away in the boat now.
- We'll have to head inland.
- No, we're heading
back for the settlement.
- Hugh, that don't make sense.
- It will if we get that
before the Charlotte does.
(regal music)
- Governor Philip.
- What is it?
- Three of the escaped prisoners, sir.
They were caught just outside the colony.
(footsteps plodding)
Tallant, there'll be no
possible explanation.
- Punish us any way you want, Governor.
But first, make sure that nobody lands
from the Charlotte when it arrives.
- And why should I do that?
- There's plague on board.
- Are you certain of this?
- Yes, sir.
- [Governor] See that the ship
is quarantined on arrival.
- Very good, sir.
(gentle music)
- Pettis here is our last case, Doctor.
- When was he taken?
- Nine days ago.
- Hmm, and none since then?
- None and no fever.
- You performed wonders.
The governor will be delighted.
- Then you take my word
for that it's over?
- Even if I didn't, I can hardly refuse
to believe the evidence of my own eyes.
You may hold on the quarantine, Pendleton.
- [Pendleton] Aye, aye, sir.
(dramatic music)
(children laughing)
- Sally, someone wants to see ya
on the knoll back at camp.
Go on, lass.
(gentle music)
(birds squawking)
(gentle music continues)
- [Hugh] Sally.
- What are you doing here?
- Waiting for you.
- Is it true the governor's
dropped all charges against you?
- Against all of us.
He's offered to let me go back
to England to get my pardon.
- When will you be sailing?
- I won't.
(gentle music continues)
(birds chirping)
(leaves crunching)
(majestic music)