(dramatic music)
(people speaking in Spanish)
(dramatic music continues)
(birds chirping)
(lieutenant speaking in Spanish)
(traveler speaking in Spanish)
(objects clanking)
(hand slapping)
(person speaking in Spanish)
(objects rattling)
(Objects clattering)
(tense suspenseful music)
(objects rattling)
(lieutenant speaking in Spanish)
(door thudding)
(metals clanking)
(person speaking in Spanish)
(gas splashing)
(fire roars)
(lieutenant speaking in Spanish)
(guns clicking)
(guns firing)
(woman screaming)
(person speaking in Spanish)
(woman screaming continues)
(lieutenant speaking in Spanish)
(woman wailing)
(gun firing)
(bright upbeat music)
(baggage thuds)
- Export metal.
(bright upbeat music continues)
(wipers squeaking)
(wipers thudding)
In Mexico, it never rains.
(bright upbeat music continues)
(car door thuds)
- What's the trouble?
- If I knew that, I'd be flying.
[Woman] You headed to the coast?
- Yeah.
(seashell curtain clattering)
- Can you drop me at Las Hadas?
- Of course.
- Great.
(dramatic light music)
- Why don't you give a tweak
to your barostatic micro switch
or watch your TOT.
(car door thuds)
(car engine rumbling)
(lively upbeat music)
I'm Joe Wiley.
- Great.
- What do they call you?
- Holbrook.
- That's it?
- That's it.
- I thought it was the igniter circuit.
- How'd you know that?
- I'm an electronics engineer?
I mean, that's what I do for a living.
Actually, I think of myself.
More of an ideas man,
one good gimmick, set for life.
- I thought most of the good
gimmicks have been taken.
- Oh no. I've had at
least a hundred of them.
Everything from suntan
bells to mung beans.
- What are mung beans?
- Bean sprouts?
Unfortunately, rats ate my first harvest
before I could sell 'em.
That put me back about three grand.
I got an ex-wife who wants more alimony,
they've upped the rent on my apartment,
and oh yeah, I just lost my job.
- So that's your story, huh?
- That's it.
What's yours?
- I'm from Philadelphia.
I live in Mexico City.
That's my helicopter
and I'm on my way to Las
Hadas for a quiet weekend.
Make a right up ahead.
- Got it.
(lively upbeat music continues)
(water sloshing)
- So what made you choose Mexico?
- Well, actually, I missed
the plane to Hawaii.
And Mexico seemed affordable and nice.
Have you ever heard of La Mordida?
- No. What's that?
- That, Wiley, is the bite,
Spanish word for inflation.
Maybe you should give Las Hadas a try.
- What's there?
- There are a lot of wealthy women there.
It's a gold mine for any man
with a little charm and initiative.
I really impressed you, huh?
- There's only one problem.
- What's that?
- Women are going for
younger men these days.
Well, nothing beats experience.
- Except stamina.
(bright upbeat music)
(car engine rumbling)
- I think I'm wearing the wrong car.
- Don't sell yourself short, Wiley.
You do all right.
You got a good body.
(car honking)
- What a surprise, madam.
Welcome to Las Hadas.
Let me help you.
- Senora Holbrook.
- Hello, Carlos.
- So delighted to see you.
We didn't think you were coming.
Senor Argenti will be so happy.
- The man in the blue shirt.
Do the impossible,
find him a room for the night.
- [Carlos] Of course.
(gentle suspenseful music)
- Hello?
What the hell?
- I thought this was my suite.
- (speaks in Spanish), senor.
This apartment is for Senor Prentis.
You see?
(speaks in Spanish)
- Well, I'm,
I'm sure you can find Mr.
Prentis a better suite.
(person speaking in Spanish)
Sorry about the mix up.
- Oh, that's perfectly all right.
Come on, I wasted enough time.
(phone ringing)
- Hello,
- [Caller] Mr. Prentis, the
samples have been delivered.
- What?
- [Caller] In the draw beside your bed.
(gems clicking)
- I'm looking at them now.
- [Caller] You are familiar
with our operation.
We propose the following,
6,000 carats at 500 a carat.
The quality of course equal
to those you now have.
- That sounds reasonable.
- [Caller] We'll show you
further samples in the morning.
- Where?
- [Caller] Playa Soledad at nine o'clock.
(gentle music)
- 6,500.
(lively sultry music)
- Liliana, you look divine.
(lively wondrous music)
(group chattering)
- Hi.
Are you here alone?
- Yeah, my wife couldn't make it.
- Oh, that's too bad.
May I ask why?
- She just divorced me.
- Oh, did she take you for everything?
- No, I got to keep the goldfish.
- Oh.
- Looks good to me.
- Oh, lunch tomorrow?
- I can't.
- Would it make any
difference if I were rich?
- But you aren't, are you, Wiley?
- Isn't she a little
outta your price range?
- Not for long.
- I believe you have a Mr.
Prentis registered here.
- Yes.
- Would you make sure that he gets this?
- For you, senor, it would be a pleasure.
- Mr. Prentis?
- [Prentis] Yes, thank you.
- Oh, I'm glad you liked them.
As the first step,
let me propose 6,000
carats at $600 a carat,
the quality the same as the samples.
(car engine rumbling)
(waves splashing)
(car door thuds)
Hi.
- We thought you might have
gone to the wrong beach.
They all look so much alike.
You know Mr. Prentis?
(Joe grunts)
(bodies thudding)
(gun firing)
- [Prentis] Drive him into the sea!
(guns firing)
(waves crashing)
(Joe groans)
(guns firing)
(water splashing)
(thrilling music)
- Welcome aboard.
(Joe groans)
(crowd chattering)
Out.
Here, eat this,
it'll help you get your strength back.
Pull your pants down.
- What?
- Well, unless you wanna
wait until it gets affected.
- All right, I can do it.
- Here, hold this.
(Joe groans)
- Ow.
How does it look?
- You'll survive as long
as you don't look down.
So you're really an electronics engineer?
- Yeah, and I'm a pretty good one too.
- Hmm, it's hard to picture.
You're lucky it's only a flesh wound.
- Well, it's my flesh.
- It is also your fault.
- Well, I'm sorry if I
lost you some business.
- What's that supposed to mean?
- There's only one difference
between you and me,
you just happen to be in a
higher price range, that's all.
(Joe screams)
(upbeat playful music)
(car honking)
(man speaks in Spanish)
(Liliana speaks in Spanish)
(car honking)
(car door thuds)
(group speaking in Spanish)
- This is Mr. Wiley.
He'll be staying with us for a few days.
(staff speaks in Spanish)
(Joe speaks in Spanish)
(mysterious music)
Welcome to my house.
I'm sure you'd like to rest up.
Josephina will show you to your room.
(mysterious music)
(dramatic music)
- What's the matter?
- Talk to me, Wiley.
- About what?
- Anything.
Tell me about one of your gimmicks.
- What did that priest say?
- It's my sister.
A few weeks ago,
she went up into the mountains
with a group of students.
- Where?
- Columbia.
She's been reported missing.
That's all I know.
- Why South America?
- Because as the younger sister,
she was always trying to
go one step further than me
and I had already gotten as far as Mexico.
- And your parents?
- Mother had the money, dad the pedigree.
Perfect match till they
drank a hole in the marriage.
I came along as a sort of penalty
for a mad moment in a parking lot
after a party in Scarsdale.
- And your sister?
- Kerry?
She was an act of despair
eight years later.
Mother left the bulk of her estate to me
with a provision for Kerry
and enough money for dad
to keep his wallet working.
- Does your father know about Kerry?
- He wouldn't be interested.
- What's he do?
- When he is not drinking?
He's connected with the diamond business.
- Then he is not hurting.
- Oh, if you think that money
is the answer to everything.
- I never had enough to know.
- If you did, would
your life be different?
- Well, I could be with a woman like you
and not feel insecure.
- You feel insecure now?
- In one way.
But in another, I feel good enough.
- Which way is that?
- This way.
(water splashes)
(group laughing)
- Meno.
- As I was on my way back to Columbia,
I decided to surprise you.
I hope I'm not intruding.
- Of course not.
I'll just tell Josephina
to prepare your room.
- Yes, just for one night, thank you.
- Well, I must change.
Wiley, you'll find dry
clothes in your room.
- Mr. Wiley.
I don't believe we've met.
How do you know Holbrook?
- Oh, we met while I was drowning.
- You do seem to have
a fondness for water.
How long do you plan to stay here?
- Why?
- I like to know better
the man I find in the
early hours of the morning
with my fiancee.
- You didn't tell me you were engaged.
Are you?
- Not only do you ask too many questions,
but you always ask the wrong ones.
- Well, who is that guy anyway?
- He's a very important man in Bogata.
- Are you gonna go away with him?
- He can help me find my sister.
Can you?
(gun firing)
(gun booms)
- You are a very good
spectator, Mr. Wiley.
You do not interfere too much.
- No more games tonight, Meno.
- Excuse me.
I must speak with Josephina.
- I understand that you're
an electronics engineer.
- That's right.
- In Columbia, I have
electronics for surveillance.
The best experts in the
world built by installation.
You should come and see
it and maybe work for me.
- What makes you think I'm good enough?
- I'm incredibly intuitive
when it comes to judging a man.
I'm seldom wrong.
Come see everything.
Perhaps you can improve on it.
I pay handsomely and you
could even steal a little.
Think about it.
- Good morning.
- Where's Mussolini this morning?
- He's gone.
He thanks me, sends me his heart,
and says goodbye to you.
He hopes you'll come to Columbia with me.
- All my gear is down at Las Hadas.
- As far as Las Hadas is concerned,
you we're never registered.
- Oh, that's terrific.
I'm out 2,000 bucks.
- Well, look at the bright side,
you get to go to Bogota.
How much do you know
about emeralds, Wiley?
- [Joe] Well, they have a
way of causing me trouble.
- [Liliana] 95% of the
world's finest stones
come from Columbia.
The government gave up trying
to control them years ago.
They gave it over to a private concession.
- [Joe] And Argenti?
- [Liliana] He is the concession.
- [Joe] And he's the ticket
to finding his sister.
- [Liliana] Precisely.
- [Joe] And I'm invited.
- [Liliana] There are no
gimmicks down there, Wiley.
- [Joe] Just emeralds.
- [Liliana] Yes, just emeralds.
$25,000 a carat for finding a
little green chip in the mud,
makes killing easy.
(sombre music)
(bells ringing)
(child cries)
(crowd chattering)
(door thuds)
Tell Miguel I'm here.
(eerie electronic music)
(elevator door thuds)
(eerie electronic music continues)
- You are now in the very
heart of my concession.
We are in the center of a city,
but one word from me and
the perimeter is closed.
And up here, I'm in my own fortress.
Every two days,
the emeralds are brought
here from the mines.
60 out of every hundred are good,
30 are very good,
and 10 are the finest in the world.
(machine buzzing)
This is my friend Jaap,
a diamond cutter, the best.
He was called supremo when
he worked for me in Milano.
We left together.
How long ago was it, 10 years?
- 11.
I left a world behind
and started a new life.
The only thing that remains
from the old world is Jaap.
He has stayed by my side through it all.
He never complains but
he misses the diamonds,
like me.
- Meno, Meno, forget diamonds.
We don't even mention the word.
- You're right.
Weight for weight and quality for quality.
The emerald is better, hmm?
- No.
(machines thumping)
- Here, we keep all our data,
who is interested in emeralds,
what they wish to buy.
We trade mostly outside the country
to avoid unnecessary
government inconveniences.
We've even done business
at certain resorts.
It's nice to combine
business with pleasure.
Don't you agree, Mr. Wiley?
Since Holbrook seems to trust you
and I, in turn, trust her judgement ,
I will now show you something
very few people are privileged to see.
(elevator thuds)
Other than that elevator,
there's no way in.
- No fire escape?
- No stairs.
- We are completely isolated
from above and below.
- What is above?
- The sky.
- I'm impressed.
- Is it not ingenious to
have my fortress in the sky
instead of the usual hole in the ground?
Now I will show you how I,
Meno Sebastiano Argenti,
am the most fortunate of men.
(door whirring)
Follow me please.
(dramatic electronic music)
You may touch if you wish.
60 or $70 million worth.
And tomorrow, there'll be more.
(dramatic electronic music continues)
This is Jochim Kellerman,
chief of my control section.
Mr. Wiley, shall we continue?
(dramatic music)
This vault is cadmium-based steal.
There isn't a torch in existence
hot enough to cut through it.
- How do the stones get here?
(doors rumbling)
(sirens blaring)
(cars honking)
(traffic roaring)
- All deliveries from the mines
come here directly by helicopter.
A plane one mile up in the
sky can set off the alarm.
And if anyone landed on this roof,
how would they get down?
You're an expert.
Can it be improved upon?
- Not by me.
(birds chirping)
- Mr. Wiley, we have not met.
I am General Botero.
The senora told me
you are very interested in
our ancient excavations.
- Is that a fact?
- General Botero has given us a jeep.
- Oh, terrific.
- Thought you'd like the idea.
- But the mountains, the bandidos.
I will send an armed escort with you,
It will be safe.
- General Botero, Wiley is a crack shot.
Aren't you, Wiley?
- Yeah, my aim's getting
better all the time.
(disc thumps)
(car engine rumbling)
(car engine roaring)
(dramatic sombre music)
I am sorry for your grief, senora.
But I've stood by many graves,
my sadness has dried up.
The army killed your sister.
The army, the emeralds, and a man's greed.
(dramatic sombre music continues)
- Would you like some water?
Hey.
You know, it's not against
the rules to cry in here.
It's okay.
(car engine rumbling)
- [Miguel] Hey, Holbrook!
Hi.
- Miguel.
- I'm sorry about your sister.
She was a friend and a compatriot.
- Is there anything I can do?
Is there anything you need?
- We're on our way back into the hills.
With a jeep, we might
stand a better chance.
- It's yours.
- It's good to have you with us.
(Miguel speaks in Spanish)
- You're not really serious
about joining up these guys, are you?
- Why not?
- Well, isn't one death enough?
- You don't understand, Wiley.
She believed in their cause.
- Yeah, but you don't.
You're just taking her place.
- I'm going up there.
- Hey, friend, where you from?
- New York.
- Yeah, I used to live there myself.
- Well, you never know when
you're gonna run into somebody
from the old neighbourhood.
- They didn't have no
blinds in my neighbourhood.
(car engine rumbling)
(chicken clucking)
- Where are we going?
- This guy's digging up
emeralds all over his farm,
so we made a little trade.
We pick his coffee beans,
he gives us the emeralds.
- Great deal for the old guy.
- We pick three or four days per emeralds,
in a month, we come
back to pick his coffee,
and all we gotta do is get
them down the mountain.
- Without getting our throats cut.
Hey, Lucho.
- [Lucho] Hey, Miguel.
- Come meet some tourists from New York.
They think coffee grows in cups.
(Miguel speaks in Spanish)
- Please, (Lucho speaks in Spanish).
- Tomorrow, we dig for green ice.
(metals clanging)
(Lucho speaks in Spanish)
(dramatic music)
(objects clanking)
- How much?
- Oh, not the best.
300 a carat maybe.
Say, 200 carats.
- 300 a carat.
- $60,000
and the old man still wants
to grow his coffee beans.
(cicadas chirping)
(Lucho sighs)
(door thuds)
(Lucho speaks in Spanish)
- This is for you.
- Ah, no, senor.
You are in my house, no.
- It is the custom of my country,
the taller guy brings the bottle.
(Lucho speaks in Spanish)
(Joe sighs)
It's so peaceful.
- I can hear the...
- Cicadas.
Cannot you hear the
cicadas in New York, senor?
- In New York, you hear sirens.
(Joe sighs)
But here's to emeralds.
- No, senor, I cannot drink to that.
They are a curse on my land.
- Why?
- If the government knew,
they would come take away my land,
they send me away.
It is my father's land.
We grow coffee.
- But with the money,
you could buy more land,
grow more coffee.
- More, more.
More is the devil, senor.
- I do not know In your country.
In this country, the devil is green.
(Lucho speaks in Spanish)
It is not true in your country, senor?
- It is true.
In my country, the devil is green too.
(Lucho speaks in Spanish)
What's that?
What do I do with it?
- Feel good?
(Joe exhales)
- But I wanna ask you about your coffee.
How many beans do you get off a tree?
- 2,000.
- And how many coffee beans to a pound?
- 2,000, senor.
- So you get one pound
of coffee for every tree.
(Lucho speaks in Spanish)
And where do you sell them?
- I sell him to town.
- You know, in New York
coffee is very expensive.
You could get double
if you exported direct.
- But I have no friend in New York, senor.
- You do now.
(Lucho speaks in Spanish)
- To my friend in New York.
(cups clinking)
(group speaking in Spanish)
(fire roars)
(group laughs)
(Lucho laughs)
(fire roars)
(Joe laughs)
(birds chirping)
- Hey, we thought you ran out on us.
- No such luck.
- Another five minutes, you
would've missed your ride.
- And all the fun that goes with it.
(car engine revving)
(car engine rumbling)
(man speaks in Spanish)
I will stop around the next
curve, then you take over.
(car engine rumbling)
(general speaks in Spanish)
(Liliana speaks in Spanish)
- No.
(general speaks in Spanish)
- Identification.
What are you doing on this road?
We got lost.
- Coming from where?
- - We were sight seeing in Lahva.
- What is your destination?
- Back to the capital.
(guns firing)
- There's enough money here for a general.
His filth.
Go.
And remember, you've got the emerald.
Just get past the next
village and you're okay.
- Let's go, Wiley.
(car engine rumbling)
- There's the Bogata road.
(tyres squealing)
(metals crashing)
- - Welcome to Barbossa, senor.
- Where's Holbrook?
Where's Holbrook?
You bastards.
(Joe groans)
(soldiers speaks in Spanish)
(objects clanking)
(Joe groans)
(soldier speaks in Spanish)
(soldiers speaks in Spanish)
Mothers!
Where's Holbrook?
(Joe groans)
(soldiers speaks in Spanish)
(Joe cries out)
(soldier speaks in Spanish)
(door thuds)
Shit!
(people chattering)
- No.
No! No! No!
(man groans)
(door rumbling)
(pigs squealing)
(man yelping)
(man speaks in Spanish)
(pigs squealing)
(man yelping)
(pigs growling)
(man screams)
(pigs growling continues)
(man groans)
(dramatic suspenseful music)
(man speaks in Spanish)
(car door thuds)
(car engine revving)
- Barbossa is a terrible prison, no?
You were fortunate I came when I did.
When you go home,
you'll have a good story to tell, huh?
(car engine revving)
(car door thuds)
(birds chirping)
(bells ringing)
- I want you to know that I'm
sorry about what's happened.
- I got off lucky compared to my sister.
- I should have stopped you from doing it.
- You couldn't have stopped me,
no one could have stopped me.
I knew what the risks were.
Anyway, we failed.
We have got to come up
with something better.
- Like what?
- I don't know.
Maybe we could hit the mines
before they take the
shipment to the concession.
- After yesterday, they're
gonna be ready and waiting.
- If we could only get our
hands on that helicopter
after it leaves the mine.
- Why are we settling
for one little shipment?
Why don't you just break
into Argenti's sky vault
and take it all?
- Oh, if we only could.
- Yeah, we could.
We could if we're a pair of lunatics.
(crowd chattering)
- All right, let's hear it.
- We've got a plan to rob the concession.
- The concession?
You're crazy, we wouldn't
get past the lobby.
- We don't have to, my plan
starts on the top floor.
- What's he talking about?
- What if I told you that
Wiley can put us on the roof?
- Does he know how to fly?
- No, but I got a friend who does.
(airplane roaring)
- Senor Claude?
- Aye, I'm Claude.
You must be Tomas.
- Yes. Can I take your bike?
- Oh, no, no, no, I
always carry my own bag,
but you can get off Wiley's.
- (speaks in Spanish), senor.
- Put your words right out
of my mouth, old buddy.
- I have kept it hidden for eight years.
Even you didn't know.
- I don't want to know.
They let you live.
You are a king here.
- A king in exile
but from my native country.
You will make a ring for me with emeralds,
but with a diamond at the core,
a wedding ring.
It'll be the last piece
you will make for me
in this godforsaken land.
- You really believe the diamond
concession will forgive you
when you are married to her?
- Her father would make sure that they do.
- Meno, you underestimate them.
They do not forget so easily.
- We will see.
(helicopter whirring)
(helicopter rumbling)
- What do you think?
- It's a whole lot better
than the beansprouts.
- It better be they got
pigs here instead of rats.
Can you get us up there?
- Sure.
- How sure?
- 80-20.
I can get us up there if you
can take care of the pigs.
- All but one.
- And he's yours.
All you gotta do is get
him to say his name.
- You like it?
- I love it.
(bright playful music)
- Very nice.
How much do I owe you?
- Hmm. Only 2,000.
It was a very short game.
- But a sweet experience.
How would you like it?
- Cash would do nicely.
- Cash you shall have for shopping.
I want you to look exceptionally
elegant this evening
for a reception
- This evening?
- To introduce my future wife.
- You don't look happy.
- No, I was just a little
surprised, that's all.
On second thought, I
would rather have a check.
- Why?
- Well, so I can say it
was written by the hand
of Meno S. Argenti.
What does the S stand for?
Salvatore?
- Sebastiano.
- Meno Sebastian Argenti.
- Meno Sebastiano Argenti.
(ominous music)
(crown chattering)
(switch clicking)
(machine whirring)
(case thumping)
(baggage thudding)
- Am I going somewhere?
Soon?
(sighs) Now?
(footsteps thumping)
(birds chirping)
What the hell is going on?
- I would've thought it obvious.
The holiday's over.
You're on a direct flight
to New York this evening.
- And what if I'm not ready to go?
- Then Herado would be happy to help you.
You'll find in your suitcase
a substantial sum for what you did.
- How much?
- More than you're worth, Mr. Wiley.
$1,000.
- Yeah. Well I think I'm worth $10,000.
- 10,000? For what?
- For finding the flaw in your system.
- The flaw. Impossible.
- See for yourself.
- What's all this?
- There's a miscalculation
in your electronic system.
Whoever made out that equation
should go back to school.
I could break into your
building blindfolded.
- Prove it.
- How much time have I got?
- 24 hours, Mr. Wiley.
(dramatic music)
(air whooshing)
- Now remember,
left hand, warm her up, up you go.
Right hand, down you come.
Left hand up, right hand down.
You got it?
- Yeah.
- Good. You nervous?
- No, scared shitless.
- Just hold onto this.
- Alright.
(air whooshing)
All right, now did you get that?
Warm her up (air whooshing),
down you go.
- Yeah.
You take out insurance?
(Claude laughs)
- I got a feeling you don't like heights.
- I can't swim too good either, cowboy.
What else is new?
- I tell you what?
You just hang onto to your butt
and Claude's cloud
hoppers will get you there
sitting down all the way.
(air whooshing)
- Let's fly.
- Jesus, I'm already going the wrong way.
(soothing upbeat music)
Hey, somebody move that tree!
(air whooshing)
- Whoa.
♪ Take a trip tonight ♪
♪ To Jupiter or Mars ♪
♪ Take a dream flight ♪
♪ To the starlight ♪
♪ Just imagination ♪
♪ Only having fun ♪
♪ Look to the stars ♪
♪ And I'll be floating on a cloud above ♪
♪ Floating ♪
♪ Floating on a cloud above ♪
- Wow, man, this is better than walking.
- Don't waste gas otherwise
you will be walking.
(soothing upbeat music)
(alluring romantic music)
- Where is everybody?
- The guests haven't arrived yet.
You might say that we are a little early.
I invited them all for tomorrow.
The night is just for you and me.
- Meno, don't play games.
What is tonight really about?
(Meno chuckles)
- I merely wanted to show
you what would be yours
when you marry me.
- I haven't said I'd marry you.
- But you must.
- Why, Meno? Why must I?
(alluring romantic music continues)
- Have you seen one of these before?
- Yes, of course.
- Your father wears it.
It's the insignia of
a very exclusive club,
the International Diamond concession.
I'm forbidden to wear it now.
- Why?
- There was a theft
of some 10 million
dollars worth of diamonds.
I didn't steal them.
I was an honest, trusted dealer.
But I bought them secretly.
And then little by little, I sold them.
Inevitably, I was caught
by the diamond concession.
The penalty is usually death.
Fortunately, I was well-connected.
They offered me a rather firm exchange,
my life for a one way
passage to South America.
I could continue to live
as long as I never set foot
outside this continent.
- But how would they ever know?
- Have you ever had the impression
that you are being watched?
It's something I've learned to live with
ever since I came here.
Perhaps I'm mistaken.
Unfortunately, there's only
one way to know for sure.
Therefore, I'm offering...
a marriage.
- A union of diamonds and emeralds.
- And with my father's connections,
you would be allowed to leave.
- Not simply to leave,
but to return home.
- I understand.
- You see, I could have lied to you.
Of course, you could live your life
without too much interference from me.
We could allow playthings.
Like Mr. Wiley, for instance.
But for the concession,
we would be husband and wife.
- Do you know that your soldiers
have killed many people?
Have you ever seen the dead
lying in the mountains?
- Just rebels and things.
- And my sister?
- She consorted with scum.
- And that was reason to kill her?
- She killed herself.
If it wasn't here and now,
it would've been tomorrow
in some other country
for some other ridiculous cause.
I must have your answer, please.
- In the morning, Meno.
Goodnight.
(dramatic music)
(air whooshing)
(soothing upbeat music)
♪ Floating on a cloud above ♪
♪ Floating ♪
♪ Take a trip tonight ♪
♪ To the Milky Way ♪
♪ Take a dream flight ♪
♪ To the starlight ♪
♪ And if you never see my face again ♪
♪ You know you had a friend ♪
♪ Look to the stars ♪
♪ And I'll be floating on a cloud above ♪
♪ Floating ♪
♪ Floating on a cloud above ♪
- Park around the back.
(dramatic music)
(air whooshing)
♪ Floating on a cloud above ♪
♪ Floating ♪
- Ease up, hombres,
we don't wanna interrupt the late show.
(air whooshing)
♪ Floating on a cloud above ♪
♪ Floating ♪
Dead on target.
♪ Floating on a cloud above ♪
♪ Floating ♪
(anchor firing)
(soothing electronic music)
(anchor clanking)
(air whooshing)
♪ Floating on a cloud above ♪
♪ Floating ♪
(air whooshing)
(thrilling dramatic music)
(guards speaking Spanish)
(thrilling dramatic music continues)
- Good luck, amigo.
(air whooshing)
- See you in Hawaii, old buddy.
(objects thudding)
(metals clinking)
(air whooshing)
(object squeaks)
(Joe grunts)
(metals clinking)
No butterfingers.
(suspenseful music)
(windows squeaking)
(metals clinking)
(Joe shushing)
Miguel.
Hold the case up to your shoulder.
- Okay, Miguel, a little forward.
A little more.
That's it.
Hold it there.
(machine whirring)
- Hey, who invited him?
Meathead, how do you like it in there?
Can you talk?
- He will.
(switch clicking)
I hope.
- Meno Sebastiano Argenti.
(switch clicking)
(metals clinking)
Now, wait a minute.
We came in,
I went to the window,
he stood here...
About there.
Come forward.
Forward, forward, hold it.
Hold it right there.
(machine whirring)
(voice warping)
(switch clicking)
(machine whirring)
- Meno Sebastiano Argenti.
(door rumbling)
(thrilling dramatic music)
(switch clicks)
(thrilling dramatic music continues)
(Joe speaks in Spanish)
(dramatic suspenseful music)
- It is magic.
(dramatic mystifying music)
We just hijacked an empire.
(dramatic mystifying music continues)
- Okay, enough.
- How much we got?
50 million?
- More like 100.
- Hey, I like you.
You come through first.
What about you guys?
A few mobile homes, huh?
Let's go.
- Mobile homes nothing.
That's Peace Corps talk.
(suspenseful music)
- Where the hell are your guys?
- Relax, the ball games over, we won.
- The hell we have.
We just emptied a man's bag.
You think he's gonna lay around
and chalk it up to one for the cause?
- He's finished, man.
It's only a matter of
time before he goes down,
and bang, we get our country back.
All my life, I fought for this change,
and now I'm gonna see it with my own eyes.
- I hate to disappoint you, Miguel,
but there are a hundred Argentis out there
just waiting their turn.
Just because you knock over one
doesn't mean another one's
not gonna pop up tomorrow.
- A hundred Miguels can
pop up tomorrow too.
- Hey, you don't get it,
do you (speaks in Spanish)?
There's a network out there
full of people like me
and my brothers and sisters
starting fires all over the world.
It's global, man.
And me and you will go
down as Robin Hoods.
- Robin Hood?
He stole from the rich.
He didn't blow up airports,
he didn't kill hostages.
- Same, man.
Today's a whole different strategy.
Sometimes you gotta do things
you don't like for the cause.
- Well, just remember, Miguel,
we got different causes.
(engine rumbling)
Here comes the cavalry.
You want to jump first?
- I don't wanna jump at all.
(engine rumbling)
- All right, keep the line taut.
And pray.
Hard.
(metals clinking)
(truck thuds)
(person speaking Spanish)
(Miguel groans)
(dramatic ominous music)
(person speaking Spanish)
- Go.
Go.
(person speaking Spanish)
(engine rumbling)
(air whistling)
(bag thuds)
- Where's Miguel?
- He didn't make it.
We're going back for him.
- He said go.
- Now, come on, let's
get the hell outta here
or we'll all end up back in that pig farm.
(car door thuds)
Let's go.
(tense sombre music)
(suspenseful upbeat music)
(helicopter rumbling)
(suspenseful upbeat music continues)
- It's too late.
It's over.
You've been living off
the people for too long,
and tonight it ended.
It's finished for your guys.
- What is he talking about?
- Go look in your vault.
We took back what you stole.
- Get him up!
(suspenseful upbeat music continues)
(object creaking)
I regret that me you will
not take to Barbossa.
(object creaking)
(rope snaps)
(Miguel thuds)
(glass containers shattering)
- It was the girl.
- No, it was you.
You let them rob me.
- It was the girl, I have proof.
- You are mad.
You know nothing.
- All the time you've spent with the girl,
she was working to destroy you.
Face the truth where she is concerned.
(object thumping)
(picture frame shatters)
(dramatic music)
(car door groaning)
(dramatic suspenseful music)
- You sure this is the right place?
- Miguel said this is
where they'd find us.
(dramatic suspenseful music continues)
- Trouble.
- Americano?
- Canadians actually.
- Where are you going?
- Fishing.
Look out, those are fish hooks,
you could stick yourself.
- We are with Miguel.
He's dead.
You come with me.
I am going to give you
the best boat we've got.
But you'd better take it now
before the Yankees who own
it get back from sightseeing.
- Don't you think
we ought to turn the
emeralds over to them?
- No, you hand them the stones,
you hand them their death warrant.
(lively upbeat music)
- Well, feeling any richer?
- They're not ours, Wiley.
- Well, what are we going to do?
- We're gonna deliver them
the way Miguel wanted.
(Joe exhales deeply)
- What? In care of the revolution?
What's our address?
Maybe we should just mail one
to every family in the country.
- If there's something on your mind,
why don't you just say it?
- Why should anything be on my mind?
I mean, I just risked my life
for something that doesn't belong to me.
Now I'm riding in a stolen boat
with someone who hasn't
even got the courtesy
to tell me where we're going.
- My family has a beach house in the Keys.
(ominous music)
- They know we're coming?
- There's seldom anyone there.
- Well, that's good.
Then they won't mind if
we don't show for dinner.
Here come the Marines.
(alarms bleating)
I'll see you on the pig farm.
- [Lieutenant] Mae
West, stop your engines.
We're coming aboard.
- Mr. and Mrs. Goldenheimer,
you're American?
- That's right.
- You're registered out of Miami.
- Right.
- You're going back to Miami?
- We're trying.
- It's a long way.
- It's home.
(lieutenant speaks in Spanish)
- Forgive me, senora,
you have to be patient.
We have much trouble
with the marimberos running
marijuana to your country.
- A beer, lieutenant?
- No, (speaks in Spanish).
(glass bottles clanking)
(door thuds)
(officer speaks in Spanish)
(lieutenant speaks in Spanish)
Why do you bring guns
on a pleasure cruise?
- Well, these are dangerous
waters, lieutenant.
- Perhaps.
- Would you bring your
wife out here unarmed?
- No, I wouldn't.
What is this?
- That's a bait well.
- This is bait for commercial fishing.
Do you have a license?
- Well, it all came with a boat.
- It is illegal.
For you, it's a sport.
For our fishermen, it is their living.
There is a heavy fine.
(water splashing)
(gentle serene music)
This time, I'll let
you off with a warning.
Senor.
Senora.
(dramatic sombre music)
(lieutenant speaks in Spanish)
(engine rumbling)
- Ah, I don't believe it.
- Unfortunately, no one else will either.
- All for nothing.
(waves crashing)
(dramatic sombre music continues)
(dramatic suspenseful music)
(glass shattering)
Smells a bit musty.
- Open the windows.
- Anything you say, Princess.
- Nobody uses the place much anymore.
Oh, this house brings back memories.
- Happy ones?
- Well, it's the only time
we ever acted very much like a family.
(cabinet thuds)
- Oh, the phone's dead.
- You expecting a call?
There's not much to eat.
- I'm not hungry.
Who's that?
- The postman checking the
mailbox of an empty house?
- Stop being paranoid.
- Does Argenti know about this place?
- What do you think?
- That's what I thought.
- How far away is the nearest neighbour?
- The local store is
about a half mile away.
- Yeah, well, you got a bullhorn
in case we gotta yell for help?
What are you doing?
- I thought I'd play some music.
- Oh, that's just what we need.
We ought to give a party
and tell everybody we're back in town.
Mussolini as men could be
here any minute, you know?
- Relax.
- I don't wanna stand around here
and wait for these people to get here.
- Well, you are the ideas man,
you come up with something.
In the meantime, I'm
gonna go get some food.
You need anything?
- Yeah, I'd like a
Phillips head screwdriver,
some double-sided tape,
and a soldering iron.
(door thuds)
(footsteps thumping)
- What are you doing?
- Oh, I think I figured out a way
to protect this place and maybe ourselves.
- I miss you.
- Really?
- I'm getting used to having you around.
- That's gonna be a problem
if your friend Argenti has
anything to say about it.
- Let's just forget him, shall we?
- Oh, I'd love to.
(object thuds)
What was that?
- Wiley.
Come on.
- Oh, I, I think one of
us ought to stay awake.
- Well, I have a better idea.
Why don't we both stay awake together?
- I, I don't think that,
that that's practical.
- No, but it could be enjoyable.
(romantic sultry music)
- How can you think of
that at a time like this?
- It could be our last night together.
(romantic sultry music continues)
(door thumping)
(alarm beeps)
(lively cheerful music)
(alarm blaring)
- The kitchen, find the fuse box.
(alarm blaring continues)
(fuse box fizzles)
(person screaming)
(Liliana groans)
(footsteps thumping)
- Holbrook we've gotta
get the hell out of here.
This is madness.
- Wiley.
- What?
- In case we don't make it,
- Oh, don't even mention that.
- I just want you to know,
what happened last night-
- This is not the time.
- Was incredible.
- Come on.
- [Joe] Let's call a
taxi and head for Miami.
Get the first plane to New York.
(guns firing)
(voice-over warping)
(gun firing)
- I am gonna head for the beach
and try and draw their fire.
You, find some cover for yourself.
Go!
(tense suspenseful music)
- [Meno] Kellerman, have you found them?
- Everything is proceeding as planned.
- [Meno] Don't tell the girl.
- She's still alive.
- [Meno] I'm coming ashore.
- That is not wise.
- [Meno] Even the diamond
concession would understand.
Kellerman, wait for me.
(guns firing)
(dramatic suspenseful music)
(gun firing)
(dramatic suspenseful music continues)
(gun clicks)
(fists thumping)
(Herado grunts)
(Joe groans)
(suspenseful music)
(fist thumping)
(Joe groans)
(suspenseful music continues)
(plank cracking)
(Herado groans)
(suspenseful music continues)
(guns firing)
- Dear God.
(footsteps thumping)
(door thumping)
(couch thuds)
(dramatic sombre music)
(Liliana moans)
(Liliana sighs)
(Liliana groan)
Hello, Wiley.
(Liliana groans)
(dramatic sombre music continues)
- A dart.
Argenti wanted me alive.
- Can we get out of this fantasy land now
and get back to reality, please?
(door creaks)
(sombre ominous music)
- Not quite yet, Mr. Wiley.
Not until you return every single stone.
- Well, we're gonna
need a little deep sea
diving equipment for that.
- Liliana, you know me well.
- Impress upon Mr. Wiley
that in times like this,
it is best not-
(dramatic foreboding music)
You?
The concession?
All these years,
you were the one I trusted.
(gun firing)
(gun clatters)
(body thuds)
- I warned you, Meno,
so many times.
(waves crashing)
(footsteps thumping)
(upbeat electronic music)
- Wiley, what exactly are we doing
down on the Brooklyn docks?
- I got a little business to take care of.
It shouldn't take me
more than a few minutes.
- It's not another gimmick.
(car door thuds)
(machine whirring)
(sirens blaring)
- This is just a sample consignment.
I should be receiving monthly
shipments from now on.
Well, be sure to check with me next time.
Ask for Linda, all right?
(engine rumbles)
(sirens blaring)
(coffee beans clattering)
(dramatic music)
(trunk thuds)
- What were you doing, counting beans?
You'll never learn will you, Wiley?
- No, I guess I'll never learn.
(romantic music)
♪ Tenderness is just a way of giving ♪
♪ Tenderness ♪
♪ Will help the phase
you're going through ♪
♪ And when you need
something to dream on ♪
♪ There's me to lean upon ♪
♪ Don't pass me by ♪
♪ Just remember I'll be there ♪
♪ To take your hand ♪
♪ Oh, darling, I'll be there ♪
♪ To help you try to understand ♪
♪ Tenderness ♪
♪ Can take away your sadness ♪
♪ Can brush away the tears for you ♪
♪ And when the hurt is gone forever ♪
♪ Please remember ♪
♪ You could be so tender to me ♪
♪ Tenderness will see us through ♪
♪ Cause I'm falling in love with you ♪
♪ Reach out for me ♪
♪ Take my hand ♪
♪ Cause I'm falling ♪
♪ Falling in love with you ♪