(DRAMATIC TRUMPET MUSIC)
(BRIGHT MUSIC)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
There she is.
(CROWD MURMURS)
There she is, the hussy.
(TENSE MUSIC)
(CROWD GRUMBLING)
Monster!
(WOMAN SHOUTS)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
(OMINOUS MUSIC)
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC)
(GENTLE MUSIC)
Hawley Harvey Crippen,
you are charged
with the willful murder
of Cora Belle Crippen,
on the 1st of February last.
Are you guilty or not guilty?
Not guilty.
Ethel Le Neve,
you are charged with being
an accessory after the fact
in the murder of Cora Belle Crippen
on the 1st February last.
Are you guilty or not guilty?
Not guilty.
You may be seated.
No, I’m very sorry, miss.
Now, come along, please,
it's not a peepshow.
Keep back, please.
Not fair,
I waited all night for a seat.
Now, come along, please.
Keep moving.
You'll read all about it
in the newspapers.
As an American citizen,
Dr Crippen's wife, known
professionally as Belle Elmore,
was not able to obtain much
employment in this country
in her capacity as singer
and music hall entertainer.
Although the couple
presented a surface appearance
of affection and normality,
in fact, the prisoner had ceased
to cohabit with his wife
for some three years.
During the exact period
that he'd been carrying on
an intrigue
with a young woman, Ethel Le Neve,
who had been in his employ
for a number of years as a typist.
Thus, an innocent woman,
whose only crime was to stand
between this man, Crippen,
and his illicit ambitions,
became an obstacle
which he resolved to remove
to satisfy his own evil ends.
A deadly purpose
which he carried out,
as the Crown will prove,
by murdering his unfortunate wife
and then mutilating
and dismembering her body
so as to mask its identity.
You will see, gentlemen,
that we're dealing with a crime
of so frightful a nature
as almost to defeat description.
An educated medical man,
using his knowledge and skill
gained for the succour of the sick
to rid himself of the encumbrance
of his legally wedded wife.
Which he effected by means so awful
that nowhere in the history
of British jurisprudence
is there a case to equal it
for horror
and callous indifference
to suffering.
The murderous work of a veritable
monster in human form.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
(BRIGHT PIANO MUSIC PLAYS UPSTAIRS)
♪ I'm not a one-man woman
♪And I'll tell you why
♪ One man ain't enough for me
♪ I’ve got a great big heart
♪And you can have a part
♪ But don't think
it's yours exclusively
♪There's a lot of love in me
♪That I'm willing to share
♪ I'd rather have a lot of arms
than just one pair
♪ So come along
and get me if you can
♪ I'm not a one-man woman
♪ But I’ve got to have
a one-woman man ♪
(BOTH LAUGH)
Oh, I'm exhausted!
Don't I get any reward
for all this key-bashing?
Well, you can talk to me
if you like.
Well, I'm a bit more
fundamental than that, love.
(SHE GIGGLES)
(BELLE GIGGLES)
(SHOE THUDS)
What are you doing, spying on me?
I dropped a shoe.
You can't give that to a lodger.
There's dust on it.
Look, I said, do this shoe again!
Yes, all right.
I'll just get rid of the clean ones
first.
(SHOE THUDS)
Doesn't he ever go on strike?
Well, against what?
Well, even a skivvy
gets one day a week off.
Oh, it's good for him.
Keeps him out of trouble.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
Does he ever get into any?
Ah, you'd be surprised.
Come on now, let's try it again.
All right.
Arthur, get on with you!
I can wait.
- But not for long.
- Mm.
♪ I'm not a one-man woman
♪And I'll tell you why
♪ One man ain't enough for me
♪ I’ve got a great big heart
♪And you can have a part
♪ But don't think
it's yours exclusively
♪ So come along
and get me if you can
♪ I'm not a one-man woman
♪ But I’ve got to have
a one-woman man. ♪
(GENTLE MUSIC)
Hello, Doc.
Hello.
Don't slam the...
(DOOR SLAMS)
(GENTLE MUSIC)
I wish you could prevail upon
your young men
not to slam the front door.
They'll break the glass.
I wish I could prevail on you
to get a move on.
The soup's boiling over.
I just want to bank up the fire.
Well, you can do that later.
- (CAT MEWS)
- Oh, be careful!
- Sorry, puss.
- (SHE SIGHS)
The cat's got feelings too,
you know.
Tramping around like a great horse.
I assure you,
I didn't do it on purpose.
Well, now where are you going?
To wash.
Oh, use the sink
like everybody else.
Ready when you are, Harry.
Hmm?
Right.
That fellow Marconi's
gone and done it, I see.
Oh? Done what?
Well, sent a wireless signal
across the Atlantic.
Pass that to the doctor,
will you, please?
Aren't the others coming down?
No, they've both have gone out
for the day.
It says here, he thinks we'll
all have wireless receivers
in our houses
during the next 50 years.
For what purpose?
Well, I suppose they'll put out
concerts, lectures,
things like that.
I wonder if they'd use me.
Why not?
It seems a poor sort
of entertainment, though,
when you can't see who's singing.
Where's the bread?
Peter, where's your manners?
Pass the bread.
Funny-looking machine, I must say.
Take the kettle off, will you?
Oh, yes.
Weird.
(WHIMSICAL MUSIC)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
(GENTLE MUSIC)
(LIVELY MUSIC PLAYS IN ROOM)
(BELLE GIGGLES)
You still at it then, Doc?
As you see.
(DISHES CLANK)
Any grub going, do you think?
You better ask Mrs Crippen.
(BELLE GIGGLES LOUDLY)
Oh, better not ask her now then,
Doc, eh?
(HE LAUGHS)
Yeah, well. Night-night, Doc.
I'll, um...
I’ll see you at the dawning.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
(DOOR CREAKS)
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC)
I think I left a book in here.
Oh.
Pardon me.
I’m just taking the bottles up.
Thank you.
We’ve just been rehearsing
my new number.
So I heard.
You wouldn't like a cup of tea
or anything?
No, thank you.
Goodnight, Doc.
Goodnight, Mr Fawcett.
(DOOR THUDS)
- (BELLE GIGGLES)
- (HARRY SIGHS)
Do you think he saw?
Luckily I heard the latch turning
just in time.
- (BOTH LAUGH)
- Your face when he came in.
I told you not to mess me about.
Oh, yes, you were very insistent,
weren't you?
Oh, what the hell.
Will he... Will he say anything?
Well, he'd better not.
If he was halfa man,
I wouldn't be messing around
with boys like you anyhow.
Well, since you are...
Who is it?
Oh, it's you.
Belle...
There's a draught.
(CLOCKTICKS)
Belle, I'm going to have to ask you
to get rid of those young men.
Oh, you are, are you?
Well, we have to take in lodgers.
I'm not using my money
to run this house for you.
I'm not criticising them, or you.
It's just that this
isn't a home anymore.
I didn't know it ever was a home.
You were happy here
when we first moved in.
The house was all right.
I realise I'm not everything
you could wish for in a husband.
But our life together
isn't all that bad.
Well, maybe not for you.
You have everything you need.
I doubt if any of your...
friends have more jewellery
or clothes.
That's not all a woman needs.
We've talked about that
so many times.
That's right,
and all we ever do is talk about it.
I've tried to explain...
How do you think it feels for me?
Sometimes when I walk down
the street,
I can see men watching me
and wanting me,
but I have to beg you
to even touch me.
Please don't cry.
Am I so repulsive?
No, of course it isn't that.
Well, what is it then?
When was the last time
you came to me
as a husband of your own free will?
When was the last time
you kissed me,
let alone made love to me?
You say yourself you don't
lack for male admirers.
But you’re my husband.
I want my husband to admire me.
Look, if you're ill,
why don't you say so?
At least I'd understand that.
No, I'm not ill.
It isn't that.
I don't care about the boys.
I wouldn't want any other man
if you would only treat me
like a woman occasionally.
You'd always want other men.
No, I wouldn't. I wouldn't!
No, no, stay with me tonight.
Stay with me
and I'll get rid of them tomorrow.
(SHE SIGHS)
Don't you find me attractive at all?
Yes, of course I do.
- (SHE SOBS)
- Oh, Peter!
Peter!
(SOMBRE MUSIC)
(PEOPLE CHATTER)
(GENTLE MUSIC)
Shop.
Cab's waiting.
Well, this is it.
The first time I've had
the old heave-ho, I must say.
No, but you do understand?
Frankly, I'm astonished
he put up with it for so long.
Poor little devil.
You'll let us know where you are?
Oh, sure.
Were you happy here, Harry?
The best billet I ever had.
And you will write?
Of course.
Now, look, the cab's waiting.
All right.
(BELLE AND HARRY KISS)
You won't think too badly of me,
will you?
What a question.
Now, look, I must go, really.
Well, good luck.
Bye-bye, Belle.
(DOOR CLOSES)
(PEOPLE CHATTER IN DISTANCE)
Was that Mr Fawcett?
Yes.
I would've said goodbye to him.
Well, he said to give you
his regards.
Well, we'll have to find you
some other interests.
Well, it's just that I get
so lonely here all day by myself.
You don't want to go on
the music halls again, do you?
It's so tough in England.
Besides, all the agents are crooked.
Isn’t there some way you could
take up with show business again?
You like the people,
and it's your natural environment,
after all.
Well, I suppose I could
join the guild or something.
Clara's always asking me to.
What guild is that?
Well, the Ladies' Music Hall Guild.
Looking after members
who've had a hard time.
It's charitable work, really.
They're all very fine women,
and prominent in theatrical circles.
It sounds much more your style.
Of course, if I did want
to go on the stage again,
they'd be able help me
get some decent dates.
Exactly.
I'll go and see Clara
this afternoon.
You could have them meet here,
if you like.
Oh, what a wonderful idea.
Of course, I'd, uh...
I'd need a new dress and a hat.
I saw a beautiful one
in Wight man’s the other day.
It was orange taffeta
and it had puff sleeves
and the neck right down to there.
Why don't you buy it, then?
I could get Mrs Thurman
to run me up something.
Yes, blue perhaps?
I saw a length of blue material
in the market
that was going for a song.
You get whatever you want.
Oh, Peter, you are kind.
(BRIGHT MUSIC)
I know, I'll go up west and see
what they've got in the shops.
Clara will know. What time is it?
Almost 10 o'clock.
Well, I'll have lunch
with Clara first,
and we can arrange
about the meeting, too.
(BRIGHT MUSIC)
(KETTLE HISSES)
The kettle's just boiling.
I don't think they want any more.
Are you sure?
Well, the meeting went on so long,
they have to be getting home.
Do you think it went well?
They certainly liked you.
Mrs Stratton's charming, isn't she?
Well, she's the most important one,
really.
She thinks you're lovely.
If they don't want any more,
I’d better get back.
-You don't have to go early, do you?
- Well, I can't be too late.
Paul will be wanting his supper.
I've something to tell you.
- So we'll meet on Wednesday then?
- Yes, dear, delighted.
I'll write Mr Ogilvie tomorrow
and see if he can let us
have the material.
I’m sure he will.
He's very interested in the guild.
Must you really go so early?
I'm afraid so, my dear.
It's nearly six already.
Well, it was lovely of you to come,
and thank you again for electing me.
Not at all, it's our gain.
It's so nice of you to let us meet
in your charming house.
- Goodbye, Belle.
- Goodbye.
- Goodbye, Mrs Crippen.
I shall look forward to seeing
much more of you in the future.
Oh, it was wonderful!
I told you.
But they're so nice, all of them.
Oh, they're all right. Of course,
we've all got something in common,
being in the theatre,
and that's a help.
What was it you wanted to tell me?
What do you think of it?
Lovely.
I was admiring it
all through the meeting.
Your husband
is really very generous.
Peter?
The only thing I get from him,
I have to wring out of him.
This was a present.
- From guess who?
- Oh, I’ve no idea.
Not Bruce Martin?
- (SHE GIGGLES)
- Yes!
And he wrote me
the most wonderful letter.
It begins,
"To my beautiful brown eyes."
Here, now, read that bit.
Well, what a thing
to say in a letter.
He was always like that.
He just doesn't care.
But what if Peter found it?
It'd do him good to know
what normal men think of me.
Oh, come on.
Peter's a devoted husband.
Everyone says so.
Yes, well, everyone
doesn't have to live with him.
I'm a woman who needs something
a bit more practical and attention,
if you get what I mean.
But he must be mad
to write like this.
Well, it's a special letter.
The anniversary of the day we met.
Now, you take my tip and burn it.
It's far too dangerous
to leave lying about.
Well, perhaps you're right.
Bruce is what I call a man.
If he walked
through that door right now,
you wouldn't see me for dust.
I thought it was all finished
years ago.
Well, only because
he went back to Chicago,
but it's possible
he might come back here,
or we might go to the States.
Oh, then what a celebration
there'd be.
I tell you, Clara, no man ever
made me feel what old Brucie did.
Oh, he's marvellous.
(WHIMSICAL MUSIC)
Mr Martin,
did your relations with
Belle Elmore at any time
come closer than mere friendship?
Absolutely not.
When did you last see her?
About six years ago,
around April 1904.
But you have communicated with her
since then?
Yeah, we've exchanged letters.
Frequently?
Oh, she used to write to me about
three or four times a year.
What kind of letters?
Good wishes, you know,
that sort of thing.
- Where do you live now?
- I beg your pardon?
I said, where do you live now?
Oh, I live in Chicago
with my wife and child.
Was there ever a proposition
that Belle Elmore
should come out to you?
Absolutely not. No such thing.
(MEN MUTTER)
Mr Martin,
as you have given up
the music hall stage,
I take it you were a failure
in that profession?
Absolutely not.
I saw the opportunity of making
a bit more money.
That's why I'm a real estate agent.
I wanted to support my family and...
During Dr Crippen's absence
in America in 1899,
how many times
did you see Mrs Crippen?
I went to her house occasionally.
How often is "occasionally"?
Two or three times a week.
At what hour of the day?
Sometimes in the afternoons
and sometimes in the evening.
But always while Dr Crippen
was absent?
Yes.
Did you write often to Mrs Crippen?
Well, not often.
On what topics?
Friendship.
Were you in love with Mrs Crippen?
Absolutely not.
But you did tell her
that you loved her?
Well, I wouldn't put it
exactly that way.
Did you indicate that you loved her?
Well, I suppose she
might've thought I did.
You mean,
you deliberately misled her?
Well, no,
I wouldn't put it exactly that way.
She meant a great deal to me
as far as friendship was concerned,
but she was a married lady
so it had to be
an entirely platonic friendship.
(PEOPLE LAUGH)
This is not a theatre.
Members of the public
will control themselves
or the court will be cleared.
Mr Martin, kindly answer
this question directly.
Were there any improper relations
between you and Mrs Crippen
at any time?
No, no, absolute not, My lord.
Platonic or not,
did you ever show your esteem
for Mrs Crippen
in any practical ways?
Once in a while I gave her a little
present. Nothing extravagant.
When was the last such gift?
About a year ago.
That would be two or three months
before her disappearance?
Yes, I guess so.
What was this gift?
Oh, a little brooch thing.
An expensive one?
Not very.
How much would it cost, then?
Oh, about ten pounds in your money,
I guess.
And you're telling us
that five years after having had
an entirely platonic friendship
with a married woman whose husband
you had somehow never met,
you sent her a gift
costing around ten pounds?
Well, yes, I like to be
generous with my friends.
Do you have many friends, Mr Martin?
Oh, yes, lots.
No wonder you needed to
take a more remunerative job
than your talents could provide
from the theatre.
(PEOPLE MUTTER)
You may stand down.
I wouldn't mind a bit of platonic
friendship with him myself!
Call Dr David Pepper.
Call Dr Pepper.
Take the book in your right hand
and read the words on the card.
"I swear by Almighty God
"that the evidence I give
shall be the truth,
"the whole truth
and nothing but the truth."
Doctor, I believe you were
requested by the police
to inspect some supposedly
human remains
on a certain date, were you not?
On July 14th this year,
I went to 39 Hilldrop Crescent
with Chief Inspector Dew.
In the cellar there,
I found that part
of the floor had been taken up,
and I saw what appeared to
be a mass of human remains.
Ugh, this is the part I don't like.
Do you want to leave then?
Are you mad?
Just tell me when he's
finished with the gory details.
..from the lower front
portion of the abdomen.
There was a mark on it
which attracted my attention,
and I afterwards examined
it with particularity.
In your opinion, what was that mark?
A scar, a little over
four inches in length.
Having examined the remains,
is it possible to say
whether the dissection
was done by a skilled person or not?
Definitely by a skilled person.
Would the position of the scar
suggest to you
a particular type of operation?
Yes, it would correspond
to an operation in a female person,
for the removal of certain organs.
Did you form an opinion
as to the cause of death?
Yes, by treating the organs
with the usual process,
I found a mydriatic alkaloid
presence.
On further tests,
I found that it corresponded
to hyoscine hydrobromide.
What are the properties
of hyoscine, Doctor?
It is a powerful narcotic, My Lord.
Have you any knowledge of its
medical use?
I have heard
that it is sometimes used
for pacifying
extreme nervous disorders
in certain American hospitals.
What is the fatal dose of hyoscine,
Doctor?
Between a quarter and half a grain.
And what amount of hyoscine
did you find in the remains?
From the amount in the organs,
there would certainly have been more
than halfa grain
in the entire body.
Doctor, just tell us what effect
a fatal dose would have
on a human being.
It would perhaps produce
delirium and excitement at first,
and then the patient
would become drowsy,
and probably die after a few hours.
Does hyoscine
have a distinguishing taste?
It is rather salt and bitter,
but it can be administered in
something with a pronounced flavour.
Like, um, stout beer,
sweetened tea or coffee.
No more questions.
Taking the remains as a whole,
it was impossible
to determine the sex.
That is correct.
As to the mark you claim
was a scar from the abdomen,
what operation in a male person
would cause it in that position?
The removal of stones
from the bladder, for one thing.
Before you formed the opinion
that the mark was a scar,
you had already learned that
Mrs Crippen had an operation.
Certainly.
On July 15th,
did not you and Dr Marshall
at the mortuary
examine the remains
together for some hours?
- We did.
- On that occasion,
you did not come to the opinion
that it was a scar.
I did not see the mark at all
on that occasion.
Was it not three days later,
about July 18th,
that you learned first
from the newspapers
that Mrs Crippen
had a scar on her abdomen?
I cannot remember
when I first heard it.
But it was certainly after your
first examination on July 15th?
Oh, yes.
That'll be all.
(PEOPLE MUTTER)
Call Emily Jackson.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
Take the book in your right hand
and read the words on the card.
"I swear by Almighty God..."
How friendly is she?
She's very devoted to the girl,
but she's so confused.
He may make her say anything.
Hmm.
Now, Mrs Jackson,
Miss Le Neve lived in your house
for some time, did she not?
I was her landlady
for nearly two years.
What were the relations between you?
We were on quite different terms
to the ordinary landlady and lodger.
From your experience of her,
did you notice any change
in her manner
at the end of January
or the beginning of February 1910?
Yes.
One day, she came home looking
very tired and strange.
Did she display other symptoms
of disquiet?
She was greatly agitated.
How did this manifest itself?
Her whole body was trembling.
She looked as though
she'd had some kind of a shock.
Did she give any explanation
for her appearance?
She went straight up to bed.
Later on, I sat up with her
until two o'clock in the morning.
Did she subsequently explain to you
the cause of the shock?
She was too ill
to go to work the next day.
I told her, if she didn't tell me
what was troubling her,
she'd go out of her mind.
What was her reply?
She said it was too dreadful
to talk about.
(CROWD MUTTER)
"Too dreadful to talk about."
Did she later embroider
on that explanation?
No.
Now, up until this time, she'd been
living at home with you continually.
Yes.
Did she remain so?
No.
Then she started
staying away nights.
And when she came back to see you,
what was her manner?
She was radiant.
Was she alone?
No. Dr Crippen was with her.
Did she bring you anything?
Yes.
She brought a number of articles
of women's clothing.
Did she explain where this
clothing had come from?
Yes.
She said it had belonged
to Mrs Crippen, who had gone away.
(CROWD MUTTER)
Mrs Jackson,
how did Miss Le Neve address you?
She called me "Mother".
Would you say you had a good memory,
Mrs Jackson?
Not bad.
I'm forgetful about some things.
Such as dates?
Well, I don't pay much
attention to time normally.
So, when you mention a time
or a date,
it's largely guesswork?
I'm afraid so.
But when the police
interviewed you in July,
six months later than the event
you've just described
to my learned friend,
you naturally tried
to fix the date for them?
Yes, they were most insistent
about that particular date.
You already knew from the newspaper
that Belle Elmore, Mrs Crippen,
had not been seen since
February 1st?
Yes, I'd read that.
Will you tell us,
was the strangeness and shock
you mentioned
confined to the end of January only?
No, she started behaving oddly
at the beginning of the month,
just after the new year.
So we may take it that
for the whole of January,
she was miserable and depressed?
Yes.
Subsequent of the conversation
you have described
to my learned friend,
did you discover
what was really troubling her?
Well, she was upset because someone
in the office didn't like her,
and she was afraid they would
turn Dr Crippen against her.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
Thank you.
That will be all.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
(BRIGHT MUSIC)
Well, I can't make head nor tail
of the doctor's writing again.
Now, what is that?
"Repeat nerve tonic number four."
It could've been Chinese,
as far as I'm concerned.
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
- Morning, Miss Curnow.
- Morning, Doctor.
Dr Crippen not in yet?
He's calling at the chemist
on the way in.
I'd be obliged
if you'd type these up for me?
Of course.
When could they be ready?
By lunchtime.
Unless you're in a rush.
No, that'll be all right.
Well, you've certainly
got what it takes.
What do you mean?
The way Dr Rogers
was looking at you,
I thought he was gonna jump down
inside that blouse.
It's nice, isn't it?
-A present?
- Mmm.
Dr Crippen is very generous.
You must give him that.
Come on, you don't think
it's a secret, do you?
I honestly don't know
what you're talking about.
Oh, no?
Good morning.
Anything in the mail?
Mostly glowing testimonials
from old ladies
who've recovered from sciatica
after using one of your remedies.
Good.
Any orders?
Three.
Only three?
Have you come into money?
No, why?
You have an air
of secret satisfaction.
It’s just that a girl
likes to be admired.
Mm-hmm.
You mean, I have a rival?
Who is it?
Just a man.
Someone you know.
Not... Rogers?
Yes. He came into the office
to give me some letters,
and couldn't take his eyes off me.
Miss Curnow thinks
he's getting sweet on me.
Well...
perhaps I’d better leave the field
free for a younger man.
He's not younger.
He's 46, I'm 48.
Well, I don't care. He looks at
least ten years older than you.
Aren't you jealous, though?
Raging with it.
Hawley.
Hmm?
When can we see each other?
Tomorrow...
..if you like.
Tomorrow?
Oh, yes.
(DOOR CREAKS)
(GENTLE MUSIC)
(DOOR THUDS IN DISTANCE)
(KEYS CLACK ON TYPEWRITER)
(BELL TOLLS IN DISTANCE)
All right?
Wonderful.
Are you sure
you don't want me to stay?
Better not, it's after six already.
I don't see why I can't stay
if I want to.
Well, we don't want people talking.
People. I hate people.
Goodnight then, Doctor.
Goodnight.
Goodnight, Dr Rogers.
I'm not disturbing you?
No, of course not.
It's rather a delicate matter,
really.
I'd be grateful if you'd have
a word with your typist
about her, um, costume.
In what way?
She has a tendency to look
a bit flash for an office.
Low-cut fronts,
too much jewellery, you know.
I'm afraid I hadn't noticed.
It's become markedly worse lately.
I've heard several comments.
I'm sorry.
Just have a word with her,
will you, Doctor?
We don't want any scandal.
You know what people are.
Yes, of course, I'll talk to
her about it in the morning.
Splendid.
(GENTLE MUSIC PLAYS ON PHONOGRAPH)
I hate this sordid hotel.
I love it.
It's the only place that
we're ever really alone.
(HE GROANS)
Here, let me help you.
Come into the light.
I haven't got my glasses.
(CARRIAGES RATTLING IN DISTANCE)
There.
I love you..
..Ethel Le Neve.
I love you too, Hawley.
Hawley.
No, I must go.
I don't want to, but I must.
Can't you tell her
you were working late?
I hate involving you
in lies and deceit.
I don't care, Hawley.
I don't care about
where we meet or how often.
Just as long as I can
go on seeing you
every day at the office.
And having these times together
occasionally.
If only I could take you out
in public just once,
just to show you off.
Maybe you will, one day.
I'm so proud of you.
We don't care about
silly old Dr Rogers, do we?
Stupid old fool.
I could've hit him.
You don't think he's right, do you?
That I am... you know?
Too flashy?
I think you're perfect.
You're always so brave...
..but I know
what it must mean to you,
never having any time to ourselves,
always hiding.
I'm going to make it up to you
one day.
I don't know how yet, but I am.
Don't talk about it.
You never do this to her, do you?
I don't care about anything.
But...
I've told you.
We've had separate rooms
for three years now.
I can take anything.
But the thought of you...
I'd kill myself if you ever
made love to her again.
It's you I love, Ethel.
The only way I can stand it
at night...
..is by thinking of you
alone in your room.
Being with you there in my mind.
You swear you never
have anything with her?
Not even kissing?
I told you, I couldn't.
That would revolt me.
Doesn't she complain?
She's not interested in me.
She has enough men
hanging around, even for her.
I hate her.
I hate the way she's tormented
and humiliated you.
Sometimes, I could strangle her.
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC)
You know what I do at home,
when things are difficult?
I think about these times.
So do I.
That way,
nothing she can do touches me.
To me, lovemaking is something...
..very sacred and special.
Something you give to the one
you love with reverence... love.
She made me feel unclean.
She's insatiable.
She filled me with such revulsion,
I could hardly bear to look at her.
Let alone...
You're a doctor.
Why didn't you
dose her with something?
It's a sickness when it's like that.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
Why are you looking at me like that?
Because I like to.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
(OMINOUS MUSIC)
Good evening, Doctor.
Good evening.
I wasn't sure you'd still be open.
Oh, you just caught me.
I'm afraid your order
won't be ready until tomorrow.
No, it wasn't that.
I was just wondering whether
you happened to have any
hyoscine hydrobromide.
Hyoscine?
That's new to me.
We wouldn't have any in stock,
I'm afraid.
How soon could you get it for me?
Hm, three or four days, I'd say.
That'll be all right.
What quantity would you like?
I'd better have five grains.
Mm-hmm, in tablet form?
No, crystals, I should think.
Very good, Doctor, thank you.
Goodnight to you.
Oh, goodnight.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
Paul.
Thank you.
What about me?
Pardon me.
Aren't you having any, Peter?
No, thank you.
Oh, come on, I hate drinking alone.
It's no good, Paul,
he hates to drink,
in case he does something rash
or abandoned,
like making love to his wife.
No-one would believe it, would they?
Now here am I, Belle Elmore,
a beautiful woman
in the prime of life,
the toast of London
and everywhere else.
To my lawfully wedded husband,
I'm as unattractive
as a piece of cold mutton.
Now, Belle...
Don’t you "Now, Belle" me!
They're our friends,
and if I want to tell them, I will.
I'll tell the whole damn world
if I want to.
Would you like a cigarette, Belle?
Why are you so scared, all of you?
It's no secret.
Peter's found himself
a little whore in the office.
Belle.
Well, it's true, isn't it?
(HE YAWNS)
Well, bedtime, I think.
Oh, sit down, Paul.
Don't be so damned British!
Clara knows all about it.
Don't you, Clara?
She knows what I’ve been through.
Why does everyone clam up
in this country
when you start talking the truth?
You're embarrassing our guests,
Belle.
I'm doing no such thing!
They love me and they've got
pity for the way you treat me.
Clara isn't embarrassed, I know.
Nor is Paul, now, are you?
Well, it's just...
Well, every couple
have their differences, Belle.
(SHE SNIGGERS)
Not the same one we've got,
brother, I'll bet.
I know no other woman
who'd put up with it. But no-one!
I'm sorry about this.
I didn't realise she'd had
quite so much to drink.
Who's had too much to drink?
I can drink you under the table
any time of the day.
Pill peddler.
I'm sure you can.
I'm sorry,
we really have to be going now.
Going?
Hell, I’m just getting in the mood.
Anyway, if you don't mind,
I think I'll just pop upstairs.
You know where it is?
I should do by this time.
We really ought to leave
when I come back.
I'm not feeling too grand.
Yes, dear, whatever you say.
You don't have to run off
and spoil the evening
just because my little bantam cock
here's nose is out of joint.
It's not that, Belle, only,
Paul really hasn't been
feeling very well all day.
I've something I want to talk about,
and it's important.
(ICE RATTLES)
Where'd Paul go?
Upstairs.
Why, you mean to tell me
you let him go up
to that icebox by himself?
It's not the first time
he's done it.
You heard what Clara said, he's ill.
Just a slight chill on the stomach.
Well, you take the
paraffin heater up to him.
- It's freezing in there.
- No, he'll be all right.
Now, don't you take his part, Clara.
My God, it's disgusting.
Letting an old man like that
go up there
on a freezing winter's night.
I'm sure Paul would much prefer
to look after himself.
Where's the brandy?
I'm sorry, I put it away.
My God, you sneaky little rat!
What are you trying to say,
that I'm drunk or something?
How do you like that?
Now, this monkey
keeps a paid trollop
in furs and finery at my expense,
and grudges me
one little bit of drink!
- Now, Belle...
- You take your hands off me!
Don't you touch me!
Belle, weren't you going to tell me
something important?
Oh...
Oh, yes, well, I was.
This is something
very interesting indeed.
Paul, what is it?
Nothing, I just feel a bit peculiar.
I think I'd better get him home
immediately.
Would you like me
to have a look at you?
No, thanks, it's just my tummy.
The usual thing.
I'll get you a cab.
Come along, dear.
Goodnight, Belle.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
Peter!
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC)
Didn't you hear me calling you?
I could hardly have missed you.
Now, don't give me any
of those smart answers.
I suppose you're very proud,
lousing up my evening?
Any lousing up was done
quite adequately by yourself.
Right, now, where are you going?
To bed.
Oh, no, not so fast.
I’ve got a couple of things
I want to talk about.
We'll talk about them
in the morning.
Oh, no, we won't!
Tomorrow I may not be here.
Oh, Belle, not again.
What do you mean "not again"?
Who the hell do you think
you're talking to?
Listen, when I want to talk,
you talk, see?
Don't do me any favours.
If you've got something to say,
please say it quickly, I'm tired.
Ah, you're always tired.
That's the trouble with you.
Belle, please.
Look, I don't like your
making a fool of me
in front of my friends.
I wasn't aware that I’d done so.
Hiding the bottle
like I was drunk or something.
You've got it quite wrong, as usual.
Listen, when I entertain my friends,
I don't like things like that.
Those Ardittis are fine people.
What do you think
they're going to think,
your pretending
that I'm drunk or something?
Are you all right?
No thanks to you.
Going to go to bed now?
Oh, yes.
Where are you going?
It's late.
(SHE GROANS)
Don't go.
(SHE MOANS SOFTLY)
That feels nice.
How is the head?
(SHE GROANS)
Leave it there.
What's the matter?
I couldn't get my breath.
Does my breath smell bad
or something?
No, no, it's not that.
What right have you to behave
like I disgust you?
Now, I'm your wife.
I've got a right
to have you love me.
Belle, please.
- (SHE SNIGGERS)
- I bet you don't shrivel up
when that little tramp kisses you.
What do you both do together,
just read poetry?
Now, listen, I’m telling you
that plenty of men
find me attractive.
I don't doubt it.
Plenty of men would be
only too happy
to have me here like this right now.
You stay right here.
You've had too much to drink.
(SHE LAUGHS)
I'm sober enough to see through you
and your little fancy girl.
I think I'll go down and lock up.
Oh, no, I want to talk about her.
It’ll be much better
if I leave right now.
Better for who?
Look, I want to talk about her.
I'm an interested party.
We'll talk about it in the morning.
We'll talk about it now!
I must've been mad, letting you
get away with it all these years.
Squandering my money
on that cheap slut
and making me a laughing stock
in front of my friends.
Nobody knows about it.
Oh, not much, they don't.
It's been the hot talking spot
of the guild for months.
I didn't care before,
but suddenly I care very much.
What do you want me to say, Belle?
You've got a plain choice.
Her or me.
Do you always
have to dramatise everything?
We've got a pretty good life here.
Except for this side of it.
Except?
(SHE SCOFFS)
Maybe it's all right for you,
playing footsie
all day at the office,
but what about me?
You haven't done so badly.
Let me tell you this, though.
You choose her,
and I'll hound you out
of every place you go.
You're a lousy doctor
at the best of times.
So how do you think
you're gonna make out
when everyone knows you're
living with a prostitute?
She's not a prostitute.
She's worse! She does it for fun.
You shut your filthy mouth!
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC)
Well, what do you know?
So the little man's
really stuck on the girl.
You can say what you like about me,
Belle,
but Ethel is good and pure.
And such talk about her
is an abomination.
She's a cheap, two-timing slut.
How dare you talk about cheapness,
you lousy overblown...
Why, you disgust her
as much as you disgust me!
Oh, so I disgust her, do I?
Oh, well, no doubt being
the little prude that she is,
the thought of you making love to me
would shatter
her pure little soul then.
I'm going to leave you, Belle.
Ah, now we're getting at it.
That fragile little dream of yours
would shatter pretty damn quick
if I told her
that you'd been coming
to my room once a week
for the past three years,
wouldn't it?
I’m going to leave you.
(SHE LAUGHS)
Pretending she's the only one
your lily-white body has touched.
Boy, am I going to enjoy this.
Belle, if you tell her, I'll...
You'll what?
You can't pretend it's flattering,
but at least it's funny.
Oh, no,
you're not going to leave me,
or I'll go down to that office
so damn quick
you won't see me for smoke.
And what I tell her
will put the kibosh on your
buttercups and daisies romance,
tout de suite!
I can promise you that.
I happen to love Ethel,
very deeply and sincerely, Belle,
and she loves me.
I never realised it would
ever happen to me, but it has.
And I'm not going to let
anything endanger it.
No, that's up to you, sport.
You keep me happy,
and I'll forget about
your skinny little friend.
Wouldn’t you divorce me?
- No, I would not.
-You've threatened to often enough.
Yeah, well, that was then.
Now is now.
What do you want me to do, Belle?
For a start, you can move
back in here and for always.
No more separate rooms.
You're not very attractive,
but you're my husband,
and you're gonna lie beside me.
I’m not going to be made a fool of.
Very well.
I'd better go downstairs
and lock up.
Yeah, you do that.
And don't be too long, lover boy.
And get me some tea.
(GENTLE MUSIC)
All right.
(SHE LAUGHS)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
(OMINOUS MUSIC)
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC)
What are you doing?
Just coming.
Well, hurry up!
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
You took your time.
The kettle wouldn't boil.
(OMINOUS MUSIC)
Three, isn't it?
Yeah.
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC)
Was there a quarrel of any sort
that you saw or heard
during that evening?
Not that I saw, no.
Did Mrs Crippen seem in good health?
Oh, yes,
she was quite her usual self.
Full of good humour, you mean?
Quite remarkably so.
Did she seem fond of Dr Crippen?
Devoted.
She was a very good and loyal wife.
What time did you leave
that evening?
About half-past one.
Did you see Mrs Crippen again?
No.
But later, Dr Crippen told you
something about her?
He said that Belle had suddenly
been called to America,
to visit a sick relative.
And this surprised you?
Very much so.
Now, do you recall anything
that he told you on March 23rd?
That was the Wednesday
before Easter.
Yes, he said that he'd
had a cable from Belle.
She'd been taken dangerously ill.
He expected to hear any moment
that she'd gone.
Did you hear from him
subsequent to that?
Yes, I had a telegram
the next morning,
saying, "Belle died yesterday
at six o'clock, Peter."
Peter. That was the name
by which you knew him?
Yes.
Now, I want to ask you
about an occasion in 1908,
when you were in
Mrs Crippen's bedroom
while she was undressing.
Did you see anything
remarkable in her appearance?
Yes.
She...
She was naked under her housecoat,
and when it fell open,
I saw that she had a scar.
Here.
Did you speak about it?
Yes.
I said, "Belle, does that hurt?"
But she just smiled
and said it didn't.
Now, Mrs Arditti,
I ask you to cast your mind back
to the evening of February 20th
this year.
Did anything of interest
occur on that date?
Oh, yes, we had our annual ball,
for the Guild Benevolent Fund.
Was Dr Crippen there?
Yes, with Miss Le Neve.
Was any comment made about them?
A lady came up,
and after she'd spoken to me,
I looked at Miss Le Neve,
and saw that
she was wearing a brooch.
Did it remind you of one
that you'd seen someone else wear?
Well, it was very like
one worn by Mrs Crippen.
Did Mrs Crippen also wear furs?
She had two sets of furs.
After Mrs Crippen's disappearance,
did you see anyone else
wearing a set like hers?
Yes, Miss Le Neve.
No more questions, M'lud.
How long did you know
Dr and Mrs Crippen?
About 18 months.
Would you say that Dr Crippen
was a kind-hearted man,
so far as you could see?
So far as I could see, yes.
Now, taking the dinner party
on Monday, January 31st,
it was a happy party, as you said,
a pleasant party?
Perfectly.
You did not notice anything unusual
in Dr Crippen's manner
on that evening?
- Not really.
- Did you or didn't you?
No.
He was happy, talking,
and all that kind of thing?
Well, he had a slight difference
with Mrs Crippen about something.
But apart from that,
he was his usual self.
What caused this difference?
Belle thought he should've
escorted my husband upstairs.
What was Dr Crippen's
reaction to that?
He didn't say very much at all.
It didn't provoke him to anger?
No, he was always very calm
and controlled.
Now, taking the ball
on February 20th,
you rather pressed him
to attend, did you not?
I asked him if he wanted to go.
And I told him the tickets
were halfa guinea each.
That was a place where he knew
if he took Miss Le Neve,
they would meet a great many
of Mrs Crippen's friends.
I suppose so.
And that piece of jewellery
you mentioned
was worn quite openly
on the bodice of her dress?
Yes.
He did not seem in anyway uneasy in
the presence of his wife's friends?
Quite the reverse.
He seemed very proud
of Miss Le Neve.
Showing her off.
Just a moment, Chief Inspector.
You say Mrs Arditti came to see you
at Scotland Yard on the 30th June?
Yes, My Lord.
This was the first time
you'd heard of the Crippens?
Yes, My Lord.
Did Mrs Arditti explain
why she had come to see you?
She made a statement, in consequence
of which I made enquiries,
between that date and the 8th July,
with reference to
the disappearance of Mrs Crippen.
And on July 8th, did you
visit a certain address?
I went with Sergeant Mitchell
to number 39 Hilldrop Crescent,
where I saw Miss Le Neve.
I had a conversation with her,
and then went with her
to Albion House,
where I saw the prisoner, Crippen.
Later that day, toward evening,
I went with Crippen and Miss Le Neve
back to number 39 Hilldrop Crescent.
Did you have an opportunity
of examining the house?
Yes, he showed me into every room,
and also round the garden.
I said to him,
"Of course, we shall have to find
"Mrs Crippen
to clear this matter up."
And he said,
"Yes, I will do everything I can.
"Would an advertisement
be any good?"
Together,
we composed an advertisement
in Crippen's handwriting,
asking for information
about his wife, Belle Elmore.
What was done with that
advertisement?
It remained with Crippen that night
when Sergeant Mitchell
and I left the house.
I'll send it to the American
papers tomorrow, Mr Dew.
I wouldn't waste any time, Doctor.
This could be a very
serious matter for you.
But surely there's
no implication that...
I mean, my wife made her
intentions very plain to me.
Maybe so. But a complaint
has been made to the police.
So we've obviously got to trace
the lady to complete our inquiry.
But you must admit that I'm not
responsible for my wife's movements.
In the normal way, of course not.
But look at the facts here,
as we know them.
You admit yourself that you're
not on normal terms with her.
She has many friends,
but she disappears without
contacting any of them.
Instead of telling the truth
about her departure,
you invent a cock-and-bull story
about a mysterious death abroad.
At the same time,
you move another lady into the house
and deck her in your
wife's jewels and clothes.
As I bought them, I rather
fancied they belonged to me.
Possibly, I'm just pointing out
how the matter might appear.
Then you suspect me of something.
I didn't say that.
I’m just pointing out that with
these elements in the case,
we can't be satisfied until
we discover where your wife is.
I understand, Inspector.
I'll see the advertisement
goes in tomorrow.
I think that would be
the wise thing, sir.
Goodnight.
Goodnight, sir.
- Goodnight.
(CARRIAGE RATTLES ON STREET)
You don't really suspect
anything, do you, Guv?
Nah.
Why put the frighteners on him then?
What do you expect me to do,
give him a medal?
At best,
he's behaved like a damned fool,
involved us in a lot
of routine work...
..which won't lead anywhere.
That Le Neve is not a bad
little filly, though. I wonder.
Can you see a rabbit like that
polishing off his wife,
or anybody else, for that matter.
Sarge, you've seen him all day.
Nobody could be that calm
if he really had anything to hide.
Here, we didn't get his signature
on the carbon copy.
I'll nip round and get it on Monday.
I've had enough of those
codfish eyes for one day.
We're definitely going to drop it,
then?
When you've tidied up the paperwork,
we're going to file Dr Crippen
and forget him.
Where do you reckon the wife is,
then?
You saw the picture, didn't you?
A healthy-looking cow,
if ever I saw one.
Oh, she's off with some young buck
from the theatre, if you ask me.
Frankly, I don't blame her.
Crippen doesn't look as if he ever
had an emotion in his life.
(SHOVEL SCRAPES IN DISTANCE)
(SHOVEL SCRAPES)
- (SHE GASPS)
- Hawley, you frightened me.
What are you doing down here?
I’m just getting some coal
for the parlour.
I don't want you to do that.
Well, I just thought...
You know I don't like
you doing heavy work.
Besides, the dust ruins your hands.
The way you treat me,
you'd think I was too precious
to do any kind of work.
You are to me.
Here, you go on upstairs.
I'll bring the bucket.
All right, darling, but there's no
need to treat me like a China doll.
I like to.
(GENTLE MUSIC)
(TENSE MUSIC)
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC)
(GENTLE MUSIC)
(OMINOUS MUSIC)
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC)
(DOOR OPENS)
Who is it?
Darling.
What's the matter?
I just couldn't sleep.
No, it's more than that.
It's something to do with
the police, isn't it?
Yes, they think
I've done some harm to Belle.
But that’s ridiculous.
She's with that man, Martin.
I know, but how can I prove it?
She'll see your advertisement.
You don't know Belle.
She hates me.
She'll realise what it means,
and deliberately not answer it
just to get me into trouble.
We'll find her. We’ll get someone
in America to go and see her.
That'd convince the police.
No, it's no use. By that time,
they will have arrested me.
They can't arrest you for nothing.
They can hold me
while they look for Belle.
Even if they do,
it can only be fora short time.
Until they discover the truth.
I'm a doctor.
The scandal would ruin me.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
You're sure there's
nothing else worrying you?
You don't know what lengths
she'll go to,
to hurt me and to get her own back.
Why, she'd even disappear in America
if she thought she could
get me into worse trouble.
(GENTLE MUSIC)
What do you want to do, Hawley?
I want to leave here.
I want to take you with me.
I'd go anywhere with you.
We'll go tomorrow.
Where to?
The continent first,
and then the States.
Oh, that's marvellous.
First thing in the morning,
I’ll go and say goodbye
to Mrs Jackson.
No, if we're going to go,
let's just walk out
and sever all ties.
All right, if you think so.
I know you think I’m overdoing it,
but I don't trust these police.
The sooner we're on our way
and with the least fuss, the better.
What a lucky thing I bought
that grey dress last week.
I can travel in that,
and I think
I’ll wear that flame hat.
If we’re going to go like this,
we don't want to leave
any trails behind us.
A middle-aged man
and a young girl...
..will be signposted
wherever they go.
You want to travel separately?
No, but I think we should
disguise ourselves,
until we're clear away from England.
That way,
even if the police, or Belle,
do try to find us,
they won't be able to.
(GENTLE MUSIC)
(BRIGHT MUSIC)
What a wonderful father
Mr Robinson is.
He never leaves his son's side.
The boy seems to look
a bit effeminate to me.
Let's sit over there, Tom.
What can I get you, sir?
Well, thank you,
my son will have a glass of milk,
and I'll take a sherry.
Very good, sir.
Why can't I have something
more interesting than milk?
Because you're only a little boy.
I always
forget to put a handkerchief
in these wretched pockets.
Here, here.
- Have mine.
- No, thank you, darling.
I want to go back
to the cabin anyway.
- Don't be long.
-Yeah.
Hello, Mr Robinson.
Mr Robinson.
Oh, sorry, Captain,
I didn't hear you.
I hope you're enjoying your trip.
Oh, yes, thank you, very much.
I must congratulate you on the ship.
She's most comfortable.
Do you mind if I join you?
No, please.
Please.
May I offer you some refreshment?
No, thank you very much.
I was just wondering
whether you and your son
would join my table again
for dinner tonight?
That's most cordial of you.
A good-looking boy, your son.
We're all quite taken with him.
Yes, he's always very popular.
Enjoying himself at sea,
do you think?
Oh, yes, indeed.
Now that it's calm.
He wasn't too happy the first
few days out from An twerp,
but then, neither was I.
He seems to have got his sea legs
now, all right.
We ought to recruit him
for the line.
The lady passengers always like
having
a handsome young cadet
about the place.
Yes, I expect they do.
As a matter of fact, I've got
a son just about his age,
that I've been trying to press-gang
aboard, but he won't have it.
He's absolutely crazy
about motor cars
and won't hear of anything else.
Has your boy made up his mind
what he wants to be yet?
No, not exactly,
but there's still plenty of time.
I expect you'll want to take him
into the family business,
like most fathers.
Engineering, isn't it?
Yes, it's in that line, anyway.
Oh, Tom, the Captain here has
been telling me about his son.
Are you fond of games, young Tom?
I quite enjoy them.
Some of the young gentlemen aboard
make up a game of
deck-hockey before breakfast.
Just shorts and a singlet.
Why don't you join them?
Well, actually, Tom hasn't been
feeling too well lately.
That's really why
I brought him on this trip.
I'm sorry to hear that.
I thought he looked a bit pale.
Well, see you this evening then.
Yes, thank you.
We're most obliged to you.
Do we really have to eat with him?
Yes, I'm afraid so.
It's quite an honour.
I wish we needn't.
I know.
But we... We've got to keep up
some appearances.
(MACHINE BEEPS)
Andrews, make this to London office.
Yes, sir.
"Further to my message,
"convinced beyond doubt
"Crippen and Le Neve
aboard travelling,
"disguised as father and son, stop.
"Believe them quite unaware
of my suspicions, stop.
"Will keep them under
constant surveillance, stop.
"Please advise."
Are you sure it's him, sir?
- Convinced.
- Well, how did you get on to them?
The English papers I saw in Antwerp
had their photographs spread
all over the front pages.
Poor devils.
Thinking they've got away with it.
I don't know how they hoped
to get away with it
disguised as father and son.
She's got a very feminine
figure fora boy of 16,
and he can't keep his hands off her,
even in public.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
Hawley, we must be more careful.
We'll be seen.
I feel so happy.
I don't really care.
Are you pleased to be going home,
darling?
Yes, of course, but...
..I've been away from America
for so long that
I'm beginning to feel
like an English gentleman.
You could never be that,
not the way you behave.
Hawley, you don't think
Belle could ever find us?
I mean, if she ever tired
of that Martin man.
America is a very big place,
my darling.
We'll find somewhere
and start a new life together.
(GENTLE MUSIC)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
Sir.
Thank you.
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC)
A Scotland Yard inspector will be
coming aboard with the pilot.
You'll meet him
and take him to Robinson's cabin,
and for heaven's sake be discreet.
Aye-aye, sir.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
(TENDER MUSIC)
Hawley, I love you.
I love you so much.
I love you.
Hawley.
(TENDER MUSIC)
(SEABIRDS CRY)
(WATER LAPS FAINTLY)
The engines have stopped.
Hmm?
Oh.
There's a cutter coming alongside.
It must be the Canadian pilot.
Only a few more hours now.
Where are we going to go
after we land?
I thought, maybe out west somewhere,
Los Angeles or San Francisco.
Six months ago, I’d made up mind
there was no future for us at all.
I thought the best
I could hope for
was seeing you once a week
in that dreadful hotel.
I thought you liked it.
Ugh, it made me vomit.
All those people looking at us
and knowing and sneering.
My poor darling.
It won’t be long now anyway.
(BELL RINGS IN DISTANCE)
I wonder how long it's gonna take
for my hair to grow.
A few weeks, I expect.
Thank you.
For what?
For being Ethel.
Forgiving me the only
real happiness I've ever had.
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
Come in.
Excuse me, sir. Someone would
like to have a word with you.
I think you know who I am, Doctor.
You come along with me now, sir.
Whatever happens now, darling,
always remember that
I loved you with all my soul.
All right, sir, come along.
(GENTLE MUSIC)
Hawley.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
You'd better come along with me.
Prisoners up.
(TENSE MUSIC)
Gentlemen, have you
agreed upon your verdict?
We have.
Do you find the prisoner, Crippen,
guilty or not guilty
of wilful murder?
We find the prisoner guilty.
(CROWD MUTTERS)
You find the prisoner guilty,
and that is the verdict of you all?
It is.
Do you find the prisoner,
Le Neve, guilty or not guilty
of being an accessory
after the fact in murder?
Not guilty.
You find the prisoner not guilty,
and that is the verdict of you all?
It is.
Ethel Le Neve, you are discharged.
No! They're all lying!
She's alive, I tell you!
She's alive!
He didn't do it. He didn't do it!
She's alive, I tell you!
She's alive!
No, look, they're lying!
They're lying! He didn't do it!
He didn't do it! No!
Prisoner at the bar...
(ETHEL SOBS)
..you stand convicted of murder.
Have you anything to say
why the Court
should not give you judgement
of death according to law?
Only, that I am innocent of murder.
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC)
Hawley Harvey Crippen,
you have been convicted on evidence
of a ghastly and wicked crime.
I have now to pass upon you
the sentence of the Court,
which is that you shall be
taken to a lawful prison,
and from thence
to a place of execution,
and there be hanged by the neck
until you are dead.
(FOREBODING MUSIC)
(TENSE MUSIC)
It's 25 past seven, Doctor.
Yes, thank you, Mr Harding.
Is there anything I can get you,
sir?
I’d like to wash, I think.
Mrs Crippen always used to say that,
"If cleanliness
was next to godliness,
"I'd die an archbishop."
She was wrong, wasn't she?
ls there anything else you'd like,
sir?
No, I don't think so.
Thank you, Mr Harding.
Except, in case I don't get a chance
to say this later, I...
I'm very grateful to you
and your colleagues
for your kindness and courtesy
during these past weeks.
It can't have been
a very pleasant assignment.
I’m really terribly sorry, Doctor.
What none of us here
can understand...
(DOOR CREAKS OPEN)
All right, Harding,
you may wait outside.
No, it's all right.
Well, very good, sir.
- (DOOR THUDS)
- Miss Le Neve sent you this telegram.
I’m sorry that regulations
forced me to open it.
Thank you.
I'm very much obliged to you
for letting me read it, Governor.
ls there anything
that I can do for you?
Yes.
I would like her
letters and photographs
buried with me,
if that's possible.
I’ll see to that myself.
If only I could be sure
that they'll give her a chance.
I could arrange to visit her myself
from time to time,
if that would be a help.
Oh, yes, please.
If only you could persuade her
that she must make
an entirely new life for herself,
take a different name,
and never, never let anybody
know who she really is.
Of course.
You'll like her, Governor.
She's simple and real,
and direct and honest.
The papers try to make her out
to be some sort of scar let woman,
but the jury weren't fooled.
They could tell what she was
just by looking at her.
You know, Crippen,
I've never met anyone
who struck me as being less likely
to commit murder than yourself,
whatever the pressures.
But I didn't murder her.
Then you still protest
your innocence?
I killed her, all right,
but it was an accident.
Why in heaven's name
didn't you say so at the trial,
or at the appeal?
Is what I say to you
treated as confidential?
Absolutely, I give you my word.
Well, I'd like somebody
to know the truth.
You see...
..Belle and I
had been growing apart,
long before I met Ethel.
She wasn't a bad woman, really,
but coarse and dirty.
Love, to her,
was a matter of appetite,
whereas to me...
Well, I found what I wanted
in Ethel.
So I planned to give Belle
regular sedatives
to calm her down.
I remember thinking
the night she died...
We'd had
a particularly dreadful quarrel.
She was drunk.
I remember thinking then
that I would've liked to kill her.
So I’m not entirely innocent.
The thought was there.
They said they found halfa grain
of hyoscine in the body.
I'm still puzzling over that.
I could've sworn I didn't give her
more than the regular sedative dose.
Anyway, she died...
..and then I panicked.
I realised there'd be an inquest,
and I didn't think they'd believe me
because of my relationship
with Ethel.
So I made up that story about
Belle going off with another man.
But when they arrested you,
why didn't you tell the truth then?
Well, by that time
there was such a hullabaloo.
I was a monster.
Worse than Jack the Ripper,
if you could believe the newspaper.
I didn't think they'd acquit me
anyway,
not after what I'd done to...
to hide the remains.
So, as my life was lost...
..the most important thing
was to keep alive the thing
I treasured more than
anything else in the world,
Ethel's love and her belief in me.
She still doesn't think I had
anything to do with that body.
She thinks Belle is alive somewhere,
laughing.
She's a very simple, lovely girl.
I couldn't have borne it
if she turned against me, too.
I'll do everything I can
to see she gets the chance
of a new life.
You won't mention any of this
to her?
Nothing that you wouldn't
want her to hear.
(DOOR CREAKS OPEN)
It's ten minutes to eight, sir.
Goodbye then.
Goodbye, sir.
Doctor.
Sir.
It's time.
I was just thinking...
Mr Harding.
In a few minutes,
it'll all be over for me.
But for her...
..it'll go on
for the rest of her life.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
(BELL TOLLS)
(SOMBRE MUSIC)