[ "Rule, Britannia" plays ]
[ Music slows, continues ]
[ Up-tempo jazz plays ]
[ Music continues ]
[ "Double Trouble" plays ]
Elvis: ♪ Some guys fall
in love with one girl ♪
♪ I've got to fall for two ♪
♪ There's just so much lovin' ♪
♪ That one heart's
supposed to do ♪
♪ So I go around with my heart
draggin' on the ground ♪
♪ Doggin' me around ♪
♪ I'm the sorriest sight
in town ♪
-♪ I got double trouble ♪
-♪ Double trouble ♪
♪ Twice as much as anybody else,
oh, yeah ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ I guess there's got to be
two dark clouds ♪
♪ A-hangin' over me ♪
♪ My future looks as bumpy
as a matchbox on the sea ♪
♪ Every time I think that I have
finally got it made ♪
♪ Some losin' cards are played ♪
♪ I just can't make the grade ♪
-♪ I got double trouble ♪
-♪ Double trouble ♪
♪ Twice as much as anybody else,
oh, yeah ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh ♪
-♪ I got double trouble ♪
-♪ Double trouble ♪
♪ Twice as much as anybody else,
oh, yeah ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh-oh ♪
[ Music ends ]
[ Applause ]
Okay.
You're on, girls.
BOTH: Is it true you're
leaving us for Belgium, Guy?
Yep.
Leaving tomorrow night.
BOTH:
Aw! Boo-hoo!
"Boo-hoo"?
That's a good title for a song.
[ Up-tempo music plays ]
Do you happen to have a light?
Is there anything else
I can do for you?
-You can sit down.
-Thank you.
You been here before,
Miss, uh...
Claire.
Claire Dunham.
I've been here every night
since you opened.
But you've haven't seen me
before -- until now.
I can't understand that.
Perhaps you've been too busy
with that pretty
little girlfriend of yours.
Oh, there's nothing wrong
with your eyesight, is there?
Are you in love with her?
Would it break your heart?
Oh.
Shatter it to pieces.
And look!
There isn't an ounce of sympathy
in your eyes.
There isn't an ounce
of sincerity in yours.
Guy?
Psst.
You gonna stay around
for a while?
Of course.
She may not turn up tonight.
Your lighter.
Thank you.
[ Music continues ]
What do you want?
Must be the maternal instinct.
-What?
-That you bring out in chicks.
Little mothers can't seem
to leave you alone.
What are you complaining about?
You're married.
That's what I'm
complaining about.
Look, Georgie.
If you don't pop
the big question,
they can't give the big answer.
Well, it can't be that easy.
I never proposed,
yet I've got a wife
and three kids
and a grabbin' ulcer.
Maybe she won't turn up.
Who? Jill?
Whatever her name is.
That's the only name I know.
I can't get a thing out of her.
Or anywhere with her.
Drink your milk, will you?
She's holding out for that
little ring on her finger --
and the one in your nose.
It won't be long now,
my friend.
I see an ulcer in your future.
Look, pal.
When we get to Bruges,
I'll still be as free as a bird.
A canary's a bird.
So?
Ever see one
that wasn't locked up?
Tweet, tweet!
Let's go to work, partner.
[ Down-tempo music plays ]
Hi.
Thank you.
[ "Baby, If You'll Give Me
All of Your Love" plays ]
♪ I'll send you red roses
by the dozen ♪
♪ Doo, doo, doo-doo ♪
♪ I'll call you sweet little
things like turtle dove ♪
♪ Doo, doo, doo-doo ♪
♪ I'll whisper pretty things
in your ear ♪
♪ The kind of things
a girl likes to hear ♪
♪ Baby, if you'll
give me all your love ♪
♪ I'll bring you pounds
and pounds of chocolate candy ♪
♪ Doo, doo, doo-doo ♪
♪ To prove it's you
that I've been thinkin' of ♪
♪ Doo, doo, doo-doo ♪
♪ Tear up all the pictures
I own ♪
♪ Of every pretty girl
I've ever known ♪
♪ Baby, if you'll give me
all your love ♪
♪ I'll take you dancin'
every night ♪
♪ Until you're ready to drop ♪
♪ I'll kiss
your sweet red cherry lips ♪
♪ Until you holler stop ♪
♪ Every night I'll serenade you
'neath your window ♪
♪ Doo, doo, doo-doo ♪
♪ If you need me, just a-whistle
and I won't need a shove ♪
♪ Doo, doo, doo-doo ♪
♪ I'll hug you, squeeze you
tight as I can ♪
♪ It ain't gonna be
no one-night stand ♪
♪ Baby, if you'll give me
all your love ♪
♪ I'll take you dancin'
every night ♪
♪ Until you're ready to drop ♪
♪ I'll kiss
your sweet red cherry lips ♪
♪ Until you holler stop ♪
♪ Every night I'll serenade you
'neath your window ♪
♪ Doo, doo, doo-doo ♪
♪ If you need me, just a-whistle
and I won't need a shove ♪
♪ Doo, doo, doo-doo ♪
♪ I'll hug you, squeeze you
tight as I can ♪
♪ It ain't gonna be
no one-night stand ♪
♪ Baby, if you'll give me
all your love ♪
-[ Music slows, continues ]
-♪ If you will give me ♪
♪ Aww ♪
♪ If you will give me, yeah ♪
♪ All your love ♪
♪ Aw, aw, aw ♪
♪ Your love ♪
[ Down-tempo music plays ]
-Hi.
-Hello.
-You're very pretty.
-Thank you.
Why don't we do
something different tonight?
We've never done anything.
I was wondering
if you noticed that.
I noticed.
Well, this is my last night
here.
Do we make the most of it or,
uh, do you disappear, as usual?
I suppose if anything's
to become of us,
it'll have to be tonight.
That's exactly the way I feel.
But you've had so many women
in your life.
I haven't looked
at another woman
since the first night
you came into the club.
But they're still looking
at you.
I don't even know her.
Good night.
Who is she?
A music lover?
That's nice.
You are beautiful.
And you're the most wonderful
thing in my life.
Come on.
I'm gonna put you in a cab
and send you straight home.
Home?
But I don't want to go home.
I want to go with you
to your flat.
I tried.
[ Steam hissing ]
And so after Mummy
and Daddy died,
I went to live
with Uncle Gerald.
He has a lovely home
in the country,
and he lived all by himself.
He's been looking after me
ever since.
You'd love Uncle Gerald, Guy.
Oh, I'm sure I would.
He's a lamb.
Oops.
You don't mind me tidying up
for you, do you?
Not a bit.
I love doing things for you.
[ Kettle whistling ]
Oops.
Tea's ready.
Do you take milk in your tea?
-No milk in the tea.
-Have you any bikkies?
"Bikkies"?
Well, not that I know of.
Biscuits, silly.
No bikkies...silly.
Oh, dear.
I suppose I'm chattering away,
but this is the first time we've
really had a chance to talk.
And talk and talk and talk.
Guy?
Yes?
Would you put something
on the record player?
What a time to dance.
Why not?
[ "Could I Fall in Love?"
plays ]
Okay. There's something
on the record player.
There we are.
Oh.
I forgot the sugar.
[ Music continues ]
Jill, you're flittin' around
like a butterfly.
Why don't you light somewhere,
baby, like here?
Oh.
Isn't that better?
Don't you just love us
like this?
You all cozy and relaxed
and me pouring your tea...
...and doing things for you.
You could do a lot more
if you just settle --
-Let me prop those pillows up.
-I don't want them propped up.
There. Comfy?
Cozy?
Comfy and cozy.
Better?
Jill, hold still
just for a minute.
-What for?
-For this.
Oh, Guy.
Our first kiss.
I knew it would be like that --
all shivers and goose bumps.
-One or two?
-What?
Lumps in your tea, silly.
Four hundred and eighteen.
I couldn't care less.
You know, it's marvelous
being here with you.
I can't believe
this is happening.
I can't believe it either.
-Guy?
-Yes?
Would you kiss me again?
Are you sure I wouldn't be, uh,
interrupting anything?
I'm sure.
[ Music continues ]
Oh, isn't that lovely?
It could have been.
The music.
The song.
Don't you remember, darling?
You said it was our song.
I did?
I did.
Sing it to me.
-Sing? At a time like this?
-Please.
You have no idea
what your singing does to me.
Oh.
♪ Could I fall in love ♪
♪ For the very first time? ♪
♪ That's what I asked myself ♪
♪ When your lips touched mine ♪
♪ Could I fall in love ♪
♪ On a night like tonight? ♪
♪ That's what I'd like to know ♪
♪ When I hold you tight ♪
♪ Now that we're alone ♪
♪ Just a kiss apart ♪
♪ I have the answer ♪
♪ From the feeling in my heart ♪
♪ Could I fall in love ♪
♪ And forever be true? ♪
♪ My heart tells me I could ♪
♪ If I fell for you ♪
[ Music slows, continues ]
Well, Jill?
Jill?
Jill!
Oh!
I must have dozed off.
You did.
Oh, Guy, I do love you.
[ Music ends ]
Aren't you going to say it back?
Sure.
Say it, Guy.
Okay.
I love you.
I'm crazy about you.
I'm nuts about you.
I'm mad about you.
Absolutely mad about you.
I just...sat on the tea service.
Yes.
I know.
Cups of hot tea spilling
all over.
Yes.
I know.
It won't take a minute
to change.
[ Laughs ]
[ Door closes ]
Guy?
It's terribly late.
GUY:
I won't be long.
I'm copying down
your telephone number.
GUY:
Help yourself.
And I'll give you a ring
tomorrow, all right?
GUY:
Anytime.
I love you!
[ Down-tempo music plays ]
"I'll ring you up tomorrow,
all right?"
That's what you think.
If I never see you again,
it'll be too soon for me.
[ Doorbell buzzing ]
Mm-hmm.
[ Glass breaking ]
B6?
I do believe I've made
a mistake.
Ah, well.
From the looks of him,
he probably deserved it anyway.
[ Telephone ringing ]
[ Ringing continues ]
[ Up-tempo music plays ]
MAN:
Hello?
Are you there?
Yeah, I'm here.
Where are you?
MAN:
Hello? Hello?
-Hello?
-Uh, Mr. Lambert?
-Yes.
Ah.
This is Gerald Waverly.
Does my name mean anything
to you?
Not a thing.
Well, then apparently, I've been
as much of a secret to you
as you've been to me.
Jillian Conway is my niece.
Jillian Conway?
I don't know --
Jill.
Then you must be Uncle Gerald.
Well, I bear that distinction,
yes.
Mr. Lambert, I think it's, uh,
I think it's high time we met.
GUY:
I agree.
This afternoon, then?
311 Surrey Road,
St. John's Wood.
Around twoish?
Around twoish.
GERALD:
Goodbye, Mr. Lambert.
Goodbye.
[ Receiver thuds ]
[ Down-tempo orchestral music
plays ]
Very nice.
It's a Constable.
Yeah.
I know.
How did you know?
Well, it's written
right here on the bottom.
Well, do sit down, Mr. Lambert.
Would you like some tea?
No, thanks.
Where's Jill?
She's here,
but she doesn't know you are.
Would you mind telling her
I'm here?
You're an entertainer,
I believe.
Rather an uncertain life,
I should think.
I mean, it's not like
steady employment, is it?
Well, we're not all on relief.
I assure you, it wasn't
my intention to offend you.
Oh, I'm not offended.
I'm just in a hurry.
I don't want to lose my place
in the bread line.
Did you, um,
did you have it in mind to marry
my niece, Mr. Lambert?
It's been nice, Mr. Waverly.
I can find my own way out.
Just a minute, please.
Look.
I'm over 21 .
No criminal record.
No hint of insanity.
If I want to marry your niece,
forgive me if I don't
consult you first.
Has Jillian told you
about her inheritance?
No.
We had other things
to talk about.
Knowing her as I do,
I think I can safely assume
she's told you nothing
about herself at all
other than the fact
that she fancies herself
in love with you, of course.
Sometimes that's all
one needs to know.
Perhaps.
But not in this case.
-[ Door closes ]
-JILL: Uncle Gerald?
GERALD:
In here, Jillian.
Uncle Gerald, I --
Guy.
If you'll excuse me.
[ Down-tempo music plays ]
You're puttin' me on.
You're not putting me on.
It looks worse than it is, Guy.
I'll be 18 in four days.
Happy birthday.
I'll send you a card.
You didn't think I was a child
last night.
You didn't look like that
Then all that's changed
are my clothes.
I'm still the same girl.
I'm not the same fella.
I love you, Guy.
Love?
What could you know about love?
[ Sobs ]
Here.
Look.
This is where you belong.
In houses like this,
with Uncle Gerald and...
and Constable over there.
-Can't I even call you?
-No.
I'm taking the boat train
to Belgium tonight.
Oh, Guy!
Oh.
Leaving so soon, Mr. Lambert?
Well, with your permission,
of course.
[ Door opens, closes ]
How long have you been spying
on me, Uncle Gerald?
Spying?
How else could you have known
about Guy?
And I trusted you.
I trusted you --
until I discovered you were
slipping out at night
when you should have been
asleep.
You needn't make it sound
so sordid.
I want to marry him.
Marriage.
You're only 17.
Ooh, how I hate that number.
Well, in four more days,
I'll be 18.
Well, being 18
still isn't old enough to marry
without my consent.
You're too young to even
contemplate such a thing.
However, a few more years of the
proper schooling should help.
School?
It's all arranged.
I have your ticket right here.
You're shipping me off like
some convict to Devil's Island.
Well, actually, it could be
a wonderful experience for you.
Brussels should be lovely
this time of year.
Brussels?
Brussels is in Belgium,
isn't it, Uncle Gerald?
Unless they've moved it, yes.
[ Down-tempo music plays ]
You'll take the boat train
tonight.
Yes, Uncle Gerald.
[ Horn blaring ]
[ Indistinct conversations ]
[ Water splashing ]
[ Woman gasps ]
Georgie!
What are you doing out there?
Trying to turn the ship around!
Oh.
I thought you had an accident.
Pull me in!
[ Laughter, horn blaring ]
Oh, Mr. Million Laughs, right?
[ Chuckles ]
I ought to shove that smile
right down your throat.
[ Both chuckle ]
It's just not my day.
It ain't your night, either.
I just saw Jill on the boat.
You're crazy.
She couldn't be.
Or could she?
[ Horn blaring ]
-[ Horn stops ]
-Jill!
Oh.
I'm sorry about that.
Time is running out, Archie.
I still don't like it, Arthur.
Too risky.
Risky, yes.
But not for us.
We pick on
a likely-looking suitcase
and let somebody else carry it
through customs.
All right. Give it a go.
But be careful.
Careful. Right.
[ Light music plays ]
I say.
I'm terribly sorry, gentlemen.
Not like that, you silly twit!
-Casual.
[ Horn blaring ]
[ Indistinct conversations ]
Actually, this is a holiday
for me --
with a little work thrown in.
I'm doing a thesis
on the historical backgrounds
-of certain European cities.
-How interesting.
-So I noticed.
-Oh, I'm sorry.
Would you like me
to help you look for him?
It's no use.
I've been over this boat
from top to bottom.
I'll catch up with him
in Bruges, anyway.
-Is that where you're going?
-Yes.
-We're going to be married.
-Well, congratulations.
Thank you.
[ Horn blaring ]
Georgie?
Georgie!
Not a sign of her.
Are you sure it was Jill
you saw?
Positive.
Okay.
Let's set up.
Have a heart, Guy.
I don't feel like playing.
You got something better to do?
Yeah.
I'm going to the railing.
Wait a minute.
First we play.
If Jill's on board,
she'll find us.
And then what?
Then we'll both go
to the railing.
[ Whistling ]
Oh, sorry, governor.
[ Indistinct conversations ]
[ Passengers murmuring ]
Casual, you nit.
But that's barbaric.
Uncivilized.
[ Chuckles ]
I agree.
Nevertheless,
without parental consent,
you can forget about
being married in Belgium --
until you're 21 , anyway.
That's downright immoral.
Too bad you're not going
to Stockholm.
Stockholm?
Sweden's lovely
this time of year,
particularly for an 18-year-old
girl with marriage on her mind.
Oh.
[ "Long Legged Girl" plays ]
-That's him!
-Who?
-Him!
-Oh.
Excuse me. Thank you.
Thanks for everything.
[ Music continues ]
All right!
♪ I been thumbin' rides,
travelin' light ♪
♪ Walkin' streets
till past midnight ♪
♪ Trampin' roads, trails,
and lanes ♪
♪ Scaling cliffs and fields
and plains ♪
♪ Searching till
the early dawn ♪
♪ For that long-legged girl
with the short dress on ♪
♪ Riding trucks, bikes,
and skis ♪
♪ Sailing lakes and brooks
and seas ♪
♪ Driving wagons, cars,
and jeeps ♪
♪ Walking stilts
in ten-foot leaps ♪
♪ Searching till
the early dawn ♪
♪ For that long-legged girl
with the short dress on ♪
♪ And everywhere I go,
she has been and gone ♪
-♪ She's fine ♪
♪ Just too bad
she's the travelin' kind ♪
-♪ So fine ♪
♪ I just can't rest
till I make her mine ♪
♪ I been from Maine
to Tennessee ♪
♪ Mexico and Waikiki ♪
♪ Rain or shine, sleet or snow ♪
♪ I'm searching high
and I'm searching low ♪
♪ Everything depends upon ♪
♪ That long-legged girl
with the short dress on ♪
-♪ She's fine ♪
♪ Just too bad
she's the travelin' kind ♪
-♪ So fine ♪
♪ I just can't rest
till I make her mine ♪
♪ Well, I've been from Maine
to Tennessee ♪
♪ Mexico and Waikiki ♪
♪ Rain or shine, sleet or snow ♪
♪ Searching high
and I'm searching low ♪
♪ 'Cause everything
depends upon ♪
♪ That long-legged girl
with the short dress on ♪
♪ The long-legged girl
[ Music ends ]
-School's out.
-Huh?
You just rang the bell.
You were right.
I thought we settled everything
this afternoon.
-We did.
-Then what are you doing here?
I happen to be on my way
to Brussels.
To Brussels?
Not Bruges?
Would you like to see my ticket?
No. Never mind.
You might at least say
you're glad to see me.
Okay.
I'm glad to see you.
Friends?
Are you sure you're going
to Brussels?
Mm-hmm.
Friends.
[ Dramatic music plays ]
[ Passengers shouting,
murmuring ]
It's okay.
-It was just an accident.
-Some accident.
You could get killed
around here.
Yeah.
I think somebody's trying to
tell me something.
You better get out of here.
Come on, Jill.
[ Passengers murmuring ]
I'd better get out of here.
-[ Grunts ]
-Which one's yours?
Uh, this one.
Sorry, miss.
MAN: Ayez vos passeports,
s'il vous plaît.
Have your passports ready,
please.
Ayez vos passeports,
s'il vous plaît.
I say! What is this?
Unhand me, sir!
How dare you?
[ Indistinct conversations,
man speaking French on P.A. ]
MAN ON P.A. Passengers,
please claim your baggage
before leaving the terminal.
It's shocking, the indignities
a man must suffer.
Speaking of indignities, Arthur,
you'd better finish dressing.
[ Indistinct conversations,
man speaking French on P.A. ]
Well, I guess it's about --
Well...
Well, watch out
for falling trunks.
Yeah.
Travel light.
[ Dramatic music plays ]
[ Woman screaming ]
[ Indistinct shouting ]
Jill, are you all right?
[ Exhales deeply ]
Yes.
Something's forever
coming between us.
Yeah.
Uh, you'd better get a move on.
You don't want to miss
your train to Brussels.
And you don't want to miss
your bus to...
-To Bruges.
-Oh, yes. Bruges.
MAN ON P.A.:
Last call for the bus to Bruges.
Last call.
The next bus leaves
in two hours.
[ Indistinct conversations,
man speaking French on P.A. ]
Can you see him?
Can I see him?
You great steaming nit.
Disappeared into thin air.
Aah!
[ "City by Night" playing ]
♪ When shadows beckon ♪
♪ On dim-lit avenues ♪
♪ Night people hear the call ♪
♪ From hidden alleys ♪
♪ And secret rendezvous ♪
♪ They come out, one and all ♪
♪ The city by night ♪
♪ I'm wide awake ♪
♪ It never sleeps ♪
♪ Make no mistake ♪
♪ Whatever sets off the spark ♪
♪ A magic glow lights the dark ♪
♪ And I'm intrigued
by the sight ♪
♪ Of the city by night ♪
♪ Those crowded nightclubs ♪
♪ Those picturesque cafés ♪
♪ Are scenes no one forgets ♪
♪ And I'm enchanted ♪
♪ As music softly plays ♪
♪ By dancing silhouettes ♪
♪ The city by night ♪
♪ I'm wide awake ♪
♪ It never sleeps ♪
♪ Make no mistake ♪
♪ The evening's full
of surprise ♪
♪ Its magic opens my eyes ♪
♪ And I'm intrigued
by the sight ♪
♪ Of the city by night ♪
[ Music slows, stops ]
Yeah.
[ Music builds, ends ]
I thought I was, uh,
rather good tonight.
Tell the boys to wrap it up.
Wrap it up, boys.
-You okay?
-I don't know.
I keep thinking about the trunk
the gate opening
and now the baggage cart.
Coincidence.
Just freaky accidents.
Well, then why do I feel like
I'm being followed?
If mine eyes don't deceive me,
I'd say that face over there
was rather familiar.
Wrap it up.
[ Billiards clacking ]
Hello again.
Hi.
You must like to travel
to come all this way
for a one-night stand.
I hope you're referring
to your itinerary.
Uh, we play Antwerp tomorrow.
Is that an invitation?
Well!
Look who's here.
Bag and baggage.
Excuse me.
What are you doing here?
What's she doing here?
Wait a minute.
I thought you'd be glad
to see me.
But oh, no.
You're doing fine.
I was.
Music lover.
-Let's go.
-Where to?
To my hotel.
Oh. Super.
Look.
We can't talk here.
I'm gonna straighten
this thing out once and for all.
Super duper.
[ Exhales sharply ]
Come on.
[ Engine revving,
tires screeching ]
Aah!
[ Tires screeching ]
Guy, darling, are you all right?
Why don't you watch where
you're going, you crazy idiot?!
Guy!
You don't scare me!
Not even that much!
[ Tires screeching,
engine revving ]
[ Chuckles ]
Come on.
[ Engine idling ]
[ Footsteps passing ]
Ow!
Shh.
[ Footsteps approaching ]
[ Door opens ]
GUY:
Running away from school?
You should know better.
You're old enough.
No, you're not.
That's just it.
You're too young.
Uncle Gerald shouldn't send you
away like that by yourself
at your age.
-Now sit down!
-I am down.
Get off that bed.
Get off the bed.
Put your shoes back on.
Put your shoes back on!
My feet hurt.
"My feet hurt."
Okay.
So you had a beef with
Uncle Gerald and you ran away.
Well, there's nothing unusual
about that.
When I was a kid, I was always
in trouble with my folks.
Were you, really?
Sure.
Running away doesn't solve
anything.
Of course, when you're older,
you'll understand that.
Yeah.
You'll, uh...
The smart thing to do
is to call Uncle Gerald.
Put that down.
You're flitting around
like a butterfly.
Why not light somewhere, baby?
Like here.
I brought you up here to talk.
And talk and talk and talk.
Get off my bed!
Don't you realize you're alone
with a man in his hotel room?
Mm-hmm.
I love you.
-No, you don't.
-And you love me.
No, I don't.
Can't you hold still
for a minute?
For what?
For this.
[ Light music plays ]
That drink you were holding.
Yes. I know.
-You spilled it.
-Yes. I know.
Won't take me a minute
to change.
It's in there.
Maybe she'd better not.
[ Snoring ]
[ Music builds, continues ]
Like it?
Seventeen.
Seventeen will get me twenty.
Oh, that's bad.
That's -- That's bad.
That's very bad. Very --
Y-You don't know
what you're doing.
Well, what I don't know,
you can teach me.
[ Light music plays ]
Some schoolgirl.
She must major in hygiene.
[ Grunts ]
-I need some air.
-Oh. We'll open a window.
[ Down-tempo music plays ]
[ Exhales sharply, stammers ]
[ Horn blares ]
Shh!
[ Down-tempo music plays ]
Eighteen in three days.
In two days now.
Imagine that.
Time flies.
-Nope. No, you don't.
-But -- But, darling!
Don't "but, darling" me.
I'm sending you home
to Uncle Gerald tonight.
You said you loved me.
You say a lot of things
when you're trying to --
[ Sighs ]
Well, you know!
Do you say it to all the girls
you're trying to...you know.
-No.
-No?
Look. You're going home tonight,
and that's that.
All right.
The worst he can do
is beat me again.
Sure.
The worst he can do is beat you.
Beat you?
Uncle Gerald?
Oh, don't worry.
He's very careful.
The bruises never show.
The man's a fink.
I don't mind the pain, really,
but I dread being locked
in my room for days at a time.
I get so hungry.
Well, don't just stand there.
Put your clothes on.
You're sending me back.
To that bluebeard?
Fat chance.
Oh, I am glad.
I'm taking you to that school.
Oh, no!
Oh, Guy,
please take me with you.
Take you with me?
There's been too many weird
things happening to me lately.
Just till Stockholm.
Please.
Stockholm?
That's three days away.
Look. Do you realize
I'm in big trouble already?
I won't be in the way.
I'll do whatever you tell me.
I promise.
And once we've reached Sweden --
Well, everything will be fine
in Sweden.
What will be so fine in Sweden?
Well, uh, I have this dear,
sweet old maiden aunt
in Stockholm to look after me.
Old maiden aunt?
Aunt Harriet.
She looks just like me.
Okay.
Well, just till Stockholm.
-Not one step further.
-Oh, darling!
And no more
of that "darling" stuff.
No more of that "darling" stuff.
If you want to travel with me,
you do exactly as I say.
Yes, Guy.
[ Light music plays ]
What is that?
I can't take you anywhere
looking like that.
No, Guy.
Well, don't you stand there.
Go in and get changed.
Yes, Guy.
Hey. You can't get changed
without this.
JILL:
No, Guy.
-Close the door.
-Yes, Guy.
[ Whistles ]
We'll dump some of your things
into my suitcase.
We'll travel faster that way.
JILL: It's all kind of exciting,
isn't it?
What's so exciting about me
serving time for kidnapping?
JILL: But you didn't kidnap me.
I'm here of my own free will.
Remember that
when my trial comes up.
JILL:
I will!
[ Dramatic music plays ]
I must be nuts.
I could get shot for this.
[ Gunshot ]
Okay, okay!
I get the message!
You don't have to hit me
over the head!
Me and my big mouth.
[ Chickens clucking ]
They're just saying
good morning.
All right, already.
Good morning.
Oh.
[ "Old MacDonald" plays ]
♪ Old MacDonald had a farm ♪
♪ E-I-E-I-O ♪
♪ And on that farm,
he had some chicks ♪
♪ E-I-E-I-O ♪
♪ With a cluck-cluck here,
a cluck-cluck there ♪
♪ Loud as they could be ♪
♪ And when those chicks
got out of line ♪
♪ Chicken fricassee ♪
♪ With a cluck-cluck here
and a cluck-cluck there ♪
♪ Loud as they could be ♪
♪ And when those chicks
got out of line ♪
♪ Chicken fricassee ♪
[ Music continues ]
♪ Well, old MacDonald
had a farm ♪
♪ E-I-E-I-O ♪
♪ And on that farm,
he had some cows ♪
♪ E-I-E-I-O ♪
♪ With a moo-moo here,
a moo-moo there ♪
♪ Cattle everywhere ♪
♪ And when those cows
got out of line ♪
♪ Hamburger medium-rare ♪
♪ With a moo-moo here,
a moo-moo there ♪
♪ Cattle everywhere ♪
♪ And when those cows
got out of line ♪
♪ Hamburger medium-rare ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Well, old MacDonald
had a farm ♪
♪ E-I-E-I-O ♪
♪ And on that farm,
he had some pigs ♪
♪ E-I-E-I-O ♪
♪ With an oink-oink here,
an oink-oink there ♪
♪ Pigs everywhere in sight ♪
♪ And when those pigs
got out of line ♪
♪ Pork and beans that night ♪
♪ With an oink-oink here,
an oink-oink there ♪
♪ Pigs everywhere in sight ♪
♪ And when those pigs
got out of line ♪
♪ Pork and beans that night ♪
♪ Hey, hey ♪
♪ Well, I'm gonna have a farm
someday ♪
♪ E-I-E-I-O ♪
♪ And I'll do things
MacDonald's way ♪
♪ E-I-E-I-O ♪
♪ With a cluck-cluck here,
a cluck-cluck there ♪
♪ A moo-moo here,
a moo-moo there ♪
♪ An oink-oink here,
an oink-oink there ♪
♪ And I can promise you ♪
♪ Those animals ever get
out of line ♪
♪ We'll have a Mulligan stew ♪
♪ Now, how about you? ♪
[ Duck squawking ]
[ Up-tempo music plays ]
[ Children shouting ]
Gosh. It's lovely.
Beautiful!
Thank you.
[ Screams, gasps ]
[ Laughs ]
Let's go.
I'll be right back.
Don't go away.
[ Vehicles passing ]
[ Light music plays ]
The boys haven't arrived yet.
First thing for us to do
is find a place to stay.
And then we can see
the festival.
You can watch it
from the hotel window.
That's no fun.
Neither was being shot at
last night.
I've got enough to worry about
without wondering where you are.
That's not fair.
You want to go back
to your uncle?
-No, Guy.
-Then you mind me.
Yes, Guy.
He's gone!
Quick!
Pick it up,
and we'll make a run for it.
-I can't reach it!
-Huh?
Look. You're closer
to the ground than I am.
-You try it.
-Oh! Very well.
You lower me down onto it,
and I'll pick it up.
Right. Right.
Here we go.
-Casual.
-Right. Casual.
-Right.
Excuse me.
[ Mid-tempo music plays ]
Oh! Don't -- Let --
Get --
Get me up!
[ Mid-tempo music playing,
crowd cheering ]
[ "I Love Only One Girl" plays ]
♪ Oh, I love only one girl ♪
♪ The one I've got
my arms around ♪
♪ I love only one girl ♪
♪ One in every town ♪
♪ In Paris, there is Mimi,
and when the moon is bright ♪
♪ I love to take her walking
along the Seine each night ♪
♪ I kiss her on the Left Bank,
I kiss her on the Right ♪
♪ Oh, I love only one girl ♪
♪ The one I've got
my arms around ♪
♪ I love only one girl ♪
♪ One in every town ♪
[ Music continues ]
♪ I'm proud of my Brunhilda
in Frankfurt on the Rhine ♪
♪ Oh, she's a lot of woman,
and all of her is mine ♪
♪ Well, she can lift a Steinway
as easy as a stein ♪
♪ Oh, I love only one girl ♪
♪ The one I've got
my arms around ♪
♪ I love only one girl ♪
♪ One in every town ♪
♪ In Naples, there's Marie ♪
♪ How she can cook and flirt ♪
♪ You can't beat her lasagna ♪
♪ I eat until I hurt ♪
♪ And then she tops it off
with amore for dessert ♪
♪ Oh ♪
[ Music continues ]
[ "O du Lieber Augustin" plays ]
[ Mid-tempo music plays ]
[ Mid-tempo flamenco plays ]
[ Music continues ]
MAN:
Bravo! Bravo!
Ai! Ai!
[ Traditional Middle-Eastern
music plays ]
[ Light music plays ]
[ Music builds, continues ]
[ Laughter ]
♪ I love only one girl ♪
♪ The one I've got
my arms around ♪
♪ I love only one girl ♪
♪ One in every town ♪
♪ Oh, I love only one girl ♪
♪ The one I've got
my arms around ♪
♪ I love only one girl ♪
♪ One in every ♪
♪ Town ♪
[ Music continues ]
♪ I love only one girl ♪
♪ She's the girl ♪
♪ For me ♪
♪ I love only one girl ♪
♪ She's the girl for me ♪
-[ Music ends ]
-Tell me.
Isn't there a man somewhere
wondering where you are?
Oh, there are many men, darling.
I have an old beau
right here in Antwerp.
That's where I'm staying --
at his studio.
-Studio?
-Mm.
He's a sculptor.
You know, he takes globs
of wet, clammy clay
pushes it here, pokes it there,
and voilà -- a nude lady.
Well, that's one way.
Would you like to see it?
We could hop in my car
and be there in no time.
Would your friend with the wet,
clammy clay object?
No.
He's in Paris.
He won't be back for a week.
Sounds cozy.
Doesn't it?
Excuse me, Mr. Lambert.
May I have your autograph,
please?
-Why not?
-Uh, not with that.
-Would you like it in blood?
-Yes, please.
After I cut your throat.
About my cozy suggestion...
Any man in his right mind
wouldn't refuse.
-Unless he were in love.
-In love?
With that silly little
schoolgirl?
You better take another look,
Professor.
It's graduation day.
Uh, Claire...
Yeah.
I know.
Some other time.
I won't call you.
You call me.
Thanks.
I'll do that.
[ Dramatic music plays ]
[ Screams ]
-[ Laughter ]
-No! Don't! No!
-[ Gasps ]
-[ Laughter ]
Oh, that's very funny!
[ Indistinct conversations,
mid-tempo music playing ]
Oh.
I'm sorry.
Hello.
[ Music playing in distance ]
It's me.
The girl from the boat train.
Amazing.
I didn't recognize you.
-What are you doing --
Ladies first.
Oh.
I'm enjoying the festival.
And having a wonderful time,
as usual?
Mind if I join you?
I really wasn't going anywhere.
Oh.
Well, then let me be your guide.
All right.
Now, did you know that Antwerp
is the seat
of the oldest stock exchange?
-No.
-Yes indeed.
It's also the world center
of the diamond trade.
JILL: That's an interesting
thing to know.
[ Indistinct conversations ]
Jill?
[ Insects chirping ]
Jill!
Oh, it's so peaceful here.
I love the sound
of the crickets.
I discovered something
interesting the other day.
-Let me show you.
-All right.
It's in here.
[ Hinges creaking ]
[ Insects chirping ]
This well is as old as Antwerp.
I think they must have built
the city around it.
Is this part of your thesis?
M-My what? Oh! Oh, yes.
Yes, it is.
I've written a couple of pages
on Antwerp already.
Oh, you've dropped something.
Uh, your uncle gave this to me.
I see.
Then you're not a friend.
My uncle hired you to follow me.
Uh, that's not quite true,
Jillian.
I don't understand.
Well, it's --
it's really very simple.
Uncle Gerald's been dipping
into your inheritance.
There comes a day
of reckoning --
your 18th birthday.
You...see now how it is,
don't you, Jillian?
It's all been leading up
to this moment.
From the time you left London,
my associate and I have followed
your every move.
[ Dog barking in distance ]
This wood is rotten.
Even your light weight
should break the fence
and go through the boards.
I don't care about the money.
If you tell Uncle Gerald that,
then maybe --
There's -- There's an element
of greed in all of us, Jillian.
Oh, no!
I'm afraid the taste
of your money has increased
-your uncle's appetite.
-Oh, no! Please!
-Oh, I'm sorry, Jillian.
-No!
In a moment,
it will all be over.
No! Please!
No!
-[ Dog barking ]
-JILL: Help!
[ Breathing heavily, screaming ]
[ Jill screaming ]
[ Screaming, sobbing ]
You play pretty rough, mister.
Want to try me?
With pleasure.
[ Grunts ]
Ha!
Oh!
[ Dramatic music plays ]
Ha!
Aah!
[ Wood clattering ]
Oh!
[ Sobs ]
[ Crowd cheering,
music playing in distance ]
[ Music continues ]
[ Screams ]
Guy!
Guy! Guy!
GUY:
Jill?
[ Dramatic music plays ]
Guy! Guy!
Jill?
Come on!
[ Laughter, music continues ]
[ Screams ]
[ Grunts ]
Oh, Guy, I'm scared.
Take it easy.
I've never seen a dead man
before.
Oh, Guy,
what are we going to do?
Just what we planned to do.
I'll take you to Sweden and
your aunt can look after you.
-My who?
-Your aunt in Stockholm.
Oh, yes.
Aunt Charlotte.
Aunt Harriet.
[ Glass clattering ]
[ Dramatic music plays ]
[ Chuckles ]
-About here, I'd say.
-In all that water?
It'll put us two hours
out of Amsterdam.
But, Captain, are you sure
there ain't an easier way?
-Easier?
-What I mean is, uh,
a little less dangerous.
There's nothing to it.
We simply plant a tiny bomb
in the boiler room.
A bomb in the b--
By the time it goes off, we'll
be long gone away in a lifeboat!
PARROT:
[ Squawks ] Mutiny. Mutiny.
Oh!
[ Laughs ]
PARROT:
You dirty rats!
Yeah.
Quiet, you traitor.
[ Chuckles ]
You know, Captain,
it does sound quite simple.
It is. [ Chuckles ]
Oh, yes, it is, matey.
I have a friend who scuttled
his ship the very same way.
And what happened to him?
He's got a grocery business
in Putney now,
all with his share
of the insurance.
Groceries, eh?
MAN: Captain!
Passengers coming aboard!
-Passengers?
[ Parrot squawks, laughs ]
[ Horn blaring in distance ]
-Captain Roach?
-Hi. And who might you be?
-Your passengers, Captain.
-PARROT: Man the lifeboat.
-[ Squawks ] Bombs away.
-Uh, listen.
Have you ever thought of going
by plane?
It's much faster, you know,
and a lot safer.
Nobody travels by sea anymore!
I think it's a lovely boat.
A ship, lady.
A canoe is a boat.
Why don't you both go by canoe?
The SS Damocles.
That's what it says
on the ticket.
on your ship.
And that's good enough for us,
Captain.
-It leaks, you know.
-Like a sieve.
All right.
Give me your boarding passes.
Uh, we don't have
any boarding passes.
You mean you haven't
picked them up yet?
No. Uh, we can't go through
immigration to pick them up.
-Oh!
What's a couple of boarding
passes among friends, huh?
What do you think, we're
a couple spies or something?
We just want to sail on your
dirty ship, not blow it up.
PARROT: You're too late. There's
a bomb in the boiler room.
[ Laughing ] Well,
you leave me no alternative.
Off.
Huh?
Off!
[ Parrot squawks, whistles ]
ROACH:
Bye!
-Bye!
-PARROT: [ Laughing ]
JILL:
What do you suppose it says?
GUY:
Aren't the pictures enough?
Let's get out of here.
Goedemiddag.
Kan ik u helpen?
-We'd like a room, please.
-Oh.
My English is not good.
You will write, please?
Name?
And passport?
May I see, please?
[ Chuckling ]
It is not your passport.
-Oh!
-Oh. Oh.
It's a -- I-It's a game we play.
Yeah.
It's called, uh, button.
-Button. Who's got the --
-The, uh, button.
If you're not a tailor,
I'm in, uh, big trouble.
Nee, nee, Gerda.
[ Speaking Dutch ]
She is not right.
She thinks you are her husband
who ran away.
Oh, great.
She thinks every man
her husband.
-Room 5.
-[ Chuckles ]
Nee, nee, Gerda.
Hij is haar man.
Oh!
I tell her he's your man.
Is that another game you play?
-Oh, it's, uh -- it's, uh...
-Y-yeah, yeah.
It's called, uh...
Be Kind to Children Week.
A friend in need is a pest.
Yes.
-Which way, please?
-Over there.
Thank you.
[ Chuckling ]
Charming room.
Elegant design.
What would you call it?
Early poverty, to me.
Oh, gosh.
I'm done in.
Yeah.
I've had it.
[ Springs squeaking ]
[ Chuckles ]
What's so funny?
Oh, I was just thinking.
What's a nice little girl like
you doing in a dump like this?
Oh.
[ Chuckles ]
[ Down-tempo music plays ]
You said no more of that.
That's right.
It wouldn't be fair.
Not if you didn't love me.
You deserve a guy who tells you
more than a bedtime story.
You deserve the marrying kind.
And you're not
the marrying kind?
That's what I've been trying
to tell you.
[ Music continues ]
It won't work.
It just won't work.
[ "There Is So Much World
to See" plays ]
♪ Baby it's wrong ♪
♪ Wrong as can be ♪
♪ To try and tie a guy like me ♪
♪ I could never settle down ♪
♪ In a little sleepy town ♪
♪ There's so much world to see ♪
♪ Sure, we'd be happy ♪
♪ For a while ♪
♪ But then we'd have to part ♪
♪ When tears replace
your loving smile ♪
♪ Well, I don't want to be
the guy ♪
♪ Who has to break your heart ♪
♪ So here's where it ends ♪
♪ Not lovers but friends ♪
♪ Though your lips
are tempting me ♪
♪ Maybe I'm a fool and yet this
wanderer just can't forget ♪
♪ There's so much world to see ♪
♪ Sure, we'd be happy ♪
♪ For a while ♪
♪ But then we'd have to part ♪
♪ When tears replace
your loving smile ♪
♪ Well, I don't want to be
the guy ♪
♪ Who has to break your heart ♪
♪ So here's where it ends ♪
♪ Not lovers but friends ♪
♪ Though your lips
are tempting me ♪
♪ Maybe I'm a fool and yet this
wanderer just can't forget ♪
♪ There's so much world to see
for me ♪
♪ There's so much world ♪
♪ To see ♪
[ Music slows, ends ]
Guy, where are you going?
Just to make a phone call.
I think I found a way
to get us into Sweden.
Oh, please don't leave me here
alone.
I'll be back
just before you know it.
There he goes, Archie.
She's still in the hotel --
alone.
Right, and with the suitcase.
[ Light music plays ]
Don't muck it.
Casual, Arthur.
Casual.
[ Music continues ]
Goedemiddag, meneer.
Kan ik u helpen?
And goedemiddag to you too.
I'm, uh, looking for a girl --
uh, girl.
Oh. Again English.
Well, I'll try.
She's about, uh, so high.
Should be alone.
There was a man with her,
but he's gone.
Yes.
A shame.
She's not right.
Is that a fact?
Over there.
Room 7.
[ Light music plays ]
[ Telephone rings ]
Hello?
GUY: Uh, hello. Claire?
This is Guy.
Look. I-I'm -- I'm in trouble.
I-I need your help.
I think I'm running out of time.
What is it, Guy?
What's the matter?
Jill's at 89 Parkstraat.
You got that?
89 Parkstraat, room 5.
Room 5.
Yes.
I've got it.
There's no time to explain now.
I want you to pick her up
and take her back to the studio.
-Will you do it?
-Yes. Of course.
Okay. Thanks.
I'll meet you there later.
[ Grunts ]
-Are you Guy Lambert?
-Uh, yes, I am.
-Are you sure?
-Yeah, I'm sure.
I'm Sergeant Havert
from the Frooten Tooten,
and these are my two assistants
hardly worth mentioning.
-Sylvester.
-How do you do?
-And Harry.
-Pleasure to meet you.
-And I'm Herbert.
-How do you do?
And I'm sorry we have
the pleasant duty to arrest you.
-Arrest me? For what?
-Yes.
-Listen. I...
-[ Overlapping speech ]
I have to go. Really.
You don't understand.
[ Light music plays ]
I am Inspector de Groote.
Be seated, please.
Um, no, thanks.
I really can't stay.
Help Mr. Lambert to sit down,
please.
Oh.
Oops.
[ Chuckles ]
Well, if you really insist.
To begin with, Mr. Lambert,
would you be good enough
to tell us where we could find
Jillian Conway?
I never heard of her.
Let me warn you.
If your memory does not improve,
this friendly visit
could lengthen
into a permanent stay.
You can't hold me, de Groote.
[ Hand thuds ]
Inspecteur de Groote.
Not without charges.
As for the charges,
I have it on very good authority
that kidnapping is still
considered a criminal offense.
Kidnapping?
DE GROOTE:
You find that amusing?
Uh...
Well, not exactly.
You mean you don't want to
question me about, uh...
Kidnapping.
Imagine that.
Do you deny you took Miss Conway
by force?
Of course I --
Would you give the trio
a five-minute break?
They're boring holes
in the back of my neck.
[ Drumroll, light music plays ]
You been in touch
with Jill's uncle?
Mr. Waverly?
He's the one
who reported her missing.
He also suggested
you might help us find her.
And did he tell you why Jill
ran away in the first place?
Ah!
But did she run away?
Or was she kidnapped,
Mr. Lambert?
Which leads right back to me,
right?
Exactly.
So let us forget Mr. Waverly.
We can't forget Mr. Waverly.
He's the reason for it.
The only thing is the story
is too crazy to be believed.
Oh, but this crazy story --
Would Miss Conway support it?
Of course she would.
Then, Mr. Lambert, where is she?
Room 5, 89 Parkstraat.
[ Buzzer sounds ]
Mr. Lambert has decided
to be cooperative.
89 Parkstraat, room 5.
Thank you, Inspector.
You've been very kind.
Don't let him get away.
He's gonna kill her.
[ Buzzer sounds ]
[ Grunts ]
-What on earth?
-Stop it!
-What on earth are you doing?!
-Stop it, you idiots!
Take your hand
out of my pockets!
-This is the wrong man!
-Ow! Get -- Ow!
Stop it.
That's the wrong man, you idiot.
-Oh!
-Sorry. Sorry.
-So sorry. Sorry.
-Well, I never!
-Excuse me.
-Very sorry.
-Disgraceful!
-[ Door closes ]
-May I leave now, Inspector?
-But of course.
-Thank you.
That's right.
Call your hatchet man.
Give him the address
and have him do the job
you hired him for.
You're beginning to irritate me,
Lambert.
Murder is
an irritating business.
Inspector,
would you be good enough
to send one of your own men
for my niece?
Oh, certainly.
But you needn't feel you have to
prove anything to me, sir.
I shall sit right here
until Jillian arrives.
Right here, Lambert,
so you can plainly see I shall
make contact with no one.
89 Parkstraat, kamer 5.
[ Speaking Dutch ]
-89 Parkstraat, kamer 5.
[ Light music plays ]
We shall all sit and wait.
[ Trunk closes, engine starts ]
[ Stammering ]
What?!
They've got away!
If we lose them now,
it's all your fault, Arthur.
What were you doing in there,
anyway?
Mmm!
-Arthur!
-[ Gasps ]
Get in and let's get after them!
Get in, you great long drink
of water!
Get in!
For goodness' sake!
Don't "Archie" me!
You ought to be ashamed
of yourself!
Baby mouse!
Come back to the mama mouse!
-Come back to the mama!
-89 Parkstraat!
Mousie!
[ Up-tempo music plays ]
[ Down-tempo waltz plays ]
Excuse me, pussycat.
Mice!
Three!
[ Gasps ]
[ Fingers tapping ]
[ Telephone rings ]
Inspector de Groote.
No. I know you're not
I am Inspector de Groote!
Idiots!
-He is angry.
-DE GROOTE: Hello?
-Let me talk to him.
-DE GROOTE: Hello? Hello? Hello?
Let me talk to him.
-HERBERT: You dropped the phone.
-HARRY: Inspecteur? Inspecteur?
Hello?
Hello? Hello? H--
Inspector?
Inspecteur?
-DE GROOTE: Idiots!
-Just a moment, Inspecteur.
-De Groote?
I'll be with you in a bit,
Inspector.
-Just a moment.
-Let me talk to him. Give me --
Hello?
Where have you been?
-Not a trace of her.
-DE GROOTE: Idiots!
Without a trace?
I see.
Miss Conway has left the address
you gave us, Mr. Lambert.
Left?
Well, I hope for your sake
nothing happens to Jillian,
Lambert.
Well, how can it
with you sitting right here?
How long do you expect
to keep me under surveillance?
-Until midnight.
-Midnight?
Then we can all help Jill
celebrate her birthday.
Oh, this is absurd.
All right, Lambert.
I accept the challenge.
Good.
Inspector, what do you do
around here for amusement?
I arrest people.
You never lock the door
and play a little cards, maybe?
I am an inspector of police,
sir!
I have a position to uphold --
a position of respect and honor.
And I am, sir,
a man of integrity.
I'll thank you to remember that.
A little, uh, draw poker, maybe?
Fine!
Mr. Waverly?
No, thanks.
I'll catch up with the news.
Mr. Lambert?
Mm.
Business must be good.
Excuse me.
[ Vehicles passing in distance ]
[ Dramatic music plays ]
[ Door rattles ]
Shh!
[ Down-tempo music plays ]
[ Whispering ]
There it is, Arthur.
They've left it in the car!
-How obliging.
-[ Laughs ]
[ Music continues ]
I'll have that open
in two seconds flat.
Casual, Arthur.
Casual.
[ Door closes ]
Shh!
-Where?
-[ Footsteps approaching ]
[ Down-tempo music plays ]
There's sure a panic going on
inside of you,
isn't there, Uncle?
The time's running out,
and you know it.
Please. Mr. Lambert,
make your play.
You're bluffing.
You've been bluffing
all evening!
-Oh, I assure you, I am not.
-I wasn't talking to you.
If I may, Inspector,
I'd like to make a phone call.
Aha!
I'm late now
for a dinner engagement.
I should phone
and make my apologies.
Not on your life.
If you don't mind, Mr. Lambert,
it is my phone.
Inspector, he's gonna call his
hatchet man and tell him to --
To what, Mr. Lambert?
To kill my niece?
And where shall I tell him
to look for her?
You're the only one
with that information.
Mr. Waverly,
please make your call.
-GERALD: Thank you, Inspector.
-Inspector, look.
You shouldn't let him do it.
Mr. Lambert,
please make your play.
GUY:
Mm. Make his play.
[ Telephone ringing ]
Hello?
Is anybody there?
Well, if it's not "hello,"
it's obviously "goodbye."
[ Chuckles ]
Cheers.
No answer.
Thank you anyway, Inspector.
[ Indistinct conversations ]
Oh, I-I can hardly keep
my eyes open.
The bedroom's
right through there.
Why don't you lie down
for a while?
I think I'd better.
Mr. Lambert, please.
Mr. Lambert, make your play,
please.
It's beginning to get to you,
isn't it?
Look at you!
Your nerves are starting
to crawl.
Aren't they?!
Well, why aren't they?!
Tell me that.
I hate a sore loser.
That phone call.
That phone call!
That's it, isn't it?
[ Foot thuds ]
You knew where Jill was
all along.
Uncle Gerald, you are a fink!
[ Mid-tempo music plays ]
What was that?
I believe Mr. Lambert
just escaped, Inspector.
You fools!
What are you doing?
After him!
Look!
He stole my car!
Oh, this is a criminal offense.
Follow me!
Are you coming, Uncle Gerald?
I wouldn't miss it.
[ Music builds, continues ]
Quick!
Move the car.
Go! Go!
-Go! Go!
-[ Siren wailing ]
[ Tires screeching ]
Do not lose sight of the car!
Faster!
[ Tires screeching,
siren wailing ]
Don't let him get away!
[ Music continues ]
[ Siren wailing ]
Left!
Turn left!
No! No, no. To the right.
To the right.
[ Siren wailing,
tires screeching ]
engine revving ]
Hello? You idiots.
Where are you?
Hello?
Hello? Idiots!
Where are you?
Why should we tell you?
Who's this speaking, please?
Attention!
This is Inspector de Groote.
Lambert is traveling west
on Plas Kubert.
Where are you?!
In police car number 6.
Where are you?
-Where am I?
-In police car number 1 .
In police car number 1 .
Idiots.
-"Over and out."
-Over and out.
"We hear you loud and clearly."
HERBERT:
We hear you loud and clearly.
-"In your hat."
-In your hat.
In your hat?
Idiot!
There he is!
[ Siren wailing ]
[ Up-tempo music plays ]
Quick!
Hello?
Lambert has just turned
north on Wiitendir.
Converge!
[ Music continues ]
[ Siren wailing,
tires screeching ]
[ Footsteps approaching ]
[ Dramatic music plays ]
[ Gas hissing ]
Faster.
Slower.
-Faster. Faster.
-Slower. Slower.
Idiot! Now we have lost him!
He's gone!
Uh...
Hello.
We have just lost sight
of Lambert.
Can you pick him up?
Can you see him?
[ Tires screeching ]
[ Music ends ]
Sylvester, can you see him?
No.
I can't even see you.
Harry, can you see him?
Not yet.
[ Zipper whirs ]
I can't see him either.
[ Gas hissing,
footsteps approaching ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Gunshot ]
CLAIRE:
Oh!
[ Grunting ]
[ Tires screech, engine stops ]
[ Gunshot ]
[ Dramatic music plays ]
[ Music continues ]
CLAIRE:
[ Grunts ]
[ Fists thudding ]
[ Gas hissing ]
[ Gun clatters ]
[ Hissing stops ]
[ Glass clattering ]
Jill?
Are you all right?
JILL:
I still feel a little groggy.
GUY:
You'll be okay now.
He's out cold.
You have an amazing right
for a singer.
Your left's not so bad, either.
That's far enough, sweetheart.
I was afraid of that.
-Look! There it is! My car.
-[ Siren wailing ]
Converge on my car!
-Hey!
-Ah.
[ Siren wailing ]
[ Engine revving ]
Sit down.
[ Crash, tires screeching ]
[ Men groaning ]
DE GROOTE:
Idiots!
Fools!
What are you doing?!
-I am Inspector de Groote --
-[ Groans ]
Oh, Uncle Gerald.
Are you all right?
-Yes, I'm all right.
-Follow me! Follow me!
I am Inspector de Groote.
I'll take charge.
Oh! Uh, no one will leave
this room until I do.
Hello, Uncle Gerald.
-Jillian!
-Alive and kicking.
The party broke up just before
the gas heater took effect.
Gas heater?
You can't connect me
with any of this, Lambert.
Would you care to make a wager?
Inspector.
Oh!
That poor sweet eye, madame!
How did that happen?
He hit me.
It's the only way I could get
this gun away from her.
Inspector, you've apparently
apprehended the right party now.
Oh, don't be so ridiculous,
Gerald.
Jail is no place for a lady.
Do you know Mr. Waverly, madame?
Intimately.
Will you be quiet, Claire?
Don't you understand, love?
If I go, you go.
Claire is the one
Uncle Gerald called
-from your office, Inspector.
-[ Detectives gasp ]
It was a signal that he was
somewhere safe with a good alibi
and for her to turn the gas on.
I'd have given you the money,
every shilling.
Now she tells him.
Claire wanted so many things.
I...
I needed the money for her.
Do you realize what
you are saying, Mr. Waverly?
Unfortunately.
Then it is my duty
to place you both under arrest.
Well, do it, then,
and get it over with.
Arrest this man!
Madame?
[ Light music plays ]
Damaging evidence.
[ Down-tempo music plays ]
[ Door closes ]
Well...
[ Sighs ]
That's that.
I guess I'll be leaving now.
[ Sighs ]
Well, goodbye.
Goodbye.
I'm sorry I lied to you
about so many things.
-I lied to you too.
-About what?
I said I didn't love you.
Oh.
Guy!
-Are you still here?
-You love me!
-You mean it!
-Now, wait a minute, Jill.
Say it.
-I love you.
-Oh!
Watch the wine.
-Kiss me.
-Not yet.
What?
-Okay. Happy birthday.
-[ Laughs ]
[ Light music plays ]
[ Laughs ]
GRAYSON:
Oh.
[ Grunting ]
[ Straining ]
Grayson's the name.
Scotland Yard!
Whoops.
[ "Rule, Britannia" plays ]
Where is it?
What?
Scotland Yard?
No.
I know where that is.
Your black suitcase.
It's in the car.
Gone!
-So are the jewels.
-What jewels?
Diamonds smuggled into
your suitcase on the boat train.
If you knew that,
then why did you wait till now?
I wanted to catch them with
the diamonds in their pockets.
Who?
Babcock and Brown, that's who!
[ Horn blaring ]
Ah. Nothing quite like an
ocean voyage, is there, Arthur?
Right.
You know, things have worked out
rather well.
Don't you think so, Archie?
They did.
They did indeed.
What do you suppose happened
to that little schoolgirl?
-Do you think he married her?
-See for yourself.
[ Horn blaring ]
[ Explosions echoing ]
Shall we go below?
[ Water splashing ]
What a kiss!
Come on, Arthur!
Come on!
Have you got the suitcase?
Have you got the case?
Don't worry, Archie!
I've got it!
You've got it, all right!
Well, you'd better go back
and get the rest of it!
Whoa!
Heave!
Ho!
-Heave! Ho!
-PARROT: [ Squawks ]
This is another fine mess
you've gotten me into, matey.
Heave!
Ho!
[ Gurgling ]
Heave! Ho!
PARROT:
[ Squawks ]
Ahoy there.
Do you know what this is?
It's the end, pal --
the ever-loving livin' end.
[ Mid-tempo music plays ]
[ Up-tempo music plays ]
[ Music ends ]